<Organization>Document</Organization> 1501
A CONVERSATION WITH DON ROBERTS. PART TWO.
     
IN THE 2ND PART OF AN OCT 80 <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization> INTERVIEW (THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> PART WAS <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization>
IN TECHNICALITIES 1 (2) JAN 81 (SEE 81/5014) DON ROBERTS <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
<Organization>PAPERLESS</Organization> REVOLUTION, <Organization>QUANTUM</Organization> LEAPS IN TECHNOLOGY, <Organization>GUERILLA COMMUNICATIONS</Organization>
(<Organization>USE</Organization> OF BIG <Organization>BUSINESS</Organization> APPARATUS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization> NETWORKS FOR ALTERNATIVE
<Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>), THE NEED TO EXPAND <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NETWORKS, AND THE
MINDS THAT ARE PRECEDING AND BEING AFFECTED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>THESE</Organization> CHANGES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1502
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>FAROE ISLANDS</Location>.
     
THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE <Location>FAROE ISLANDS</Location> (FAERO COUNTY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, NOW CALLED
FOROYA LANDSBOKASAVN) WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1828. <Organization>DESCRIBES ITS DEVELOPMENT</Organization>
DESPITE MANY ACUTE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>, DETERIORATION AFTER THE DEATH OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> IN
1878, RECOVERY FROM 1920 (THANKS TO A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization>), AND MOVEMENT <Organization>INTO</Organization> A NEW
<Organization>BUILDING</Organization> IN 1980. OUTLINES THE FINANCIAL SITUATION OF THE ISLANDS&apos; <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND GIVES FIGURES FOR STOCK, BORROWERS, AND LOANS. DRAWS ATTENTION
TO THE SITUATION OF THE FAROESE LANGUAGE-IT WAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> TAUGHT IN <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> SCHOOLS
UNTIL <Organization>THIS</Organization> CENTURY; 80-100 BOOKS AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>SMALL</Organization> PUBLICATIONS ARE <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN
FAROESE ANNUALLY; AND MOST PRINTED MATTER IS IN DANISH.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1503
OREGONIANS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES.
     
COMPILED IN <Organization>RESPONSE</Organization> TO QUESTIONS FROM OREGON CITIZENS ABOUT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization>, <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>REPORT</Organization> CONTAINS&apos; (1) <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
DESCRIPTION OF THE GOVERNOR&apos;S <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES
HELD IN JUNE 78; (2) DELEGATE&apos;S VIEWPOINT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE THE WHITE HOUSE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES (WHCLIS); (3) SAMPLING OF WHCLIS RESOLUTIONS;
(4) INTERVIEW WITH OREGON&apos;S <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization>, MARCIA LOWELL; (5) SYNOPSIS OF
RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE GOVERNOR&apos;S <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>; (6) GLOSSARY; (7) LISTING OF
OREGON&apos;S DELEGATES TO WHCLIS; (8) REPRINT OF A WALL STREET <Organization>JOURNAL</Organization> EDITORIAL
<Organization>ON</Organization> WHCLIS; AND (9) MAIL-BACK FOR READERS OF THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization>. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>
FROM NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1504
<Organization>EXTENDING SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND COMMUNITY <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> TO A SCATTERED
<Organization>POPULATION</Organization>&apos; <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>.
     
IT WILL BE APPARENT FROM THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> FACING <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location> TODAY; THE
OBSTACLES FOUND IN THE TERRAIN, THE <Organization>INADEQUATE ROAD SYSTEMS</Organization>, THE CULTURAL AND
LINGUISTIC DIVERSITY, THE UNEQUAL <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>ITS</Organization>
PEOPLE, THAT THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A <Organization>NATIONWIDE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, EVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>PRIMARY SCHOOL</Organization> LEVEL, AND THE SPREAD OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RELEVANT TO THE PEOPLE&apos;S
<Organization>WAY</Organization> OF <Organization>LIFE</Organization> AND HELPFUL IN A <Organization>TIME</Organization> OF URGENT CHANGE, IS AN ENORMOUS TASK. TO
SPEAK OF <Organization>EXTENDING SERVICES</Organization> WHERE ALMOST NONE EXIST <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE TO IGNORE THE
REALITIES AFFECTING THE DEVELOPMENT OF SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MEANS OF
KEEPING PEOPLE INFORMED THROUGH THE MEDIUM OF <Organization>PRINT</Organization>. <Organization>SOME</Organization> PROPOSALS FOR
<Organization>INCREASING</Organization> THE EFFICIENCY OF <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> SCHOOLS TO ENABLE THEM TO SERVE THE
COMMUNITY IN DIFFERENT WAYS ARE OFFERED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1505
<Location>GREENLAND</Location>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> THROUGH 150 YEARS.
     
1980 WAS THE 150<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNIVERSARY OF <Location>GREENLAND</Location>&apos;S 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (IN THE
CAPITAL, <Location>GODTHAB</Location>) AND WAS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> THE YEAR IN WHICH RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE
COUNTRY&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> PASSED FROM <Location>DENMARK</Location> TO GREENLAND&apos;S <Organization>HOME</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>.
<Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> OUTLINES THE SERVICE&apos;S HISTORY UP TO 1956 AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> SUBSEQUENT
EVENTS IN GREATER DETAIL. IN 1956, A <Organization>PROPER COUNTRY-WIDE SERVICE</Organization> WAS
ESTABLISHED TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> DANISH-LANGUAGE CHILDREN&apos;S BOOKS TO <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> TEACHING OF
DANISH IN SCHOOLS, AND GREENLANDIC MATERIAL FOR THOSE SPEAKING ONLY THAT
LANGUAGE. THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>GODTHAB</Location> (LATER DESIGNATED THE <Location>GREENLAND</Location> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>) BEGAN TO BUILD A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF GREENLANDIC MATERIAL. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE&apos;S <Organization>MAIN</Organization> HANDICAP IS THE ACUTE SHORTAGE OF MATERIAL IN GREENLANDIC.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1506
GIANTS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.
     
ATTEMPTS TO IDENTIFY THE SIGNIFICANT CONTRIBUTORS IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>. WORK CITED IN 4 DIFFERENT EDITIONS OF THE 2HANDBOOK OF
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK1, <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> ASLIB, <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>BEEN</Organization>
CONSIDERED AS THE BASE FOR <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization>. THE NAME OF S.R. RANGANATHAN TOPS THE
LIST OF 25 NAMES SELECTED <Organization>BY</Organization> ANALYSING THE DATA. RESULTS OBTAINED IN <Organization>THIS</Organization>
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>BEEN</Organization> COMPARED WITH AN EARLIER <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1507
ZZZZ.
     
A <Organization>NEW</Organization> QUARTERLY <Organization>JOURNAL</Organization> AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> A FORUM FOR <Organization>INTERDISCIPLINARY</Organization>
COOPERATION IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF PRINCIPLES FOR THE <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
OF <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> SIGNIFICANCE. ATTEMPTS TO UNDERSTAND THE
NATURE OF PSYCHOLOGICAL PROCESSES IN THE <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
<Organization>PUBLISHED BY INFORMATION DESIGN</Organization> <Organization>JOURNAL LTD</Organization>, THE WHITE HOUSE, POOLSIDE,
MADELEY, CREWE, CW3 9DX.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1508
PRESENT <Organization>STATE</Organization> AND PROSPECTS OF STANDARDISATION IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization>.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF <Organization>FURTHER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF STANDARDISATION IN <Organization>SOVIET</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHY</Organization>, EDITING AND
<Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> EFFORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CREATING</Organization> A COMPLEX STANDARDISATION PROGRAMME
FOR 1980 AND 1981-85 AND STRESSES <Organization>ITS</Organization> IMPORTANCE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1509
QUALITATIVE APPROACHES TO THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>.
     
AN INVITED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SEMINAR <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>APPLICATION</Organization> OF QUALITATIVE APPROACHES TO
THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> WAS HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>UK OPEN UNIVERSITY</Organization>, NOV 79.
<Organization>THIS</Organization> SYMPOSIUM IS AN ATTEMPT TO BUILD UPON THE SEMINAR DISCUSSIONS AND TO OPEN
THE DEBATE TO A WIDER AUDIENCE. IT CONTAINS REVISED AND EXPANDED VERSIONS OF
<Organization>SOME</Organization> SEMINAR PAPERS AND SPECIALLY-PREPARED PAPERS <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> A <Organization>FULLER</Organization>
BACKGROUND TO THE DEBATE. FOR <Organization>ABSTRACTS</Organization> OF THE PAPERS, SEE THE FOLLOWING
SERIAL NUMBERS:.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1510
<Organization>USING</Organization> QUALITATIVE METHODS.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ISSUE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>APPLICATION</Organization> OF QUALITATIVE APPROACHES TO
THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>. AN IN-DEPTH DISCUSSION OF ONE QUALITATIVE
APPROACH-ETHNOGRAPHY. <Organization>ITS</Organization> DISTINCTIVE CHARACTER DERIVES FROM <Organization>ITS</Organization> UNDERLYING
<Organization>METHODOLOGICAL</Organization> PRINCIPLES-A CONCERN WITH THE DISCOVERY, GENERATION, AND
DEVELOPMENT, AS WELL AS <Organization>TESTING</Organization>, OF THEORY; A COMMITMENT TO LEARNING THE
CULTURE OF THOSE BEING STUDIED; AND A RECOGNITION OF THE IMPORTANCE OF
CONTEXT. <Organization>AGAINST</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> BACKGROUND, OUTLINES <Organization>SOME</Organization> ETHNOGRAPHICAL
TECHNIQUES-GROUNDED THEORISING (THEORETICAL SAMPLING AND THE CONSTANT
COMPARATIVE METHOD) AND <Organization>TESTING</Organization> THEORY (TRIANGULATION AND ANALYTIC INDUCTION).
STRESSES THAT <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS A <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TRADITION STILL IN THE THROES OF DEVELOPMENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1511
SOURCES OF ANTAGONISM TO &apos;QUALITATIVE&apos; <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>APPLICATION</Organization> OF QUALITATIVE APPROACHES TO THE
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>. <Organization>CONSIDERS</Organization> WHY <Organization>QUANTITATIVE</Organization> METHODS ARE BELIEVED
TO BE MORE &apos;<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>&apos;, RIGOROUS, AND VALID THAN QUALITATIVE ONES AND ARGUES
THAT THE TERM &apos;QUALITATIVE&apos; IS APPLIED TO DIFFERENT ASPECTS OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WHICH
ARE SUFFICIENTLY INDEPENDENT OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> TO MAKE THE
<Organization>QUANTITATIVE</Organization>/QUALITATIVE DISTINCTION ARTIFICIAL. SUGGESTS THAT CRITICISMS OF
QUALITATIVE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARE &apos;IDEOLOGICAL IN THE SENSE THAT THEY GIVE <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> TO
<Organization>EXISTING</Organization> INSTITUTIONS WHEREIN <Organization>SOME</Organization> CLASSES OR GROUPS (<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SPONSORS) TRY
TO EXERT CONTROL OVER OTHERS&apos;. TYPICAL CRITICISMS OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARE
ANALYSED TO EXPOSE THE NATURE OF THE UNDERLYING EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1512
A CASE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IN QUALITATIVE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>?.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>APPLICATION</Organization> OF QUALITATIVE APPROACHES TO THE
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>. REFLECTS UPON THE METHODOLOGY ADOPTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
AUTHOR IN PROJECT INISS (<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES IN LOCAL
AUTHORITY <Organization>SOCIAL SERVICES</Organization> DEPARTMENTS). THE CHOSEN METHOD, <Organization>STRUCTURED</Organization>
OBSERVATION, COMBINED QUALITATIVE AND <Organization>QUANTITATIVE</Organization> MODES OF ANALYSIS AND
REPORTING. <Organization>CONSIDERS VARIOUS RESEARCH MANAGEMENT</Organization> ISSUES IN FIELD <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> OF
<Organization>THIS</Organization> KIND. THE AUTHOR&apos;S <Organization>AIM</Organization> IS TO FIND A MEANS OF <Organization>GATHERING</Organization> MORE MEANINGFUL
<Organization>QUANTITATIVE DATA</Organization> RATHER THAN <Organization>REJECTING QUANTITATIVE DATA</Organization> AS <Organization>SUCH</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1513
THE TRAVELLING WORKSHOPS EXPERIMENT: AN ATTEMPT <Organization>AT</Organization> &apos;ILLUMINATIVE EVALUATION&apos;.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>APPLICATION</Organization> OF QUALITATIVE APPROACHES TO THE
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>. AN ACCOUNT OF THE BACKGROUND <Organization>AGAINST</Organization> WHICH A
NON-TRADITIONAL STRATEGY OF EVALUATION WAS ADOPTED IN <Location>NEWCASTLE</Location>-UPON-TYNE
POLYTECHNIC&apos;S TRAVELLING WORKSHOPS EXPERIMENT (SEE 77/3731). THE CLEAR-CUT
DISTINCTIONS ORIGINALLY ENVISAGED FOR THE INTERNAL AND EXTERNAL COMPONENTS OF
THE EVALUATION BECAME BLURRED AND THERE WAS CONFLICT BETWEEN PRESSURES FOR A
TRADITIONAL, TIGHTLY-CONTROLLED EVALUATION AND THE RESEARCHERS&apos; PREFERENCE FOR
A MORE EXPLANATORY EVALUATION STRATEGY. ILLUMINATIVE EVALUATION WAS USED; <Organization>THIS</Organization>
ESCHEWS PRE- AND POST-TESTING IN FAVOUR OF A WIDE-RANGING <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE
CONTEXTUAL DETERMINANTS OF A VENTURE&apos;S SUCCESS. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> POSES MANY <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>
BECAUSE IT IS A BROAD STRATEGY RATHER THAN A SET OF SPECIFIC TECHNIQUES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1514
<Organization>USING</Organization> CASE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>APPLICATION</Organization> OF QUALITATIVE APPROACHES
TO THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>. <Organization>EXAMINES</Organization> CASE-STUDY <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, <Organization>ITS</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS. THE AUTHOR HAS RECENTLY STARTED A
PROJECT WHICH USES MULTI-SITE CASE STUDIES TO EXAMINE 6TH-FORMERS&apos; CAPACITY
FOR INDEPENDENT LIBRARY-BASED WORK. USES <Organization>THIS</Organization> AS A FRAMEWORK TO DISCUSS
QUESTIONS TO BE CONSIDERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THOSE CONTEMPLATING <Organization>THIS</Organization> SORT OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
<Organization>CONSIDERS</Organization> 3 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> SOURCES OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (INTERVIEWS, DOCUMENTS, AND
OBSERVATION); <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INTEGRATION <Organization>INTO</Organization> CASE RECORDS; AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF NARRATION,
VIGNETTE, AND ANALYSIS AS REPORTING METHODS. POINTS <Organization>OUT</Organization> THAT IT IS CRUCIAL TO
FIND FORMS OF PRESENTATION CONDUCIVE TO A CRITICAL REACTION FROM THE READER.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1515
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RESEARCH-SCRUTINY OF AN INVESTIGATION.
     
COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A PROGRAMME
FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. APPROVES THE PROGRAMME&apos;S STRESS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
QUALIFICATIONS FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. THE PROGRAMME IS THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> ATTEMPT
<Organization>AT</Organization> A SURVEY AND ANALYSIS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location> AND RIGHTLY STRESSES
THE NEED FOR DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DIFFERENT ATTITUDES TO AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
ARTS AND THE <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>. <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT NEGLECTS AN OBVIOUS <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AREA-COOPERATION
BETWEEN DIFFERENT TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR EFFICIENT <Organization>USE</Organization> OF SCARCE RESOURCES. IN A
<Organization>TIME</Organization> OF ECONOMIC DIFFICULTIES IT BECOMES NECESSARY TO CARRY <Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WHICH
MAY <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> ARGUMENTS VIS-A-VIS THE <Organization>GRANT</Organization> GIVING AUTHORITIES FOR
&apos;NON-QUANTIFIABLE INCOME&apos; <Organization>OR SERVICE</Organization> IMPROVEMENTS. THE EMPHASIS IN THE
PROGRAMME WILL <Organization>AT</Organization> 1<Organization>ST</Organization> RIGHTLY BE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> STUDIES AND STUDIES AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>IMPROVING SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1516
CULTURAL STRUGGLE AND CIVIL <Organization>COURAGE</Organization>.
     
INTERVIEWS AASE BREDSDORFF, UNTIL RECENTLY INSPECTOR WITH THE DANISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
INSPECTORATE DEALING MAINLY WITH CHILDREN&apos;S SERVICES. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> HER
INVOLVEMENT WITH IFLA, WHERE SHE WAS CHAIRMAN OF THE CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SECTION UNTIL 1971 AND THEN <Organization>MEMBER</Organization> OF THE <Organization>STANDING ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization>. SHE WAS
CHAIRMAN OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INSPECTORATE&apos;S <Organization>WORKING PARTY ON LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO
IMMIGRANT CHILDREN. HER PROPOSAL IN THE <Organization>REPORT ON CENTRAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO
CHILDREN, THAT CONSULTANTS FROM THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD BE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS REGRETFULLY <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>TAKEN</Organization> UP. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> STAFFING OF
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND EDUCATION OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE DANISH
<Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>, WHERE SHE HAS TAUGHT SINCE 1948 AND <Organization>BEEN</Organization> A <Organization>MEMBER</Organization> OF A CONTACT
COMMITTEE. COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DISCUSSION OF <Organization>WHETHER SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD BE
PLACED UNDER THE SCHOOLS <Organization>ACT</Organization> OR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> HER INVOLVEMENT
WITH THE ILLEGAL MOVEMENT IN OCCUPIED <Location>DENMARK</Location> AND AFTER THE WAR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
DEBATE AND TRADE UNION <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>. COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE QUALITY OF CHILDREN&apos;S
BOOKS, THE PRINCIPLE OF COMPREHENSIVENESS IN RELATION TO ACQUISITION OF
CHILDREN&apos;S BOOKS, AND THE ROLE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN DEFENCE OF CIVIL LIBERTIES IN
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1517
<Organization>NATIONAL WORKING PARTY</Organization> OF <Organization>INDIAN COOPERATIVE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND DOCUMENTATION
<Organization>OFFICERS</Organization> (N.C.U.I.).
     
OUTLINES THE OBJECTIVES AND FUNCTIONS AND COMPOSITION OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>WORKING</Organization>
PARTY OF <Organization>INDIAN COOPERATIVE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND DOCUMENTATION <Organization>OFFICERS</Organization> (OF THE
<Organization>NATIONAL COOPERATIVE UNION</Organization> OF <Location>INDIA</Location>) AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> CONSTITUENT COMMITTEES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1518
<Organization>MAP</Organization> COLLECTIONS AND <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>&apos; A SYNOPSIS.
     
OUTLINES THE HISTORY OF LAND SURVEYING AND MAPPING IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>, AND REVIEWS
<Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> THE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>MAP</Organization> COLLECTIONS IN&apos; <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DEPARTMENTS; <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND UNIVERSITIES. NOTES THE CONTENT, STAFFING, STORAGE, AND
ACCOMMODATION OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> COLLECTIONS, AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE PRESENT FACILITIES FOR
THE TRAINING OF <Organization>MAP</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. POINTS <Organization>OUT</Organization> THE NEED FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF A
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>MAP</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, AND A <Organization>NATIONAL UNION</Organization> CATALOGUE OF MAPS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1519
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IN <Organization>SCIENTIFIC COMMUNICATIONS</Organization>.
     
A LOOK <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RECURRENCE AND A COMPARATIVE ANALYSIS OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> FRAMEWORK ARE
BROUGHT TO BEAR <Organization>ON</Organization> A VERIFICATION OF THE <Organization>CONCEPT</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization>
IS PROVED TO BE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND MORE SELECTIVE IN <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> THAN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, TRANSLATION, OR <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>. IT DIFFERS FROM <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
DEVELOPMENT <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> GOALS AND FUNCTIONS. ARGUES THAT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>TASKS</Organization> SHOULD
BE <Organization>DISTRIBUTED</Organization> AMONG THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> UNITS AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>OR DESIGN</Organization> DIVISIONS OF
A <Organization>GIVEN ENTERPRISE OR OFFICE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1520
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> DESIGN&apos; <Organization>HAVE</Organization> THEY ANYTHING TO COMMUNICATE
TO ONE ANOTHER?.
     
<Organization>EXAMINES</Organization> THE <Organization>CONCEPT</Organization> OF &apos;<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>&apos; AS THE TERM IN &apos;<Organization>INFORMATION DESIGN</Organization>&apos;
STILL LARGELY <Organization>TAKEN</Organization> FOR GRANTED AND PROPOSES AN APPROACH FROM <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> WHICH <Organization>CAN</Organization> <Organization>OFFER</Organization> A <Organization>USEFUL THEORETICAL FOUNDATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>INFORMATION DESIGN</Organization>
TOO. IT <Organization>ALSO</Organization> LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE WAYS OF THINKING ABOUT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WHICH ARE
EMPLOYED <Organization>BY</Organization> PRACTITIONERS IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK, THOSE WHO DEAL WITH TEXTS FROM
THE POINT OF VIEW OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RETRIEVAL AND WHO <Organization>ACT</Organization> AS INTERMEDIARIES
BETWEEN GENERATORS AND USERS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PRACTICE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization>
GROUP OF INTERMEDIARIES IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> HAS, IT IS ARGUED, <Organization>SOME</Organization>
<Organization>USEFUL</Organization> INSIGHTS FOR THAT OF THE <Organization>OTHER GROUP</Organization>-INFORMATION DESIGNERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1521
THEORY AND PRACTICE IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>&apos; THE TEACHING-LEARNING PROCESS.
     
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE PROBLEM OF THEORY AND PRACTICE IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>. <Organization>BASIC</Organization> TO A
RESOLUTION OF PRINCIPLES AND TECHNIQUES IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IS THE NEED TO
ARTICULATE A CONCEPTUAL FRAMEWORK FOR SELF-APPROPRIATED LEARNING, <Organization>SO</Organization> THAT AN
UNDERSTANDING OF THEORY, GROUNDED IN PRACTICAL <Organization>TASKS</Organization>, ARISES FROM THE LOGICAL
PROCESSES OF A SECURE AND RELIABLE PEDAGOGY. THE WORK IS INTENDED FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATORS, STUDENTS AND PRACTISING PROFESSIONALS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1522
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>&apos; A <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> VIEW.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE ESSENTIAL ELEMENTS OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>, AND
<Organization>CONSIDERS</Organization> THE IMPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP EDUCATION</Organization> OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> RECENT WORLD
TRENDS IN THE PROFESSION, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>&apos; THE DEVELOPMENT OF DATA BASES; THE
<Organization>APPLICATION</Organization> OF THE MANAGEMENT <Organization>CONCEPTS</Organization> OF COST CONTROL, COST-BENEFIT AND
EFFECTIVE MANPOWER PLANNING; THE TREND TOWARDS THE NOTION OF A GRADUATE
PROFESSION; AND THE TENDENCY FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK TO COME
TOGETHER. HIGHLIGHTS THE NEED FOR GREATER COHESION AND UNDERSTANDING BETWEEN
THE EDUCATORS AND THE PROFESSIONALS IN PRACTICE, AND FOR MORE ATTENTION TO
OVERALL MANPOWER PLANNING BOTH FOR THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PLANNING
OF SERVICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1523
THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PREPARATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS AT UNIVERSITY</Organization> LEVEL.
     
THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> TRAINING OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> HAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> IMPROVED IN <Location>ITALY</Location> DURING THE
LAST 50 YEARS. UNIVERSITY REFORM HAS COMPLETELY IGNORED THE PROBLEM OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> IN RESPECT OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND TEACHING. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> SHOULD TAKE
DEGREE COURSES IN THE SPECIFIC DISCIPLINES OF THE CULTURAL AREAS SERVED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN WHICH THEY INTEND TO WORK. <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PREPARATION <Organization>CAN</Organization><Organization>NOT</Organization> BE
CONSIDERED COMPLETE WITHOUT ADEQUATE PRACTICAL EXPERIENCE. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> LACKING
THE CAPACITY TO ORGANISE A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> TRADITIONAL LINES WILL <Organization>NOT</Organization> PROFIT MUCH
FROM THE ASSISTANCE OF <Organization>ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY</Organization>. THE UNIVERSITY SHOULD RATIONALISE
<Organization>ITS</Organization> OWN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND CONCENTRATE <Organization>ITS INTERNAL SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> LEVELS <Organization>ON</Organization>
SATISFYING THE REQUESTS OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> POTENTIAL READERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1524
EDUCATION OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization> IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A FINNISH ISSUE. <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> <Organization>SURVEYS</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>, PARTICULARLY DURING THE 1970S, AND OUTLINES THE 4
1/2-YEAR COURSE LEADING TO A MASTER&apos;S DEGREE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>TAMPERE</Location>
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1525
CONTINUALLY CHANGING.
     
COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>BORAS LIBRARY HIGH SCHOOL</Organization>, <Location>SWEDEN</Location> FOR 1979-80.
THE CHANGING FORMS OF THE EDUCATION FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND THE QUESTION OF AN
EDUCATION FOR TUTOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE DISCUSSED. WHEN REVIEWING THE CAPACITY OF
THE SCHOOL IT IS CLEAR THAT IT HAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> RESPONDED WELL TO THE CHANGING LABOUR
MARKET, SOMETIMES PRODUCING OVER-, SOMETIMES UNDERCAPACITY. CRITICISES THE
PLANS FOR <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> SHORTER TRAINING COURSES AS THEY MIGHT REDUCE INTEREST IN
THE 2-YEAR <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> COURSE. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> THE EDUCATION FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> SHOULD BE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> WITH SPECIALISATION AFTER A FOUNDATION COURSE,
AS THE STUDENT REPRESENTATIVES WANT, OR <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> COURSES SHOULD BE
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> EARLIER, AND ARGUES FOR MORE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> KNOWLEDGE OF
ADMINISTRATION, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK, AND OUTREACH <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, WHICH <Organization>CAN</Organization><Organization>NOT</Organization> BE
<Organization>ACQUIRED</Organization> THROUGH COSTLY IN-SERVICE TRAINING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1526
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT</Organization>-A SURVEY.
     
REPORTS THE RESULTS OF A SAMPLE SURVEY CONDUCTED TO FIND <Organization>OUT</Organization> THE NATURE OF
JOBS PERFORMED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization> WITH TRAINING IN <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, RELATING
THEM TO THE CONTENTS OF <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> COURSES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1527
THE DIPLOMA IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>: A CRITICAL <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.
     
REPLY TO AN ARTICLE IN OPEN 12 (9) SEPT 80, 397-404 (SEE 81/1865) IN WHICH
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> FOR THE DIPLOMA IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN <Location>THE
NETHERLANDS</Location> WAS CRITICISED FOR THE LACK OF A PRACTICAL BASE. HOWEVER, STUDENTS
FOLLOWING THE COURSE IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE P.A. <Organization>TIELE SCHOOL</Organization> OF
LIBRIANSHIP IN <Location>THE HAGUE</Location> RECEIVE LECTURES FROM PRACTISING <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
AND THE SYLLABUS IS REVIEWED ANNUALLY IN CONSULTATION WITH STUDENTS AND WITH
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> FROM <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IN ADDITION THE VARIETY OF POSTS IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OPEN TO STUDENTS COMPLETING THE COURSE <Organization>MAKES</Organization> IT IMPRACTICAL TO SUIT
THE SYLLABUS TO A SINGLE TYPE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. IT IS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> CLEAR THAT TOO LITTLE IS
KNOWN ABOUT THE COURSE <Organization>BY</Organization> PRACTISING <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1528
<Organization>BETTER EDUCATION</Organization> IN IMMIGRANT MATTERS FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IS WANTED.
     
TRADITIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> FOR ESTABLISHED <Organization>USER</Organization> GROUPS ARE STILL THE NORM
IN <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND IMMIGRANT SERVICES ARE CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> AS HUMANITARIAN
AID WITH CONSEQUENT LOW STATUS. IF DEMAND FOR IMMIGRANT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> WERE
TREATED LIKE THAT FOR COOK BOOKS OR STAMP CATALOGUES A LESS EMOTIONAL ATTITUDE
<Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE ACHIEVED. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MUST HELP IMMIGRANTS TO RETAIN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> MOTHER
TONGUE AS WELL AS TO LEARN <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>. THERE ARE GOVERNMENTAL GUIDELINES <Organization>ON</Organization>
STOCKING OF IMMIGRANT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND CHANNELS OF SUPPLY ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
COORDINATION OF ACQUISITION AND CATALOGUING IS NEEDED. MORE CONTACT WITH
IMMIGRANT ORGANISATIONS AND <Organization>BETTER</Organization> EDUCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE NECESSARY. WHAT
HAS <Organization>ALREADY</Organization> <Organization>BEEN</Organization> DONE IS LARGELY DUE TO THE WORK OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION&apos;S <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> IMMIGRANT AND MINORITY QUESTIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1529
THE IMAGE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;. A ONE-DAY COURSE ORGANIZED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>ARLIS</Organization> AND HELD <Organization>ON</Organization> FRIDAY, 20 FEBRUARY 1981.A
     
N &apos;IMAGE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; IS ANY SYSTEMATIC <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF <Organization>VISUAL</Organization> IMAGES THAT EXIST FOR
ANY PURPOSE WHATSOEVER, AND AS <Organization>SUCH</Organization>, EMBRACES THE SLIDE AND PHOTOGRAPHIC
COLLECTIONS FOUND IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AS WELL AS COMMERICAL
PICTURE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>PRINT</Organization> AND PHOTOGRAPH COLLECTIONS IN MUSEUMS, AND <Organization>THESE</Organization>
IMAGES ELEVATED TO THE STATUS OF &apos;<Organization>ART</Organization>&apos; AND STORED IN <Organization>ART</Organization> GALLERIES. SUMMARISES
PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ONE-DAY COURSE, WHICH WERE&apos; AN INTRODUCTION TO THE
IMAGE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> ANTHONY BURTON; IMAGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND MODERN <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization>
DAVID LEE; A PAPER, <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> DAVID LEE, <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>BBC</Organization> HULTON PICTURE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S
<Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> SCHEME; A TALK <Organization>ON</Organization> THE V&amp;A DEPARTMENT OF PRINTS AND DRAWINGS, <Organization>BY</Organization>
MICHAEL SNODIN; AND A PAPER <Organization>ON</Organization> RECENT WORK <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>COMPARISON</Organization> OF THE USEFULNESS
OF AACR2 AND MDA WHEN CATALOGUING <Organization>VISUAL</Organization> MATERIAL <Organization>ACQUIRED</Organization> FOR <Organization>ITS</Organization> DOCUMENTARY
VALUE, <Organization>BY</Organization> WENDY SHERIDAN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1530
TEACHING THE THEORIES OF MANAGEMENT IN AN <Organization>AFRICAN LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE AUTHOR&apos;S REACTIONS TO HIS ATTEMPTS TO TEACH THE <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> OF
ALLEGED OBSTACLES TO <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> MANAGEMENT IN AN <Organization>AFRICAN LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>.
<Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND PSYCHOLOGICAL FACTORS <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> SCENE WERE OF
<Organization>PARAMOUNT</Organization> IMPORTANCE IN THE STUDIES. <Organization>EARLY SCIENTIFIC MANAGEMENT</Organization> THEORY
INSISTED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE NEED FOR A SYSTEMATIC ANALYSIS OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS, AND
ANYTHING WHICH LEADS TO THE SAME KIND OF STUDIES IN <Organization>AFRICAN</Organization> SOCIETIES SHOULD
BE ENCOURAGED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1531
PROCESS AUTOMATION IN DEVELOPING TRAINING CURRICULA.
     
SHOWS THE NECESSITY OF <Organization>ESTABLISHING</Organization> AN <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR COMPILING <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization>
CONTENT AND PLANNING CURRICULA FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OFFICER TRAINING PROGRAMMES;
<Organization>CONSIDERS</Organization> IMPORTANT PRINCIPLES CONCERNING THE ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>;
AND IDENTIFIES THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> BASES AS A <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> PLANNING STRUCTURE, A LIST OF
<Organization>REQUIREMENTS</Organization> FOR <Organization>EACH INFORMATION OFFICER GROUP</Organization>, AND A SET OF RETRIEVAL
PROCEDURES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1532
<Organization>ON</Organization> PROBLEM AREAS IN TRAINING SPECIALISTS IN THE FIELD OF PATENT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN
THE <Location>USSR</Location>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>SOVIET</Organization> PATENT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECIALIST TRAINING <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization>
PARTICULAR <Organization>ORGANISATIONAL</Organization> FORMAT HAS <Organization>BEEN</Organization> CAUSED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SPECIFIC FEATURES OF
THE PATENT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> ECONOMY SPECIALISTS; <Organization>THESE</Organization> FEATURES
STEM FROM THE PLANNED NATURE OF THE SOCIALIST ECONOMY AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> INFLUENCE
THROUGHOUT <Organization>INDUSTRY</Organization>. STRESSES THE <Organization>KEY</Organization> ROLE OF THE <Organization>USSR STATE COMMITTEE</Organization> FOR
INVENTIONS AND DISCOVERIES, WHICH SUPERVISES THE PATENT SPECIALIST TRAINING
AND IN-SERVICE TRAINING ESTABLISHMENTS; OUTLINES A TYPICAL <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>; AND
POINTS <Organization>OUT</Organization> THE NECESSITY OF TEACHING FUNDAMENTAL PRINCIPLES OF PATENT <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1533
PERFECTING THE COURSE CONTENT IN THE INSTITUTE FOR THE <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> TRAINING OF
<Organization>INFORMATION WORKERS</Organization>.
     
PRESENTS THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> CURRICULA OF THE INSTITUTE FOR THE <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> TRAINING OF
<Organization>INFORMATION WORKERS</Organization>, <Location>MOSCOW</Location>. <Organization>THEIR DESIGN</Organization> INCORPORATES A MODULAR APPROACH,
<Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> TRAINING, AND THE HIGHEST <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> CORRELATION BETWEEN COURSE
CONTENT AND <Organization>REQUIREMENTS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SYSTEMS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1534
TRAINING NEEDS IN FEDERAL <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; SURVEY <Organization>REPORT</Organization>.
     
IN SUMMER 78, <Location>CANADA</Location>&apos;S COUNCIL OF <Organization>FEDERAL LIBRARIES COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization>
EDUCATION SURVEYED THE TRAINING NEEDS OF FEDERAL <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE
RESULTS INDICATED THAT FEDERAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> PARTS OF THE COUNTRY ARE IN
NEED OF <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>OR PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PROGRAMMES. PRESENTS
<Organization>THESE</Organization> RESULTS AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> OPTIONS FOR TRAINING PROGRAMMES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1535
SPECIALISATION OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> TRANSLATORS IN DISCIPLINARY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE TRAINING OF TRANSLATORS OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES AND <Organization>MAKES</Organization> A CASE FOR <Organization>SOVIET</Organization> FACTORIES AND OFFICES TO
ESTABLISH A SCIENTIFICALLY-GROUNDED TRANSLATOR TRAINING <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE
<Organization>EXISTING</Organization> FRAMEWORK OF <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> TRAINING AND QUALIFICATION IMPROVEMENT. THE
3 LEVELS OF THE TRANSLATOR TRAINING <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1536
<Organization>USE</Organization> OR VALUE OF GOALS AND OBJECTIVES <Organization>STATEMENTS</Organization>.
     
MAN <Organization>ABSTRACTS</Organization> EXPERIENCE <Organization>INTO</Organization> SYMBOLS AND USES THEM TO REDIRECT HIS ENERGIES
IN MANIPULATING THE REAL WORLD. THE <Organization>ORGANISATIONAL</Organization> ENVIRONMENTS THUS
ABSTRACTED CHANGE <Organization>SO</Organization> RAPIDLY THAT MAN HAS DIFFICULTY IN DESCRIBING THEM.
ABSTRACTIONS OF ORGANISATIONS (<Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) SHOULD <Organization>NOT</Organization> BE MISTAKEN AS
HAVING A REALITY. <Organization>STATEMENTS</Organization> <Organization>MADE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PURPOSE AND GOALS OF ORGANISATIONS
ARE <Organization>AT</Organization> BEST LIKE HYPOTHESES WHICH ARE TEMPORARY DESCRIPTIONS OF AN ENVIRONMENT
THAT MUST BE TESTABLE TO BE OF VALUE. THE MARK OF A HEALTHY <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> RESTS
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE FERVOUR WITH WHICH IT TESTS GOALS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1537
THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location> MINISTER FOR <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE OCCASION OF
THE OPENING OF THE EXTENSION TO ADCOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, 15 OCT 80. THE <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> FUNCTION
OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FOR AND TO EDUCATE <Organization>ITS</Organization>
USERS-LIBRARIES ARE THEREFORE SOURCES OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND CENTRES OF LEARNING
AND EDUCATION, AND THE SUCCESS OR FAILURE OF A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>THESE</Organization>
SERVICES DEPENDS LARGELY <Organization>ON</Organization> THE QUALITY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WHO RUN IT.
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE ESSENTIAL SERVICES TO <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1538
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN BAVARIA.
     
BAVARIA HAS A <Organization>POPULATION</Organization> OF 10.8 MILLION OF WHOM ONLY 25% LIVE IN THE 6 <Organization>MAIN</Organization>
CITIES. THERE IS A <Organization>STRONG</Organization> TRADITION OF BOOK <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization>, WITH OVER 200
PUBLISHERS IN <Location>MUNICH</Location> ALONE. THE BAVARIAN <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS THE <Organization>LARGEST</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
IN THE FEDERAL REPUBLIC WITH A STOCK OF 4 MILLION VOLUMES. THERE ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> 10
UNIVERSITY AND 11 <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. 745 INDEPENDENT MUNICIPAL
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAD 971,000 REGISTERED READERS IN 1979 AND ISSUES WERE 21.6 MILLION.
THERE IS CLOSE COOPERATION BETWEEN SCHOOLS AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, WITH BRANCHES
FREQUENTLY LOCATED IN SCHOOLS. THE CHURCHES MAKE AN IMPORTANT CONTRIBUTION-THE
<Organization>CATHOLIC CHURCH</Organization> PROVIDES 1,273 SERVICE POINTS AND THE <Organization>EVANGELICAL CHURCH</Organization> 179.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1539
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE GROWTH OF KNOWLEDGE (IN CHINESE).
     
TRANSLATION OF AN ARTICLE ORIGINALLY <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN LIBR. Q. 49 (1) JAN 79 (SEE
79/2634) AND THEN AGAIN IN LIBR. Q. 50 (1) JAN 80.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1540
JEWETT&apos;S ROLE IN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR THE <Location>USA</Location>.
     
IN 1835, THE <Location>USA</Location> RECEIVED A BEQUEST UNDER THE WILL OF JAMES SMITHSON (A <Location>UK</Location>
CHEMIST) FOR FOUNDING IN <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>, <Location>D.C.</Location>, AN ESTABLISHMENT &apos;FOR THE INCREASE
AND DIFFUSION OF KNOWLEDGE AMONG MEN&apos;. FOLLOWS THE DISCUSSIONS IN <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization>
LEADING TO THE INTRODUCTION OF THE <Organization>SMITHSONIAN</Organization> INSTITUTION ORGANISING <Organization>ACT</Organization> IN
1844, <Organization>ITS</Organization> SIGNING IN 1846, AND THE WORK OF THE <Organization>SMITHSONIAN BOARD</Organization> OF REGENTS
WHICH PLANNED THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>. FOCUSES <Organization>ON</Organization> CHARLES COFFIN JEWETT&apos;S ROLE IN
<Organization>ESTABLISHING</Organization> THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>; HIS DESIRE TO MAKE IT A FOCAL POINT FOR <Location>US</Location>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>; HIS CAMPAIGN FOR A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; AND HIS DREAM OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
UNION CATALOGUE. REPRODUCES HIS 1<Organization>ST</Organization> ANNUAL <Organization>REPORT</Organization> TO THE BOARD OF REGENTS,
1848 (HE WAS ASSISTANT SECRETARY), IN WHICH HE PRESENTS AND EXPLAINS HIS
BELIEFS AND DESIRES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1541
SECTION OF <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (IFLA).
     
THE OBJECTIVES OF THE IFLA SECTION OF <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE COVERED.
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> LISTED ARE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS CURRENTLY IN PROGRESS AND PLANS FOR <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF THE SECTION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1542
THE PEACE PALACE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>THE HAGUE</Location>.
     
FOUNDED AS A RESULT OF THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> HAGUE PEACE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> IN 1899, THE PEACE
PALACE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PRIMARILY SERVES THE ORGANISATIONS IN THE PEACE PALACE
(INTERNATIONAL COURT OF JUSTICE OF THE <Organization>UNITED NATIONS</Organization>, PERMANENT COURT OF
ARBITRATION, AND <Location>THE HAGUE</Location> <Organization>ACADEMY</Organization> OF INTERNATIONAL <Organization>LAW</Organization>), <Organization>BUT</Organization> IS <Organization>ALSO</Organization>
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>. IT SPECIALISES IN INTERNATIONAL <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND PRIVATE
LAW, RECEIVES 3,300 <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> AND <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>, AND ADDS 3,000 WORKS TO <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> ANNUALLY. IT IS A DEPOSITORY FOR MANY INTERGOVERNMENTAL
ORGANISATIONS AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>WOULD</Organization> OCCUPY 20 KILOMETRES IF STACKED
LINEARLY. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> COLLECTIONS, ACQUISITION POLICIES AND METHODS,
AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> TECHNIQUES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1543
SECTION OF BIOLOGICAL AND <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
ONE OF IFLA&apos;S NEWEST SECTIONS, THE SECTION OF BIOLOGICAL AND <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1977. PROJECTS IN PROGRESS ARE MENTIONED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1544
PROFILES OF TWELVE MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> INSTITUTIONS OFFERING GRADUATE
DEGREES IN MUSIC (A <Organization>WORKING</Organization> DRAFT).
     
AN ANALYSIS OF 12 MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> PRESENTS DOCUMENTATION FOR THE DEVELOPMENT
OF GUIDELINES FOR MUSIC COLLECTIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> INSTITUTIONS OFFERING GRADUATE MUSIC
PROGRAMMES. THE PROFILES EXAMINE <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization> AND <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>,
<Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>, AND SERVICES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SELECTED
INSTITUTIONS. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FROM NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1545
SECTION OF GEOGRAPHY AND <Organization>MAP</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
THE HISTORY OF THE IFLA SECTION OF GEOGRAPHY AND <Organization>MAP</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
PROJECTS FROM 1968 ARE TRACED. ON-GOING PROJECTS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> PROJECTS
UNDERTAKEN IN COOPERATION WITH <Organization>OTHER INTERNATIONAL</Organization> ORGANISATIONS, ARE COVERED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1546
<Location>COLUMBUS</Location> MEMORIAL LIBRARY-BIBLIOTECA CONMEMORATIVA DE COLON-OF THE <Organization>PAN
AMERICAN UNION</Organization>, <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>.
     
1889-90 <Organization>MADE</Organization> PROVISIONS FOR THE CREATION OF A LATIN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO BE
ESTABLISHED IN <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, KNOWN AS THE <Location>COLUMBUS</Location> MEMORIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
(BIBLIOTECA CONMEMORATIVA DE COLON) WAS FORMED <Organization>BY</Organization> CONTRIBUTIONS OF PRINTED
MATERIAL FROM <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE <Organization>MEMBER</Organization> STATES AND IS ONE OF THE MOST OUTSTANDING
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>US</Location> OF BOOKS RELATING TO THE IBEROAMERICAN COUNTRIES,
SPECIALISING IN <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization>, GEOGRAPHICAL AND LITERARY WORKS, MAPS, MANUSCRIPTS
AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS. WHILE THE <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> PURPOSE OF THE <Location>COLUMBUS</Location> MEMORIAL
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS TO SERVE THE <Organization>PAN AMERICAN UNION</Organization> AND ORGANIZATION OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> STATES
<Organization>BY</Organization> PREPARING MATERIAL IN ORDER TO HELP SOLVE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> POLITICAL, ECONOMIC AND
CULTURAL <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>, THE <Location>COLUMBUS</Location> MEMORIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> HAS BECOME A CENTRE FOR
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, BESIDES ATTENDING TO THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>. <Organization>FURTHER</Organization>
MORE, IT KEEPS IN CLOSE CONTACT WITH THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> AND SOUTH
<Location>AMERICA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1547
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> FOR ADMINISTRATIVE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES.
     
ATTEMPTS TO REVIEW THE <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> BEING OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
ADMINISTRATIVE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (ATTACHED TO THE DEPARTMENTS/MINISTRIES OF THE
FEDERAL, <Organization>STATE</Organization> AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> GOVERNMENTS) IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES. EXCLUDED FROM
THE PURVIEW OF THE ASSESSMENT ARE UNIVERSITY AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IT IS
HOPED THAT THE APPRAISAL WILL <Organization>LEAD</Organization> TO FRUITFUL DISCUSSIONS, AND THAT A
PROGRAMME MAY BE DRAWN UP FOR <Organization>FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF ADMINISTRATIVE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN THE DEVELOPING COUNTRIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1548
DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS MEANS OF MAKING <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> MORE EFFECTIVE.
     
THE <Organization>VARIOUS SYSTEMS</Organization> OF DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>USSR</Location>, <Location>HUNGARY</Location> AND <Location>EAST
GERMANY</Location> ARE <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> OUTLINED. IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location> THE FEDERAL <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
DECLARATION NO. 237 FROM 1977 AND THE SLOVAK <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DECLARATION NO. 417
FROM THE SAME YEAR ARE CONCERNED WITH THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> OF DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
THE <Organization>NATIONAL COORDINATION CENTRE</Organization> WORKED <Organization>OUT</Organization> IN 1979 A PROPOSAL FOR THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>BRATISLAVA</Location>. IT IS ENVISAGED THAT THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WILL BE
BUILT IN ZABI MAJER NEAR RACA, CLOSE TO BRATISLAVA <Location>CITY</Location>. THE <Organization>ACTUAL</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization>
IS EXPECTED TO BE READY <Organization>BY</Organization> 1987; UP TO <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>TIME</Organization> THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> DEPOSITORY
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WILL FUNCTION IN TEMPORARY PREMISES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1549
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
     
INTERVIEW WITH N. MOORE, PROJECT OFFICER IN CHARGE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>AT</Organization> THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. DEFINES <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AS THEORETICAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, WHICH
PROVIDES <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> BACKGROUND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> USERS, AND
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WHICH SEEKS TO SOLVE SPECIFIC <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> AND HELP <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization>
<Organization>BETTER SERVICES</Organization>. <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE MAINLY INTERESTED IN THE LATTER. RECENT
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HAS BEGUN TO LOOK <Organization>AT</Organization> WHY PEOPLE <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE RESULTS
ARE BEING USED TO <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> SERVICES. THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SUPPORTS <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
INVESTIGATING <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> DISTRIBUTION, COOPERATION AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> IN
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND EXAMINING THE ROLE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN RELATION TO
<Organization>FURTHER EDUCATION</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IS AS FAR AS <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization>
PRACTISING <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, OFTEN IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS. THE
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> FINANCES <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> CENTRES, WHICH INITIATE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, BUILD
UP COLLECTIONS OF <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> MATERIAL AND ADVISE RESEARCHERS. AN <Organization>ADVISORY</Organization> COMM
ITTEE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HELPS THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COORDINATE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1550
FINNISH ISSUE).A
     
 <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FINNISH ISSUE, PRESENTING DIFFERENT ASPECTS OF FINNISH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. FOR <Organization>ABSTRACTS</Organization> OF THE CONTRIBUTIONS, SEE THE FOLLOWING SERIAL
NUMBERS:.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1551
FINNISH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TODAY.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A FINNISH ISSUE. AN ACCOUNT OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION,
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>, <Organization>HOW</Organization> COSTS ARE SHARED <Organization>BY</Organization> MUNICIPALITIES AND <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>,
AND THE SITUATION REGARDING <Organization>STATE</Organization> SUBSIDIES. INCLUDES STATISTICS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> IN 1979.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1552
A LICK AND A PROMISE?: FRANS STEIN&apos;S INTERVIEW WITH FRANS VAN DE ROER <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
<Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.
     
THE VIEWS EXPRESSED IN AN INTERVIEW WITH FRANS STEIN IN BIBLIOTHEEK EN
SAMENLEVING 8 (11) NOV 80, 311-316 (SEE 81/3084), <Organization>BY</Organization> FRANS VAN DE ROER, HEAD
OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SECTION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>DUTCH MINISTRY</Organization> OF CULTURE, RECREATION AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
SERVICES REPRESENT A SERIOUS THREAT TO THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>THE
NETHERLANDS</Location>. IN SPITE OF <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> ASSURANCES THAT ACCESS TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SHOULD BE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> SECTIONS OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, VAN DE ROER IS CLEARLY IN
FAVOUR OF <Organization>INCREASING</Organization> MEMBERSHIP CHARGES FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN AN EFFORT TO
REDUCE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> SPENDING. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> MUST CONVINCE THE AUTHORITIES THAT
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> SHOULD BE REGARDED AS PART OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
POLICY AND <Organization>NOT</Organization> AS PART OF THE <Organization>LOCAL SOCIO-CULTURAL SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1553
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO THE RURAL AREAS OF SOUTHEAST <Location>ASIA</Location>.
     
<Organization>EXAMINES</Organization> THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO THE DENSELY POPULATED RURAL
AREAS OF SOUTHEAST <Location>ASIA</Location>. THE LOW, AS WELL AS THE POOR QUALITY OF BOOK
<Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization>, THE HIGH ILLITERACY RATE, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>ENTRY INTO COMMUNITY</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>CONCEPT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>JOINT-USE SCHOOL</Organization>/<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES ARE DISCUSSED. THE DIFFERENT TYPES OF <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPERIMENTS IN
THE <Location>UK</Location>, AS WELL AS THE IMAGINATIVE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN
SCANDINAVIA MAY <Organization>OFFER</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> SOLUTIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1554
<Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN <Organization>NEW</Organization> PROVIDENCE (<Location>BAHAMAS</Location>).
     
LOOKS <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> IN THE <Location>UK</Location> DURING THE 18<Organization>TH</Organization> AND <Organization>EARLY</Organization> 19<Organization>TH</Organization>
CENTURIES AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE INFLUENCE OF <Organization>EARLY</Organization> <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MOVEMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE DEVELOPMENT IN THE <Location>BAHAMAS</Location>. NEWSPAPERS OF 1804 AND 1835 MENTION
CIRCULATING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>NASSAU</Location> AND NASSAU <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS ESTABLISHED IN
1837. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> TOWNS FOUNDED <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE 1850S-60S. QUOTING FROM
<Organization>CONTEMPORARY</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE SIZE AND CHARACTER OF <Location>NASSAU</Location>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND NUMBER OF SUBSCRIBERS IN THE 1850S AND OUTLINES THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S
DEVELOPMENT UP TO THE PRESENT. <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> MENTIONS <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE
<Location>BAHAMAS</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1555
DISTRICT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN HIMACHAL PRADESH&apos; A SURVEY.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE ROLE OF THE DISTRICT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND INDICATES THE <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT OF DISTRICT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN HIMACHAL PRADESH. GIVES AN ASSESSMENT OF
RESOURCES OF <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> DISTRICT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND REVIEWS THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF <Organization>THESE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. INCLUDES THE STATISTICS REGARDING <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, HOLDINGS, SERVICES, ETC.,
AND MENTIONS THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> SUGGESTIONS FOR IMPROVEMENT OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1556
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN AN <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> <Organization>TOWN</Organization> AND PORT <Location>KOTKA</Location>.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A FINNISH ISSUE. <Location>KOTKA</Location> MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> WAS
OPENED IN 1977. THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> HAS AN AREA OF 6,000 SQ.M., OF WHICH 5,000 BELONG
TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND 1,000 TO THE <Organization>REGIONAL INSTITUTE</Organization> OF MUSIC. IT MAINLY SERVES
THE 15,000 INHABITANTS OF THE <Organization>TOWN CENTRE</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> THE CENTRE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
OPERATIONS IN THE AREA (WHICH HAS 62,000 INHABITANTS). IT CONTAINS 107,000
BOOKS; 316,000 LOANS WERE <Organization>MADE</Organization> IN 1979. APPROXIMATELY 1,300 PEOPLE VISITED THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>EACH</Organization> DAY IN 1979, 300 OF WHOM CAME FOR A NON-BORROWING PURPOSE.
INCLUDES PLANS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1557
FIFTY YEARS OF <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>MANCHESTER</Location>, 1931-1981.
     
THE <Organization>POPULATION</Organization> OF <Location>MANCHESTER</Location> EXPANDED RAPIDLY IN THE YEARS FOLLOWING WORLD WAR
I AND THERE WAS A DEMAND FOR MORE <Organization>BRANCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE NECESSARY MONEY WAS
<Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>, <Organization>SO</Organization> THE <Location>CITY</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> SUGGESTED A TRAVELLING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
LINES OF THOSE <Organization>ALREADY</Organization> IN <Organization>USE</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location> AND THE <Location>UK</Location>&apos;S 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TOOK
TO THE STREETS OF <Location>MANCHESTER</Location> <Location>IN</Location> JULY 1931. THE SERVICE WAS WELL-USED AND
EXPANDED, WAS SUSPENDED DURING WORLD WAR II, AND WAS RESUMED IN 1948. IT IS
NOW AN INTEGRAL PART OF THE <Location>CITY</Location>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, SERVING AREAS UNABLE TO
<Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> A <Organization>BRANCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THOSE UNABLE TO VISIT A <Organization>BRANCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND AREAS
WHERE CUTS IN EXPENDITURE <Organization>HAVE</Organization> FORCED <Organization>BRANCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CLOSURES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1558
<Organization>USER SERVICES</Organization> IN THE UNIVERSITY OF JORDAN LIBRARY (IN ARABIC).
     
THE EFFECTIVENESS OF ANY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS MEASURED MAINLY <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> COLLECTIONS AND THE
SERVICES IT <Organization>OFFERS</Organization> TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> CLIENTELE. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE SERVICES OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
UNIVERSITY OF JORDAN LIBRARY, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> BORROWING, <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>, <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> AND
<Organization>PHOTOCOPYING SERVICES</Organization>; READING FACILITIES; <Organization>USER EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMMES;
PUBLICITY AND BIBLIOGRAPHICAL SERVICES; AND EXTRA SERVICES <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS
EXHIBITIONS, LECTURES AND MEETINGS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1559
A <Organization>LIBRARY ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization> REPORTS TO THE UNIVERSITY PRESIDENT.
     
IN THE PREFACE TO THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization>, NORMAN D. STEVENS EXPLAINS THAT THE UNIVERSITY
OF CONNECTICUT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPERIENCED A PARTICULARLY DIFFICULT <Organization>TIME</Organization> IN 1979-80.
THE RESULTANT REDUCTION IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HOURS GENERATED MUCH ADVERSE PUBLICITY AND
IT WAS FEARED THAT <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> BUDGET ALLOCATIONS <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE <Organization>INADEQUATE</Organization>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization> WERE ENCOURAGED TO PLAY A MORE VISIBLE ROLE IN BRINGING THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> TO THE ATTENTION OF THE <Organization>UNIVERSITY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>. THE
<Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> PREPARED A <Organization>REPORT</Organization> AS AN INTRODUCTION TO AN ORAL PRESENTATION <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
COMMITTEE TO THE UNIVERSITY PRESIDENT. PRESENTS THE TEXT OF THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization>, WHICH
STRESSES THE VITAL <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> ROLE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN A <Organization>STRONG UNIVERSITY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1560
THE TULANE <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>NEW ORLEANS</Location>&apos; A WINDOW <Organization>ON</Organization> THE WORLD.
     
THE <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT TULANE UNIVERSITY (NEW ORLEANS</Organization>, LOUISIANA) REFLECTS THE
<Organization>HISTORICAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF THE CIVIL <Organization>LAW</Organization> (THE <Organization>CONTINENTAL EUROPE</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, AS
LOUISIANA WAS A COLONY OF <Location>FRANCE</Location> AND SPAIN BEFORE <Organization>ITS</Organization> PURCHASE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Location>USA</Location> IN
1803) AND <Organization>COMMON</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization> (ANGLO-AMERICAN) SYSTEMS. IT HAS A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF OVER
200,000 VOLUMES. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> THE ULTIMATE RESPONSIBILITY FOR BOOK <Organization>SELECTION</Organization> AND
<Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> RESTS WITH THE HEAD <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization>, <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>,
FACULTY, AND STUDENTS ARE ENCOURAGED TO MAKE SUGGESTIONS. A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> COURSE IN
LEGAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND WRITING IS <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> AS A REQUIRED COURSE
FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> FRESHMEN J.D. STUDENTS AND INTRODUCTORY LECTURES IN LEGAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARE
<Organization>GIVEN</Organization> TO THE GRADUATE STUDENTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1561
A SECTION WITHOUT A PAST&apos; <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 40<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNIVERSARY OF THE SECTION FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE <Organization>DUTCH ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, DOCUMENTALISTS AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS.
     
THE FORMATION OF THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SECTION OF THE NEDERLANDSE VERENIGING
VAN BIBLIOTHECARISSEN, DOCUMENTALISTEN EN LITERATUURONDERZOEKERS (<Organization>DUTCH</Organization>
ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, DOCUMENTALISTS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS) IN <Location>THE
NETHERLANDS</Location> IN 1941 WAS DUE LARGELY TO THE EFFORTS OF <Organization>DR</Organization>. L.J. VAN DER WOLK,
<Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> OF THE <Organization>NITROGEN PRODUCTS DIVISION</Organization> OF THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> MINES IN LIMBURG. <Organization>AT</Organization>
VAN DER WOLK&apos;S SUGGESTION, MEMBERSHIP OF THE SECTION WAS ORIGINALLY RESTRICTED
TO <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF COMMERCIAL AND <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE FIRST COMMITTEE MEETING
OF THE SECTION WAS HELD IN THE <Organization>STATE MINES CENTRAL LABORATORY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> GELEEN <Organization>ON</Organization> 17
SEPT 41 AND THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> MEETING OF <Organization>MEMBERS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> 29 OCT FOLLOWING IN THE <Organization>PARK HOTEL</Organization>,
<Location>AMSTERDAM</Location>. MEMBERSHIP OF THE SECTION HAS GROWN FROM 204 IN 1948 TO 760 IN
1980.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1562
THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Organization>SOVIET</Organization> CONSUMER COOPERATIVES&apos; ACTIVITY.
     
THE <Location>USSR</Location> HAS OVER 7,000 CONSUMER COOPERATIVES WITH A <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> MEMBERSHIP OF
NEARLY 60 MILLION. THE <Organization>MAIN COOPERATIVE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS THE CENTROSOYUS <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>MOSCOW</Location>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> 60,000-VOLUME <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> CONTAINS RUSSIAN AND FOREIGN
BOOKS, <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>, STANDARDS AND CATALOGUES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND POLITICAL TOPICS,
MANAGEMENT, <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF LABOUR, AND <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF COOPERATIVE <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>.
IT RUNS THE <Organization>CENTRAL INFORMATION FUND</Organization> FOR COOPERATIVES AND IS THE
<Organization>METHODOLOGICAL CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>ALL COOPERATIVE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1563
<Location>TEHRAN</Location> MOSQUE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND A <Organization>COMPARISON</Organization> WITH <Organization>AMERICAN CHRISTIAN CHURCH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
GIVES BRIEF DETAILS OF THE COLLECTIONS HELD, AND SERVICES OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> 8 MOSQUE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>TEHRAN</Location>, CAPITAL OF <Location>IRAN</Location>. COMPARES <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH <Location>US</Location>
<Organization>CHRISTIAN CHURCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, NOTING A NUMBER OF SIMILARITIES AND CONTRASTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1564
<Organization>AFRICAN</Organization> MATERIALS AND THE <Organization>BIBLE SOCIETY</Organization>.
     
THE BRITISH AND <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> <Organization>BIBLE SOCIETY</Organization> WAS FOUNDED IN 1804. ONE OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> 1<Organization>ST</Organization> ACTS
WAS TO ESTABLISH A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. IT LAUNCHED A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> APPEAL FOR COPIES OF <Organization>ALL</Organization>
EDITIONS OF THE SCRIPTURES AND RESOLVED TO DEPOSIT IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> 6 COPIES OF
<Organization>EVERY SOCIETY</Organization> PUBLICATION. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NOW CONTAINS 28,000 VOLUMES IN NEARLY
2,000 LANGUAGES (<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> 500 <Organization>AFRICAN</Organization> LANGUAGES). IT HAS A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> INTEREST
IN <Location>EUROPE</Location> AND AFRICA (<Organization>ITS</Organization> SISTER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>NEW YORK</Location> CONCENTRATES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
AMERICAS AND ASIA-PACIFIC). OUTLINES THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT, <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> WORK, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> ARCHIVAL AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1565
<Organization>REPORT</Organization> TO THE <Organization>WISCONSIN</Organization> VETERANS <Organization>HOME</Organization> (KING <Organization>WISCONSIN</Organization>). <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF RESIDENT&apos;S
READING AND MEDIA INTERESTS AS A BASIS FOR THE DEVELOPING PROGRAM OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization>&apos; (1) IDENTIFIES THE LIBRARY-RELATED NEEDS AND INTERESTS OF THE
RESIDENTS OF THE <Organization>WISCONSIN</Organization> VETERANS <Organization>HOME</Organization> (<Organization>WVH</Organization>), (2) SEARCHES FOR CLUES <Organization>ON</Organization>
ACTIVATING A PROGRAMME OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, AND (3) EXPLORES THE FEASIBILITY OF
<Organization>ESTABLISHING</Organization> THE <Organization>WVH</Organization> AS A COMMUNITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR KING, <Organization>WISCONSIN</Organization>. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>NOT</Organization>
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FROM NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1566
THE PROVISION OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN SMALLER HOSPITALS IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.
     
IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> THE PROVISION OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN HOSPITALS WITH LESS
THAN 100 BEDS IS SERIOUSLY <Organization>INADEQUATE</Organization>. A SURVEY OF SMALLER HOSPITALS IN THE <Location>US</Location>
IN 1975 SHOWED THAT 1/3 OF HOSPITALS SURVEYED HAD <Organization>SOME</Organization> FORM OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE
PROVISION OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> HOSPITALS IS HINDERED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>INADEQUATE</Organization>
BOOKFUNDS, <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND ACCOMMODATION. FURTHERMORE, IN THE SMALLER HOSPITALS
DOCTORS ARE TOO BUSY WITH ROUTINE WORK TO <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. SMALLER
HOSPITALS COULD <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> &apos;CORE&apos; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>TEXTBOOKS</Organization> AND
<Organization>PERIODICALS AT MINIMAL COST</Organization>. <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> CORE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS FORMED IN 1973 <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE <Organization>PRINCESS IRENE HOSPITAL</Organization> IN ALMELO AND <Organization>BY</Organization> 1979 THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONTAINED 266
BOOKS AND 6 <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> TITLES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1567
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>PRISON DEPARTMENT</Organization> ESTABLISHMENTS.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF READING MATERIAL PROVISION FOR <Location>UK</Location> PRISONERS OVER
THE LAST 200 YEARS. DURING THE LAST 10 YEARS, <Organization>PRISON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> COME UNDER
<Organization>INCREASING</Organization> SCRUTINY AND ASSESSMENT AND A <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION WORKING PARTY</Organization> IS
PREPARING GUIDELINES. PRESENT ARRANGEMENTS ARE CHARACTERISED <Organization>BY</Organization> VARIATIONS
AMONG ESTABLISHMENTS. THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE RUN <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>HOME OFFICE</Organization> <Organization>PRISON</Organization>
DEPARTMENT AND ARE TREATED AS A COMPONENT OF <Organization>GENERAL EDUCATION</Organization> PROVISION. THEY
ARE FINANCED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> FUNDS, RECEIVING A PER CAPITA RATE
DETERMINED FROM A FORMULA AGREED BETWEEN THE <Organization>PRISON DEPARTMENT</Organization> AND LOCAL
AUTHORITY ASSOCIATIONS. <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FACILITIES OPERATED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> PRISONS. <Organization>ON</Organization> 31 MAR 81, 70.5% OF PRISONERS HAD AN AVERAGE
OF 4 BOOKS <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> LOAN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1568
ISSUE DEVOTED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES TO THE DISABLED).I
     
SSUE TO MARK THE <Organization>UNITED</Organization> NATION&apos;S INTERNATIONAL YEAR OF THE DISABLED. FOR
<Organization>ABSTRACTS</Organization>, SEE THE FOLLOWING SERIAL NUMBERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1569
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>UNITED</Organization> NATION&apos;S INTERNATIONAL YEAR OF THE DISABLED.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR THE DISABLED.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE SIGNIFICANCE OF THE INTERNATIONAL YEAR OF THE DISABLED IN A
PRESENT AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONTEXT. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MUST ASSIST HANDICAPPED PEOPLE
TO TAKE PART IN THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND CULTURAL <Organization>LIFE</Organization> OF THE COMMUNITY <Organization>ON</Organization> EQUAL TERMS
WITH EVERYONE ELSE, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> MEANS THAT THEY MUST <Organization>HAVE</Organization> EQUAL ACCESS TO THE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND EXPRESSIVE <Organization>HUMAN</Organization> EXPERIENCE CAUGHT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE PRINTED WORD. A
<Organization>TOTAL</Organization> OR PARTIAL READING HANDICAP WILL HINDER <Organization>THIS</Organization> ACCESS. TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
FALLS THE TASK OF BREAKING DOWN THE BARRIERS WHICH PREVENT THOSE WITH A
READING HANDICAP FROM GAINING ACCESS TO THE <Organization>MESSAGE</Organization> CONTAINED <Organization>BY</Organization> WORDS IN
<Organization>PRINT</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1570
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR THE SICK AND HANDICAPPED IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A FINNISH ISSUE. THE <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF HOSPITAL AND NURSING <Organization>HOME</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>FINLAND</Location> IS BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 1961 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>, THE RELEVANT PASSAGES
OF WHICH ARE PROBABLY DERIVED FROM THE EXPERIENCES OF THOSE MUNICIPALITIES
WHICH <Organization>HAVE PROVIDED SUCH SERVICES</Organization> SINCE THE 1940S. THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE THE
RESPONSIBILITY OF THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND RECEIVE HIGHER <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
GRANTS THAN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE INSTITUTION AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATE
CLOSELY IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S DAY-TO-DAY RUNNING. OUTLINES THE <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, DEFICIENCIES, <Organization>STAFF</Organization> TRAINING, AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR
NON-HOSPITALISED HANDICAPPED PEOPLE. THE <Organization>WHOLE</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> IS BEING INVESTIGATED
<Organization>BY</Organization> 2 <Organization>WORKING</Organization> GROUPS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1571
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION FOR THE VISUALLY HANDICAPPED IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR THE DISABLED. <Organization>STATE</Organization>
OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> REVIEW OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO THE VISUALLY HANDICAPPED IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>,
WITH DETAILS OF <Location>FINLAND</Location>&apos;S ONLY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SPECIFICALLY</Organization> FOR THE VISUALLY
HANDICAPPED OR OTHERWISE DISABLED, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS THEMSELVES, AUDIOBOOK
ACTIVITY IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>, WAYS OF REACHING <Organization>NEW</Organization> BORROWERS, AND <Organization>NEW</Organization> TECHNOLOGY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1572
<Organization>USE</Organization> OF BOOKS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> GIVE GREATER POSSIBILITIES TO MENTALLY RETARDED
CHILDREN, YOUNG PEOPLE AND ADULTS.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR THE DISABLED.
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> A PROJECT WHICH BEGAN IN MAY 79 <Organization>AT</Organization> TROMS COUNTY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Location>NORWAY</Location>, <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF BOOKS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TOGETHER WITH MENTALLY RETARDED CHILDREN, YOUNG
PEOPLE AND ADULTS. THE WORK WENT <Organization>ON</Organization> UNTIL JUNE 80, AND A <Organization>REPORT</Organization> HAS SINCE <Organization>BEEN</Organization>
PRINTED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE WORK DONE AND EXPERIENCE GAINED. MOST OF THE WORK <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
PROJECT WAS CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Location>TROMSO</Location>, AND THE PRACTICAL ASPECTS OF IT IN
COOPERATION WITH INSTITUTIONS, SCHOOLS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>TOWN</Organization>. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
ABOUT EXPERIENCE GAINED ELSEWHERE IN <Location>NORWAY</Location> WAS OBTAINED AND USED AS
BACKGROUND MATERIAL AND AS MATERIAL FOR CORRECTION AND <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> AS THE WORK
PROGRESSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1573
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE BOOKS AND THE MENTALLY RETARDED.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR THE DISABLED.
VANGEDEHUSE IS A DANISH COUNTY INSTITUTION, WHICH ACCOMMODATES ABOUT 300
CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS, <Organization>ALL</Organization> OF WHOM ARE WHAT IS KNOWN AS MENTALLY
RETARDED. MANY <Organization>ALSO</Organization> SUFFER FROM <Organization>OTHER</Organization> EXTENSIVE HANDICAPS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>
BLINDNESS, DEAFNESS, PSYCHOSES AND SPASTIC PARALYSIS. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>FUN</Organization> AND
THE PLEASURE WHICH <Organization>THESE</Organization> YOUNG PEOPLE GET <Organization>OUT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DESPITE <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
MANY AND TERRIBLE HANDICAPS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1574
SERVICE TO OLDER ADULT USERS OF <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization>
ATTITUDES.
     
(<Organization>PHD</Organization> THESIS-UNIVERSITY OF <Location>PITTSBURGH</Location>.) A QUESTIONNAIRE WAS SENT TO 311
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> US COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES SPONSORING ELDERHOSTEL (A PROGRAMME
FOR ADULTS AGED OVER 60, OFFERED <Organization>ON</Organization> MANY CAMPUSES) FOR <Organization>AT</Organization> LEAST 2 YEARS DURING
1977-79. THE 197 <Organization>REPLIES CONTAINING USABLE DATA</Organization> INDICATED THAT THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
DISAGREED WITH STEREOTYPIC <Organization>STATEMENTS</Organization> CONCERNING OLDER ADULTS; CONTACT WITH
OLDER ADULT RELATIVES WAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> A SIGNIFICANT FACTOR IN THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos;
RESPONSES TO THE <Organization>STATEMENTS</Organization>; IMPLEMENTING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROGRAMMES FOR OLDER ADULTS
WAS A SIGNIFICANT FACTOR IN <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos; AGREEMENT WITH SUGGESTED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES FOR OLDER ADULTS, WHILE PLANNING PROGRAMMES FOR THEM WAS LESS
SIGNIFICANT AND VOLUNTEER COMMUNITY WORK WAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> A SIGNIFICANT FACTOR; AND
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> FELT THAT AGE IS <Organization>NOT</Organization> NECESSARILY A DEBILITATIVE FACTOR WITH REGARD
TO LEARNING AND MOTIVATION TO LEARN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1575
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN THE <Organization>ASEAN</Organization> REGION.
     
THE PRESENT SITUATION IN CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN THE <Organization>ASEAN</Organization> (ASSOCIATION OF
SOUTH-EAST ASIAN <Organization>NATIONS</Organization>) REGION, COVERING <Location>INDONESIA</Location>, <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>, <Location>PHILIPPINES</Location>,
<Location>SINGAPORE</Location> AND THAILAND, IS DESCRIBED. THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization> IS BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A QUESTIONNAIRE
SENT FROM THE <Organization>STANDING COMMITTEE</Organization> OF THE CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SECTION OF IFLA TO
INDIVIDUAL RESPONDENTS IN THE AREA. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS VIEWED <Organization>AGAINST</Organization> THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
CULTURAL, SOCIO-ECONOMIC AND POLITICAL BACKGROUND OF THE REGION AS A <Organization>WHOLE</Organization>.
THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization> COVERS <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK <Organization>BUT</Organization> FOCUS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> BOOK
PROVISION (LANGUAGE, <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization>) AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FACILITIES AND SERVICES. <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization>
COVERED IS THE ROLE OF SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE POSITION OF CHILDREN&apos;S
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1576
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>CHILD</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization>.
     
ARGUES THAT, DESPITE THE <Organization>INCREASING</Organization> EVIDENCE OF A MORE FLEXIBLE ATTITUDE <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE PART OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FACILITIES <Organization>BY</Organization> CHILDREN DURING THE
PAST 2 DECADES, THERE IS STILL A PERCEPTION <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PART OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> CHILDREN AND
