<Organization>Document</Organization> 1001
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE LOOSE.

REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> VISITS TO <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> <Location>ZIMBABWE</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> VISITS TO THE <Organization>LEEDS POLYTECHNIC LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>, <Organization>MAKERERE UNIVERSITY</Organization>
IN <Location>KAMPALA</Location>, <Location>UGANDA</Location>, AND VARIOUS TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>. IMPLICATIONS OF
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>OBSERVATIONS</Organization> FOR <Location>ZIMBABWE</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE DETAILED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1002
THIRD WORLD <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND CULTURAL IMPERIALISM.

REPRINT OF AN ARTICLE FIRST PUBLISHED IN THE ASSISTANT LIBRN. (72 (10) OCT
79). FOR ABSTRACT, SEE: 80/4104.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1003
<Organization>SLA SUMMER SCHOOL</Organization>: 3 POINTS OF VIEW.

LINDA WARNOCK, RAY RIPPINGALE (<Organization>FROM</Organization> ENGLAND), AND TED MOY (<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>USA</Location>) GIVE
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> REACTIONS TO THE 1981 <Organization>SUMMER SCHOOL</Organization> OF LIBRARIANSHIP, SPONSORED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Organization>SCOTTISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>. TOPICS COVERED <Organization>INCLUDED</Organization> CONSUMER <Organization>NEEDS</Organization>, TEENAGE
READERS, <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, COMPUTER <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE,
TELETEXT, AND <Organization>VIEWDATA</Organization> SERVICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1004
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE IN <Location>POLAND</Location>.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN <Location>POLAND</Location> AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
AREAS OF EMPHASIS IN POLISH LIBRARIANSHIP. THE <Organization>BACKGROUND</Organization> FOR THE DESCRIPTION
IS THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ESTABLISHMENT OF CULTURAL FACILITIES IN <Location>POLAND</Location> WHICH BEGAN IN
1918. DISCUSSES THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE AS A UNIVERSITY DISCIPLINE,
AS WELL AS THE BROAD RANGE OF TOPICS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, AND
SIGNIFICANT PUBLICATIONS IN THE FIELD.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1005
SECTION DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>SINGAPORE</Location> <Organization>ANNUAL</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
MEETING, 22 MARCH 80).A

NNUAL REPORT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>SINGAPORE</Location> FOR THE YEAR ENDING MAR
80, LISTS OF OFFICERS, COUNCIL AND COMMITTEE MEMBERS, AND DETAILS OF THE
ACCOUNTS OF THE ASSOCIATION AND OF <Organization>ITS PUBLICATIONS COMMITTEE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1006
A <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>&apos; PURPOSE AND FUNCTIONS WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
<Location>ZAMBIA</Location>.

(MLS THESIS.) EXAMINES <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> REGARDING <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES, INTERNATIONAL <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization>, AND <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> WITHIN <Location>AFRICA</Location>,
ESPECIALLY THE EASTERN, <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> AND <Organization>SOUTHERN</Organization> AFRICAN REGION, AGAINST THE
<Organization>BACKGROUND</Organization> OF <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> WITHIN <Location>ZAMBIA</Location>. THE ZAMBIAN <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> ARE SHOWN
TO BE <Organization>INADEQUATE</Organization> AND TOO UNCOORDINATED AND THE COUNTRY&apos;S <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES ARE CLAIMED NOT TO BE SUFFICIENTLY <Organization>ORIENTED</Organization> TOWARDS MEETING <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
POLITICAL AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> ASPIRATIONS. A <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IS DESIGNED WHICH
WILL (1) MEET <Location>ZAMBIA</Location>&apos;S SPECIFIC <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> AND (2) CO-EXIST SMOOTHLY WITH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PARTS OF THE WORLD.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1007
NEBRASKA PRE-WHITE HOUSE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES,
MARCH 29-31, 1979, <Location>LINCOLN</Location>, NEBRASKA.

SCIENCE. THE PRE-CONFERENCE WAS ORGANISED TO DETERMINE NEBRASKA&apos;S <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> AND
LIKELY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICE <Organization>NEEDS</Organization>; TO RECOMMEND TO WHCLIS POLICIES
AND PROGRAMMES DERIVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> ISSUES IDENTIFIED IN THE 1976 NEBRASKA GOVERNOR&apos;S
<Organization>CONFERENE ON LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>; TO ENCOURAGE <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND MEDIA
CENTRES; TO EXAMINE THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> PROGRAM FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES
AND DETERMINE NEBRASKA&apos;S ROLE THEREIN; AND TO SELECT AND PREPARE DELEGATES FOR
PARTICIPATION IN WHCLIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1008
EXCELLENCE IN SCHOOL MEDIA PROGRAMS.

FESTSCHRIFT TO ELIZABETH T. FAST. THE WORK IS DIVIDED <Organization>INTO</Organization> 4 SECTIONS: THE
CHILD; THE <Organization>SCHOOL MEDIA CENTER</Organization>; THE COMMUNITY; AND THE FUTURE, AND COMPRISES
SELECTED WRITINGS <Organization>BY</Organization> A VARIETY OF AUTHORS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> ARTICLES <Organization>BY</Organization>
ELIZABETH FAST.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1009
TH <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INTERNATIONAL FEDERATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ASSOCIATIONS</Organization>
AND INSTITUTIONS, 18-23 AUGUST 1980, <Location>MANILA</Location>, <Location>PHILIPPINES</Location>.RE

PORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>, WHOSE THEME WAS &apos;THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>&apos; GLOBAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> EXCHANGE FOR <Organization>GREATER INTERNATIONAL</Organization>
UNDERSTANDING&apos;. PAPERS AND PROCEEDINGS ARE SUMMARISED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1010
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization>: A WORLD OF BOOKS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> READERS: PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
IFLA 50TH ANNIVERSARY WORLD <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization>, <Location>BRUSSELS</Location> 1977.

PAPERS AND DISCUSSION IN ENGLISH, FRENCH AND <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> VARIOUS ASPECTS OF THE
IMPACT OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES WITHIN THE FIELDS OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
WORLD; THE WORLD OF <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>, LAW AND POLITICS; THE WORLD OF EDUCATION AND
<Organization>LEARNING</Organization>; BUSINESS, COMMERCE AND INDUSTRY; SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, AND READING
FOR PLEASURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1011
A SELECT LIST OF NEWSLETTERS IN THE FIELD OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENCE.

A SELECT ANNOTATED ALPHABETICAL LIST OF ENGLISH-LANGUAGE NEWSLETTERS IN THE
FIELD OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE, GIVING TITLE TOGETHER WITH
SUBTITLE, EXPANSION OF ACRONYMS, RELEVANT EXPLANATORY NOTES; NAME AND ADDRESS
OF <Organization>PUBLISHER OR EDITORIAL OFFICE</Organization>; <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> DETAILS; AND NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> NATURE
OF CONTENTS. CRITERIA FOR INCLUSION WAS A PROBLEM. IT WAS DECIDED TO
CONCENTRATE <Organization>ON</Organization> PUBLICATIONS HAVING A <Organization>SMALL</Organization> NUMBER OF PAGES COVERING A <Organization>LARGE</Organization>
NUMBER OF ITEMS, BUT EXCLUDE THOSE PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> SPECIFIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, MOST
DIVISIONS OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ASSOCIATIONS</Organization>, <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ASSOCIATIONS</Organization>, AND
COOPERATIVE SCHEMES AND EXCLUDE THOSE WHICH ARE NO <Organization>LONGER</Organization> IN EXISTENCE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1012
FOR OUR 25TH ANNIVERSARY.

THE CRITERIA USED TO STUDY THE CHARACTERISTICS OF 5 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> IN AN
EARLIER <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> (SEE 80/4136) WERE <Organization>APPLIED</Organization> TO THE AUTHORSHIP STUDY OF LIBR.
RESOUR. TECH. SERV.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1013
INTRODUCTION TO COMPARATIVE LIBRARIANSHIP.

A SERIES OF LECTURES <Organization>ON</Organization> COMPARATIVE LIBRARIANSHIP, ENTITLED THE NATURE OF
COMPARATIVE LIBRARIANSHIP; SYSTEMS THEORY IN A <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> CONTEXT; DATA <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
AND ANALYSIS; SOURCES IN COMPARATIVE LIBRARIANSHIP; CASE <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>;
INTERNATIONAL ASPECTS; AND IN CONCLUSION. STRESSES THE PRACTICAL VALUE OF
COMPARATIVE LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> ROLE AS A <Organization>BASIC</Organization> ELEMENT IN <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> FOR
CHANGE AND IMPROVEMENT AND IN <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. THE PRACTICE OF COMPARATIVE
LIBRARIANSHIP PROVIDES A METHOD OF DEVELOPING A LIBRARIANSHIP THEORY AND <Organization>CAN</Organization>
BE SAID TO BE THE <Organization>END</Organization> PRODUCT OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> BRANCHES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STUDY AND <Organization>ALSO</Organization>
THE BEGINNING OF PURPOSEFUL APPLICATION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> THAT IS LEARNT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THEM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1014
<Organization>HOW</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> <Organization>WE</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>?.

INTRODUCTIONS TO A DEBATE HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 14TH <Organization>NORDIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEETING IN <Location>STOCKHOLM</Location>
AUG 80. O. HARBO DISTINGUISHES 4 TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> USES. THE
MOST IMPORTANT IS <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> AREA, I.E. <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>INTO ACQUISITION</Organization>, STORING AND RETRIEVAL OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. THE RESULTS <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE
USED DIRECTLY, OR INDIRECTLY FOR THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> BENEFIT OF THE PERSON
CARRYING OUT THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. MANY <Organization>LARGE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PROJECTS <Organization>CAN</Organization> ONLY BE CARRIED
OUT <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BODIES. M. OKKO POINTS TO THE DANGERS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WHICH IS CARRIED OUT FOR <Organization>ITS</Organization> USEFULNESS ONLY AND <Organization>IIS</Organization> DIRECTED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>OUTSIDE</Organization> INTERESTS. THE <Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization> RESULTS OF <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE MUST
PERMEATE THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> THINKING AND PRACTICE. B. QUENTZER DETECTS A
MISTRUST OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> THINKING IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. EDUCATION FOR LIBRARIANSHIP MUST
BE CHANGED <Organization>SO</Organization> THAT IT IS MORE PROBLEM ORIENTATED AND <Organization>CRITICAL</Organization>, THUS AN
INTEREST IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE BUILT UP. INCLUDES CONTRIBUTIONS TO  THE
DEBATE <Organization>BY</Organization> G. RENBORG AND E. STARFELT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1015
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.

COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE REPORT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization>
FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, PUBLISHED AUTUMN 80. THE REPORT SHOWS LACK OF
CLASSIFICATION PRINCIPLES AND CLEAR DEFINITIONS. THUS THE TERMS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE ARE USED INTERCHANGEABLY. THE ORGANISATION OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IS NOT DISCUSSED, AND <Organization>HOW</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SCHOOL <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE
LINKED TO ONGOING FIELD <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IS HARDLY DEALT WITH. ORGANIZATIONAL CONTACT
WITH <Organization>GOTEBORG UNIVERSITY</Organization>, AS SUGGESTED, IS NOT ENOUGH, LINKS SHOULD <Organization>ALSO</Organization> BE
ESTABLISHED WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND WITH THE CENTRE FOR
INTERDISCIPLINARY <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>. THE SUGGESTED APPOINTMENT OF A DOCUMENTALIST TO
<Organization>DOCUMENT</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IS PRAISED. THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> SHOULD BE
SENT TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> INSTITUTIONS FOR DISCUSSION BEFORE DECISIONS
ARE MADE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1016
THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> COMPLETED.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY HIGH SCHOOL</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HAS NOW COMPLETED
<Organization>ITS</Organization> WORK AND DRAWN UP A <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization>. THE <Organization>BACKGROUND</Organization> TO THE WORK WAS THE REFORM
OF <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> IN 1977, WHICH ENCOURAGED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, GIVING PRIORITY TO&apos;
DEVELOPMENT OF FOUNDATION <Organization>COURSES</Organization> WHICH ENCOURAGE THE STUDENTS TO MAKE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS, FURTHER <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF LECTURERS, AND IMPROVEMENT OF
FACILITIES FOR LECTURERS TO FOLLOW <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. THE <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization>
1ST MEETING IN AUG 78 ADOPTED <Organization>THESE</Organization> GUIDELINES&apos; TO EXAMINE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization>
<Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> PLANS TO SEE <Organization>HOW</Organization> FAR THEY PROMOTE <Organization>STUDENT</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>;
TO ESTABLISH CONTACT WITH INTERNATIONAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>; TO PROMOTE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SKILLS
AMONG TEACHERS OF LIBRARIANSHIP; TO INITIATE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS. A PERMANENT
<Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WAS SET UP IN 1978 AND PARTICIPANTS WERE SENT <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>COURSES</Organization> AND CONFERENCES. AN EXAMINATION OF ON-GOING LIBRARY-RELEVANT <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
IN <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> INSTITUTIONS WAS MADE  AND TO FACILITATE THE MONITORING
OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> A COMPUTER <Organization>BASED</Organization> INDEX&apos; <Organization>NORDIC</Organization> BDI INDEX, HAS BEEN CREATED.
IT REMAINS TO PLAN A COURSE BRIDGING THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND
RESEARCHERS IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FIELD.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1017
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> REPORT: THE STRANGE CAREER OF <Location>ADELAIDE</Location> HASSE.

AN ACCOUNT OF THE CAREER AND PERSONALITY OF <Location>ADELAIDE</Location> R. HASSE, WHO BEGAN HER
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CAREER IN 1891, DEVISED THE CLASSIFICATION <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR <Location>US</Location> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
<Organization>DOCUMENTS</Organization>, FINALLY RETIRED IN 1952 AFTER A WIDE-RANGING SEQUENCE OF POSTS, AND
DIED AGED 85 IN 1953.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1018
MOSTLY IN THE LINE OF DUTY&apos; THIRTY YEARS WITH BOOKS.

AFTER AN INTRODUCTORY CHAPTER <Organization>ON</Organization> HIS WAR EXPERIENCES, LIEBAERS DISCUSSES HIS
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ACTIVITIES AS A LIBRARIAN, <Organization>FROM</Organization> WORK <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF
<Location>BELGIUM</Location>, THROUGH INVOLVEMENT IN THE BUILDING OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>GENEVA</Location>, <Location>BRUSSELS</Location>,
<Location>PARIS</Location> AND TEHERAN, TO REMINISCENCES OF THE PERIOD SPENT AS IFLA PRESIDENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1019
BLISS WITH PLUMBE-A TRIBUTE TO WILFRED J. PLUMBE.

WILFRED J. PLUMBE RETIRED <Organization>FROM</Organization> HIS POSITION AS LIBRARIAN OF THE <Location>PAPUA NEW
GUINEA</Location> UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY IN OCT 80, AFTER NEARLY 50 YEARS IN
LIBRARIANSHIP, MUCH OF IT IN THIRD WORLD COUNTRIES. COMPRISES REMINISCENCES <Organization>BY</Organization>
SOME OF HIS FORMER COLLEAGUES&apos; HEDWIG ANUAR, IN <Location>SINGAPORE</Location>; LIM HUCK-TEE, IN
<Location>MALAYSIA</Location>; AN ANONYMOUS CORRESPONDENT <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Location>MALAWI</Location>; B.L.B. MUSHONGA, <Organization>FROM</Organization>
<Location>GUYANA</Location>; AND SUSIL BHAN, <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Location>FIJI</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1020
<Organization>FRIENDS</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SOURCEBOOK.

SUMMARISES AND EXPANDS UPON A <Organization>US NATIONWIDE</Organization> SURVEY OF <Organization>FRIENDS</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ORGANISATIONS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> SOURCEBOOK, <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>TYPICAL COMMITTEE</Organization> STRUCTURE OF A
<Organization>FRIENDS GROUP</Organization>, PROVIDES SUCCESSFUL, PROVEN EXAMPLES OF ACTIVITIES, AND
EXAMINES THE PROBLEMS OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> VOLUNTEER ORGANISATIONS. THE IDEAS PRESENTED MAY
BE USED <Organization>BY</Organization> BOTH <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1021
LIBRARIANSHIP IS A PROFESSION.

CONTENDS THAT LIBRARIANSHIP IS A PROFESSION, RATHER THAN A JOB, AND IT
REQUIRES THAT THE PRACTITIONER SHOULD HAVE AN <Organization>ADVANCED EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. DISCUSSES THE DEDICATION NEEDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN IN
ORDER TO SERVE THE COMMUNITY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1022
THE ESSENCE AND NATURE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> TASKS.

NOTE. AN ENGLISH TRANSLATION OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> ARTICLE IS PUBLISHED IN <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>, (1) 1980, 33-41. DISCUSSES THE TASKS OF
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RELATIONSHIP TO USERS. ENQUIRIES REFLECT THE
USERS&apos; RELATIONSHIP TO THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> WORDS, THE TASK IS TO THE ENQUIRY
AS &apos;POSSIBILITY&apos; IS TO &apos;REALITY&apos;. THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> TASKS OF <Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE
<Organization>DEFINED</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1023
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE AND ARCHIVE WORK.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization>, WITH INDIVIDUAL PROFILES, WORK AS AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTIST AND AS
AN ARCHIVIST. INTERVIEWS WITH AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>STUDENT</Organization>, 2 <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENTISTS, A SENIOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANT AND A COUNTY ARCHIVIST ARE INTERSPERSED
WITH DETAILS OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>ASSOCIATIONS</Organization>, <Organization>COURSES</Organization> AND RESUMES OF THE WORK OF
BOTH <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS AND ARCHIVISTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1024
PRACTICAL CONSIDERATIONS <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN <Organization>APPLIED</Organization> MATHEMATICS
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE.

COMPUTER MODELLING AS AN ASPECT OF <Organization>APPLIED</Organization> MATHEMATICS IS DISCUSSED. THE
INTEGRATION OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> TYPE OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WITH <Organization>RESEARCH ON INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> IS
EXAMINED, WITH IMPLICATIONS FOR THE <Organization>APPLIED</Organization> MATHEMATICIAN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1025
CLASSICS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> SELECTED READINGS IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.

SELECTED PAPERS <Organization>FROM</Organization> A VARIETY OF PUBLISHED SOURCES <Organization>ON</Organization> VARIOUS ASPECTS OF
LIBRARIANSHIP, UNDER THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> HEADINGS&apos; JANET DOE LECTURES; THE
PROFESSION; THE LIBRARIAN; THE ECOLOGY OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; <Organization>INNOVATIONS</Organization> AND
SERVICES; TECHNOLOGIES; THE HISTORY OF MEDICINE AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; AND
BIOGRAPHICAL VIGNETTES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1026
A FEW WORDS <Organization>ABOUT PUBLIC SERVICE</Organization>, HENRY MILLER AND WHAT BROUGHT <Location>US</Location> TO WHERE <Organization>WE</Organization>
ARE.

RUMINATES <Organization>ON</Organization> WHAT MAKES <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> EMBARK <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> CHOSEN CAREER AND
SUGGESTS THAT <Organization>EACH</Organization> IS ENGAGED IN WRITING HIS OWN VERSION OF HENRY MILLER&apos;S THE
BOOKS IN MY LIFE (IN WHICH MILLER DISCUSSES WHAT CERTAIN BOOKS AND WRITERS
HAVE MEANT TO HIM). EVERY TIME A PATRON ASKS A LIBRARIAN TO SUGGEST A TITLE,
THE LIBRARIAN THINKS BACK, MAKES A SUGGESTION, WRITES ANOTHER CHAPTER IN HIS
VERSION OF MILLER&apos;S <Organization>BOOK</Organization>, AND REPAYS THE DEBT OWED TO THE SUGGESTED TITLE&apos;S
AUTHOR (FOR ENRICHING THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S LIFE) <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>KEEPING</Organization> HIS WORDS ALIVE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1027
PERCEPTIONS OF THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>SCHOOL MEDIA</Organization> SPECIALIST.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT AND FORMATIVE EVALUATION OF AN ATTITUDE
QUESTIONNAIRE REGARDING PERCEPTIONS OF THE ROLE OF <Organization>PUBLIC SCHOOL MEDIA</Organization>
SPECIALIST/SCHOOL LIBRARIAN. THE QUESTIONNAIRE WAS USED TO DETERMINE
DIFFERENCES IN <Organization>EXPECTATIONS HELD BY COLLEGE</Organization> AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LEVEL MEDIA</Organization>
EDUCATORS, <Organization>PRACTISING MEDIA</Organization> <Organization>SPECIALISTS</Organization>, PRINCIPALS, AND TEACHERS IN AN
EASTERN ALABAMA 10-DISTRICT SCHOOL CONSORTIUM. THE RESPONSES CLEARLY
DEMONSTRATED THAT THE PERCEPTIONS OF THE MEDIA EDUCATORS ARE MOST DIVERGENT
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THOSE OF THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> GROUPS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1028
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>SINGAPORE</Location>. SILVER JUBILEE. 1955-1980.

A COMMEMORATIVE PUBLICATION CONTAINING MESSAGES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PRESIDENT OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>SINGAPORE</Location> AND THE HEADS OF <Organization>SEVERAL INTERNATIONAL</Organization>
LIBRARIANSHIP ORGANISATIONS; A LETTER <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>, <Organization>BY</Organization> WILFRED J.
PLUMBE; ARTICLES REMINISCING <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE ASSOCIATION&apos;S BIRTH AND GROWTH, <Organization>BY</Organization> L.M.
HARROD, ISOBEL ANDREWS, JEAN M. WALLER, HEDWIG ANUAR, P. LIM PUI HUEN, CHAN
THYE SENG, AND WEE JOO GIM; LISTS OF ASSOCIATION PUBLICATIONS, ACTIVITIES, AND
PRESIDENTS; AND THE ASSOCIATION&apos;S CONSTITUTION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1029
<Organization>EXTERNAL</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP. VOLUME 1-REPORT.

AN <Organization>INVESTIGATION</Organization> <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE POTENTIAL EFFICACY OF <Organization>EXTERNAL</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN
LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>BASE</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LEVEL</Organization> WITH RECOMMENDATIONS
<Organization>ON</Organization> POSSIBLE PATTERNS OF <Organization>EXTERNAL</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> PROVISION AND THE IDENTIFICATION OF
MINIMUM REQUIREMENTS FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization> IMPLEMENTATION HAVING REGARD TO <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> AND
ECONOMIC VIABILITY. (THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WAS FUNDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE EDUCATION <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
DEVELOPMENT COMMITTEE, <Location>CANBERRA</Location> <Organization>ACT</Organization>).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1030
<Organization>EXTERNAL</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP. VOLUME II-APPENDICES.

APPENDICES TO THE REPORT FUNDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE EDUCATION <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT
COMMITTEE, <Location>CANBERRA</Location> <Organization>ACT</Organization>, FOR AN ABSTRACT OF WHICH, SEE THE PREVIOUS ABSTRACT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1031
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EDUCATION&apos; A <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> PROBLEM.

IT IS OFTEN SUPRISING TO ENQUIRERS TO <Organization>LEARN</Organization> THAT THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF
<Location>SINGAPORE</Location> (<Organization>LAS</Organization>) HAS <Organization>SO</Organization> MANY QUALIFIED <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND YET <Location>SINGAPORE</Location> HAS NO
<Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> HAS BEEN A PERPLEXING PROBLEM THROUGH THE 25
YEARS OF EXISTENCE OF THE <Organization>LAS</Organization>. DISCUSSES THE NEED FOR A <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> IN
<Location>SINGAPORE</Location>, AND TRACES THE HISTORY OF <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> THROUGH
THE WORK OF THE PERSATUAN PERPUSTAKAAN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>, AND THE <Organization>LAS</Organization>, RENAMED IN 1966
AS PERSATUAN PERPUSTAKAAN SINGAPURA. LOOKS FORWARD TO THE TIME WHEN THE
QUESTION OF <Organization>FORMAL LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> WOULD BE REVIEWED MORE REGULARLY <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AUTHORITIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1032
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> AND THE NEED FOR COORDINATION (IN ARABIC).

THE <Organization>JORDAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> HAS SUPPLIED JORDANIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH TRAINED
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> SINCE <Organization>ITS</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>COURSES</Organization> BEGAN IN 1964, AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION CENTRE</Organization> WAS LATER ESTABLISHED TO TAKE THE RESPONSIBILITY IN <Organization>THIS</Organization>
FIELD. SUGGESTS THAT <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IS HAMPERED <Organization>BY</Organization> EXCESSIVE INTEREST IN
FINANCIAL CONCERNS AND LACK OF <Organization>PROPER</Organization> <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>. CONTENDS THAT&apos; <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>
QUALIFICATIONS AND FIELD EXPERIENCE OF INSTRUCTORS SHOULD BE <Organization>STANDARDISED</Organization>;
INSTITUTIONS QUALIFIED TO TEACH LIBRARIANSHIP MUST BE <Organization>DEFINED</Organization>; THE REAL
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> OF THE COUNTRY SHOULD BE CONSIDERED; QUALITY MUST NOT BE
SACRIFICED TO OUTPUT OF GRADUATES; AND COORDINATION BETWEEN INDIVIDUAL
INSTITUTIONS AND THE <Organization>JLA</Organization> WOULD BE ADVANTAGEOUS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1033
<Organization>EXTENDED LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMS&apos; PROCEEDINGS OF A <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE, <Organization>COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY</Organization>, 13-14 MARCH 1980.

THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> <Organization>INCLUDED</Organization> <Organization>FORMAL</Organization> PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> VARIOUS ASPECTS OF THE PROBLEM, BRIEF
QUESTION-AND-ANSWER SESSIONS, A PANEL OF EMPLOYERS OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>
GRADUATES, AND <Organization>INFORMAL</Organization> DISCUSSION. PRESENTS THE <Organization>FORMAL</Organization> <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> PAPERS AND
SOME OF THE RESULTING DISCUSSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1034
<Organization>LIBRARY COUNCIL</Organization> OF <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>. <Organization>ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.
FIRST REPORT: NOVEMBER 1980.

THE COMMITTEE WAS ESTABLISHED <Organization>ON</Organization> 11 SEPT 80 TO ADVISE THE COUNCIL <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION MATTERS, AND HAS 6 MEMBERS. TOPICS DISCUSSED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 1ST 2 MEETINGS
INCLUDE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COURSE ENTRY QUALIFICATIONS; SHORT <Organization>COURSES</Organization>, COMMENDED FEATURES
OF <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization>, AND DIFFICULTIES WITH THE SAME; <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> RELATIONS
WITH THE PROFESSION; THE RANGE OF LONG <Organization>COURSES</Organization>; AND <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
QUALIFICATIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1035
ALTERNATIVE MODES FOR <Organization>PROVIDING GRADUATE EDUCATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Organization>OHIO</Organization>&apos;
FINAL REPORT.

REPORT OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> INITIATED DUE TO THE FACT THAT ONLY 2 <Organization>OHIO</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS
ACCREDITED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE ALA ARE LOCATED IN NORTHEASTERN <Organization>OHIO</Organization>, <Organization>MERELY</Organization> 35 MILES APART.
THE STUDY INCLUDES A <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> ASSESSMENT, A RESOURCES ASSESSMENT, AND AN ANALYSIS
OF 4 ALTERNATIVE APPROACHES-A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> MODEL, A <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> TRANSFER MODEL,
AN EXTENSION MODEL, AND A CONSORTIUM MODEL. AMONGST THE CONCLUSIONS ARE THE
<Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization>&apos; NORTHEASTERN <Organization>OHIO</Organization> WILL CONTINUE TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> 40% OF THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
EMPLOYMENT OPPORTUNITIES IN THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> THROUGH 1990; A <Organization>NEW GRADUATE SCHOOL</Organization> WILL
NOT BE WARRANTED IN THE 1980S BECAUSE OF THE TIGHT JOB MARKET; AND TRANSFER OF
KENT&apos;S <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> TO COLUMBUS WOULD LEAVE A SERIOUS <Organization>GAP</Organization> IN NORTHEASTERN <Organization>OHIO</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1036
<Organization>SERIALS EDUCATION</Organization> IN MASTER&apos;S DEGREE PROGRAMS IN ACCREDITED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS IN
THE <Location>UNITED STATES</Location> AND CANADA.

(<Organization>PHD THESIS-FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY</Organization>.) A QUESTIONNAIRE SURVEY WAS SENT TO THE
DIRECTORS OF THE 68 <Location>US</Location> AND CANADIAN ACCREDITED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, CONCERNING
<Organization>COURSES ON SERIALS ACQUISITION</Organization>, <Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, CONTROL, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>,
AND CLASSIFICATION. 9 <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization> INTERVIEWS WERE HELD WITH THE TEACHERS OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization>
<Organization>COURSES</Organization> TO IDENTIFY <Organization>THEIR</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS AND OBJECTIVES. THE 56 QUESTIONNAIRE
RESPONSES SHOWED THAT LESS ATTENTION WAS PAID TO <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> CONTROL THAN TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
SERIALS-RELATED TOPICS AND THAT THERE WERE SIGNIFICANT DIFFERENCES IN TEACHING
OF CONCEPTS IN SEPARATE AND NON-SEPARATE <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1037
RATL-<Location>GLASGOW</Location>.

REPORT OF A RECENT RUNNING A <Organization>TOY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (RATL) WEEKEND COURSE IN <Location>GLASGOW</Location>,
WHICH <Organization>INCLUDED PRESENTATIONS ON FUND</Organization> RAISING, SETTING UP AND RUNNING A <Organization>TOY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE WORK OF THE <Organization>TOY LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, <Organization>TOY</Organization> MAINTENANCE AND REPAIR,
THE ROLE OF PLAY IN <Organization>HUMAN DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, AND RECOMMENDED TOYS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1038
EDUCATION FOR <Organization>MAP</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.

OUTLINES THE HISTORY OF <Organization>MAP LIBRARIANSHIP EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location>, AND DISCUSSES
CRITICALLY THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCIENCE EDUCATION</Organization> GENERALLY. INDICATES SOME
SPECIFIC REQUIREMENTS OF <Organization>MAP LIBRARIANSHIP EDUCATION</Organization>, AND MAKES
RECOMMENDATIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MAP</Organization> LIBRARIAN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1039
EDUCATION IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> DOCUMENTATION IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>.

<Organization>DESCRIBES EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> DOCUMENTATION AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> IN
<Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>. THERE ARE 3 PRINCIPAL LEVELS OF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>&apos; (1) DOCUMENTATION
ASSISTANT; (2) DIPLOMA (DEGREE) IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> INFORMATICS, INFORMATICS
(COMPUTING) WITH <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization>, OR MEDICINE WITH COMPUTER <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization>;
AND (3) CERTIFICATE OF THE GMDS, THE HIGHEST ACCOLADE AND A <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
RECOGNITION CONFERRED <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>LEARNED SOCIETY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1040
CONCEPTUAL FRAMEWORKS FOR <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> INSTRUCTION.

DISCUSSES THE NECESSITY FOR CONCEPTUAL FRAMEWORKS TO ORGANISE THE CONTENTS OF
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> INSTRUCTION AND MAINTAINS THAT <Organization>SUCH</Organization> FRAMEWORKS <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> A BASIS
FOR GENERALISABLE AND MEANINGFUL <Organization>LEARNING</Organization>. <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF 7 CONCEPTUAL
FRAMEWORKS IN <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> INSTRUCTION-TYPE OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TOOL, SYSTEMATIC
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization>, FORM OF PUBLICATION, PRIMARY/<Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> SOURCES,
PUBLICATION SEQUENCE, CITATION PATTERNS, AND INDEX STRUCTURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1041
THE TEACHING OF ONLINE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization>
IN <Location>U.K.</Location> SCHOOLS OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE.

IN LATE 79 THE 16 SCHOOLS OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE IN THE <Location>UK</Location>
WERE SURVEYED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> TEACHING OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> AS WELL
AS <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH AS MICROCOMPUTER SYSTEMS</Organization>, INTELLIGENT
<Organization>TERMINALS</Organization>, <Organization>VIEWDATA SYSTEMS</Organization> AND <Organization>SO</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE RESULTS ALONG WITH
DETAILS OF <Organization>BLR&amp;D</Organization> FUNDED WORK IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> AREA IN 7 OF THE SCHOOLS. INCLUDES
RECOMMENDATIONS FOR FURTHER WORK IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> AREA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1042
THE TEACHING OF ONLINE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization>
IN <Location>U.K.</Location> SCHOOLS OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE.

FOR AN ABSTRACT OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> ARTICLE SEE:.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1043
<Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PERSONNEL IN THE <Location>UK</Location>.

THE MAIN <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> SURVEY WAS TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THAT WOULD FACILITATE
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> OF <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THERE
WERE 3 MAIN AREAS OF ENQUIRY&apos; (1) CHARACTERISTICS OF PERSONNEL WITH REGARD TO
<Organization>AGE</Organization>, EXPERIENCE, EMPLOYMENT BASIS, <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> ATTAINMENT, <Organization>FORMAL</Organization>
EDUCATION IN LIBRARIANSHIP, JOB ACTIVITIES AND <Organization>LEVEL</Organization> OF RESPONSIBILITY; (2)
<Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> REQUIREMENTS IN RESPECT OF CONTENT, MODE AND VENUE OF <Organization>COURSES</Organization>; (3)
GEOGRAPHICAL LOCATION AND TYPE OF INSTITUTION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1044
CONDITIONS FOR DEVELOPMENT&apos; <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> SIX ACCREDITED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOLS WITH SELECTED ADDITIONAL RESOURCES. A REPORT TO THE <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization>
EDUCATION COMMITTEE, KENTUCKY, <Organization>OHIO</Organization>, MICHIGAN <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROGRAM.

UNDERTAKEN TO DETERMINE TO DETERMINE WHAT POTENTIAL EXISTS FOR <Organization>GREATER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOL INVOLVEMENT IN <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> FOR HEALTH SCIENCE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN
KENTUCKY, <Organization>OHIO</Organization>, AND MICHIGAN, <Organization>THIS</Organization> STUDY HAD 4 <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> OBJECTIVES&apos; (1) TO ASSESS
THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> STATUS FOR <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN THE REGION AS PROVIDED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION PROGRAMMES, (2) TO IDENTIFY POSSIBLE AREAS OF FUTURE INVOLVEMENT <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMMES IN <Organization>REGIONAL OR STATEWIDE CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>
ACTIVITIES, (3) TO IDENTIFY THE REWARDS <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FOR <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>
ACTIVITIES OFFERED, AND (4) TO IDENTIFY RESOURCES WHICH COULD BE MADE
<Organization>AVAILABLE OFFERING CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> ACTIVITIES IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.
REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1045
INTERNSHIP PROGRAMS IN <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A MUTUALLY BENEFICIAL EXPERIENCE FOR
LIBRARIAN AND <Organization>STUDENT</Organization>.

DISCUSSES CRITERIA FOR THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN WHEN DECIDING <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> TO <Organization>USE</Organization>
INTERNS (<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STUDENTS) IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. INCLUDES THE BENEFITS,
RESPONSIBILITIES AND AVAILABILITY OF INTERNSHIPS. WORK PROGRAMMES ARE
SUGGESTED AND <Organization>SAMPLE</Organization> PROJECTS CONSIDERED FOR FIELD WORK.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1046
W.H. SMITH &amp; SON&apos;S CIRCULATING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

(MLS THESIS.) TRACES THE HISTORY OF W.H. SMITH &amp; SON&apos;S CIRCULATING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> INCEPTION AROUND 1860 TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> CLOSURE IN 1961. CONSIDERS THE FACTORS
INFLUENCING <Organization>ITS</Organization> ESTABLISHMENT, AND DISCUSSES <Organization>ITS</Organization> ORGANISATION AND USERS.
EXAMINES THE CIRCULATING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S POWER TO INFLUENCE <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization> PRACTICE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1047
THE <Location>LONDON</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BORROWINGS OF THOMAS CARLYLE, 1841-1844.

THOMAS CARLYLE&apos;S CRUSADE FOR A LENDING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>LONDON</Location> (<Location>UK</Location>) CULMINATED WITH
THE OPENING OF THE <Location>LONDON</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN 1841 AND MANY OF THE BOOKS PURCHASED
DURING THAT YEAR WERE OBTAINED TO SATISFY HIS <Organization>NEEDS</Organization>. HIS <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
UNTIL 1844 IS TRACED THROUGH THE LENDING REGISTERS AND USED AS A GUIDE TO HIS
INTERESTS DURING THAT PERIOD.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1048
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE SEVENTIES&apos; A GUIDE TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SOURCES.

ANNOTATED BIBLIOGRAPHY OF SOURCES REPRESENTATIVE OF THE MOST USEFUL MATERIALS
OF THE 1970S <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>OPERATION</Organization>, MANAGEMENT AND COLLECTIONS OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF
SCI-TECH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES. <Organization>ALL</Organization> OF THE 500 CITATIONS ARE
PUBLICATIONS IN ENGLISH, WRITTEN <Organization>FROM</Organization> A PRACTICAL, RATHER THAN PURELY
<Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization> VIEWPOINT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1049
<Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> (<Organization>MLA</Organization>) 81. <Organization>ANNUAL</Organization> MEETING <Location>MONTREAL</Location>, <Location>CANADA</Location>, MAY
29-JUNE 4, 1981 (IN NORWEGIAN).

REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE MEETING WITH DISCUSSION OF INDIVIDUAL SESSIONS WHICH <Organization>INCLUDED</Organization>
<Organization>TAX-BASED HEALTH CARE</Organization>; THE BIOMEDICAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CONNECTION; AND <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization>
EDUCATION <Organization>COURSES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1050
ILLUSTRATIONS TO THE HISTORY OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>IRELAND</Location> 1877-1977.

ILLUSTRATED ACCOUNT OF SOME OF THE MORE INTERESTING FEATURES OF, AND
CHARACTERS INVOLVED WITH THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>IRELAND</Location>, IN PART A SUPPLEMENT
TO ALF MACLOCHLAINN&apos;S&apos; THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>IRELAND</Location> 1877-1977, (IRISH
UNIVERSITY REVIEW, AUTUMN 77).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1051
THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Location>PHILIPPINES</Location>.

THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Location>PHILIPPINES</Location> IS A <Organization>GOVERNMENT AGENCY</Organization>, COMING UNDER
THE MINISTRY OF EDUCATION AND CULTURE. ESTABLISHED IN 1900, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS
MADE UP OF 8 DIVISIONS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE FILIPINIANA AND ASIA DIVISION, THE
<Organization>PUBLIC DOCUMENTS DIVISION</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE DIVISION</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> 3 READING
ROOMS <Organization>CAN</Organization> ACCOMMODATE APPROXIMATELY 532 READERS <Organization>EACH</Organization>, AND THE AUDITORIUM SEATS
400. THE BOOKSTACK CAPACITY IS 1,000 VOLUMES, <Organization>ON</Organization> 8 FLOOR LEVELS OF STACKS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1052
THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>CANADA</Location>: TWENTY-FIVE YEARS AFTER.

<Organization>RETROSPECTIVE</Organization> OVERVIEW PUBLISHED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE OCCASION OF THE 25TH ANNIVERSARY OF
THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>CANADA</Location>. EMPHASISES <Organization>ITS</Organization> EVOLUTION, PROBLEMS,
SHORTCOMINGS AND ACHIEVEMENTS AND THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> CHANGES THAT HAVE TAKEN PLACE IN
<Organization>ITS</Organization> 1ST 25 YEARS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1053
SURVEY OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>GERMAN PATENT OFFICE</Organization>.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>WEST GERMAN PATENT OFFICE</Organization>, WHICH IS AMONG THE LARGEST
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>GERMANY</Location>, SERVES BOTH AS INTERNAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>PATENT OFFICE</Organization>
AND FEDERAL <Organization>PATENT</Organization> COURT AND AS A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S
HOLDINGS OF <Organization>PATENT</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTS</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND THE <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> AIDS
FOR USERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1054
SURVEY OF <Organization>STATE LIBRARY AGENCIES</Organization>, 1977.

<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF <Organization>STATISTICAL TABLES WHOSE DATA</Organization> WERE DERIVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> A SURVEY OF
<Organization>STATE LIBRARY AGENCIES</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> ACTIVITIES DURING 1977. SUBJECT MATTER OF THE
TABLES INCLUDES&apos; (1) LOCATION OF <Organization>STATE LIBRARY AGENCIES</Organization> WITHIN <Organization>STATE</Organization>
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DEPARTMENTS; (2) SERVICES ADMINISTERED; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIAL
COLLECTIONS, AND ADDITIONS TO <Organization>THESE</Organization> COLLECTIONS; (3) SOURCE, AMOUNT, AND <Organization>USE</Organization>
OF FUNDS; (4) EXPENDITURES; (5) <Organization>STAFF</Organization>; (6) UNFILLED POSITIONS; (7) <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization>
FACILITIES; (8) ACQUISITION, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, AND <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> SERVICES OPERATED
<Organization>ON</Organization> A STATEWIDE BASIS; (9) AUTHORITY FOR PROVISION OF <Organization>CONSULTANT SERVICES</Organization>; AND
(10) NUMBER AND TYPE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKS WITHIN THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>.
REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1055
INTER-LIBRARY COMPARISONS&apos; DESIGN STUDY AND FIELD TRIAL RELATING TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE WORK WAS UNDERTAKEN WITH THE COOPERATION OF A GROUP OF 10 <Organization>LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization>&apos;
<Organization>THESE</Organization> WERE 6 ENGLISH COUNTIES, A <Location>LONDON</Location> BOROUGH, A <Organization>SCOTTISH</Organization> DISTRICT AND 2
METROPOLITAN-COUNTY DISTRICTS. THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INVITED THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
INVOLVED TO BE PART OF A <Organization>CONSULTATIVE COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> INTER-LIBRARY COMPARISONS.
OTHERS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE COMMITTEE CAME <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, THE DEPARTMENT OF
EDUCATION AND SCIENCE, THE <Organization>CHARTERED INSTITUTE</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> FINANCE AND
ACCOUNTANCY AND A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1056
HISTORY OF &apos;<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; IN CARMARTHENSHIRE.

(FLA THESIS.) TRACES <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE &apos;<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; ESTABLISHED IN
CARMARTHENSHIRE, WALES, <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PAROCHIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF DR. BRAY AND HIS
ASSOCIATES (FOUNDED IN 1699) TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> REORGANISATION IN 1974.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1057
<Organization>SOCIALIST LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>GDR</Organization>.

SUMMARY OF A THESIS PRESENTED TO THE <Organization>SITTARD SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN 1980. <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> HAS A HIGHLY <Organization>DEVELOPED</Organization> NETWORK OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF THE COUNTRY&apos;S 14 REGIONS <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE BEEN
<Organization>DESIGNATED</Organization> TO <Organization>ACT</Organization> AS <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> CENTRES FOR THE SMALLER DISTRICT AND
<Organization>LOCAL COMMUNITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> ARE GOVERNED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>ACT</Organization> OF 1968 AND <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE MEMBERS OF THE <Organization>EAST GERMAN UNION</Organization> OF
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IN CONTRAST TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>WESTERN EUROPE</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>EAST
GERMANY</Location> HAVE A <Organization>STRONG</Organization> POLITICAL CHARACTER AND ARE COMPELLED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization> TO <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization>
THE <Organization>SOCIALIST</Organization> ECONOMIC <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE RUN <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>LIBRARY COUNCIL</Organization> WITH
<Organization>REPRESENTATIVES</Organization> DRAWN <Organization>FROM</Organization> USERS, <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> ORGANISATIONS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1058
THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

REVIEW OF THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SITUATION IN <Location>DENMARK</Location>, <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND OBSERVATION GATHERED <Organization>ON</Organization> A VISIT TO THE 45TH IFLA <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>
AND A SHORT STUDY TOUR OF THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> INSPECTORATE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
SELECTED <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE ADMINISTRATION OF THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, THE BIBLIOTEKSCENTRALEN, AND SERVICES AND ACTIVITIES OF
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1059
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND ASSOCIATION <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> STATISTICS 1979.

COMPILED <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SUBMITTED <Organization>BY</Organization> NEW <Location>YORK</Location> <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization>, TABULATES DETAILS OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AND NON-BOOK MATERIALS
HOLDINGS, ADDITIONS TO STOCK DURING 1979, LOANS, AND FINANCES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1060
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT IN THE <Location>SOLOMON ISLANDS</Location>.

AIMS TO SHOW THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE NOT A LUXURY BUT <Organization>BASIC</Organization> TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF
THE <Location>SOLOMON ISLANDS</Location>. PRESENTS A <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> REVIEW OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCENE IN THE SOLOMONS, AND SUGGESTS THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD BE WITHIN EASY REACH
OF THE WHOLE POPULATION OF THE <Location>SOLOMON ISLANDS</Location>, WITH FREE AND OPEN <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO
<Organization>ALL</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1061
A CASE FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

OPEN LETTER USED IN A LOBBY OF PROVINCIAL PREMIERS OF <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>, <Location>PORT
MORESBY</Location>, OCT 80. <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION IN PROVINCIAL
<Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>, AND REQUESTS THE <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> OF THE PREMIERS IN THE DEVELOPMENT
OF A SERVICE, WHICH <Organization>CAN PROVIDE EDUCATION</Organization>, RECREATION, COMMUNICATION,
SELF-IMPROVEMENT, <Organization>RURAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERACY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1062
GETTING DOWN TO 2%: BOOKS FOR <Organization>RURAL</Organization> SCOTLAND.

2% OF THE MAINLAND <Organization>SCOTTISH</Organization> POPULATION ARE SPREAD OVER 70% OF THE LAND. <Organization>THIS</Organization>
<Organization>RELATIVELY</Organization> LOW POPULATION DENSITY AND GEOGRAPHICAL COMPLICATIONS LIMIT THE
POTENTIAL OF <Organization>RURAL</Organization> <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; THERE ARE NO STANDARDS; AND THERE IS NO
PHILOSOPHY OF <Organization>MOBILE SERVICE</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> ROLE IN THE COMMUNITY. A QUESTIONNAIRE
WAS SENT TO <Organization>SCOTTISH</Organization> <Organization>AUTHORITIES RUNNING MOBILE SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> WERE
VISITED TO OBTAIN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> POLICIES CONCERNING MOBILES; USAGE; TIME
SPENT <Organization>AT</Organization> STOPS, TRAVELLING, AND <Organization>ON</Organization> MAINTENANCE; STAFFING; ISSUE FIGURES; <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
SELECTION; <Organization>OTHER</Organization> STOCK; STOCK CHANGES; ISSUE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>; <Organization>VEHICLE CARE</Organization>; PROBLEMS;
<Organization>OTHER RURAL SERVICES</Organization>; EFFECT OF <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> COSTS <Organization>ON</Organization> FUTURE ROLE AND EXTENT OF
<Organization>MOBILE SERVICES</Organization>; AND EFFECTS OF BUDGET CUTS. THE RESULTS ARE DISCUSSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1063
<Location>KIRUNA</Location> TOWN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; A PRESENTATION.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE HISTORY OF <Location>KIRUNA</Location> TOWN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. IT BEGAN IN 1903 AS A LENDING
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO THE <Organization>RAILWAY WORKERS</Organization>, WHO HAD BEGUN TO ARRIVE <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> PARTS OF
<Location>SWEDEN</Location> IN 1899, BUT <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1905 IT WAS OPEN TO <Organization>ALL</Organization>. IN 1932 THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BECAME A
COUNCIL RESPONSIBILITY AND THE 1ST <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN WAS APPOINTED IN
1930. CIRCULATING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO THE OUTLYING AREAS HAVE BEEN SENT OUT, OFTEN <Organization>BY</Organization>
UNUSUAL TRANSPORT MEANS, SINCE 1940. THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> BUILDING, WHERE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
HAS BEEN HOUSED <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1923, WAS EXTENSIVELY ALTERED IN 1980. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
CONTAINS A UNIQUE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE LAPPS AND IN LAPPISH. A
<Organization>LOCAL COUNCIL</Organization> <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS BEEN OPERATING SINCE 1980 AND THE COUNCIL
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> COOPERATES IN A <Organization>NORDIC</Organization> <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> WHICH COVERS THE BORDER
AREAS OF <Location>NORWAY</Location>, <Location>FINLAND</Location> AND SWEDEN. THERE ARE 2 MINE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 1 SURFACE AND
UNDERGROUND. INCLUDES A <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> INSERT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1064
SELLING TO SURVIVE.

EDITED AND ABRIDGED VERSION OF A TALK GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S
BRANCH AND <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES GROUP WEEKEND SCHOOL</Organization>, LYTHAM ST. ANNES, OCT-NOV
80. ALTHOUGH INCOME-GENERATING <Organization>INNOVATIONS</Organization> WILL HELP THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE
SHORT TERM, THE RESULTANT REVENUE WILL ALWAYS BE A <Organization>RELATIVELY</Organization> <Organization>SMALL</Organization> PROPORTION
OF THE BUDGET AND <Organization>SUCH</Organization> ACTIVITIES COULD PREJUDICE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S LONG TERM
SURVIVAL <Organization>BY</Organization> GIVING THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> THE WRONG IMPRESSION. ONLY A MORE BUSINESS-LIKE,
PLANNED, BALANCED APPROACH THAN PREVIOUSLY PRACTISED <Organization>CAN</Organization> SAVE THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. MARKETING <Organization>CAN</Organization> OFFER <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AN APPROACH. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD TAILOR
SERVICES TO MEET THE <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> OF <Organization>ITS COMMUNITY</Organization>, TRAIN <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> TO BE
SALESPEOPLE, AND WORK <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> COMMUNICATION WITH THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1065
<Organization>SEMINAR ON UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>NORWAY</Location>.

A COMMITTEE WAS APPOINTED <Organization>BY</Organization> NORWAY&apos;S MINISTRY OF EDUCATION TO <Organization>EVALUATE</Organization>
UNIVERSITY AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>NORWAY</Location>, AND A <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> WAS ARRANGED IN
<Location>OSLO</Location>, 1 JUNE 81. THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> WAS TO OBTAIN VIEWS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROLES OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN THE FUTURE <Organization>FROM</Organization> BOTH <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1066
<Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SURVEY, 1978-1979.

RESULTS OF THE 9TH <Organization>ANNUAL</Organization> SUMMARY OF HEGIS-LIBGIS (<Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SURVEY-LIBRARY <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SURVEY) <Organization>STATISTICAL DATA</Organization> FOR
STATE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> CODSULI (THE COUNCIL OF DIRECTORS OF
STATE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>ILLINOIS</Organization>). STATISTICS ARE ARRANGED IN 2 SETS OF
TABLES&apos; THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> TABLES SUMMARISE <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> FIGURES FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF THE 14 CODSULI
MEMBER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND SUPPLEMENTARY TABLES GIVE MORE DETAILED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>AT NORTHERN ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>SOUTHERN</Organization> <Organization>ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
CARBONDALE AND EDWARDSVILLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1067
BREAKING <Organization>NEW</Organization> GROUND <Organization>AT</Organization> EUROCENTRES.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE EUROCENTRE LEE GREEN, <Location>LONDON</Location>-PROBABLY <Location>BRITAIN</Location>&apos;S MOST <Organization>MODERN</Organization>
SCHOOL OF ENGLISH AS A <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> <Organization>LANGUAGE</Organization>. THE <Organization>MULTI-MEDIA RESOURCES DEPARTMENT</Organization>
COMPRISES A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>/<Organization>STUDENT RESOURCES CENTRE</Organization> (<Organization>SRC</Organization>) AND LISTENING CENTRE, 2
<Organization>LANGUAGE LABORATORIES</Organization>, A CLASSROOM FITTED WITH COLOUR, <Organization>CLOSED-CIRCUIT TV</Organization>, A
SOUND RECORDING STUDIO AND AN AV WORKSHOP.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1068
AN ANALYSIS OF THE <Organization>LEARNING RESOURCES CENTER</Organization> CONCEPT IN THE TWO-YEAR
INSTITUTIONS OF SELECTED SOUTHEASTERN STATES.

(<Organization>PHD</Organization> THESIS-UNIVERSITY OF GEORGIA.) <Organization>ALL</Organization> 271 2-YEAR INSTITUTIONS IN THE <Location>US</Location>
SOUTHEASTERN STATES WERE SENT QUESTIONNAIRES CONCERNING <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LEARNING</Organization>
<Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> CENTRES AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> COMPLIANCE WITH THE <Location>US</Location> GUIDELINES FOR TWO-YEAR
COLLEGE <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> RESOURCES PROGRAMS AND QUANTITATIVE STANDARDS FOR TWO-YEAR
<Organization>LEARNING</Organization> RESOURCES PROGRAMS; 124 USABLE REPLIES WERE RECEIVED. <Organization>THESE</Organization> RESPONSES
INDICATED THAT THE <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> RESOURCES CENTRES AND PROGRAMMES ARE WELL
ORGANISED AND FUNCTION WELL ABOVE THE &apos;SATISFACTORY <Organization>LEVEL</Organization>&apos;.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1069
GUIDE TO THE ORGANISATION AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>RESOURCE CENTRE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COLLEGES.

MANUAL OF PRACTICE DEALING WITH THE ROLE AND ORGANISATION OF THE <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization>
CENTRE IN A <Organization>TECHNICAL COLLEGE</Organization>, WITH SECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>STUDENT</Organization> ORIENTATION AND
INTEGRATION OF THE <Organization>RESOURCE CENTRE</Organization> WITH TEACHING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1070
<Organization>ANNUAL</Organization> DIRECTORY ISSUE).I

SSUE DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>ANNUAL</Organization> DIRECTORY OF THE <Organization>SPECIAL LIBRARIES ASSOCIATION</Organization>.
PART 1 LISTS DUES AND FEES, ASSOCIATION <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, BYLAWS, AND A MEMBER TALLY <Organization>BY</Organization>
CHAPTER AND DIVISION; PART 2 COMPRISES LISTS OF DIRECTORS, OFFICERS, ADVISORS,
COMMITTEES, <Organization>REPRESENTATIVES</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> OFFICIALS; PART 3 COMPRISES HISTORICAL
HIGHLIGHTS, CHARTER MEMBERS, HONOURS AND AWARDS, EDITORS OF SPEC. LIBR., PAST
PRESIDENTS, PAST CONVENTIONS AND CONFERENCES, AND FUTURE CONFERENCES AND
MEETINGS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1071
FUNCTIONS OF SELECTED COMPANY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>.

A SURVEY OF SELECTED FUNCTIONS OF <Location>US</Location> COMPANY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>&apos;
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND INDEXING; FILES, COLLECTIONS AND <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> WORK;
DISTRIBUTION AND CONTROL FUNCTIONS; REFERENCES AND <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> FUNCTIONS;
LIST PREPARATION AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PUBLICATION FUNCTIONS. THERE WERE 108 <Organization>RESPONDENTS</Organization>
IN 9 INDUSTRY CATEGORIES&apos; ADVERTISING, AIRCRAFT AND MISSILES, CHEMICALS, FOOD,
LAW, NEWSPAPERS, OFFICE MACHINES, PETROLEUM AND PHARMACEUTICALS. TRENDS ARE
NOTED IN BUDGET, CLIENTELE, AND SERVICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1072
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR THE DISABLED, WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DEAF, THE
PHYSICALLY AND VISUALLY HANDICAPPED.

DETAILED REVIEW OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> NEEDED FOR THE DISABLED IN <Location>PAPUA NEW
GUINEA</Location>, <Organization>BASED ON INFORMATION GATHERED ON SERVICES</Organization> TO THE DISABLED IN
INDUSTRIALISED COUNTRIES, AND FOCUSING PARTICULARLY <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> OF THE DEAF,
AND THE PHYSICALLY AND VISUALLY HANDICAPPED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1073
<Organization>PLANNING SERVICES</Organization> FOR OLDER ADULTS.

24 MILLION <Location>US</Location> CITIZENS (1 IN 9 OF THE POPULATION) ARE <Organization>AT</Organization> LEAST 65 YEARS OLD
AND <Organization>THIS</Organization> NUMBER IS GROWING. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> POLITICAL ACTIVITY IS 2ND ONLY TO THE 35-54
<Organization>AGE</Organization> RANGE AND IS EXPECTED TO INCREASE SHARPLY. APPROPRIATE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES MUST RECEIVE INCREASED ATTENTION. INCLUDES A LIST OF SERVICES FOR
WHICH A NEED IS FELT <Organization>BY</Organization> OLDER ADULTS AND CALLS FOR <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 3<Organization>RD</Organization> WHITE HOUSE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> AGING, SCHEDULED FOR DEC 81.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1074
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF PRINT AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MEDIA IN NURSING HOMES OF WISCONSIN IN 1975 AND A
RELATED SURVEY OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO OLDER ADULTS.

<Organization>THIS</Organization> IS BOTH A DESCRIPTIVE STUDY OF THE <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> CLIMATE OF NURSING
HOMES FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF PRINT AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MEDIA, AND A STUDY OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE TO OLDER ADULTS AND TO RESIDENTS OF NURSING HOMES IN WISCONSIN. IT
CONCLUDES A DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO OLDER ADULTS AND
NURSING HOME RESIDENTS TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> A BASIS FOR DESIGN OR MORE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization>
<Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF SERVICE TO THE ELDERLY. THE SURVEY QUESTIONNAIRE TO NURSING HOMES
IS DESIGNED TO EXPLORE THE <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> FACILITIES, THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> CLIMATE FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization>
OF PRINT AND MEDIA, AND THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> READINESS OF NURSING HOME <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND
VOLUNTEERS TO <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> MATERIALS. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
<Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1075
A CONTEMPLATION OF CHILDREN&apos;S SERVICES IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF WISCONSIN.

REPORT OF THE CONTEMPLATION OF CHILDREN&apos;S SERVICES IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF
WISCONSIN, <Location>MADISON</Location>, 4-5 AUG 79, ATTENDED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>REPRESENTATIVES</Organization> OF 12 OF THE
<Organization>STATE</Organization>&apos;S 15 <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF THE DIVISION FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES (THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>STATE LIBRARY AGENCY</Organization>). SERVICES OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
DIVISION&apos;S <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>CONSULTANT</Organization> FOR CHILDREN&apos;S AND YOUNG <Organization>ADULT SERVICES</Organization>
WERE RANKED ACCORDING TO USEFULNESS AND 27 QUESTIONS CONCERNING CHILDREN&apos;S
SERVICES WERE DRAWN UP FOR DISCUSSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1076
YOUTHVIEW: SURVEY OF CHILDREN&apos;S SERVICES IN <Organization>MISSOURI</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PREPARATORY WORK LEADING TO THE ISSUE IN APR-MAY 81 OF A
QUESTIONNAIRE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MISSOURI</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CHILDREN&apos;S SERVICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1077
TOWARDS INDIVIDUALITY: THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>?.

EXAMINES THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> REASONS FOR THE EXISTENCE OF A SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND EXPLAINS
<Organization>HOW</Organization> A SCHOOL LIBRARIAN <Organization>CAN</Organization> RESPOND TO INDIVIDUAL <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> AND <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>EACH</Organization> PUPIL
WITH CONTROLLED EXERCISES OR <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> PROGRAMMES AS THE NEED ARISES.
EMPHASISES THE PHILOSOPHY OF REGARD FOR THE INDIVIDUAL.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1078
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN EDUCATION WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

REVIEW OF THE IMPORTANCE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN EDUCATION; TOPICS COVERED INCLUDE&apos;
AIMS AND METHODS IN THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS PART OF THE SCHOOL;
<Organization>BOOK</Organization> SELECTION; FURNITURE AND BUILDING; AND THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
PRIMARY EMPHASIS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1079
THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND PROGRESSIVE EDUCATORS: TWO POINTS OF VIEW.

A BRIEF SURVEY OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>US PROGRESSIVE EDUCATION</Organization> MOVEMENT,
1920-50, SHOWING THE AMBIVALENCE OF PROGRESSIVE EDUCATORS TOWARD THE SCHOOL
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. SOME OF THE FOREMOST PRACTITIONERS BELIEVED THAT THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
RESOURCES COULD ENRICH AND EXPAND THE NATURE OF EXPERIENCE AND &apos;<Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization>
DOING&apos;; OTHERS WERE APPARENTLY INDIFFERENT OR OPENLY HOSTILE TO THE CONCEPT OF
THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1080
THE <Organization>COMBINED SCHOOL</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN OLNEY, TEXAS.

THE DEDICATION IN JUNE 79 OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> CONSTRUCTED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FACILITY IN OLNEY,
TEXAS, BROUGHT TOGETHER THE COLLECTIONS OF THE SCHOOL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
WHICH HAD BEEN ADMINISTERED AS A SINGLE UNIT WITH ONE BOARD, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
COORDINATOR, AND BUDGET, SINCE 1974. A STUDY CONDUCTED TO <Organization>EVALUATE</Organization> THE
COORDINATED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WHICH EXISTED <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1974-79 EXAMINED THE <Organization>OPERATION</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BOTH <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE</Organization> POINT OF VIEW AND <Organization>ON</Organization> A DAY-TO-DAY BASIS,
PROBLEMS WHICH AROSE AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SOLUTIONS, COMMUNITY ATTITUDES TOWARD THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND THE ADVANTAGES AND DISADVANTAGES OF <Organization>SUCH LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. REPORT
NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1081
THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> CENTRES IN <Organization>SECONDARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN SCOTLAND.

(MA THESIS.) EXAMINES THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> CENTRES IN <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization>
EDUCATION IN SCOTLAND, IDENTIFYING 3 LEVELS OF PROVISION-CENTRAL, AREA, AND
SCHOOL, DEFINING THE ROLE OF <Organization>EACH</Organization>, THE FUNCTIONS WHICH THEY SHOULD PERFORM AND
THE SERVICES WHICH THEY SHOULD <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization>. DISCUSSES THE REASONS FOR THE
EMERGENCE OF <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> CENTRES, <Organization>NEW</Organization> THEORIES IN EDUCATION, <Organization>PRESSURES</Organization> FOR
CURRICULUM CHANGE AND THE RESPONSE OF EDUCATION <Organization>AUTHORITIES</Organization> TO <Organization>THESE</Organization>
<Organization>PRESSURES</Organization>. TREATS <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>LEVEL</Organization> OF <Organization>RESOURCE CENTRE</Organization> SEPARATELY, AND EXAMINES AREA
<Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> CENTRES, DRAWING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE EXPERIENCE OF THE <Organization>GLASGOW EDUCATION</Organization>
DEPARTMENT. EXAMINES THE <Organization>THEORETICAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF THE CENTRES THROUGH THE
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF THE FIELD. COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> POSITION OF <Organization>RESOURCE CENTRE</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT, AND PUTS FORWARD REASONS FOR THE LACK OF <Organization>WIDE</Organization> SPREAD <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> FOR
SCHOOL <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> CENTRES. OUTLINES THE EMERGENCE OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization>
CENTRES AND THE DIRECTION OF FUTURE DEVELOPM ENTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1082
<Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>NEEDS</Organization>.

APART <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RETRIEVAL THERE IS VIRTUALLY NO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREA OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WHICH HAS OCCASIONED AS MUCH <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> EFFORT AND WRITING AS &apos;<Organization>USER</Organization>
<Organization>STUDIES</Organization>&apos;. WITHIN <Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> THE <Organization>INVESTIGATION</Organization> OF &apos;<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>NEEDS</Organization>&apos; HAS
BEEN THE SUBJECT OF MUCH DEBATE AND NOT LITTLE CONFUSION. ATTEMPTS TO REDUCE
THE CONFUSION <Organization>BY</Organization> DEFINING SOME CONCEPTS, AND <Organization>BY</Organization> PROPOSING THE BASIS FOR A
THEORY OF THE MOTIVATIONS FOR INFORMATION-SEEKING BEHAVIOUR.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1083
<Location>PORT MORESBY</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>: A SNAPSHOT IN TIME.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> SOME OF THE EFFORTS UNDERWAY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>PORT MORESBY</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, ELA
BEACH, <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>, AND THE WAIGANI <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO HELP <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> TO KNOW THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> THEY SERVE. A QUESTIONNAIRE
SURVEY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS WAS CARRIED OUT <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND STATISTICS STUDENTS
<Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE COLLEGE</Organization>, <Location>PORT MORESBY</Location>, TO DETERMINE USERS&apos; NATIONALITY,
SEX, <Organization>AGE</Organization>, EDUCATION, RESIDENCE, MODE OF TRAVEL, TIME SPENT TRAVELLING TO THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, FREQUENCY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> VISITS, REASON FOR VISIT, AND <Organization>SUGGESTIONS</Organization> OF
MATERIAL FOR PURCHASE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. RESULTS ARE TABULATED AND ANALYSED, WITH
COMMENTARY <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> IMPLICATIONS FOR IMPROVEMENT OF SERVICES IN THE 2
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1084
THE CONDUCT OF <Organization>USER</Organization> SURVEYS.

AFTER <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> COMMENTS <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> SURVEYS, DISCUSSES <Organization>THEIR</Organization> GOALS, THE VARIETY
OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> SURVEYS, AND OFFERS SOME METHODOLOGICAL POINTERS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE CONDUCT OF
<Organization>USER</Organization> SURVEYS. ABOVE <Organization>ALL</Organization>, RESEARCHERS MUST ASK THEMSELVES WHY THEY ARE
CONDUCTING THE SURVEY, <Organization>SO</Organization> THAT THE SURVEY WILL BE DESIGNED IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A <Organization>WAY</Organization> THAT
IT HELPS RESEARCHERS TO ANSWER <Organization>THEIR</Organization> MOST IMPORTANT QUESTIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1085
BENEFIT ASSESSMENT METHODOLOGY: THE <Organization>KEY</Organization> PRIORITY FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.

<Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE AUTHOR&apos;S <Organization>BOOK</Organization>, DO <Organization>WE</Organization> REALLY NEED <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (SEE 81/3169).
DISCUSSES 2 RECENT <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN WHICH THE QUESTION OF MONEY VALUES WAS
DELIBERATELY AVOIDED AND AN ATTEMPT WAS MADE TO JUDGE A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S PERFORMANCE
<Organization>BY</Organization> ASSESSING (1) <Organization>HOW</Organization> WELL IT WAS GETTING THROUGH TO THE <Organization>CUSTOMERS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> WHOM THE
SERVICE WAS AIMED AND (2) WHAT IMPACT THE SERVICE HAD <Organization>ON</Organization> THOSE EXPOSED TO IT.
THE 2 ESTABLISHMENTS THUS EVALUATED WERE THE <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>GREATER</Organization>
<Organization>LONDON COUNCIL (UK)</Organization> AND THE <Organization>MANAGEMENT INFORMATION CENTRE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BRITISH
INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1086
THE NEED FOR READING ROOMS.

IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES LIKE <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>, MOST PEOPLE LIVE IN <Organization>RURAL</Organization> AREAS
<Organization>WITHOUT ELECTRICITY</Organization> SUPPLY, OR STUDY FACILITIES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> HOMES.
THOSE WHO HAVE <Organization>SUCH</Organization> FACILITIES ARE OFTEN SURROUNDED <Organization>BY</Organization> DISTRACTIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> HOME.
READING ROOMS ARE VITAL IN <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location> TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO THE PERSON
WITH NO HOME STUDY FACILITIES. THEY SHOULD BE PART OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDING,
BUT <Organization>OUTSIDE</Organization> THE MAIN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ITSELF, AND OFTEN AFTER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HOURS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1087
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> WEEK, 1980&apos; A REPORT.

IN 1980, THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location> TOOK RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE
ORGANISATION OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> WEEK AND COORDINATED ACTIVITIES, TO PROMOTE AN
AWARENESS OF BOOKS AND THE KNOWLEDGE AND ENJOYMENT THAT <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE GAINED <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THEM. POSTERS AND BOOKMARKS WERE PREPARED, CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HOURS WERE HELD,
AND <Organization>BOOK</Organization> EXHIBITIONS WERE ORGANISED. A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> REPORT <Organization>BY</Organization> GILLIAN HOWELLS IS
FOLLOWED <Organization>BY</Organization> BRIEF REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> ACTIVITIES <Organization>AT WAIGANI COMMUNITY SCHOOL</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> MUGEN
FOREPE; <Organization>AT</Organization> MT. <Location>HAGEN</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> HENRY MALU; <Organization>AT</Organization> MADANG, <Organization>BY</Organization> ELIZABETH
BOMAI; AND <Organization>AT</Organization> <Location>RABAUL</Location>, <Organization>BY</Organization> CATHERINE BASILIUS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1088
SELF-DIRECTED <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> AND THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>: A CHOICE?.

REFERS TO A STUDY IN WHICH SELF-DIRECTED LEARNERS PLACED THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> 6TH OUT
OF 7 LOCATIONS IN DESIRABILITY AS A <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> PLACE AND RANKED <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
BOTTOM OUT OF 7 CATEGORIES OF PEOPLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> WHOM THEY OBTAINED HELP. DISCUSSES
THE IMPLICATIONS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> RESULTS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND OFFERS SOME
THOUGHTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DIFFICULTY <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> HAVE WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> ROLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1089
GREEN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DEDICATION ADDRESS&apos; THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AN OUTPOST OF CULTURAL
CONTINUITY.

DELIVERED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE DEDICATION OF THE <Organization>EAST</Organization> WING OF THE CECIL H. GREEN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
<Organization>STANFORD UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization>, 11 APR 80. IN THE 7TH CENTURY, THE VENERABLE
BEDE COLLECTED THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> SOURCES REQUIRED FOR AN UNDERSTANDING OF HIS ENTIRE
HERITAGE AND HIS OBSCURE MONASTERY <Organization>AT</Organization> JARROW BECAME AN OUTPOST OF CULTURAL
CONTINUITY IN AN <Organization>AGE</Organization> OF FEW <Organization>SUCH</Organization> OUTPOSTS. SUGGESTS THAT THE GREEN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MAY
WELL BECOME &apos;JARROW-ON-THE-PACIFIC&apos;. EXPANDS THE ANALOGY AND URGES THE GREEN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO REPAY THE DEBT OWED TO BEDE <Organization>BY</Organization> BUILDING A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> FOR POSTERITY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1090
THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> STRUCTURE OF BIBLIOTHERAPY AND THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>JOURNAL</Organization> IN
THE FIELD&apos;S DEVELOPMENT.

PROVIDES A BRIEF INTRODUCTION TO THE TERMINOLOGY AND THEORY OF BIBLIOTHERAPY
AND EXAMINES THE SUBSTANTIAL ROLE PLAYED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>SERIAL</Organization>
ARTICLES IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD. DISCUSSES SOME RELEVANT BIBLIOGRAPHIES, INDEXES AND
DISSERTATIONS, TOGETHER WITH SOME OF THE PROBLEMS INVOLVED IN <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> THE
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF BIBLIOTHERAPY. EXPLAINS THE VALUE OF JOURNALS FOR THE
BIBLIOTHERAPY PRACTITIONER, AND MAKES A PLEA FOR <Organization>BETTER</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> CONTROL
IN THE FUTURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1091
EVALUATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES <Organization>BY</Organization> EXPERTS.

<Organization>NEW</Organization> ITEMS ACQUIRED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>ALTAI MOTOR</Organization> BUILDING COMPANY ARE
EVALUATED <Organization>BY</Organization> A GROUP OF EXPERTS-EACH EXPERT IS RESPONSIBLE FOR THE EVALUATION
OF A CERTAIN PROPORTION OF THE NEW STOCK (DETERMINED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>STAFF</Organization>). DISCUSSES THE TERMS OF A COMPETITION ORGANISED FOR THE EXPERTS ENGAGED
IN THE EVALUATION. SUGGESTS THAT THE HELP OF THE EXPERTS WITH THE EVALUATION
OF THE STOCK MADE IT POSSIBLE TO INCREASE THE <Organization>EFFECTIVENESS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICE PROVIDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1092
A <Organization>CRITICAL</Organization> COMMENTARY <Organization>ON</Organization> LEIMKUHLER&apos;S &apos;EXACT&apos; FORMULATION OF THE <Location>BRADFORD</Location> <Organization>LAW</Organization>.

ARGUES THAT POWERFUL OPERATIONAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TECHNIQUES OPERATE ONLY <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>SMALL</Organization>
FRACTION OF THE <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> USUALLY PROVIDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
SCIENCES. USES THE ARGUMENT TO ILLUSTRATE LEIMKUHLER&apos;S RECENT CLAIM TO HAVE
FOUND AN &apos;EXACT&apos; FIT TO BRADFORD&apos;S LAW. AN <Organization>ELEMENTARY</Organization> THEOREM OF <Location>SHANNON</Location>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THEORY SHOWS THAT HIS NEW FUNCTION IS <Organization>APPLIED</Organization> TO ONLY 2.3% OF THE
<Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INHERENT IN THE BIBLIOGRAPHY HE CHOOSES AND THAT
<Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S ORIGINAL <Organization>SIMPLE</Organization> FORMULATION NOT ONLY FITS <Organization>THIS</Organization> SEGMENT BUT <Organization>ALSO</Organization> THE
WHOLE BIBLIOGRAPHY MORE CLOSELY THAN THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> FORMULATION. AS EVERY <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> LOSS <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE MEASURED, IT <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE SHOWN THAT SOPHISTICATED
MATHEMATICAL TECHNIQUES <Organization>CAN</Organization>NOT COMPENSATE FOR THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THEY SQUANDER.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1093
READING MATERIALS IN <Organization>LARGE</Organization> TYPE.

A LIST OF PRODUCERS AND DISTRIBUTORS OF LARGE-TYPE MATERIALS (GIVING
ADDRESSES, SUBJECT SCOPE, AND LOAN FACILITIES-MOST ARE IN THE <Location>USA</Location>, THE REST IN
<Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>) AND A LIST OF SELECTED LARGE-TYPE MATERIALS FOR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> (GIVING DETAILS OF DISTRIBUTOR, PRICE, AND LOAN CONDITIONS).
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> GIVES DETAILS OF RELEVANT BIBLIOGRAPHIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1094
<Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>MONOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS: A SELECTED CLASSIFIED
BIBLIOGRAPHY MID 1978-MID 1979.

CONTINUES AND EXPANDS THE BIBLIOGRAPHY, <Organization>BY</Organization> AMY LOVGREN, PUBLISHED IN
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS REVIEW 6 (1) 1979, 37-46.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 1095
<Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS: A SELECTED CLASSIFIED
BIBLIOGRAPHY MID 1976-MID 1979.
