<Organization>Document</Organization> 2001
<Organization>MICROFILM</Organization> IN THE <Organization>ELECTRONIC OFFICE</Organization>.
     
THE RESULTS OF A SURVEY OF THE <Organization>MICROFILM</Organization> INDUSTRY <Organization>CONCERNING</Organization> THE ROLE AND
<Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF <Organization>MICROFILM</Organization> IN THE <Organization>ELECTRONICS ORIENTATED OFFICE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> ARE
REPORTED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2002
A-V&apos; AN INDUSTRY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE INTERFACE.
     
<Organization>GIVES</Organization> BRIEF DETAILS OF RECENT ANNOUNCEMENTS OF <Organization>JOINT</Organization> VENTURES, HARDWARE
LAUNCHES, AND COMPANY DEVELOPMENTS WHICH INDICATE THAT THE GROUNDSWELL OF
<Organization>MOVEMENT TOWARDS INTEGRATING PREVIOUSLY UNRELATED TECHNOLOGIES</Organization> AND MARKETS
(<Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>, <Organization>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Organization>, COMPUTERS, VIDEOTEX, TELECONFERENCING,
<Organization>SATELLITE SERVICES</Organization>) IS NOW GATHERING A REASONABLE <Organization>HEAD</Organization> OF STEAM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2003
MAGB ANNUAL REPORT.
     
1980/81 ANNUAL REPORT OF THE <Organization>MICROFILM ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>GREAT BRITAIN</Location>, WITH
DETAILS OF COUNCIL, FINANCES AND PROGRAMME, MEMBERSHIP AND SUBSCRIPTION TO
2MICRODOC1, <Organization>MICROFILM BUREAU</Organization> EXECUTIVES, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ACTIVITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2004
MICROFORMATTED <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS.
     
FIRST ARTICLE IN A NEW, IRREGULAR FEATURE. THE ARTICLE <Organization>COVERS</Organization> THE <Location>UK</Location> AND
<Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> SCENE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2005
VISIT TO ORDNANCE SURVEY-11<Organization>TH</Organization> JUNE, 1980.
     
REPORT OF A VISIT <Organization>BY</Organization> MEMBERS OF THE <Organization>MICROFILM ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>GREAT BRITAIN</Location>
(MAGB) TO THE ORDNANCE SURVEY HEADQUARTERS, 11 JUNE 80. <Organization>GIVES</Organization> A BRIEF HISTORY
OF THE ORDNANCE SURVEY, AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> WORK, WITH PARTICULAR ATTENTION TO
THE MICROFILMING OF MAPS, WHICH IS UNDERTAKEN <Organization>ON</Organization> BOTH 35 <Organization>MM</Organization> AND 70 <Organization>MM</Organization> ROLL
FILM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2006
GONE FICHE-ING..
     
MICROFICHE PROJECTION HAS BEEN SUGGESTED AS AN <Organization>ALTERNATIVE</Organization> TO SLIDE OR
OVERHEAD PROJECTORS <Organization>BY</Organization> A SUCCESSION OF HARDWARE PRODUCERS. IT IS A VERY
ATTRACTIVE IDEA, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THERE ARE DRAWBACKS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> AMBIENT LIGHT, THE NEED TO
<Organization>USE</Organization> THE FICHE IN ORDER WITH NO DODGING <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> BACK AND FORTH, AND THE INABILITY
OF THE PRESENTER TO DRAW OR WRITE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FICHE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2007
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN THE HUMANITIES&apos; CASE <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN <Organization>REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization>,
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization>, AND MANAGEMENT.
     
A SERIES OF 28 CASE <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> DESIGNED FOR LIBRARIANSHIP STUDENTS TO ASSIST THEM
IN LEARNING TO COPE WITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>ART</Organization>, <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, MYTHOLOGY,
MUSIC, PHILOSOPHY AND RELIGION. ALSO TO BE USED FOR IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>BY</Organization> STUDENTS OF HUMANITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2008
THE PHILOSOPHY OF <Organization>RECORDING</Organization> KNOWLEDGE.
     
ALTHOUGH MUCH HAS BEEN SAID <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> <Organization>HOW</Organization> MANKIND HAS RECORDED KNOWLEDGE, THE
QUESTION OF WHY RECORD KNOWLEDGE <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> HAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> BEEN TREATED SYSTEMATICALLY.
INFERENCES AND DEDUCTIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> <Organization>RECORDING</Organization> FORMATS LEAD TO THE
CONCLUSION THAT <Organization>WHILE TECHNOLOGY</Organization> HAS <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> THE <Organization>ART</Organization> OF RECORD KEEPING, THE
UNDERLYING PURPOSES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> REMAINED ESSENTIALLY THE SAME-TO COMMEMORATE,
COMMUNICATE, PRAY, CALCULATE, MEASURE, AND PRESERVE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2009
REPORT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE MINISTER FOR THE <Organization>ARTS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MATTERS DURING
1981.
     
PRESENTED TO THE <Location>UK</Location> PARLIAMENT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SECRETARY OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> FOR EDUCATION AND
SCIENCE, DEC 81. INCLUDES A REVIEW OF DEVELOPMENTS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES COUNCIL (FORMERLY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>ADVISORY COUNCIL</Organization>) WHICH WELCOMES RECENT ADVANCES IN <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> AND POLICY,
IDENTIFIES <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> ISSUES OF <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> CONCERN, AND CALLS FOR THE 1980-81
INITIATIVES TO BE PURSUED AND DEVELOPED. STRESSES THE NEED TO MAINTAIN BRITISH
<Organization>LIBRARY LENDING DIVISION SERVICES</Organization>, ACKNOWLEDGES THE REPERCUSSIONS OF FUNDING
CONSTRAINTS, AND MENTIONS THE NEED FOR <Organization>IMPROVED STATISTICAL DATA</Organization> AS A BASIS
FOR <Organization>EFFICIENT MANAGEMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>FORWARD</Organization> <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2010
SCOTTISH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 1978-1980.
     
A TRIENNIAL REVIEW COVERING <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF SCOTTISH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
LIBRARIANSHIP, <Organization>USING</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> ANNUAL REPORTS, NOTES, BOOKS, AND
ARTICLES IN <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> JOURNALS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2011
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS A PARTNER&apos; COMMENTARY AND REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ANNUAL
<Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> OF THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Location>COLOGNE</Location>, MAY
81.
     
THE RUSSIAN AUTHOR LEV KOPELEV OPENED THE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> OF THE VEREIN DER
BIBLIOTHEKARE AN OFFENTLICHEN BIBLIOTHEKEN (ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) WITH A TALK <Organization>ON</Organization> FREEDOM OF SPEECH, CONTRASTING THE AUTHOR&apos;S
POSITION IN THE WEST AND IN <Organization>COMMUNIST</Organization> COUNTRIES. THE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>MAIN</Organization> THEME
WAS <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS; SEVERAL
SPEAKERS ADVOCATED MORE ACTIVE COOPERATION BETWEEN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
MUSEUMS, <Organization>ADULT EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>CENTRES</Organization> AND THEATRES. REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S ROLE
IN THE ADVANCEMENT OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, THE PREPARATION OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> KEYWORD <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>
RULES <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>GERMAN LIBRARY INSTITUTE</Organization>, THE WORK OF THE INSTITUTE&apos;S COMMITTEE
<Organization>ON</Organization> RAK (<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> ALPHABETICAL <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> RULES) AND <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> WERE PRESENTED AND DISCUSSED. THE CHAIRMAN&apos;S REPORT COVERED
MEMBERSHIP INCREASES, <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PRO GRESS IN SALARY NEGOTIATIONS AND FINANCE.
THE MINUTES OF THE MEMBERS&apos; MEETING <Organization>ON</Organization> 28 MAY WERE INCLUDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2012
SOLVING THEORETICAL AND <Organization>METHODOLOGICAL</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
BASIS OF LENIN&apos;S IDEAS.
     
LENIN&apos;S WRITINGS AND STATEMENTS <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP, TOGETHER WITH N.K.
<Organization>KRUPSKAYA</Organization>&apos;S INTERPRETATION OF HIS IDEAS, <Organization>FORM</Organization> A BASIS FOR <Organization>MODERN</Organization> SOVIET
LIBRARIANSHIP. OF PARTICULAR SIGNIFICANCE TODAY ARE HIS IDEAS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>INTO</Organization>
THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> NEEDS AND <Organization>READING</Organization> INTERESTS OF THE SOVIET PEOPLE, THE NECESSITY
OF OUTREACH ACTIVITIES <Organization>INTO</Organization> BOTH SCHOOLS AND WORKPLACES, THE ROLE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN THE <Organization>OVERALL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF SOCIETY AND THE NEED TO <Organization>PROMOTE</Organization> POLITICAL
<Organization>AWARENESS</Organization> <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> PROPAGANDA AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>AWARENESS</Organization> <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> <Organization>GUIDANCE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2013
THE CONTRIBUTION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES TO THE ECONOMIC
EXPLOITATION AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENT OF THE URALS, SIBERIA AND <Location>THE FAR EAST</Location>.
     
THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN <Organization>THESE</Organization> AREAS IS YOUNG, <Organization>BUT</Organization> STATISTICS OF USAGE SHOW A
<Organization>RAPID</Organization> GROWTH. THE NEED FOR WELL-TRAINED <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND FOR ADEQUATE TRANSPORT <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
BEEN KEY FACTORS IN <Organization>ITS DEVELOPMENT</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> THERE SPECIALISE IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>RELEVANT</Organization> TO THE EXPLOITATION OF THE AREA&apos;S <Organization>NATURAL</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> AND TO <Organization>SUCH</Organization>
PROJECTS AS THE BAIKAL-AMUR RAILWAY, IN THE BIBLIOGRAPHICAL CONTROL OF
LOCALLY-PRODUCED <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> AND IN <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> HISTORY <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>. REQUIREMENTS FOR
<Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> THE SERVICE <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization>&apos; (1) A MORE BALANCED GEOGRAPHICAL DISTRIBUTION
OF SERVICE POINTS; (2) THE REDISTRIBUTION OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> STOCK TO ENSURE <Organization>BETTER</Organization>
USAGE; (3) THE DISCOVERY, <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> OF MORE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization>;
(4) <Organization>BETTER</Organization> COOPERATION BETWEEN BOTH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> MUSEUMS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2014
THE CHINESE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCENE&apos; REFLECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> A VISIT TO CHINA IN
JUNE 80.
     
IMPRESSIONS GAINED DURING AN OFFICIAL VISIT TO CHINA IN JUNE 80. <Location>CHINA</Location> HAS A
FEW VERY LARGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH STRONG COLLECTIONS AND GENEROUS FUNDING. MANY
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> SERIOUS GAPS IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> COLLECTIONS AS A RESULT OF THE
<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> REVOLUTION. THE EMPHASIS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> LIBRARIES-THERE
SEEM TO BE NO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. SERVICES ARE UNDEVELOPED, BUILDINGS AND
EQUIPMENT ARE <Organization>NOT</Organization> OF A <Organization>HIGH</Organization> QUALITY, THERE IS NO <Organization>PLANNED</Organization> <Organization>INTERLENDING</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>
OR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COORDINATION</Organization>, AND MOST <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IS CONCERNED WITH <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> RATHER THAN LIBRARIANSHIP. THE CHINESE WISH TO SOLVE <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
<Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> THEMSELVES, ALTHOUGH THEY WELCOME HELP. THE WHOLE SITUATION IS IN A
<Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>RAPID</Organization> CHANGE AND DEVELOPMENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2015
<Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> ISSUE.
     
ISSUE DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>SOUTH AFRICAN INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENCE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>, SEPT 80. FOR ABSTRACTS OF 6 PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>, 2SEE1 THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> SERIAL NUMBERS&apos;.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2016
THE CONTRIBUTION OF THE <Organization>SOUTH AFRICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> TO THE DEVELOPMENT
OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR THE REPUBLIC OF <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 1980 <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SOUTH AFRICAN INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR
LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE (SAILIS), TO WHICH <Organization>THIS</Organization> ISSUE IS
DEVOTED. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE CONTRIBUTION OF THE <Organization>SOUTH AFRICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
(PREDECESSOR OF SAILIS) IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>&apos;S <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> UNDER THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> HEADINGS&apos; <Organization>COORDINATION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SECTOR;
DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>; <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> CONTROL AND
<Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>; MANPOWER; AND THE ORGANISED PROFESSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2017
PURSUING HAPPINESS IN THE GOLDEN <Organization>STATE</Organization>: ALA CONFERENCE REPORT.
     
REPORT OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S 100<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNUAL <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>, <Location>SAN
FRANCISCO</Location>, CALIFORNIA, 26 JUNE-2 JULY 81. THE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> THEME WAS &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
AND THE PURSUIT OF HAPPINESS&apos;. 12,555 MEMBERS ATTENDED. SIGNIFICANT
COUNCIL/MEMBERSHIP ACTIONS INCLUDED PASSING A RESOLUTION DIRECTING THE ALA TO
DEVOTE MAXIMUM <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> TO PUBLICISING INADEQUATE SALARIES;
APPROVING A RESOLUTION URGING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> MAXIMUM <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> <Organization>KU</Organization> KLUX KLAN ACTIVITIES; AND ENDORSING A RESOLUTION
EXPRESSING CONCERN OVER LIMITED <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO <Organization>US CENSUS BUREAU DATA</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2018
A CONVERSATION WITH JOHN BERRY.
     
THE 1ST <Organization>PART</Organization> OF A JUNE 81 INTERVIEW WITH JOHN BERRY, EDITOR OF 2LIBR. J1., IN
WHICH HE TALKS <Organization>ABOUT AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> POLITICS, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
JOURNALISM, AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> DANGEROUS TRENDS IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION. THE 2ND <Organization>PART</Organization>
OF THE INTERVIEW WILL BE PUBLISHED IN A <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> ISSUE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2019
CHANGES AND <Organization>EXCHANGES</Organization>&apos; <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> VIEWPOINTS.
     
COLLECTED PAPERS <Organization>BY</Organization> THE LIBRARIANS-IN-RESIDENCE <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>, PRESENTED BETWEEN 1978 AND 79. THE <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> MATTER IS
DISPARATE, RANGING <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCENE TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN A
PERIOD OF FINANCIAL STRINGENCY. ALSO INCLUDED IS THE PROBLEM OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
KNOWLEDGE IN LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>BY</Organization> W. BOYD RAYWARD, VISITING LECTURER TO THE
COLLEGE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2020
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> REVIEW&apos; <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF ACCESSING RECENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> 10 ARTICLES
RECENTLY PUBLISHED IN <Location>UK</Location> AND US LIBRARIANSHIP JOURNALS. THE SURVEY DRAWS
TOGETHER POINTS MADE <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHICAL SOURCES AVAILABLE, AND AVAILABILITY
OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> REVIEWS; <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>; PUBLISHERS IN THE FIELD
AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> POLICIES; AND THE ROLE OF THE LIBRARIAN AS BOTH PRODUCER AND
CONSUMER OF <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> SOURCES. THE RELATIVE ABSENCE OF BIBLIOGRAPHICAL
MATERIALS IN SPANISH FOR LATIN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> COUNTRIES IS EMPHASISED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2021
RECENT <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> PUBLISHED <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP IN THE <Location>US</Location> IN RECENT YEARS REFLECTS THE
DEVELOPMENTS AND <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD, THE MOST IMPORTANT OF WHICH ARE NEW
PLANS TO ORGANISE <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> MORE EFFICIENTLY, <Organization>NEW</Organization> FORMS OF
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> CONTROL AND THE INCREASING IMPORTANCE OF DATA PROCESSING
SYSTEMS. 1976 WAS THE CENTENARY OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND 2
IMPORTANT BOOKS WERE PUBLISHED IN CONNECTION WITH <Organization>THIS</Organization> OCCASION&apos; 2<Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY-A BIBLIOGRAPHY1, AND 2DICTIONARY OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
(NCLIS) PUBLISHED <Organization>ITS</Organization> PROGRAMME IN 1975&apos; 2TOWARDS A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> PROGRAM OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICE1.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2022
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE CONGRESSES&apos; EVALUATION AND PERSPECTIVES.
     
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE AIMS AND ACTIVITIES OF THE 10<Organization>TH</Organization> BRAZILIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CONGRESS, COMPARING THE CAREFUL STRUCTURE IMPLEMENTED HERE WITH
THE HAPHAZARD NATURE OF <Organization>PREVIOUS</Organization> MEETINGS. THE ACCOUNT ANALYSES THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>
PREVIOUSLY ENCOUNTERED IN <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>, RESULTING IN LOSS OF
PRINCIPLE FOCUS AND DISSIPATION OF INTEREST. IN CONTRAST <Organization>THIS</Organization> CONGRESS WAS
BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>DOMINANT</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> THEME, SUB-THEMES WERE KEPT STRICTLY <Organization>RELEVANT</Organization>, AND
BOTH OFFICIAL AND UNOFFICIAL PAPERS CAREFULLY MONITORED. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF
PROCEDURES AND CRITERIA FOR SELECTING TOPICS AND PAPERS. THE SESSIONS,
DISCUSSION GROUPS AND WORKSHOPS WERE SIMILARLY CONTROLLED, TO ACHIEVE A
<Organization>SESSION</Organization> IN WHICH INTEREST AND PURPOSE WERE MAINTAINED THROUGHOUT. SUGGESTS
<Organization>FURTHER</Organization> WAYS OF <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> KIND OF CONGRESS <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> AND EMPHASISES
<Organization>ITS</Organization> BENEFITS TO THE PROFESSION AS A WHOLE AND <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> PARTICIPANTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2023
HERE IS THE (<Organization>OTHER</Organization>) NEWS.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> 2THE RADICAL BOOKSELLER1, THE ORGAN OF THE RADICAL <Organization>BOOK</Organization> TRADE, WHICH
WAS LAUNCHED IN AUTUMN 80 IN <Location>LONDON</Location>, <Organization>BY</Organization> A GROUP OF <Organization>BOOKSELLERS</Organization>, PUBLISHERS,
DISTRIBUTORS AND <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, <Organization>WORKING</Organization> WITH THE <Location>LONDON</Location> LABOUR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE
PUBLICATION APPEARS MONTHLY, AND HAS PROVED EXTREMELY <Organization>SUCCESSFUL</Organization>; IT LISTS
AROUND 80 ITEMS PER MONTH, WITH FULL BIBLIOGRAPHICAL DETAILS, AND CARRIES NEWS
ITEMS, <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> REPORTS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> WHICH MAY <Organization>HAVE</Organization> ESCAPED
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos; ATTENTION. THE MAGAZINE IS AVAILABLE <Organization>ON</Organization> SUBSCRIPTION <Organization>AT</Organization> *615 FOR
INSTITUTIONS AND *610 FOR INDIVIDUALS PER ANNUM. SPECIMEN COPIES ARE AVAILABLE
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE EDITOR.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2024
ZZZZ.
     
NEWSLETTER OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>&apos;S COMMUNITY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> INTEREST GROUP, DESIGNED TO <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> IDEAS, INITIATIVES,
AND <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD AND CONTAINING ARTICLES, NEWS ITEMS, AND REVIEWS.
THE EDITOR IS SUE HEALY, <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>VICTORIA</Location>, 328 SWANSTON STREET,
<Location>MELBOURNE</Location> 3000, <Location>VICTORIA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2025
ZZZZ.
     
THE 1ST ISSUE OF 2VISUAL <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>&apos; AN INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>1, PUBLISHED TRIANNUALLY IN SPRING, FALL AND WINTER <Organization>BY</Organization>
ICONOGRAPHIC PUBLICATIONS, P.O. BOX 327, <Location>REDDING</Location> RIDGE, CT 06876 IN NORTH AND
<Location>SOUTH AMERICA</Location>, AND <Organization>BY</Organization> OXFORD <Organization>MICROFORM</Organization> PUBLICATIONS, 19A PARADISE STREET,
OXFORD, ENGLAND OX1 1LD. CONCERNED WITH THE <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> OF VISUAL MATERIALS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2026
THE PROCESSES OF THE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> METHOD OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP (IN
ARABIC).
     
DEFINES THE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> METHOD OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AS THE ORGANISED THOUGHT OR ACCURATE
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> THAT EMPLOYS <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> PROCESSES FOR THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF DATA, PROVIDED
THAT IT IS <Organization>NOT</Organization> AFFECTED <Organization>BY</Organization> PERSONAL ATTITUDES WHICH MAY INFLUENCE THE
OUTCOMES. <Organization>THIS</Organization> METHOD CONSISTS OF 5 STEPS&apos; SELECTION OF THE PROBLEM TO SUBMIT
TO INVESTIGATION; IDENTIFICATION OF THE PROBLEM; HYPOTHESES; <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE PROBLEM; AND ANALYSIS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND THE
PRESENTATION OF THE FINDINGS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2027
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SHOULD BE DEFINED AS BROADLY AS <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization>.
     
COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> A COMMITTEE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos;
UNION. IT WRONGLY CONTRASTS <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND ACADEMICS AS MOST <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
AN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT STRESSES THE NEED FOR A <Organization>RESEARCH COUNCIL</Organization>
SPECIFICALLY <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> SPHERE. URGES THAT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SHOULD BE DEFINEED AS BROADLY AS <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization>, AND THAT IT SHOULD <Organization>HAVE</Organization> AN
<Organization>AIM</Organization> WIDER THAN THAT OF INCREASING EFFICIENCY. EMPLOYERS AND UNIONS SHOULD <Organization>NOT</Organization>
BE <Organization>PART</Organization> OF A <Organization>LIBRARY RESEARCH COUNCIL</Organization>, AS SUGGESTED IN THE REPORT. THE REPORT
RIGHTLY STRESSES THE NEED FOR <Organization>FURTHER EDUCATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IS WRONGLY
AGAINST GIVING FORMAL CREDIT TO <Organization>SUCH</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN THE <Organization>FORM</Organization> OF A DEGREE, FEARING
UNNECESSARILY THE CREATION OF ELITE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2028
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
THE CYRIL AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS THE <Organization>NATIONAL RESEARCH CENTRE</Organization> IN
THE FIELD OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND BIBLIOGRAPHY. <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IS CARRIED OUT IN CLOSE
COOPERATION WITH THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>SOFIA</Location>, <Location>AS</Location> WELL AS <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>USSR</Location>. ALTHOUGH THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS
<Organization>PLANNED</Organization> FOR THE 8<Organization>TH</Organization> 5-YEAR PLAN (1981-85) ARE STRICTLY <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> THEY ARE <Organization>NOT</Organization>
OUT OF TOUCH WITH REALITY. <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF THE <Organization>COUNTRY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND, INDEED,
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> AS A WHOLE WILL BENEFIT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE RESULTS. THE ISSUES UNDER
INVESTIGATION <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization> PROPAGANDA OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, GUIDED <Organization>READING</Organization>, OPEN <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> IN
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>, <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> CATALOGUES, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES IN <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, RECOMMENDED BIBLIOGRAPHIES, AND THE RELATIVE
IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> COLLECTIONS TO PARTICULAR TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2029
INTERVIEW&apos; CECILIA ANDREOTTI ATIENZA.
     
THE LIBRARIAN RESPONSIBLE FOR <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND ORGANISING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVING THE
<Location>SAO PAULO</Location> CHAMBER OF REPRESENTATIVES ANSWERS QUESTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>HOW</Organization> THE
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRE WAS ESTABLISHED, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>OPERATION</Organization> AND
SERVICES, WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>FEDERAL DATA</Organization> <Organization>BASE</Organization>
PRODASEN. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> COLLECTIONS AND <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> COVERAGE. THE
INTERVIEW ALSO <Organization>COVERS</Organization> <Organization>HER</Organization> <Organization>PREVIOUS</Organization> EXPERIENCE IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK AND IN
ORGANISING <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> THROUGHOUT THE <Organization>COUNTRY</Organization>. SHE
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>HER</Organization> WORK <Organization>ON</Organization> THE BRAZILIAN LEGAL DEPOSIT INDEX, AND <Organization>HER</Organization> OBJECTIVES AS
A <Organization>STATE</Organization> ADVISER <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN RELATION TO <Organization>HER</Organization> VIEWS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROLE OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. FINALLY SHE <Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> OF COMPOSITION, SCOPE AND
STRUCTURE OF <Organization>HER</Organization> RECENTLY PUBLISHED WORK <Organization>ON</Organization> LEGAL <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2030
MENAHEM ZUI BARKAI (1910-1978). A BIBLIOGRAPHY (IN HEBREW).
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE WORK OF THE LATE M.Z. BARKAI WHO SERVED IN <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> CAPACITIES IN
THE JEWISH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> 40 YEARS. HE SERVED <Organization>ON</Organization>
MANY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BODIES AND WAS ONE OF THE FOREMOST INDEXERS IN HEBREW. HE
COMPILED THE INDEXES TO THE 1ST YEARS OF THE KNESSET PAPERS, TO SEVERAL
<Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> PUBLICATIONS AND TO THE HEBREW ENCYCLOPAEDIA. BIBLIOGRAPHY LISTS
HIS INDEXES, ARTICLES, <Organization>BOOK</Organization> REVIEWS, AND REPORTS PRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> HIM IN HIS
OFFICIAL CAPACITIES, AND ALSO <Organization>SOME</Organization> REVIEWS OF HIS INDEXES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2031
THOMAS GREENWOOD&apos; <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ENTHUSIAST.
     
THOMAS GREENWOOD (1851-1908) WAS BORN <Organization>INTO</Organization> POVERTY AND HARDSHIP; MADE THE MOST
OF HIS EDUCATION <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> EXTENSIVELY AND LATER ATTENDING A MUTUAL
<Organization>IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY</Organization>; AND EVENTUALLY BECAME A <Organization>SUCCESSFUL</Organization> PUBLISHER OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
BOOKS AND PERIODICALS. WISHING TO HELP OTHERS MAKE THE <Organization>BEST</Organization> OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> LIVES,
HIS <Organization>MAIN</Organization> PREOCCUPATION WAS WITH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> BECAUSE IN THEM HE DISCOVERED
AN <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTION WHICH REFLECTED MANY OF HIS OWN IDEALS. FOR MUCH OF
HIS LIFE, HE GAVE UNSPARINGLY HIS TIME, MONEY, AND ENERGY TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>MOVEMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2032
COUNCIL <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>, 23<Organization>RD</Organization> ANNUAL REPORT, 1979.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE ACTIVITIES AND FINANCIAL STATUS OF THE COUNCIL <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> (CLR) DURING THE 1978-79 FISCAL YEAR. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> AVAILABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization>
NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2033
<Organization>GERMAN RESEARCH ASSOCIATION LIBRARY COMMITTEE</Organization>.
     
<Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> SPRING MEETING THE COMMITTEE MADE RECOMMENDATIONS <Organization>CONCERNING</Organization> THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>BONN</Location> OVER THE 2-YEAR PERIOD
1982-84, TO BRING IT UP TO THE STANDARD OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization> FACULTY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> NOW THAT
SUITABLE PREMISES ARE UNDER <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization>. IN <Location>BERLIN</Location> A <Organization>PERIODICAL DATA BANK</Organization>
WILL <Organization>LINK</Organization> THE FEDERAL STATES AND WILL <Organization>INCLUDE HOLDINGS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MAIN UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>FEDERAL BUREAU</Organization> OF STATISTICS. THERE HAS BEEN NO PROGRESS IN
SETTING UP AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>ARTS</Organization>. IT WAS DECIDED TO PUBLISH A
CATALOGUE OF <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> GOTTINGEN AND TO PUT <Organization>ON</Organization> FILM THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
CATALOGUE FOR NORTH RHINELAND/WESTPHALIA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2034
CRITERIA FOR <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> STATUS OF LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
DESCRIPTION OF THE DISTINGUISHING CHARACTERISTICS, CRITERIA, AND
RESPONSIBILITIES OF A TRUE PROFESSION PROVIDES AN ANALYSIS OF THE TRAITS
ATTRIBUTED TO <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SERVICES BY SOCIETY</Organization> IN THE HOPE THAT <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
WILL <Organization>USE</Organization> THEM TO <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> THE STATUS OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FIELD. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> AVAILABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization>
NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2035
DEFENDING INTELLECTUAL FREEDOM.
     
PRESENTS THE AUTHOR&apos;S PREVIOUSLY PUBLISHED ARTICLES, EDITORIALS, LETTERS, AND
REVIEWS AND ALSO <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE THEME OF INTELLECTUAL FREEDOM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2036
THEORY <Organization>VS</Organization>. PRACTICE&apos; STUDENT PREFERENCES.
     
THE LONG-STANDING DISCUSSION OF THE THEORETICAL <Organization>VERSUS</Organization> THE PRACTICAL
ORIENTATION OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> IS EXAMINED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE STUDENT&apos;S
PERSPECTIVE. RESULTS OF A SURVEY REVEAL THE INFLUENCE OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> VARIABLES AS
SEX, TERM OF RESPONDENT, <Organization>UNDERGRADUATE</Organization> DEGREE, <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> DEGREE,
PREPROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE, TYPE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> JOURNAL
SUBSCRIPTIONS, THE BROWSING OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> THEORETICAL OR
PRACTICAL ORIENTATION AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT IT MEANS TO BE A
LIBRARIAN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2037
DR. T. CHILDERS&apos; VISITING FELLOWSHIP&apos; FINAL REPORT.
     
DESIGNED TO RECORD THE <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>, ACTIVITIES AND ASSESSMENT OF THE VISITING
FELLOWSHIP OF DR. T. CHILDERS OF THE <Organization>GRADUATE SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE,
<Organization>DREXEL UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>PHILADELPHIA</Location>, WHICH TOOK PLACE <Organization>FROM</Organization> SEPT TO DEC 78. THE
REPORT HAS BEEN COMPILED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE ORGANISER OF THE FELLOWSHIP <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>LEEDS</Location>
SCHOOL OF LIBRARIANSHIP WHERE DR. CHILDERS WAS BASED, AND IT CONTAINS AN
ACCOUNT OF THE ACTIVITIES WHICH TOOK PLACE DURING THE FELLOWSHIP AND THE
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IMPLICATIONS ARISING <Organization>FROM</Organization> IT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2038
A DIRECTED INDEPENDENT <Organization>STUDY</Organization> APPROACH TO A FOUNDATIONS COURSE.
     
UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS, HAS TRIED SEVERAL APPROACHES TO PRESENTING THE
&apos;FUNDAMENTALS&apos; OF LIBRARIANSHIP TO STUDENTS. IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>FORM</Organization>, THE
&apos;DIRECTED INDEPENDENT <Organization>STUDY</Organization>&apos; APPROACH, THE FUNDAMENTALS COURSE CONSISTS OF A
SERIES OF MODULES. FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> MODULE THE STUDENT RECEIVES A MINITEXT, A <Organization>SET</Organization> OF
READINGS AND A WORKBOOK. THE STUDENT MUST <Organization>STUDY</Organization> THE TEXT AND READINGS AND
COMPLETE THE WORKBOOK ASSIGNMENTS <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO <Organization>THIS</Organization> MODULE. THE STUDENT PASSES
THE COURSE WHEN <Organization>ALL</Organization> COMPONENT MODULES ARE COMPLETED TO THE SATISFACTION OF THE
STUDENT&apos;S FACULTY ADVISOR. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE REASONS FOR ABANDONING THE EARLIER
METHODS, THE EVOLUTION OF THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> FORMAT AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> ADVANTAGES AND
LIMITATIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2039
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE IN THE <Location>UNITED STATES</Location>.
     
A SUMMARY TRANSLATION OF A PAPER GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>SAO PAULO</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1979,
SURVEYING THE <Location>US</Location> SITUATION, WHERE THE NECESSITY FOR <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE
EDUCATION IS GENERALLY AGREED, <Organization>BUT</Organization> SATISFACTORY IMPLEMENTATION OF <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>
IS <Organization>NOT</Organization> YET FULLY ACHIEVED. THE ACCOUNT <Organization>COVERS</Organization> ACTIVITIES TO DATE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS, AND <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BODIES; THE FIELDS IN
WHICH <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IS MOST ESSENTIAL; AND THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF SPONSORSHIP FOR COURSES,
SYSTEMS OF OFFICIAL RECOGNITION, AND LOCATION AND <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2040
LEARNING THE CONCEPT OF &apos;BIBLIOGRAPHICAL CITATION&apos; <Organization>USING</Organization> THE &apos;<Organization>SET</Organization> OF CONCEPTS&apos;
METHOD&apos; A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> COMPARING <Organization>THIS</Organization> METHOD WITH <Organization>TRADITIONAL</Organization> LEARNING METHOD.
     
IN A THEORETICAL INTRODUCTION, THE METHODOLOGY UNDERLYING THE &apos;<Organization>SET</Organization> OF
CONCEPTS&apos; LEARNING PROCEDURE IS EXPLAINED WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
THE PERFORMANCES OF 2 GROUPS OF STUDENTS IN LEARNING THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> CONCEPT OF
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> CITATION, ONE <Organization>USING</Organization> A TEXTBOOK AND THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> THE &apos;<Organization>SET</Organization> OF
CONCEPTS&apos; METHOD, WERE EVALUATED AND COMPARED. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE TEST
GROUPS, TEST CONDITIONS, AND TEST PROCEDURES. THE TECHNIQUE USED TO EVALUATE
RESULTS IS OUTLINED AND CALCULATIONS PRESENTED IN FULL, WITH TABULAR
SUMMARIES. THE CONCLUDING DISCUSSION REFERS TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> CORROBORATING THE
<Location>SUPERIOR</Location> EFFICIENCY OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> METHOD, REPORTED IN THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2041
AN <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> PROFICIENCY APPROACH TO PRE-PROFESSIONAL LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
     
TAKING AS A STARTING POINT THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
ACCREDITATION&apos;S <Organization>LIST</Organization> OF ESSENTIAL REQUIREMENTS FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, PRESENTS A
DETAILED ITEMISATION OF THE MINIMUM <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> SKILLS ESSENTIAL FOR A
PRE-SERVICE LIBRARIAN, STRUCTURED IN 6 PRINCIPLE DIVISIONS, COVERING
UNDERSTANDING OF&apos; THE DEVELOPMENT AND COMMUNICATION OF HUMAN KNOWLEDGE;
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE; <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization>; <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MATERIALS; <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>; AND MANAGEMENT TECHNIQUES. APPLICATIONS OF <Organization>THIS</Organization>
ANALYTICAL PRESCRIPTION IN <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND <Organization>EVALUATING</Organization> CURRICULA ARE SUGGESTED,
WHICH <Organization>WOULD</Organization> ENSURE INCLUSION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> ESSENTIAL PHILOSOPHICAL AND THEORETICAL
COMPONENTS IN <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2042
<Organization>ALTERNATIVE</Organization> MODES FOR <Organization>PROVIDING GRADUATE EDUCATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Organization>OHIO</Organization>.
FINAL REPORT.
     
REPORTS THE RESULTS OF THE <Organization>GRADUATE EDUCATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Organization>OHIO</Organization>
PROJECT&apos;S INVESTIGATION <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE NEED FOR AND <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION IN THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>. PROVIDES INITIAL ASSESSMENT OF THE 4 OPTIONS STUDIED
AND EXPRESSES THE HOPE THAT <Organization>THIS</Organization> REPORT WILL <Organization>FOSTER FURTHER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF
<Organization>ALTERNATIVE</Organization> OPPORTUNITIES FOR <Organization>SUCH EDUCATION</Organization> THROUGHOUT THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>, ESPECIALLY
THOSE WHICH MAXIMISE <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO <Organization>STATE</Organization> RESIDENTS CONVENIENTLY AND
COST-EFFECTIVELY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2043
PARTICULAR <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF HIGHER-QUALIFIED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
     
MANY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS SUFFER <Organization>FROM</Organization> HAVING TOO FEW QUALIFIED LECTURERS,
OVER-LOADED AND ILL-PLANNED SYLLABUSES, AND <Organization>FROM</Organization> PAYING TOO LITTLE ATTENTION
TO POST-GRADUATE WORK. UNTIL <Organization>THESE</Organization> FAULTS ARE REMEDIED THERE IS LITTLE HOPE OF
<Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> SIGNIFICANTLY THE <Organization>FURTHER EDUCATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. THERE IS A NEED
FOR A MORE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> SYLLABUS, SO THAT STUDENTS EMERGE WITH DETAILED KNOWLEDGE
OF A WIDE RANGE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES. POST-GRADUATE STUDENTS NEED TO BE MORE
CAREFULLY SELECTED AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> DISSERTATIONS MORE CLOSELY SUPERVISED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2044
THE ROLE OF PSYCHOLOGY IN THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
     
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> NEED TO <Organization>HAVE</Organization> AN UNDERSTANDING OF PSYCHOLOGY IN ORDER TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization>
<Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> <Organization>GUIDANCE</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS. PSYCHOLOGY SHOULD BE AN INTEGRAL
<Organization>PART</Organization> OF THE SYLLABUS TAUGHT IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, WITH A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
PRINCIPLES LEADING <Organization>ON</Organization> TO MORE <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> FIELDS. THE COURSE TAUGHT <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>LENINGRADSKII GOSUDARSTVENNYI INSTITUT</Organization> KUL&apos;TURY <Organization>IM</Organization>. N.K. KRUPSKOI (N.K.
<Organization>KRUPSKAYA STATE INSTITUTE</Organization> OF CULTURE IN <Location>LENINGRAD</Location>) <Organization>SHOWS</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE
POSSIBILITIES AVAILABLE, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THERE IS MUCH WORK TO BE DONE IN THE PROFESSION
AS A WHOLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2045
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND EDUCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INSTRUCTION <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A THEMATIC ISSUE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> INSTRUCTION. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> INSTRUCTION (<Organization>BI</Organization>) <Organization>MOVEMENT</Organization> IN <Location>US</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE THRUST OF THE <Organization>BI EDUCATION</Organization> EFFORT OVER THE PAST DECADE AS IT
<Organization>EMANATES FROM CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>. REVIEWS BRIEFLY THE CONTRIBUTION OF ALA
<Organization>RELATED</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
INSTRUCTION CONCEPT. CONSIDERS <Organization>SOME</Organization> REASONS FOR THE RESISTANCE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOLS TO ADDING COURSES THAT <Organization>WOULD</Organization> TRAIN PROSPECTIVE TEACHERS FOR
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> INSTRUCTION, AND EXPRESSES THE HOPE THAT RECOGNITION OF THE NEED
FOR FORMAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR THE TEACHING LIBRARIAN OR THE <Organization>TEACHER</Organization> OF BIBLIOGRAPHY
WILL STRENGTHEN THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE INSTITUTIONAL SETTING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2046
THE DEVELOPMENT AND SIGNIFICANCE OF THE CORE CURRICULUM IN ARCHIVES, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>.
     
(<Organization>PHD</Organization> THESIS.) AN ATTEMPT TO IDENTIFY THE <Organization>COMMON</Organization> GROUND BETWEEN ARCHIVES,
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> WHICH A CORE CURRICULUM COULD BE DERIVED
FOR THE PROFESSIONALS IN THE 3 FIELDS. THE UNDERLYING CONCEPT IS THAT THE 3
FIELDS MUST BE VIEWED AS A WHOLE WITHIN THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECTRUM. THE
<Organization>HISTORICAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF LIBRARIANSHIP; <Organization>EARLY LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>UK</Location>,
<Location>USA</Location>, AND BRAZIL; <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> TRENDS TOWARDS PARTICIPATION IN
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>NETWORKS</Organization> AND SYSTEMS; AND LIKELY MANPOWER REQUIREMENTS ARE <Organization>ALL</Organization>
TAKEN <Organization>INTO</Organization> ACCOUNT. <Organization>CURRENT GENERAL EDUCATION</Organization> TRENDS ARE ALSO CONSIDERED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2047
MODEL OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SPECIALISATION.
     
THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SPECIALISATION <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> IN THE INSTITUTE FOR THE <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
OF <Organization>INFORMATION WORKERS</Organization>, <Location>MOSCOW</Location>, IS REPRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> A STOCHASTIC HIERARCHICAL
CONTINUOUSLY-DEVELOPING STRUCTURE HAVING PARAMETERS DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
DEVELOPMENT PATTERN OF THE STATEWIDE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. THE INSTITUTE&apos;S REALISED AND <Organization>PLANNED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SPECIALISATIONS DERIVED
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE MODEL IN QUESTION ARE LISTED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2048
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INSTRUCTION WITHIN THE <Organization>MEDICAL RECORD ADMINISTRATION</Organization> CURRICULUM.
     
THE UNIVERSITY OF <Organization>TENNESSEE CENTER</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCES <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS
DEVELOPED A COURSE FOR <Organization>MEDICAL RECORD ADMINISTRATION</Organization> STUDENTS WHICH IS
INTENDED TO (1) TRAIN STUDENTS IN THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCES <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>
AND SERVICES AND (2) <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>BASIC</Organization> INSTRUCTION IN THE <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>, <Organization>OPERATION</Organization>,
AND MANAGEMENT OF A <Organization>SMALL HOSPITAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE NEED FOR <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A
COURSE, BRIEFLY <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE CURRICULUM, AND PRESENTS THE RESULTS OF A SURVEY
OF STUDENTS WHO <Organization>HAVE</Organization> COMPLETED THE COURSE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2049
<Organization>ALLERTON INVITATIONAL CONFERENCE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCES
LIBRARIANSHIP&apos; PROCEEDINGS OF A <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> MONTICELLO, ILLINOIS, APRIL
2-4, 1979.
     
COMPRISES THE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> SCHEDULE, KEYNOTE ADDRESS, A <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> PERSPECTIVE,
6 POSITION PAPERS (WITH RESPONDENTS&apos; COMMENTS, GROUP DISCUSSIONS AND
RECOMMENDATIONS), CONCLUDING REMARKS, AND A <Organization>LIST</Organization> OF <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> PARTICIPANTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2050
TEACHING AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> WORK IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
FINAL REPORT OF A PROJECT WHICH EXAMINED THE METHODS OF TEACHING AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
RELATING TO <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> WORK IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO COST. THE COST
OF <Organization>USING OUTHOUSE DATA</Organization> BASES (<Organization>LOCKHEED</Organization> DIALOG AND BLAISE MARC) WITHIN
<Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> DESIGNED TO MAKE MAXIMUM <Organization>USE</Organization> OF INHOUSE PACKAGES WAS INVESTIGATED.
INHOUSE <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> ARE ESSENTIAL FOR PRACTICE WORK-THE BLAISE EDITOR WOULD BE
PROHIBITIVELY EXPENSIVE TO <Organization>USE</Organization>. <Organization>SOFTWARE</Organization> FOR HANDLING MARC WAS FOUND TO BE
GENERALLY INADEQUATE. THE <Organization>HEWLETT-PACKARD</Organization> 2645A DISPLAY STATION WAS FOUND
ACCEPTABLE FOR <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PURPOSES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2051
STUDENT&apos;S GUIDE TO <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN SUSSEX.
     
INTENDED TO HELP THE PURPOSIVE <Organization>USER</Organization> TO IDENTIFY THOSE SUSSEX <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> STOCK <Organization>RELEVANT</Organization> TO HIS NEEDS. COMPRISES 3 SECTIONS&apos; RESOURCES-AN
ALPHABETICAL <Organization>LIST</Organization> OF SUBJECTS GIVING <Organization>AT</Organization> LEAST 1 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization>;
KEY-INDICATES LOCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND DIRECTORY-PROVIDING <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2052
CALIFORNIA <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STATISTICS AND DIRECTORY, 1980. FISCAL YEAR 1978-79 DATA
FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>, <Organization>SPECIAL STATE AGENCY</Organization> AND <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> ANNUAL DIRECTORY CHARACTERISES <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN CALIFORNIA <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
<Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> TABLES, A PROFILE OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, DESCRIPTIONS OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS, A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DIRECTORY, AND SEVERAL INDEXES. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization>
AVAILABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2053
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND THE WHITE HOUSE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization>&apos; <Organization>FROM</Organization> COMPLACENCY, TO
CONCERN, TO COMMITMENT.
     
THE ATTITUDE OF <Location>US</Location> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> TOWARDS THE WHITE HOUSE <Organization>CONFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES (HELD IN NOV 79) WAS SLOW TO EVOLVE <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
INITIAL COMPLACENCY TO A STRONG COMMITMENT. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> EVOLUTION AND
<Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE PARTICIPATION OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION IN CONFERENCE-RELATED ACTIVITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2054
WHERE THERE IS NO VISION THE PEOPLE PERISH.
     
PRESIDENTIAL ADDRESS TO THE 80<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNUAL MEETING OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION, <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>, <Location>D.C.</Location>, 17 JUNE 80. FORCES ARE <Organization>ALREADY</Organization> IN MOTION THAT
WILL CHANGE THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCES LIBRARIANSHIP. IN ADDITION TO
CHANGES IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> <Organization>CENTRES</Organization>, CHANGES IN THE PUBLISHING INDUSTRY, THE
MODE OF DELIVERING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMPUTERS IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
MANIPULATION AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>, USERS&apos; <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, AND COMMUNICATIONS
TECHNOLOGY ARE BRIEFLY DESCRIBED. PROPOSES THAT <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCES <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> CAN
PARTICIPATE IN THE CREATIVE <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> OF <Organization>CONSTRUCTING</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
<Organization>BY</Organization> BEING INFORMED, <Organization>EXPANDING COOPERATIVE</Organization> EFFORTS, <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>, CEASING TO HOLD A
ROMANTIC VIEW OF THE PROFESSION, AND BECOMING ACHIEVERS RATHER THAN
SUSTAINERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2055
THE ROUND TABLE OF <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
     
THE ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization> ROUND TABLE OF <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> SINCE <Organization>ITS</Organization>
ESTABLISHMENT IN 1977 ARE COVERED. ALSO INCLUDED ARE <Organization>ITS</Organization> MEDIUM-TERM
PROGRAMME, <Organization>ITS</Organization> OBJECTIVES AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> PLANS FOR THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2056
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF THE <Organization>CZECHOSLOVAK FEDERAL</Organization> ASSEMBLY.
     
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF THE <Organization>CZECHOSLOVAK FEDERAL</Organization> ASSEMBLY CONSISTS OF A
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AN <Organization>ARCHIVE</Organization> AND A <Organization>PRESS OFFICE</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>MAIN</Organization> <Organization>TASK</Organization> IS TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO THE <Organization>MPS</Organization> <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AND <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> COLLECTIONS AND <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
<Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> CONTAINING <Organization>DOCUMENTS</Organization> <Organization>CONCERNING</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE
<Organization>CZECHOSLOVAK</Organization> REPUBLIC. <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ACTIVITIES OF THE ORGANS OF
THE PARLIAMENT IS PROVIDED <Organization>BY</Organization> A BULLETIN. THE HISTORY AND A DESCRIPTION OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, FOUNDED IN 1918, ARE GIVEN IN GREATER DETAIL.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2057
REPORT OF THE <Organization>INTERDEPARTMENTAL COMMITTEE</Organization> TO CONSIDER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES TO <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DEPARTMENTS AND INSTRUMENTALITIES.
     
APPOINTED IN MAY 76, THE COMMITTEE TO CONSIDER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES TO <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DEPARTMENTS AND INSTRUMENTALITIES WAS CHARGED TO MAKE
RECOMMENDATIONS TO THE <Organization>TASMANIAN</Organization> MINISTER FOR EDUCATION <Organization>ON</Organization> THE EFFECTIVENESS
OF <Organization>EXISTING SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>HOW</Organization> THEY COULD BE <Organization>IMPROVED</Organization>, AND <Organization>HOW</Organization> THEY COULD BE
EXTENDED TO MORE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> OFFICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2058
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> STORAGE AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> IN THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. OBSERVATIONS
<Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SECOND AND FOURTH REPORTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>SELECT COMMITTEE</Organization>
<Organization>ON EDUCATION</Organization>, SCIENCE AND <Organization>ARTS</Organization> <Organization>SESSION</Organization> 1979-80.
     
PRESENTED TO THE <Location>UK</Location> PARLIAMENT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE MINISTER FOR THE <Organization>ARTS</Organization>, APR 81. LISTS THE
RECOMMENDATIONS OF THE <Organization>SELECT COMMITTEE</Organization>&apos;S 2ND AND 4<Organization>TH</Organization> REPORTS OF THE 1979-80
<Organization>SESSION</Organization> AND <Organization>GIVES</Organization> THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>&apos;S RESPONSE TO <Organization>EACH</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2059
CYRIL AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> 1878-1978.
     
A COPIOUSLY-ILLUSTRATED ACCOUNT OF THE HISTORY AND <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> ACTIVITIES OF
<Location>BULGARIA</Location>&apos;S CYRIL AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2060
A COMMISSION WITH POSSIBILITIES-IN SPITE OF <Organization>ALL</Organization>.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE FUNCTIONS OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION</Organization>
(FOLKBIBLIOTEKSUTREDNINGEN) IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location> AFTER 1 YEAR&apos;S WORK. SUGGESTS THAT THE
COMMISSION SHOULD FORMULATE <Organization>NOT</Organization> ONLY <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
GOALS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IT SHOULD INDICATE WAYS IN WHICH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
COOPERATION WITH SCHOOLS AND <Organization>ADULT</Organization> EDUCATION ORGANISATIONS CAN SAVE THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
<Organization>AT</Organization> A TIME WHEN AURAL AND VISUAL MEDIA THREATEN TO TAKE OVER. TO <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>END</Organization> THE
COMMISSION HAS BEGUN TO COOPERATE WITH THE <Organization>CULTURAL COUNCIL</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>PLANNED</Organization>
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> CAMPAIGN IN THE KOPPARBERG REGION. THE COMMISSION CAN CONTRIBUTE TO
THE EQUALISATION OF SERVICES <Organization>BY</Organization> PLACING MORE EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S ROLE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> RESPECT. ANY EXTRA MONEY SHOULD BE CHANNELLED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
THE <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2061
A REVIEW OF THE DEVELOPMENT AND POTENTIAL OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IN EAST
<Location>AFRICA</Location>.
     
(<Organization>MLS</Organization> DISSERTATION.) TO EXAMINE <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> THE <Organization>HIGH TECHNOLOGY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>
FAVOURED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE WEST IS APPLICABLE TO <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES, IT IS <Organization>NECESSARY</Organization> TO
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> THE HISTORY OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN A PARTICULAR AREA, <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> STATUS, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>PLANNED FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization>. THE <Organization>EAST AFRICAN COMMUNITY</Organization>
(<Location>KENYA</Location>, <Location>UGANDA</Location>, AND TANZANIA) WAS CHOSEN FOR <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> AS <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT HAS BEEN SUFFICIENTLY LONG TO ENABLE A CAUSE-AND-EFFECT ANALYSIS.
IN <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>, THERE MUST BE A BALANCE BETWEEN ACCEPTANCE OF APPOSITE <Organization>WESTERN</Organization>
IDEAS AND REJECTION OF THOSE IDEAS HARMFUL TO THE COMMUNITY. FINANCIAL <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization>
IS BECOMING MORE ASSURED; THE RECOGNITION OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> REQUIREMENTS MUST FOLLOW.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2062
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN A <Organization>FREE ENTERPRISE SOCIETY</Organization>.
     
STATES THAT THE <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>FORM</Organization> IS A UNIQUELY <Location>US</Location>
INSTITUTION, REFLECTING THE NATION&apos;S COMMITMENT TO <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> <Organization>INITIATIVE</Organization> AND
<Organization>FREE ENTERPRISE</Organization>-READY <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO BOOKS FOR <Organization>SELF-HELP</Organization> AND SELF-IMPROVEMENT HAS
BEEN PERCEIVED AS ESSENTIAL TO <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> CHARACTER AND SELF-RELIANCE FOR
GENERATIONS. TRACES THE VITAL ROLE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE LIVES OF LEADING
<Location>US</Location> INVENTORS, BUSINESSMEN, AND INDUSTRIES AND CALLS FOR <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
(<Organization>THROUGH</Organization> THE <Organization>PROPOSED</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES <Organization>ACT</Organization>) IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
<Organization>PRESENT</Organization> FINANCIALLY-STRAINED CIRCUMSTANCES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2063
A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS FOR THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>.
     
<Location>US</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> REPRESENT THE IDEAL (GOALS WHICH ARE ALWAYS BEING PURSUED)
AND THE REAL (PRACTICES WHICH MUST BE FOLLOWED LEST NIHILISM RESULT).
PRACTICALITY HAS REVEALED THAT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> PEOPLE, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>
THE HANDICAPPED AND THOSE OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> RACES. <Organization>THIS</Organization> HAS RESULTED IN THE ADJUSTMENT OF
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR THE ACCOMMODATION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization>, THE EXPANSION OF SERVICES WITHIN THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>EXTENSION</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>FACILITIES</Organization> OUTSIDE <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization>.
IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization>, THE REAL IS REALISED AND THE IDEAL IS STILL PURSUED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2064
<Organization>RURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN WEST <Location>MALAYSIA</Location> WITH RECOMMENDATIONS.
     
(<Organization>MLS</Organization> DISSERTATION.) IN RECENT YEARS, THERE HAS BEEN A GROWING INTEREST IN
<Organization>RURAL LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> AUTHORITIES IN WEST <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>
THE SERVICES OFFERED <Organization>BY GOVERNMENT AGENCIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
CORPORATIONS AND <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>. MAKES RECOMMENDATIONS AND HOPES THAT THE
CORPORATIONS WILL ABSORB THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> <Organization>RURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>ALREADY</Organization> ESTABLISHED <Organization>INTO</Organization>
<Organization>THEIR OWN SYSTEMS</Organization> AS SOON AS IT IS FEASIBLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2065
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR <Organization>SMALL</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNITIES</Organization>&apos; A STATE-OF-THE-ART REVIEW.
     
IN MAR 77 THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COMMISSIONED A BRIEF STATE-OF-THE-ART REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR <Organization>SMALL</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNITIES</Organization> BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RELEVANT</Organization> <Location>UK</Location>
AND OVERSEAS PRACTICE. IT WAS FOUND THAT OBJECTIVES AND THE RANGE, LEVEL AND
TYPE OF SERVICES PROVIDED AND THE <Organization>DELIVERY SYSTEMS</Organization> USED VARIED SIGNIFICANTLY
BOTH WITHIN AND BETWEEN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTHORITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2066
<Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN JORDAN (IN ARABIC).
     
IN JORDAN, THE 1ST <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS FOUND IN HEBRON <Organization>BY</Organization> THE MINISTRY OF
EDUCATION IN 1956. IN 1970 THERE WERE <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> 15 <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization>
NUMBER GRADUALLY DECREASED AND NOW THERE ARE ONLY 3; IN IRBID, ZARKA AND HAYA
<Organization>CULTURAL CENTRE</Organization> IN <Location>AMMAN</Location>. THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> ARE
CAUSED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SHORTAGE OF QUALIFIED <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIALS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2067
ARE <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> A PROFITABLE MEANS OF <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> FOR
STRUCTURALLY WEAK AREAS?.
     
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> FOR <Organization>RURAL</Organization> AREAS HAS ALWAYS BEEN DIFFICULT. A COMPARISON
BETWEEN <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> AND <Organization>SMALL</Organization> VILLAGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>SHOWS</Organization> THAT <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE,
CONTRARY TO POPULAR OPINION, CHEAPER TO RUN; THEY <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>LARGER</Organization> AND MORE
FREQUENTLY CHANGED STOCKS AND <Organization>DO</Organization> <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> TO PAY OVERHEADS FOR HEATING AND
LIGHTING. VILLAGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CAN<Organization>NOT</Organization> BE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> CRYSTALLISATION <Organization>CENTRES</Organization> IF
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> STOCKS ARE INADEQUATE. CHILDREN ARE THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> USERS OF VILLAGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
WHICH THEREFORE STOCK MAINLY CHILDREN&apos;S BOOKS. <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CARRY A <Organization>LARGER</Organization>
PROPORTION OF <Organization>ADULT</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization>; FEWER CHILDREN&apos;S BOOKS ARE NEEDED HERE SINCE THE
CHILDREN <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO <Organization>GOOD</Organization> SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>GOOD</Organization> QUALITY <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
<Organization>PROVISION</Organization> IS ALWAYS PROFITABLE AND IN CONTRAST WITH VILLAGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>MOBILE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ALWAYS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> QUALIFIED <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. THE TRAVELLING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS A <Organization>GOOD</Organization>
ADVERTISEMENT FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2068
THE ELGIN <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
     
THE ELGIN <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> (<Location>ONTARIO</Location>) <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> WAS FOUNDED IN 1936; IT WAS A
COOPERATIVE VENTURE AND <Organization>BY</Organization> 1964 IT <Organization>HAD</Organization> 12 MEMBER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>THESE</Organization> WERE
INDEPENDENT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND MOST <Organization>HAD SOMEWHAT PRECARIOUS FINANCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THE <Organization>COUNTY COUNCIL</Organization>, <Organization>LOCAL COUNCIL</Organization>, AND INTERESTED INDIVIDUALS AND
ORGANISATIONS. IN 1964, A FULLY TAX SUPPORTED <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS
SUGGESTED TO REPLACE THE ASSOCIATION. <Organization>THIS</Organization> WAS AGREED AND THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> WAS
FOUNDED IN 1966. BRIEFLY <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>&apos;S DEVELOPMENT TO DATE,
FINANCING, AND PLANS FOR THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2069
SCOTLAND 1980 (<Organization>PART</Organization> TWO). <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> VISITED IN <Location>GLASGOW</Location> AND EDINBURGH.
     
THE CONCLUSION OF THE REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> VISIT TO SCOTLAND <Organization>BY</Organization> A GROUP OF <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. (FOR <Organization>PART</Organization> 1, 2SEE1 82/550) A VERY DETAILED DESCRIPTION IS
GIVEN OF <Location>GLASGOW</Location>&apos;S <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE MITCHELL&apos; POINTS COVERED
<Organization>INCLUDE</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> STATISTICS, <Organization>FACILITIES</Organization>, LAYOUT, AND HOLDINGS; PLANS OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> 7
FLOORS ARE INCLUDED. BRIEFER ACCOUNTS COVER 2 <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> AREA <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 1 <Organization>OLD</Organization>
AND 1 NEW; 3 <Organization>BRANCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND THE <Location>CITY</Location>&apos;S <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> AND POLICY OF THE <Location>GLASGOW</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS FULLY
DESCRIBED. A SUCCINCT ACCOUNT OF <Location>EDINBURGH</Location>&apos;S <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS GIVEN, AND IN
CONCLUSION <Organization>SOME</Organization> COMPARISONS ARE DRAWN WITH THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2070
<Location>HOUSTON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ANNUAL REPORT, 1979.
     
THE NEWLY-CONSTRUCTED JULIA IDESON BUILDING, <Organization>CENTRAL LIBRARY PUBLIC SERVICE</Organization>
PROGRAMME, <Organization>BRANCH</Organization> AND <Organization>EXTENSION</Organization> AND SERVICES, <Organization>SUPPORT SERVICES</Organization>, AND THE
<Organization>HOUSTON PUBLIC LIBRARY BOARD</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> REVIEW OF THE <Location>HOUSTON</Location>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S ACTIVITIES IN 1979. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> AVAILABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2071
MATERIALS CENTERS&apos; A DREAM OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
     
PRESENTS AN OVERVIEW OF THE RATIONALE OF CURRICULUM MATERIALS <Organization>CENTRES</Organization> IN
<Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INITIAL FORMATION TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> STATUS AND
ENVISIONS <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> ROLES. TERMINOLOGY <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> IN THE FIELD IS DEFINED.
A HISTORY OF MATERIALS <Organization>CENTRES</Organization> IS TRACED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE 20S WHEN CURRICULUM
LABORATOREIS WERE FIRST CONCEPTUALISED, AND FOCUSES <Organization>ON</Organization> 2 AREAS&apos; THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
OF TEACHING MATERIALS OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> KINDS, AND THE <Organization>WORKSHOP OR LABORATORY</Organization> FOR
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTING</Organization> CURRICULUM AND SUPPLEMENTARY TEACHING MATERIALS.
REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> AVAILABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2072
THE <Organization>TRIER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MODEL.
     
THE <Organization>TRIER UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS OPENED IN AUTUMN 70 SHORTLY BEFORE THE
UNIVERSITY ITSELF. IT FACED MANY <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE START AND THEY <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>NOT</Organization> YET
<Organization>ALL</Organization> BEEN SOLVED ALTHOUGH THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS NOW OPERATING SUCCESSFULLY. IT IS RUN
AS AN <Organization>INTEGRATED UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> BROUGHT CONSIDERABLE
<Organization>OPPOSITION FROM UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> WHO PREFERRED <Organization>TRADITIONAL INSTITUTE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS IDEALLY CONSTRUCTED FOR <Organization>ITS</Organization> PURPOSE, AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
<Organization>FACILITIES</Organization>, PRESENTATION AND CONTENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STOCK ARE ALSO SATISFACTORY.
THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> STILL <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> ARE CONNECTED TO THE UNIVERSITY LAWS CONCERNING
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WHICH <Organization>DO</Organization> <Organization>NOT</Organization> GUARANTEE THE COMPETENCE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DIRECTOR IN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATTERS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> HAS LED TO INTERFERENCE IN <Organization>LIBRARY AFFAIRS</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
UNIVERSITY BODIES AND DEMANDS FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> RIGHTS <Organization>BY UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2073
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>&apos; A DESCRIPTIVE OUTLOOK.
     
(<Organization>MLS</Organization> DISSERTATION.) <Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE MALAYSIAN <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> ENVIRONMENT AND THE
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ROLE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE MALAYSIAN UNIVERSITIES. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> BACKGROUND, <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, <Organization>STAFFING</Organization>, ACCOMMODATION, SERVICES AND
<Organization>FACILITIES</Organization>, AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> SERVICES OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITIES OF
AGRICULTURE, TECHNOLOGY, AND SCIENCE, <Organization>NATIONAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> OF <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>, AND
UNIVERSITY MALAYA. <Organization>DESCRIBES THEIR COOPERATIVE</Organization> ACTIVITIES. THEY ARE MUCH
<Organization>BETTER</Organization> DEVELOPED THAN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MALAYSIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ARE CONTROLLED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, ARE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> COLLECTIONS VERY QUICKLY, AND <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
DEVELOPED RAPIDLY IN THE AREAS OF SERVICES AND <Organization>FACILITIES</Organization>. <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization>
SYSTEMS ARE BEING INTRODUCED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2074
<Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO <Organization>NIGERIAN</Organization> UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
HIGHLIGHTS THE NEED FOR <Organization>NIGERIAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> TO MAKE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> MORE EASILY ACCESSIBLE PHYSICALLY TO USERS. DISTINGUISHES BETWEEN
THE CONCEPTS OF AVAILABILITY AND ACCESSIBILITY, AND BETWEEN <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
ACCESSIBILITY AND <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> ACCESSIBILITY. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE EFFECT OF THE
<Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> FACTORS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO COLLECTIONS&apos; THE UNIVERSITY LIBRARIAN&apos;S NARROW
SERVICE CONCEPT; OPEN AND CLOSED <Organization>ACCESS SYSTEMS</Organization>; RIGID <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> POLICIES;
AND THE <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> DECENTRALISATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIALS. OFFERS <Organization>SOME</Organization>
SUGGESTIONS FOR REMOVING THE BARRIERS WHICH EXIST TO <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2075
<Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>KENYA</Location> WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
<Organization>STAFFING</Organization>, ACQUISITIONS AND <Organization>USE</Organization>.
     
(<Organization>MLS</Organization> DISSERTATION). SURVEYS 3 ACUTE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> FACING <Organization>KENYAN UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (<Organization>STAFFING</Organization>, ACQUISITIONS, AND <Organization>USE</Organization>) AND SUGGESTS SOLUTIONS THAT <Organization>WOULD</Organization>
ENABLE THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO FULFIL <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE EFFECTIVELY IN FURTHERING <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
PARENT INSTITUTIONS&apos; GOALS. ACKNOWLEDGES THE EXISTENCE OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> WHICH
COULD <Organization>NOT</Organization> BE COVERED HERE, ESPECIALLY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACCOMMODATION IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
EFFECTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ASPECTS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MORALE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2076
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STATISTICS 1980.
     
TABULATED STATISTICS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> AND SERVICES IN 19 <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> AND 7
<Organization>NEW ZEALAND UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, COVERING <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, LENDING, SEATING, HOURS,
<Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>, EXPENDITURES AND UNIVERSITY POPULATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2077
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> SITUATION, AS IT HAS DEVELOPED IN THE CONTEXT OF
<Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>&apos;S GEOGRAPHICAL CHARACTERISTICS, POPULATION DISTRIBUTION, <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
STRUCTURES, AND EDUCATION <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. TRACES THE HISTORY OF UNIVERSITIES AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE INITIAL PERIOD DOMINATED <Organization>BY</Organization> BRITISH INFLUENCE, TO THE
PERIOD OF GROWTH WHICH BEGAN IN 1957, CAUSED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE INCREASE IN STUDENT
NUMBERS. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF FINANCE, <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>, PERSONNEL REQUIREMENTS, AND
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. THE INTRODUCTION OF <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>, COOPERATIVE PROJECTS, AND THE
ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NETWORKS</Organization> ARE DISCUSSED, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ORGANISATIONS. FINALLY <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PROSPECTS ARE SURVEYED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2078
LOUISE DARLING AND THE UCLA <Organization>BIOMEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
     
THE 33-YEAR-OLD <Organization>BIOMEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, <Location>LOS
ANGELES</Location>, IS 1 OF THE <Organization>TOP</Organization> RANKED <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location>. LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S HISTORY AND FOUNDING LIBRARIAN LOUISE DARLING&apos;S ROLE IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> CREATION
AND EXPANSION. EXAMINES <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND
SERVICES. LISTS <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF MISS DARLING&apos;S PUBLICATIONS WHICH REFLECT THE PROGRESS
AND CHALLENGES OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP IN THE LAST 30 YEARS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2079
<Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN A <Organization>COMMUNITY-BASED MEDICAL SCHOOL</Organization>&apos; A CASE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IN
<Organization>SOUTH</Organization> DAKOTA.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> BACKGROUND OF COMMUNITY BASED <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> SCHOOLS IN THE
<Location>USA</Location>, WITH EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE EXPERIENCES OF THE UNIVERSITY OF <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> DAKOTA LOMMEN
<Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCES <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE STEPS TAKEN <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO MEET THE
ACCREDITATION STANDARDS OF THE <Organization>LIASON COMMITTEE</Organization> FOR <Organization>MEDICAL EDUCATION</Organization> FOR A
FULL 4 YEAR MD GRANTING INSTITUTION, AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE GOVERNANCE STRUCTURE OF
THE PARTICIPATING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE <Organization>AFFILIATED TEACHING HOSPITALS COUNCIL</Organization>.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> ENCOUNTERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization>
SERVICE TO A <Organization>MEDICAL SCHOOL</Organization> WHICH IS <Organization>DECENTRALISED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A STATEWIDE BASIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2080
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE DISABLED AND DISADVANTAGED.
     
A SUMMARY OF PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Location>ONTARIO</Location> <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>
<Organization>WORKSHOP</Organization>, 27 MAR 81. <Organization>THESE</Organization> INCLUDED&apos; <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO <Organization>FACILITIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> BRIAN FORSYTH;
RETARDED ADULTS <Organization>BY</Organization> HAZEL MOGGACH; BLISSYMBOLICS <Organization>BY</Organization> ANN KENNEDY; LEARNING
DISABLED CHILDREN <Organization>BY</Organization> AHMED MOTIAR; <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> WITH RETARDED
CHILDREN; <Organization>BY</Organization> MARTHA DYNES; AND MUSIC <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> FOR DEAF CHILDREN <Organization>BY</Organization> RENA
SINGHA REDDY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2081
READERSHIP CHARACTERISTICS AND ATTITUDES. SERVICE TO BLIND AND PHYSICALLY
HANDICAPPED USERS.
     
PRESENTS FINDINGS BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A SURVEY OF USERS OF THE <Location>US</Location> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SURVEY&apos;S OBJECTIVES WERE TO DEVELOP A PROFILE OF THE <Organization>NLS</Organization> READERSHIP AND TO
HELP <Organization>NLS</Organization> IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PROGRAMME <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> IDENTIFYING READERS&apos; INTERESTS
AND CONCERNS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2082
GRAY AND GROWING. PROGRAM PACKAGES FOR THE OLDER <Organization>ADULT</Organization>. A MANUAL AND A
SUPPLEMENT MANUAL.
     
DESIGNED FOR PRESENTATION <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, ACTIVITY DIRECTORS, <Organization>OR SERVICE</Organization>
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> REPRESENTATIVES, <Organization>THIS</Organization> MANUAL AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> SUPPLEMENT OUTLINE WAYS TO
MAKE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE MATERIALS PROVIDED OR AVAILABLE, <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> DISCUSSION
AND FOLLOW-UP GUIDELINES. AND <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization> DIRECTIONS FOR <Organization>USING</Organization> FILM AND SLIDE
PROJECTORS AND CASSETTE PLAYERS. A TYPICAL PROGRAMME PACKAGE CONSISTS OF 2 OR
MORE PROFESSIONALLY PRODUCED FILMS OR SLIDE <Organization>SHOWS</Organization> CHOSEN FOR COMPATIBILITY,
QUALITY, AND EFFECTIVENESS. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> AVAILABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2083
RECENT ADVANCES IN SCHOOL LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
AN ACCOUNT OF THE WORLD-WIDE GROWTH AND DEVELOPMENT OF SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
COOPERATION AND <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> IN SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ATTAINMENT OF THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
ROLE OF THE SCHOOL LIBRARIAN, AND EDUCATION OF SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. INCLUDES THE
<Organization>UNESCO SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA</Organization> SERVICE MANIFESTO.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 2084
<Organization>EARLY</Organization> CHILDHOOD <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROGRAMMING&apos; MEASUREMENT AND EVALUATION.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEMONSTRATION PROJECT WAS UNDERTAKEN TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> STYLES AND
TECHNIQUES OF EVALUATION WHICH ARE APPLICABLE TO <Organization>EARLY</Organization> CHILDHOOD PROGRAMMING
IN SCHOOL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND TO IDENTIFY <Organization>SOME</Organization> METHODS OF MEASURING
