<Organization>Document</Organization> 4001
<Organization>COPYRIGHT</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COMMUNICATION-AN INTRODUCTION.
     
PROVISIONS OF THE <Organization>GERMAN FEDERAL</Organization> <Organization>COPYRIGHT</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> MOST RELEVANT FOR THE DELIVERY
OF <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED. <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> CONSIDERATION IS GIVEN TO LEGAL
QUESTIONS CONCERNING PHOTOCOPYING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4002
<Organization>COPYRIGHT</Organization> SHOULD REST <Organization>ON</Organization> AGREEMENTS <Organization>NOT</Organization> FORCE.
     
INTERVIEWS THE CHAIRMAN OF THE <Organization>COPYRIGHT LAW REVISION COMMITTEE</Organization>, MOGENS
KOKTVEDGAARD. HE ARGUES THAT THE PROPOSALS CONTAIN NO CHANGE OF PRINCIPLE, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
THAT THE PROBLEM OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> COPYING OF MUSICAL WORKS ESPECIALLY HAS BEEN
TACKLED; MORE SEVERE PUNISHMENT FOR INFRINGEMENTS OF <Organization>COPYRIGHT</Organization> IS ENVISAGED.
PHOTOCOPYING OF PRINTED MATTER <Organization>BY</Organization> EDUCATIONAL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> INSTITUTIONS IS BEING
BROUGHT UNDER CONTROL WITH <Organization>BETTER SYSTEMS</Organization> OF REPORTING <Organization>USE</Organization>. IT IS UP TO THE
ORGANISATIONS <Organization>REPRESENTING</Organization> THE <Organization>COPYRIGHT</Organization> HOLDERS TO PRODUCE A SYSTEM OF
<Organization>COLLECTIVE ADMINISTRATION</Organization> FOR DEALING WITH <Organization>USERS</Organization>. ABOLITION OF <Organization>COPYRIGHT</Organization>,
ARGUED <Organization>BY</Organization> THOSE WHO WANT A FREE MARKET IN <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> PRODUCTS, WOULD LEAD TO THE
DEATH OF CULTURE. LICENCE AGREEMENTS ARE MUCH TO BE PREFERRED TO <Organization>COMPULSORY</Organization>
LICENCES. <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A SYSTEM MUST BE COMBINED WITH FORMS OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> FOR
THE PRODUCERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4003
<Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> FOR CHILDREN&apos; A <Organization>SELECTION</Organization>.
     
AN EXAMINATION OF SOME OF THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> FOR CHILDREN WHICH ARE FOUND
MOST FREQUENTLY IN <Organization>ELEMENTARY SCHOOL</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS. THE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INCLUDES SOME VALUE <Organization>JUDGEMENTS</Organization> PERTAINING TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> QUALITY, <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
POPULARITY WITH CHILDREN, AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> POTENTIAL <Organization>USE</Organization> IN THE SCHOOL, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
AND THE <Organization>HOME</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4004
THE 1978-80 FAXON PERIODICAL PRICES UPDATE.
     
IN THE PAST THESE COMPARATIVE <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> OF <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> PRICES WERE PUBLISHED
ANNUALLY IN THE 1 OCTOBER ISSUES OF 2<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> JOURNAL1.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4005
<Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> PRICES 1979-1981 UPDATE.
     
IN THE PAST THESE COMPARATIVE <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> OF <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> PRICES WERE PUBLISHED
ANNUALLY IN THE 1 OCTOBER ISSUES OF 2<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> JOURNAL1.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4006
EXTEMPLO-REFLECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> A YEAR.
     
THE <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> JOURNAL VIA SCANNET, EXTEMPLO, COMPLETED <Organization>ITS</Organization> 2ND YEAR IN 1980.
IT DRAWS TOGETHER NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> LECTURES, COURSES AND CONFERENCES <Organization>ON</Organization> SCIENTIFIC
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE <Organization>NORDIC</Organization> COUNTRIES. <Organization>ITS</Organization> DECENTRALISED EDITING, <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
EDITORS IN THE <Organization>NORDIC</Organization> COUNTRIES, MAY BE A PRECURSOR TO THE
AUTHOR/EDITOR/REVIEWER COMMUNICATION IN <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> SCIENTIFIC <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> JOURNALS.
EXTEMPLO IS ENTERED VIA A FAIRLY SIMPLE EDITING PROCEDURE INTO THE DEC10
COMPUTER <Organization>AT</Organization> GOTHENBURG&apos;S MEDICINDATA. <Organization>ITS FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> WILL BE GREATLY
INFLUENCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE ONGOING CHANGES IN THE <Organization>LONG DISTANCE</Organization> TELECOMMUNICATION
<Organization>NETWORK</Organization> AVAILABLE IN THE <Organization>NORDIC</Organization> COUNTRIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4007
BUILDING A READERSHIP FOR AN <Organization>ONLINE</Organization> SCIENTIFIC JOURNAL.
     
INSPEC RECENTLY LAUNCHED <Organization>EMIS</Organization> (<Organization>ELECTRONIC MATERIALS INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization>). ONE
OF THE <Organization>FACILITIES</Organization> OFFERED IS <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> PUBLICATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS AND
THE AUTHORS DISCUSS SOME OF THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> ENCOUNTERED, AS WELL AS THE SOLUTIONS
ADOPTED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4008
<Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>.
     
A PERSONAL ACCOUNT OF SOME OF THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> ENCOUNTERED IN THE PREPARATION OF A
SERIES OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> WORKS-BIOGRAPHICAL DICTIONARIES OF ARTISTS, PHOTOGRAPHERS
AND ARCHITECTS, FOR EXAMPLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4009
THE POSITION OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>.
     
<Location>FINLAND</Location> HAS PROPORTIONATELY A VERY <Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> PRODUCTION (710 VOLUMES
PER MILLION POPULATION IN 1970, AS AGAINST 280 IN <Location>USA</Location>). <Organization>BOOK</Organization> LOANS/SALES <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
<Organization>INCREASED</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 17.4/4.9 PER HEAD IN 1950 TO 32.4/13.6 IN 1970, WHILE THE
PROPORTION OF FICTION PUBLISHED FELL <Organization>FROM</Organization> ONE-THIRD TO 10-15%. <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LOANS
<Organization>INCREASED</Organization> SEVENFOLD DURING 1945-70, WHILE BORROWERS <Organization>INCREASED</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 8% TO 26%
OF POPULATION. THE FIRST MOBILE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> APPEARED IN 1961; <Organization>BY</Organization> 1971 THERE WERE
73, LENDING 8% OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TOTAL</Organization>. BOOK-CLUBS CONTRIBUTE TOWARDS AUTHORS&apos;
ROYALTIES AND GRANTS. FINNISH AUTHORS ARE LESS WELL SUBSIDISED THAN <Organization>NORWEGIAN</Organization>,
<Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> BOOKS SELL IN LARGER QUANTITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4010
<Location>ARGENTINA</Location>&apos; A <Organization>BOOK</Organization> WORLD, A WORLD AWAY.
     
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE ARGENTINIAN <Organization>BOOK</Organization> <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization>
INDUSTRY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4011
THE <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SUPPLY SCENE.
     
ATTEMPTS TO HIGHLIGHT ASPECTS OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> INDUSTRY INVOLVED IN THE MARKETING
AND DISTRIBUTION OF BOOKS TO <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, INCLUDING THE OPERATIONS OF
<Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> DISTRIBUTORS, AS WELL AS BOOKSELLERS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SUPPLIERS. SUCCESSFUL <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SUPPLIERS MUST TAKE ADVANTAGE OF ANY
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> SUPPLY ARRANGEMENTS BENEFICIAL TO THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MARKET, AND
BYPASS THOSE WHICH DO <Organization>NOT</Organization> MEET <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> REQUIREMENTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4012
<Organization>FILM</Organization> RECORD-A RECORD SHEET FOR <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PHOTOGRAPHY.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> A <Organization>FILM</Organization> RECORD SHEET (DESIGNED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE AUTHOR) TO BE COMPLETED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
PHOTOGRAPHER AFTER THE <Organization>FILM</Organization> HAS BEEN PROCESSED. EACH ROLL OF <Organization>FILM</Organization> IS THE
<Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> OF A RECORD SHEET GIVING DETAILS OF CAMERA, LENS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
ITEMS, CONTENT OF PHOTOGRAPHS, AND PLACE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4013
<Organization>VIDEODISCS TECHNOLOGY</Organization>&apos; EQUIPMENT, SOFTWARE, AND EDUCATIONAL <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization>.
     
REVIEWS THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>VIDEODISCS</Organization> IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE LASER
SYSTEMS AND CAPACITANCE <Organization>ELECTRONIC DISC SYSTEMS</Organization> IN PARTICULAR. AVAILABILITY
AND DISTRIBUTION OF VIDEODISC SOFTWARE IS COVERED ALONG WITH THE DEVELOPMENT
AND TESTING OF SYSTEMS IN EDUCATION AND BUSINESS. THE ARTICLE IS <Organization>FOLLOWED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> A
SURVEY REPORT (P 325-334) COVERING 4 VIDEODISC PLAYERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4014
<Organization>MICROGRAPHICS</Organization> (TABLE OF CONTENTS ONLY).
     
<Organization>COVERS MICROGRAPHIC TECHNOLOGY</Organization>, EQUIPMENT AND MARKETS. THE TECHNOLOGY WHICH IS
REVIEWED INCLUDES RECORDING, PROCESSING AND DUPLICATING, COMPUTER INPUT/OUTPUT
<Organization>ON</Organization> MICROFILM, VIEWING, PRINTING, STORAGE AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4015
MICROFORMS. 1973-AUGUST, 1981 (CITATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>NTIS DATA</Organization> <Organization>BASE</Organization>).
     
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF MICROFORM MATERIALS ARE CITED IN THE
UPDATED BIBLIOGRAPHY. INCLUDED ARE MICROFILM AND MICROFICHE FORMAT STANDARDS,
UTILISATION, AND CARE. MUCH OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS DISCUSSED IN RELATION TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES, AND EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> LEVELS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4016
COMPUTER OUTPUT TO MICROFILM (COM). JANUARY, 1975-OCTOBER, 1981 (CITATIONS
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE PHYSICS AND ENGINEERING
<Organization>COMMUNITIES DATA</Organization> <Organization>BASE</Organization>).
     
<Organization>COVERS</Organization> CONCEPTS, TECHNIQUES, EQUIPMENT, AND SYSTEMS FOR COMPUTER OUTPUT
MICROFILM (COM) AND ALLIED TECHNOLOGY EMPLOYED IN A WIDE VARIETY OF
<Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization>. SOME ATTENTION IS GIVEN TO ECONOMIC CONSIDERATIONS OF COM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4017
<Organization>WORD</Organization> PROCESSING OUTPUT MICROFORM: AFTER COM CAN <Organization>WORD</Organization>
PROCESSOR/MICRO-/MINI-COMPUTER OUTPUT MICROFORM TAKE OFF?.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE BENEFITS TO BE HAD <Organization>BY</Organization> PRODUCING MICROFORMS DIRECT <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>WORD</Organization>
PROCESSOR OR MINI/MICRO-COMPUTER OUTPUT WITHOUT PRODUCING ANY PAPER
INTERMEDIARY. HOWEVER, WHILE COM RECORDERS CAN ACCEPT THE MAGNETIC TAPE OUTPUT
OF MOST MAINFRAME COMPUTERS, FEW COM RECORDERS CAN ACCEPT FLOPPY DISCS DIRECT
AND THOSE THAT CAN WILL ONLY ACCEPT <Organization>IBM</Organization> FORMATTED FLOPPY DISCS. THE ARTICLE
GOES <Organization>ON</Organization> TO REVIEW THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> METHODS THAT ARE CURRENTLY EMPLOYED TO PRODUCE
<Organization>WORD</Organization> PROCESSING OUTPUT MICROFORM AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE WORK THAT NRCD IS DOING IN
<Organization>THIS</Organization> AREA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4018
A <Organization>NEW ARTS COUNCIL</Organization> FOR <Location>QUEBEC</Location>.
     
THE <Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF A MEMOIR JOINTLY PRESENTED TO THE FEDERAL <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> OF <Location>CANADA</Location> <Organization>ON</Organization>
1 MAY 81, <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>QUEBEC LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, THE NORTH <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>
<Organization>LANGUAGE PUBLISHERS GROUP</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>QUEBEC WRITERS UNION</Organization>, SETTING <Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
VIEWS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>IMPORTANCE</Organization> OF LITERATURE IN <Organization>CULTURAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ROLE</Organization>
TO DATE IN UPHOLDING THE BURDEN OF RESPONSIBILITY FOR <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> AND
<Organization>COMMUNICATING</Organization> LITERATURE IN <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>. AN APPEAL FOR <Organization>STATE</Organization> AID IS PRESENTED <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE GROUNDS OF THE NECESSITY FOR A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> ORGANISM TO MEDIATE <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND LOCAL INTERESTS IN SUPPORTING MINORITY CULTURE, AND THE
OBJECTIVES OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>POLICY</Organization> ARE BRIEFLY OUTLINED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4019
LEXICOGRAPHY&apos; AN INTRODUCTION TO THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF DICTIONARIES.
     
<Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> A STRUCTURAL ANALYSIS OF THE DICTIONARY INCORPORATING BOTH FORM AND
CONTENT <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>USING</Organization> A TYPOLOGY WHICH TAKES ACCOUNT EQUALLY OF THE PURPOSE AND
<Organization>LINGUISTIC</Organization> SCOPE OF EACH TYPE. THE STRUCTURE OF THE DICTIONARY ENTRY AND THE
<Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF DEFINITION ARE DISCUSSED IN DETAIL, AND A COMPARISON MADE WITH THE
THESAURUS. FINALLY THE THESAURUS IS DISTINGUISHED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>LANGUAGE</Organization> OF
THESAURI, AS USED IN INFORMATICS TO SHOW THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> AND
KEYWORD. CONCLUDES THAT <Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> ABOUT THESAURUS <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization>
SHOULD BE BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> SEMANTICS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4020
MODE OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>ROLE</Organization> IN SEMANTIC REPRESENTATIONS OF SENTENCES.
     
CONCEIVES A MODE OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AS A GENERALISATION OF A VARIETY OF <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization>
CONCEPTS USED <Organization>BY</Organization> LINGUISTS AND LOGICIANS IN DESCRIBING RELATIONS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
<Organization>LINGUISTIC</Organization> EXPRESSIONS AND NON-LINGUISTIC REALITY (<Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS TERM, PREDICATE,
REFERENTIALITY). PROPOSES A CALCULUS FOR THE MODE OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> OF A RUSSIAN
NOUN PHRASE, BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>SET</Organization> OF FEATURES OF A NOUN PHRASE WHICH EXHAUSTIVELY
CHARACTERISE <Organization>ITS</Organization> MODE OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>. EXPLORES THE INFLUENCE OF THE MODE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
PHRASE&apos;S SYNTACTIC AND ANAPHORIC PROPERTIES AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE POSSIBILITY OF
INDICATING THE MODE OF A NOUN PHRASE IN SEMANTIC REPRESENTATIONS OF SENTENCES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4021
SOME CLASS OF MERGING ALGORITHMS.
     
A GENERALISED <Organization>MODEL</Organization> OF MERGING ALGORITHMS OF THE +N-TH ORDER, <Organization>USING</Organization> THE
CONCEPT OF A BINARY TREE, IS CONSIDERED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4022
<Organization>ACS COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> NOMENCLATURE&apos; ANNUAL REPORT FOR 1980.
     
NOMENCLATURE COMMITTEES, BOTH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL, WERE VERY <Organization>ACTIVE</Organization> IN
1980, RESULTING IN SUBSTANTIAL PROGRESS IN MANY <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> FIELDS. A SUMMARY OF
THE MORE IMPORTANT MEETINGS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS FOLLOWS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4023
<Organization>PRESENT</Organization> STATUS OF INORGANIC <Organization>CHEMICAL</Organization> NOMENCLATURE.
     
A SYSTEMATIC <Organization>CHEMICAL</Organization> NAME IS ONE WHICH PORTRAYS THE ESSENTIAL STRUCTURAL
FEATURES OF A <Organization>CHEMICAL</Organization> COMPOUND <Organization>BY</Organization> SOME <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PATTERN. FOR MOST PURPOSES IT
IS UNNECESSARY TO WRITE NOMENCLATURE RULES IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> DETAIL AS TO PROVIDE A
SINGLE NAME FOR EACH COMPOUND. LIKE <Organization>ALL</Organization> HUMAN <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> NOMENCLATURE PATTERNS
CHANGE WITH <Organization>TIME</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS ESSENTIAL TO MEET <Organization>NEW</Organization> CONDITIONS, TO SECURE <Organization>GREATER</Organization>
GENERALITY, OR TO OBTAIN SIMPLER NAMES. WHILE NOMENCLATURE SPECIALISTS MUST BE
ATTUNED TO THE NEEDS OF NOMENCLATURE <Organization>USERS</Organization>, <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SUGGESTED SOLUTIONS TO BE
SUCCESSFUL MUST BE ACCEPTABLE TO THE <Organization>USERS</Organization>. THE PRESENTATION DETAILS WITH
PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO INORGANIC CHEMISTRY (1) THE COMMITTEE-COMMISSION
STRUCTURE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> COUNTRY AND INTERNATIONALLY, (2) SIGNIFICANT ACCOMPLISHMENTS
IN THE PAST HALF-CENTURY, (3) DEVELOPMENTS IN PROGRESS, AND (4) AREAS <Organization>WHERE</Organization>
NOMENCLATURE DEVELOPMENTS ARE NEEDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4024
PATENTING, PROFITABILITY AND MARKETING CHARACTERISTICS OF THE PHARMACEUTICAL
INDUSTRY.
     
BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>UNPUBLISHED CITY UNIVERSITY (LONDON)</Organization> MSC THESES OF K.A. WITHERS
AND M.P. NOLAN. ANALYSES THE PATENTING ACTIVITY OF PHARMACEUTICAL COMPANIES IN
THE <Location>UK</Location>; THE GLOBAL EVOLUTION OF PHARMACEUTICAL PATENTING DURING 1951-77; AND
THE FATE OF PATENTS PUBLISHED IN THE <Location>UK</Location> DURING 1951-61. <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> <Organization>HOW</Organization> MUCH
COMPANIES VARY IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PATENTING <Organization>POLICY</Organization>; WHETHER <Organization>THIS</Organization> CORRELATES WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
PROFITABILITY; AND THE AMOUNT OF LICENSING <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> COMPANIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4025
THE DIARY OF THE HUMAN RACE: <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN A TROUBLED <Organization>AGE</Organization>.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE AN INDEX TO THE CULTURE <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> WHICH THEY
EXIST-PROVIDING A REPOSITORY OF WHAT HAS BEEN DISCOVERED, IMAGINED OR HOPED,
AND SERVING AS ARENAS <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> WHICH PEOPLE CAN GRAPPLE WITH <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> TASKS AND
ATTEMPT TO COPE WITH THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>. <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> A BRIEF <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> REVIEW OF THE <Location>US</Location>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>ROLE</Organization> IN <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE, AND HIGHLIGHTS <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> AND LIKELY <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
DIFFICULTIES IN MEETING THAT GOAL, AS <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE FACED WITH INFLATIONARY
PRESSURES, THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>&apos;S INCREASING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF TELEVISION INSTEAD OF BOOKS, AND
<Organization>HIGHER</Organization> LABOUR COSTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4026
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE TWO CULTURES.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. CULTURE MAY MEAN AN ACQUAINTANCE WITH THE BEST THAT HAS
BEEN KNOWN AND SAID IN THE WORLD, AND THE WHOLE CONGERIES OF WAYS IN WHICH A
PARTICULAR PEOPLE CONSTRUCT BUILDINGS, MANUFACTURE ARTIFACTS, WORSHIP DEITIES,
MAKE WAR AND LOVE, RAISE CHILDREN, AND LIVE WITH ONE ANOTHER. TRACES THE
<Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE 2 CULTURES, CONTENDING THAT
THE MAKEUP OF SOCIETIES AND CULTURES THAT ARE THOUSANDS OF YEARS <Organization>OLD</Organization> IS <Organization>NOT</Organization>
MUCH INFLUENCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SMALL NUMBER WHO SEEK CULTURE, AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> REMAIN
PERIPHERAL IN THE CULTURE OF THE PEOPLE AS A WHOLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4027
<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> MODERNIZATION.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. A SIGNIFICANT HISTORIOGRAPHICAL SHIFT HAS TAKEN PLACE
AMONG <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> HISTORIANS <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE LAST 2 DECADES, AND A MORE COMBATIVE AND
CRITICAL STANCE TOWARD <Location>US</Location> INSTITUTIONS IS APPARENT, WHICH SERVES AS A BRIDGE
FOR THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DEBATE TO ENTER THE LARGER ARENA. IDENTIFIES AND
ACCOUNTS FOR THE HISTORIOGRAPHICAL CHANGE, RAISES SOME QUESTIONS ABOUT <Organization>ITS</Organization>
CONCLUSIONS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RELATIONSHIP TO MODERNISATION. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> REFLECTS UPON THE
CONNECTION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> HISTORY AND <Organization>CONTEMPORARY</Organization> <Organization>POLICY</Organization> DEBATES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4028
ANCIENT BURIALS OF METAL DOCUMENTS IN STONE BOXES-THEIR IMPLICATIONS FOR
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. ARCHAEOLOGICAL DIGS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> UNEARTHED MANY BARREL CYLINDERS,
STONE OR METAL TABLETS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ARTEFACTS <Organization>ON</Organization> WHICH WERE INSCRIBED A PERMANENT
RECORD OF THE LABOURS OF PARTICULAR SOCIETIES. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> SOME OF THE MAJOR
FINDINGS <Organization>AT</Organization> PERSEPOLIS AND ELSEWHERE. THE HISTORY OF BOOKS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS
THE HISTORY OF 2INSTRUMENTS, 1AND THUS THE <Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> OF THE ANCIENT
NEAR EAST ARE AN INTEGRAL PART OF THE HISTORY OF LIBRARIANSHIP; ANCIENT
RECORDS COME <Organization>NOT</Organization> IN SINGLE BOOKS <Organization>BUT</Organization> IN WHOLE LIBRARIES-ORGANIC ENTITIES
<Organization>REPRESENTING EVERY DEPARTMENT</Organization> OF HUMAN KNOWLEDGE, OF OBVIOUS SIGNIFICANCE TO
THE HISTORY OF LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4029
METHODS OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> IN CASSIODORUS.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. THE 2PSALM COMMENTARY, 1<Organization>BY</Organization> THE 6TH-CENTURY <Organization>LATIN CHURCH</Organization>
FATHER, CASSIODORUS, USED A TYPE OF FORMAT CREATED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE AUTHOR HIMSELF-ONE
NEVER TO BE USED AGAIN IN THE HISTORY OF THE MEDIAEVAL <Organization>BOOK</Organization>. SHOWS <Organization>HOW</Organization>,
<Organization>THROUGH</Organization> THE <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AND <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF MARGINAL SYMBOLS,
CASSIODORUS WAS ABLE TO <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> TO HIS STUDENTS A HANDBOOK <Organization>FROM</Organization> WHICH THEY
COULD LEARN THE RUDIMENTS OF THE LIBERAL ARTS <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF DIVINE
SCRIPTURE. THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> CONSTITUTES A SELF-HELP <Organization>MANUAL</Organization>, WITH THE NARRATOR SPEAKING
DIRECTLY TO THE <Organization>READER</Organization>. CRITICAL MARKS WERE ADDED TO <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> PLACES IN THE
<Organization>TEXT</Organization> TO ALLOW THE <Organization>READER</Organization> TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WHATEVER HE WANTS IN THE <Organization>TEXT</Organization>, SIMPLY <Organization>BY</Organization>
LOCATING LIKE SYMBOLS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4030
STOIC INFLUENCES IN LIBRARIANSHIP: A CRITIQUE.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. EXPRESSES A DEEP INDEBTEDNESS <Organization>BY</Organization> LIBRARIANS AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS TO THE THOUGHT AND CULTURE OF ANCIENT <Location>GREECE</Location>, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
SOUNDS A WARNING TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS THAT SOME OF THE LESSONS LEARNED
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE GREEKS ARE BEING BLINDLY AND UNTHINKINGLY MISAPPLIED TODAY, TO THE
DETRIMENT OF CLEAR THINKING ABOUT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE ANCIENT
GREEK THEORY OF THE SIGN EXPRESSING THE RELATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> WORDS, THOUGHTS, AND
THINGS WHICH IS STILL INFLUENTIAL IN PHILOSOPHY, LINGUISTICS, AND PSYCHOLOGY,
<Organization>BUT</Organization> IS OFTEN INAPPROPRIATELY INVOKED IN THESE DISCIPLINES AND IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF COMMUNICATION. THE <Organization>MODEL</Organization> IS AMBIGUOUS,
AND SO AN ALTERNATIVE, BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> HUMAN LINGUISTICS, IS PROPOSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4031
AN IDEA OF LIBRARIANSHIP: AN OUTLINE FOR A ROOT-METAPHOR THEORY IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. WITH GROWTH COMES COMPLEXITY; AND LIBRARIANSHIP BECOMES
INCREASINGLY COMPLEX AS IT GROWS. A 2-FOLD APPROACH TO THE UNDERSTANDING OF
LIBRARIANSHIP IS SUGGESTED. FIRSTLY, LIBRARIANSHIP SHOULD BE VIEWED AS A
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> DISCIPLINE AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS SHOULD BE STUDIED AS A WHOLE, AND
SECONDLY, <Organization>BASIC</Organization> COMPONENTS OF LIBRARIANSHIP SHOULD BE IDENTIFIED, <Organization>BY</Organization> REDUCING
THE COMPLEXITY OF THE FIELD TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> SIMPLEST PARTS-ITS &apos;ROOTS&apos;. PROPOSES A
<Organization>MODEL</Organization> OF &apos;METALIBRARIANSHIP&apos; BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> ANALYSIS, AND INVOLVING ASSUMPTIONS
ABOUT <Organization>ITS</Organization> NATURE IN TERMS OF THE MECHANISM, EXPANDED CONTEXTUALISM AND
FORMISM, AND SUGGESTING THAT THE PRIMARY ROOT <Organization>METAPHOR</Organization> OF METALIBRARIANSHIP IS
THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE GENERIC <Organization>BOOK</Organization>, <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> MATTER, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>READER</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4032
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND PRINTERS IN THE FIFTEENTH CENTURY.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. TREATISE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
PRINTERS IN THE 15TH CENTURY, WHEN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OFTEN <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization> THE <Organization>BASE</Organization> TEXTS, IN
MANUSCRIPT FORM FOR THE PRINTERS. FOCUSES PARTICULARLY <Organization>ON</Organization> JOHANN AMERBACH, A
PRINTER AND PUBLISHER IN BASEL, <Location>SWITZERLAND</Location>, AND HIS RELATIONSHIP WITH THE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH FURNISHED HIS TEXTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4033
ISSUE DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp;
CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>, TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80).PAP
     
ERS ARE IN 7 SECTIONS: PLENARY SESSIONS; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND ANTIQUITY; PHILOSOPHY
OF LIBRARIANSHIP; <Organization>EARLY</Organization> MODERN <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>UNIQUE</Organization>
COLLECTIONS; NOTABLE BIBLIOGRAPHERS; AND <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> LIBRARIES-<Location>FRANCE</Location> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
AFRICAN COLONIES. FOR ABSTRACTS OF THE PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SEMINAR, SEE
THE FOLLOWING <Organization>SERIAL</Organization> NUMBERS:-.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4034
CRITICISM OF BOURGEOIS LIBRARIANSHIP IN SOVIET <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LITERATURE.
     
<Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> A CHRONOLOGICAL ANALYSIS OF THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF LIBRARIANSHIP IN WESTERN
COUNTRIES AS REFLECTED IN THE WRITINGS OF SOVIET LIBRARIANS. CONTRIBUTIONS
<Organization>FROM</Organization> 1920S AND 1930S REVEAL <Organization>NOT</Organization> ONLY CRITICISM OF THE WESTERN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> THEORIES
<Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> APPRECIATION OF PRACTICAL <Organization>ACHIEVEMENTS</Organization>. INCONSISTENCY OF THEORY
(NON-POLITICAL ORIENTATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) WITH PRACTICE (MIDDLE CLASS BIAS OF
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) WAS 1 OF THE MAIN AREAS OF CRITICISM IN THE 1940S AND 1950S.
1960S BROUGHT WIDER INTEREST IN <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> ENCOUNTERED
IN <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> COUNTRIES. THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> INTEREST IS THE INFLUENCE OF WESTERN
LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4035
<Organization>SCOTTISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 1978-1980. A TRIENNIAL REVIEW.
     
<Organization>COVERS</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, COLLEGE, SCHOOL, UNIVERSITY AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF SCOTLAND, <Organization>SCOTTISH LIBRARIES CO</Organization>-OPERATIVE <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization> PROJECT,
EDUCATION IN LIBRARIANSHIP AND THE <Organization>SCOTTISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4036
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>FRANCE</Location>: THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> SITUATION.
     
A COMMENTARY <Organization>BY</Organization> THE PRESIDENT OF THE ASSOCIATION DES BIBLIOTHECAIRES FRANCAIS
(<Organization>ABF</Organization>) FOR THE 1981 CONFERENCE, SURVEYING THE POSITION AS COMPARED TO THE
PREVIOUS YEAR. ADVANCES AS REASONS FOR RESTRAINED OPTIMISM RECENT <Organization>ACHIEVEMENTS</Organization>
CONSOLIDATING AND ADVANCING THE INTERESTS OF THE PROFESSION, INCLUDING THE
ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS, INTEGRATION OF TEACHING PROGRAMMES,
AND IMPROVEMENTS IN <Organization>BUDGET</Organization> ALLOCATION. RECENT <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> MEASURES ARE
DISCUSSED AS EVIDENCE OF WIDER <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND OFFICIAL RECOGNITION OF THE
<Organization>IMPORTANCE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES, AND IN CONCLUSION URGES
LIBRARIANS TO CAPITALISE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> OPPORTUNITIES NOW OPENING UP.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4037
AFRICAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. WESTERN TRADITION AND COLONIAL BRAINWASHING.
     
FOCUSES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INTRODUCTION INTO <Location>AFRICA</Location> (A PREDOMINANTLY ORAL OR PRELITERATE
CULTURE) OF SOME OF THE TECHNOLOGICAL ARTIFACTS AND RELATED INSTITUTIONS
<Organization>REPRESENTING</Organization> THE COLONISER&apos;S POWER AND AUTHORITY. IN PARTICULAR, ATTENTION IS
DRAWN TO THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND PSYCHOLOGICAL SIGNIFICANCE OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AS AN ARMOURY
OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, EDUCATION, AND COMMUNICATION AMONG AFRICANS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4038
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> IN FRENCH-SPEAKING <Location>AFRICA</Location>: <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
<Organization>ROLE</Organization>, 1803-1975.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> VARIES IN THEORY, IN
PRACTICE AND IN LAW. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>UNDERLYING</Organization> THEORY OR PHILOSOPHY OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> AS IT EVOLVED IN FRANCOPHONE <Location>AFRICA</Location> TO THE MID-70S. SECTIONS
INCLUDE&apos; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS AN ANTIDOTE TO EXILE, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR <Organization>EXTENDING</Organization> <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>
CULTURE, AND THE MOVEMENT FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4039
ANNUAL REVIEW OF CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. PREDICTIONS TO THE YEAR 2010.
     
BROAD-BASED REVIEW OF POSSIBLE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS <Organization>FOLLOWED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> EXTENSIVE
BIBLIOGRAPHIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4040
ANNUAL REVIEW OF ISSUES AFFECTING CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
REVIEW <Organization>COVERS</Organization> THOSE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> WHICH ARE <Organization>NOT</Organization> WIDELY READ <Organization>BY</Organization> LIBRARIANS DUE TO
THE FACT THAT THEY COVER RELATED DISCIPLINES <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS ARCHIVES, BIBLIOGRAPHY,
<Organization>BOOK</Organization> ARTS, LITERACY, <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization>, <Organization>MICROGRAPHICS</Organization> AND PRINTING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4041
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>NETWORKS</Organization>, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN SOURCE, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization>
EXPERIENCES.
     
A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A 1979 <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> CONFERENCE SURVEYING RECENT DEVELOPMENTS
IN THE CONTEXT OF <Location>BRAZIL</Location>&apos;S RESTRICTED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RESOURCES.
DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN INSTITUTE</Organization> OF BIBLIOGRAPHY AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>
(IBBD)&apos;S <Organization>CATALOGUE CARD REPRODUCTION SERVICE</Organization>, SIC, CREATED IN 1942, AND THE
<Organization>SUBSEQUENT</Organization> CALCO PROJECT TO PROVIDE A SPANISH-PORTUGUESE <Organization>LANGUAGE</Organization> EQUIVALENT
TO MARC FOR THE WHOLE OF <Location>LATIN AMERICA</Location>. <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN SOURCE <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> ARE
OUTLINED WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization>, AND THE OPERATION OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
COOPERATIVE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> PROJECT SINCE 1956 EVALUATED. FINALLY THE PROJECTED
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SYSTEM (SNICT) IS DESCRIBED IN
<Organization>FULL</Organization>, WITH DETAILS OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> STRUCTURE, OBJECTIVES, <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> SYSTEM,
AND IMPLEMENTATION SCHEDULE. EVALUATES THE FEASIBILITY OF THE PROJECT AS A
WHOLE, IN RELATION TO THE INADEQUACY OF <Organization>EXISTING REGIONAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4042
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN AN INDEPENDENT <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>.
     
PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A SEMINAR SPONSORED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location> BRANCH OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>, 14-16 SEPT 1973.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4043
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS A SOURCE OF ENERGY.
     
REPORT OF A JOINT <Organization>STUDY</Organization> HELD IN <Location>PARIS</Location> <Location>IN</Location> NOV 81, ATTENDED <Organization>BY</Organization> REPRESENTATIVES
OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE 5 <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS CONCERNED WITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK, TO EXAMINE THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PUBLICATIONS AVAILABLE TO
PROFESSIONALS. THE OPENING SESSION COVERED THE 5 REVIEWS PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS, AND 3 <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> REVIEWS PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> INDEPENDENT
AGENCIES; THE EDITORS CONCERNED GAVE DETAILS, REPORTED IN SUMMARY, OF <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization>
COVERAGE, READERSHIP, <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization>, AND FREQUENCY. THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MAIN SESSION
COVERED <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> PUBLICATIONS DEALING WITH <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY;
HERE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> THE 5 EDITORS CONCERNED DESCRIBED THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> AND
STRUCTURE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> BULLETINS, AND <Organization>THEN</Organization> DISCUSSED <Organization>AT</Organization> LENGTH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SOURCES OF
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. THE REPORT SUMMARISES THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> DEBATES HELD <Organization>ON</Organization>
RELATIONS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROFESSION AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> INSTITUTIONS, AND
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE PROFESSION AND THE PRESS, AND CONCLUDES WITH A BRIEF OUTLINE OF
THE ARGUMENTS PRESENTED FOR <Organization>ESTABLISHING</Organization> AN <Organization>INFORMATION BUREAU</Organization> TO SERVE THE
<Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> NEEDS OF THE PROFESSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4044
THIRTY YEARS OF THE 2BIBLIOTEKAR1.
     
A CRITICAL EVALUATION OF ALMOST 30 YEARS OF 2BIBLIOTEKAR&apos;S 1HISTORY.
<Organization>INADEQUATE FINANCIAL</Organization> RESOURCES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> MEANT THAT AUTHORS FEES ARE <Organization>NOT</Organization> GENEROUS,
AND THE QUALITY OF THE PUBLISHED MATERIAL SUFFERS. IT IS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> IMPOSSIBLE TO
IMPROVE THE JOURNAL&apos;S LAYOUT, ALTHOUGH THE PRINTING <Organization>FACILITIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CYRIL
AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARE GRATEFULLY APPRECIATED. CERTAIN SUGGESTIONS
SHOULD IMPROVE 2BIBLIOTEKAR&apos;S 1QUALITY AND IMAGE, E.G. ARTICLES SHOULD BE
<Organization>PLANNED</Organization> WELL IN ADVANCE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE CYRIL AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
MAJOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. FREELANCE CORRESPONDENTS <Organization>ALL</Organization> OVER THE COUNTRY SHOULD REPORT
REGULARLY ABOUT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> REGIONS. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> FREELANCE COLLABORATORS,
WITH A GOOD COMMAND OF MODERN LANGUAGES, SHOULD PROVIDE REVIEWS OF FOREIGN
<Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP AND DESIGNATE ARTICLES WORTHY OF <Organization>FULL</Organization> <Organization>TRANSLATION</Organization>
INTO BULGARIAN. A <Organization>SPECIAL COMMISSION</Organization> SHOULD BE APPOINTED TO SPECIFY
2BIBLIOTEKAR&apos;S1 STATUTE WHICH WOULD STRENGTHEN <Organization>ITS</Organization> POSITION AS THE ONLY
JOURNAL CATERING FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF LIBRARIANS IN <Location>BULGARIA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4045
ZZZZ.
     
FORMERLY 2<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COMPUTER EQUIPMENT REVIEW1, THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> TITLE REFLECTS THE FACT
THAT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CONTAINED IN THE JOURNAL IS OF INTEREST TO A WIDE RANGE OF
<Organization>INFORMATION PROCESSING AGENCIES</Organization> AND <Organization>SPECIALTIES</Organization> AND <Organization>NOT</Organization> JUST TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4046
ZZZZ.
     
THE CHANGE IN TITLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> 2JOURNAL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>1 TO 2<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
TECHNOLOGY AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>1 REFLECTS THE BROADENING OF THE FIELDS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization> TO ENCOMPASS <Organization>OTHER TECHNOLOGIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4047
SEMINAR FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> OFFICERS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 21-23 FEB 1979.
     
<Organization>COURSE</Organization> OBJECTIVES WERE TO PROVIDE PRACTICAL INSTRUCTION <Organization>ON</Organization> A NUMBER OF ASPECTS
OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> METHODOLOGY, <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AIMS AND REPORT WRITING AND TO CONSIDER THE
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>, <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4048
THE WORK OF THE <Organization>ASLIB RESEARCH DEPARTMENT</Organization>.
     
REVIEWS RECENT AND <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> WORK OF THE <Organization>ASLIB</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND CONSULTANCY
DIVISION, WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> FUNDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4049
THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IN <Location>QUEBEC</Location>&apos; REPORT OF
A SURVEY (PART 2).
     
<Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> THE RESULTS OF 1 SECTION OF THE SURVEY CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> IN DEC 80 <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
COMMITTEE FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>. THE GLOBAL COMPILATION WAS
PRESENTED IN 2ARGUS 110(3-4) 81 (SEE 82/2521). <Organization>THIS</Organization> REPORT <Organization>COVERS</Organization> THE
UNIVERSITY SECTOR ONLY. 6 <Location>QUEBEC</Location> UNIVERSITIES COMPLETED A QUESTIONNAIRE <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> DURING THE PERIOD 1975-80. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF FINDINGS <Organization>ON</Organization>
RESEARCHERS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PROJECTS, REASONS FOR <Organization>NOT</Organization> PURSUING <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, AND OF
SUGGESTIONS AND COMMENTS MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> RESPONDANTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4050
<Organization>MR</Organization>. ACRL&apos; CHARLES HARVEY BROWN (1875-1960).
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE LIFE AND CAREER OF CHARLES HARVEY BROWN <Organization>WHOSE</Organization> CHIEF CONTRIBUTION
TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION WAS THE FOUNDING OF THE ASSOCIATION OF COLLEGE AND
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (ACRL). HOWEVER <Organization>THIS</Organization> WAS ONLY 1 OF A SERIES OF MAJOR
CONTRIBUTIONS WHICH HE MADE TO THE PROGRESS OF <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.
2SCIENTIFIC <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>1 WAS HIS <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> CONTRIBUTION AND THE CULMINATION OF A
LIFETIME DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF LITERATURE. HE ENDED HIS CAREER AS IOWA <Organization>STATE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DIRECTOR.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4051
DRAHOSLAV GAWRECKI.
     
A PROFILE OF THE LEADING CZECHOSLOVAK SPECIALIST IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ARCHITECTURE-DRAHOSLAV GAWRECKI-WHOSE WORK IN THE FIELD SPANS THE LAST 30
YEARS. DURING <Organization>THIS</Organization> PERIOD GAWRECKI PUBLISHED SOME 370 TITLES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>,
DESIGN AND EQUIPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS AND PARTICIPATED IN MAJOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> PROJECTS IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>. HE INITIATED THE ESTABLISHMENT, IN
<Location>EASTERN EUROPE</Location>, OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> COMMISSIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARCHITECTURE AND EQUIPMENT
AND FOUNDED THE MEZHDUNARODNYI KOORDINATSIONNYI TSENTR <Organization>PO</Organization> STROITEL&apos;STVU,
OBORUDOVANIYU I TEKHNICHESKOMU OSNASHCHENIYU BIBLIOTEK (INTERNATIONAL
<Organization>COORDINATING CENTRE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization>, EQUIPMENT AND TECHNOLOGY IN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>). HIS CONTRIBUTION TO INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION INCLUDED THE
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF SEMINARS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARCHITECTURE AND <Organization>ESTABLISHING</Organization> CONTACTS
WITH SPECIALISTS IN WESTERN COUNTRIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4052
MUNSHI NAWAL KISHORE (1836-1895) MIRROR OF URDU PRINTING IN BRITISH <Location>INDIA</Location>.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE CAREER AND <Organization>ACHIEVEMENTS</Organization> OF MUNSHI NAWAL KISHORE, A PRINTER AND
PUBLISHER IN 19TH CENTURY BRITISH <Location>INDIA</Location>, WHO BUILT UP SINGLE HANDED 1 OF THE
MOST FAMOUS PRINTING HOUSES IN THE EAST. ANALYSES THE OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTION
MADE TO URDU PRINTING <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>KISHORE PRESS</Organization>, AND <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>CONSIDERS</Organization> <Organization>KISHORE</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>ROLE</Organization>
AS AN AUTHOR, EDITOR, TRANSLATOR, AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SERVANT. FOR AN ABSTRACT OF A
PAPER WITH THE <Organization>SAME</Organization> TITLE, 2SEE1 81/5056.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4053
<Organization>BOOK</Organization> COLLECTOR, BIBLIOGRAPHER, AND BENEFACTOR OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>: SIR WILLIAM OSLER.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> SOME DETAILS OF WILLIAM OSLER (1849-1919), A
CANADIAN TEACHER AND PHYSICIAN, AS A <Organization>BOOK</Organization> COLLECTOR AND BENEFACTOR OF
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND FOCUSES <Organization>ON</Organization> OSLER AS A BIBLIOGRAPHER.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4054
THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> STATUS OF LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
THE ADVENT OF DATA PROCESSING AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> HAS <Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> THE
STANDING OF LIBRARIANSHIP AS A PROFESSION AND <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>SAME</Organization> <Organization>TIME</Organization> CREATED A
<Organization>DEMAND</Organization> FOR <Organization>BETTER</Organization> QUALIFICATIONS, ESPECIALLY <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> ENTRY. <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> AN IMPORTANT <Organization>ROLE</Organization> TO PLAY IN PUTTING PRESSURE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AND
<Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> TO IMPROVE THE STATUS OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> MEMBERS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> STATUS VARIES
CONSIDERABLY <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1 COUNTRY TO ANOTHER, ALTHOUGH THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> TREND IS UPWARDS,
AND <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1 KIND OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO ANOTHER. IN SOME UNIVERSITIES, LIBRARIANS ENJOY
<Organization>FULL</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> STATUS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> A LIBRARIAN MUST BE MORE THAN A PURE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> AND
MUST BE PROFICIENT IN THE PRACTICAL ADMINISTRATIVE SKILLS AS WELL.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4055
THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> <Organization>COURSE</Organization> OF <Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> THEORY IN THE <Location>UNITED STATES</Location>.
     
ARCHIVISTS WISHING TO PURSUE THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> THEORY MUST FIRST DEFINE
THAT CONCEPT AND <Organization>THEN</Organization> WEIGH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> DEFINITION AGAINST THE WORK DONE IN THE
FIELD SO FAR. ONE APPROACH WOULD BE TO CONSIDER THEORY AS THE DEVELOPMENT OF
<Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> LAWS, AND TO FRAME HYPOTHESES IN <Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> FORM AND TEST <Organization>THEM</Organization>
AGAINST THE EVIDENCE. ADDRESSES THE LIKELY <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> TRENDS IN <Location>US</Location> <Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> THEORY
AGAINST <Organization>THIS</Organization> BACKGROUND, CONCLUDING THAT THERE IS HOPE FOR THE PROFESSION IF&apos;
(1) THE PROFESSION ITSELF REALISES THAT IT IS BOTH A <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND A CRAFT; AND
(2) CERTAIN ARCHIVISTS MAKE THE MOVE <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE WORKPLACE TO THE <Organization>ACADEMY</Organization> AS A
PERMANENT CAREER COMMITMENT. THERE THEY MUST REALIGN THEMSELVES WITH <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>
HISTORIANS AND OTHERS TO PRODUCE A BODY OF <Organization>BASIC</Organization> PRINCIPLES, A SYSTEM OF
IMMUTABLE LAWS-A LITANY OF THEORY AND DOGMA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4056
PROLEGOMENA TO AN <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> CODE OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ETHICS FOR LIBRARIANS.
     
THE SUBSTANCE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> PAPER WAS DELIVERED AS AN ADDRESS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SPRING FESTIVAL
DINNER OF THE <Organization>ACT</Organization> BRANCH OF THE <Organization>LAA</Organization>, 25 SEPT 81. <Organization>EXAMINES</Organization> CRITICALLY THE CODES
OF ETHICS FOR LIBRARIANS WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN PUBLISHED IN THE <Location>USA</Location> AND THE <Location>UK</Location>, AND
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> A NUMBER OF POINTS FOR CONSIDERATION WHEN DRAWING UP <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A CODE FOR
<Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>CONSIDERS</Organization> THE ISSUES THAT GIVE RISE TO QUESTIONS OF
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ETHICS-IN PARTICULAR LITERATURE CONTROLS (CENSORSHIP) AND THE
<Organization>CLIENT</Organization>&apos;S RIGHT TO PRIVACY (FREEDOM TO READ). ARGUES THAT <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A CODE SHOULD BE
PRECISE AND CLEAR AND TAKE COGNIZANCE OF THE FACT THAT LIBRARIANS DISPOSE OF A
LOT OF POWER.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4057
PRAGMATIC ASPECTS OF INQUIRY.
     
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> OBSERVATIONS ABOUT THE MANNER IN WHICH PEOPLE SEARCH FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
WHICH THEY KNOW OR BELIEVE TO EXIST. ANALYSES <Organization>LANGUAGE</Organization> AND THE DEVELOPMENT OF
A SEMANTIC THEORY THAT WOULD HELP EXPLAIN THE PROCESS OF INQUIRY; DEMONSTRATES
THAT EVEN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> STRAIGHTFORWARD USES OF <Organization>LANGUAGE</Organization> AS AUTHORS&apos; NAMES AND
CITATIONS ARE VERY COMPLEX <Organization>LINGUISTIC</Organization> PHENOMENA; ANALYSES <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> METHODS USED
IN THE CONDUCT OF INQUIRY; AND IDENTIFIES AND <Organization>CONSIDERS</Organization> THE MAJOR CONSEQUENCES
OF THE PRAGMATIC THEORY OF INQUIRY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4058
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE OCCASION OF THE 75TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE <Organization>FRENCH LIBRARIANS ASSOCIATION</Organization>
(<Organization>ABF</Organization>)&apos; A RETROSPECTIVE VIEW.
     
A SURVEY PREPARED FOR THE 1981 CONFERENCE, DESCRIBING THE ORIGINAL
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF THE ASSOCIATION DES BIBLIOTHECAIRES FRANCAIS (<Organization>ABF</Organization>) AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>SUBSEQUENT DEVELOPMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>ACHIEVEMENTS</Organization>. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>HOW</Organization> THE
PROFESSION WAS FIRST ORGANISED, THE ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PROGRAMMES,
INTERNATIONAL <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS AND THE
DEVELOPMENT OF SPECIALIST SECTIONS <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE <Organization>ABF</Organization>. THROUGHOUT <Organization>ITS</Organization> HISTORY, THE
<Organization>ABF</Organization> HAS CONSISTENTLY STRIVEN TO ACHIEVE THE GOALS OF THE ORIGINAL FOUNDERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4059
WILLIAM C. MILNER AND <Organization>MARITIME</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE FORMATIVE YEARS OF <Location>CANADA</Location>&apos;S <Organization>MARITIME LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
EFFORTS TO ORGANISE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>MARITIME</Organization> STATES 1918-24.
CONCENTRATES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE WORK OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> 2ND PRESIDENT WILLIAM C. MILNER, WHO
ULTIMATELY FAILED TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN NOVA SCOTIA OR <Organization>NEW</Organization> BRUNSWICK.
REASONS FOR THE FAILURE WERE ECONOMIC AND POLITICAL CIRCUMSTANCES THOUGH SOME
REASONS WERE DUE TO MILNER HIMSELF.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4060
THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN EDUCATION, STANDARDS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
<Organization>SUPPORT SERVICES</Organization> FOR MEMBERS.
     
EMPHASISES THE MAJOR <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN THE
EXCHANGE OF MATERIALS AMONG <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE EXCHANGE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OF
<Organization>IMPORTANCE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> OPERATION OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE EDUCATION OF
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> AND MEDICAL-RELATED LIBRARIANS AND DEVELOPMENT OF STANDARDS AND
GUIDELINES. POSES SOME OF THE <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> RELATED TO EACH OF THESE <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> AND
ROLES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4061
THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF THE PERSATUAN PERPUSTAKAAN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location> (<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF
<Location>MALAYSIA</Location>) IN <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> LEADERSHIP IN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>.
     
(MA DISSERTATION). THE PERSATUAN PERPUSTAKAAN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location> (PPM) WAS INAUGURATED
<Organization>ON</Organization> 25 MAR 55 AS THE <Organization>MALAYAN LIBRARY GROUP</Organization>, AND IT MARKED THE EARLIEST ATTEMPT
TO FORM AN ASSOCIATION <Organization>BY</Organization> LIBRARIANS IN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location> (<Organization>THEN</Organization> MALAYA) AND SINGAPORE.
PPM HAS ASSUMED THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF THE LEADER OF THE MALAYSIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION.
<Organization>EXAMINES</Organization> THE STYLE OF LEADERSHIP, QUESTIONING <Organization>ITS</Organization> EFFICACY AND
PROFESSIONALISM. ATTEMPTS TO DETERMINE THE STRENGTHS AND WEAKNESSES OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION VIS-A-VIS THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> WHICH PPM CAN PLAY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4062
THREE PIOUS HOPES.
     
GREETING OF THE INCOMING PRESIDENT TO THE SOCIETY OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> ARCHIVISTS <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> 44TH ANNUAL MEETING, <Location>CINCINNATI</Location>, OHIO, 3 OCT 80, EXPRESSING 3 &apos;PIOUS
HOPES&apos;: (1) THAT MEMBERS OF THE SOCIETY WILL VOICE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FEELINGS STRONGLY TO
COUNCIL AND OFFICERS; (2) THAT THE SOCIETY CAN THINK CONSTRUCTIVELY ABOUT THE
ROLES OF THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND ELECTED OFFICERS; AND (3) THAT ATTENDANCE
WILL BE GOOD <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SOCIETY&apos;S NEXT ANNUAL MEETING IN <Location>BERKELEY</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4063
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ETHICS OF THE LIBRARIAN <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE VIEWPOINT OF EDUCATION
AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
     
<Organization>SOCIALIST LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> <Organization>AIM</Organization> TO IMPROVE THE EDUCATIONAL LEVEL OF THE PEOPLE
IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> SUBJECTS, TO PROVIDE SOUND COMMUNIST <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND TO <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> THE
<Organization>FURTHER</Organization> GROWTH OF <Organization>SOCIALIST SOCIETY</Organization>. THE EDUCATION AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF LIBRARIANS
MUST, THEREFORE, BE IN ACCORDANCE WITH THESE OBJECTIVES. THE LIBRARIAN HAS A
RESPONSIBILITY TO SOCIETY TO PROVIDE FOR THE GROWING <Organization>DEMAND</Organization> FOR LITERATURE AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, TO <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> AND TO <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> <Organization>SOCIALIST EDUCATION</Organization>.
WHATEVER BRANCH OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK THE STUDENT WILL EVENTUALLY BE INVOLVED IN,
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SHOULD <Organization>NOT</Organization> BE RESTRICTED TO LEARNING FACTS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> METHODOLOGY
TECHNIQUES <Organization>BUT</Organization> SHOULD <Organization>ALSO</Organization> PROVIDE A FLEXIBLE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN THE SOCIO-ECONOMIC
ASPECTS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK. A LIBRARIAN SHOULD BE ABLE TO RELATE HIS PARTICULAR
<Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>ROLE</Organization> IN HIS BRANCH OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK TO THE <Organization>SOCIALIST</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEM AS A
WHOLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4064
TAKING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>OUT</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.
     
LACK OF STATUS IS AN <Organization>OLD</Organization> PROBLEM FOR LIBRARIANS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>ADOPTING</Organization> THE NAME OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MANAGER AND SWITCHING TO INDUSTRY DOES <Organization>NOT</Organization> APPEAR TO BE A
SOLUTION. SUGGESTS THAT <Organization>EXTENDING LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMMES TO 2 YEARS MAY
HELP <Location>US</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS TO SURVIVE. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN THE RELEVANCE OF
CURRICULA AND MORAL VALUES OF THE PROFESSION WITH THE DEVELOPMENT OF NEW
TECHNOLOGIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4065
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> REPORT 1980.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> REPORT, THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> IN A SERIES OF ANNUAL <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> SURVEYS, IS DESIGNED TO
<Organization>PRESENT STATISTICAL INFORMATION ABOUT LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location> AND CANADA.
THE REPORT IS DIVIDED INTO 5 SECTIONS&apos; FACULTY, <Organization>BY</Organization> RUSSELL E. BIDLACK;
STUDENTS, <Organization>BY</Organization> CAROL L. LEARMONT; INCOME AND EXPENDITURES, <Organization>BY</Organization> JAMES KRIKELAS;
<Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> ELSPETH POPE; <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> TIMOTHY W. SINEATH.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4066
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> <Organization>PACIFIC</Organization>.
     
A REVIEW OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> AND NON-PROFESSIONAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP IN
THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> <Organization>PACIFIC</Organization> WITH EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> PAPUA NEW GUINEA AND FIJI. INCLUDES
SECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> FOREIGN AID, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4067
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND CERTIFICATION IN HAWAII.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>GRADUATE SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>, UNIVERSITY OF HAWAII AND
EDUCATIONAL REQUIREMENTS FOR POSITIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF HAWAII AND IN
<Organization>STATE</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN HAWAII. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> BRIEFLY <Organization>LOOKS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SPECIALIST CERTIFICATE, A 2-YEAR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TECHNICIAN <Organization>COURSE</Organization>, EXPERIENCE
REQUIREMENTS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS AND <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> EDUCATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4068
YEARS OF THE DEPARTMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (1956-81).WOR
     
K DONE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE DEPARTMENT IS REVIEWED, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CONCERNING THE FACULTY
MEMBERS IS GIVEN BRIEFLY AND A BIBLIOGRAPHY OF PUBLICATIONS PRODUCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
DEPARTMENT IS PRESENTED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4069
SCHOOL ENTRANCE REQUIREMENTS AND THE TIMING OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization>
<Organization>PACIFIC</Organization>...A FEW THOUGHTS.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>UNESCO</Organization>/<Organization>IFLA PRE-CONFERENCE SEMINAR ON LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>,
<Location>MANILA</Location> 80. <Organization>CONSIDERS SCHOOL</Organization> ENTRANCE REQUIREMENTS AND THE TIMING OF EDUCATION
<Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE CONTEXT OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMMES IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES,
PARTICULARLY THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> <Organization>PACIFIC</Organization> AND OCEANIA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4070
LIBRARIANSHIP WILL BE MY VOCATION.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES LIBRARIANSHIP EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>ON SECONDARY SCHOOL</Organization> LEVEL. THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> PART IS
AN ANALYSIS OF THE RESULTS OF AN ENQUIRY, CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> AMONG 4TH YEAR STUDENTS
OF ONE OF THESE SCHOOLS, AS TO STUDENTS&apos; MOTIVATION, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization> TO
<Organization>THEM</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> WHICH THEY BASED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> DECISION TO SELECT <Organization>THIS</Organization> VOCATION, WHICH BRANCH
OF LIBRARIANSHIP THEY ARE INTERESTED IN, AND <Organization>HOW</Organization> THEY ASSESS <Organization>THEIR</Organization> 4 YEAR
<Organization>COURSE</Organization>. THE NEXT PART DEALS WITH PRACTICAL WORK IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN WHICH THE 4TH
YEAR STUDENTS TAKE PART. THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> IS COMPLETED <Organization>BY</Organization> FINAL EXAMINATIONS WHICH
COUNT AS EQUIVALENT TO FINAL EXAMS <Organization>AT</Organization> AN <Organization>ORDINARY SECONDARY SCHOOL</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4071
SOME COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> OF THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> BRANCH OF STUDY-LIBRARY <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>,
INTRAMURAL <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.
     
THE INTRAMURAL <Organization>COURSE</Organization> OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>HUMBOLDT UNIVERSITY</Organization> IN <Location>BERLIN</Location> LEADING TO
A DEGREE IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> LIBRARIANS WITH SCIENTIFICALLY
BASED KNOWLEDGE AND GOOD PRACTICAL CAREER <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. A STUDENT FOLLOWS COURSES
IN SUBJECTS RELATED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>, MARXISM AND LENINISM, AND FOREIGN
LANGUAGES, RUSSIAN, ENGLISH AND <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>. <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> PRACTICAL WORK PERIODS SPENT
IN <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MAKE UP PART OF THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization>.
LIBRARIAN STUDENTS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>ATTEND</Organization> COURSES IN SUBJECTS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>, TECHNOLOGY AND MODERN MEDIA TO ENABLE <Organization>THEM</Organization> TO FOLLOW <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
DEVELOPMENTS IN THESE FIELDS AFFECTING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEM. THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization>
LASTS 8 TERMS, THE LAST OF WHICH IS SPENT IN A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DOING PRACTICAL WORK
AND RESEARCHING FOR A THESIS FOR THE FINAL EXAMINATION. THE TITLE AWARDED TO
LIBRARIANS <Organization>ON</Organization> PASSING THE FINALS IS DIPLOMBIBLIOTHEKAR (DIPLOMA LIBRARIAN).
THE CO URSE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> TRIES TO STIMULATE STUDENTS TO INDEPENDENT <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WHILE <Organization>AT</Organization>
UNIVERSITY AND TO EXPAND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> KNOWLEDGE CONTINUOUSLY IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> CAREERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4072
TEACHING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>. THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>COLOGNE</Location> PROGRAMME.
     
<Organization>TRANSLATION</Organization> OF A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A 1980 SEMINAR IN <Location>WARSAW</Location> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE PROFESSOR
OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> COLOGNE, THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>GERMAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> TO INCORPORATE A
<Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> PROGRAMME OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> INTO <Organization>ITS</Organization> CURRICULA. FOR THE
PURPOSE OF INSTRUCTION, THE FIELD OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IS DIVIDED INTO 5
COMPONENTS&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> THEORY, <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP, <Organization>LIBRARY TECHNOLOGY</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
HISTORY, AND FORMS OF PUBLICATION AND MATERIALS USED FOR <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization>. THE
CONTENT AND STRUCTURAL SUBDIVISIONS OF THESE AREAS ARE DELINEATED, AND DETAILS
GIVEN OF THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> DEGREES AND ELECTIVE PROGRAMMES OFFERED, TOGETHER WITH
THE <Organization>CORRESPONDING UNIVERSITY</Organization> REGULATIONS. THE PROGRAMME IS SUGGESTED AS A
<Organization>MODEL</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> TEACHING IN <Location>GERMANY</Location> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COUNTRIES. FOR
COMPARISON THE FUNDAMENTAL ELEMENTS COMPRISING THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
PROGRAMME <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>LOS ANGELES</Location> ARE APPENDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4073
<Organization>ON</Organization> SOME <Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization> AND PRACTICAL ASPECTS OF THE <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY <Organization>WITHIN</Organization>
THE INTRAMURAL <Organization>COURSE</Organization> OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.
     
<Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY IS DIVIDED INTO 7 THEMATIC GROUPS&apos; <Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization>
FUNDAMENTAL PRINCIPLES OF BIBLIOGRAPHY; <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization>
LITERATURE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND METHODS OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> ACTIVITY; HISTORIC
DEVELOPMENT OF BIBLIOGRAPHY; <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> LEVEL OF <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY; <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>
LEVEL OF SCIENTIFIC BIBLIOGRAPHY; <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> LEVEL OF RECOMMENDATORY BIBLIOGRAPHY
IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> AND USSR; AND THE BIBLIOGRAPHY OF BIBLIOGRAPHY. THESE 7 THEMES
ARE CLOSELY LINKED AND INTERSECT IN MANY AREAS ESPECIALLY IN THE CASE OF THE
BIBLIOGRAPHY OF BIBLIOGRAPHY, WHICH OFTEN ACCOMPANIES <Organization>OTHER</Organization> THEMES. THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization>
IN BIBLIOGRAPHY IS A BALANCED MIXTURE OF THEORY AND PRACTICE. IT IS IMPORTANT
THAT STUDENTS SHOULD BE EDUCATED TO THE <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> LEVEL OF BIBLIOGRAPHY AS IT
EXISTS IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> AND USSR. THE <Organization>TIME</Organization> ALLOTTED TO THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> IS <Organization>NOT</Organization>
<Organization>ADEQUATE</Organization> AND STUDENTS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> INDEPENDEN TLY WHICH REQUIRES A GOOD
KNOWLEDGE OF LANGUAGES AS MUCH OF THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> LITERATURE IS IN RUSSIAN AND
ENGLISH.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4074
SUMMARY PROCEEDINGS OF A <Organization>SYMPOSIUM</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> EDUCATING LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENTISTS TO PROVIDE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES TO BLIND AND PHYSICALLY
HANDICAPPED <Organization>INDIVIDUALS</Organization>.
     
PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>SYMPOSIUM</Organization> HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> SAN FRANCISCO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
COMMUNICATIONS CENTER, 2-4 JULY 81. &apos;A HISTORY OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>
FOR THE BLIND AND PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> JIM MCGINNIS; &apos;RESULTS OF AN
ATTITUDINAL SURVEY&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> HENRY DEQUIN AND SYLVAI FAIBISOFF; &apos;INCORPORATING
INSTRUCTION FOR THE BLIND AND HANDICAPPED <Organization>INDIVIDUALS INTO LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>
CURRICULUMS&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> GERALD JAHODA; &apos;<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES FOR
HANDICAPPED <Organization>INDIVIDUALS</Organization>: THE <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization>
HARRY MCCLASKEY; &apos;INDEPENDENCE FOR <Organization>DISABLED</Organization> PERSONS <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE CONTEXT OF
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> DISABILITIES&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> ELEANOR BISCOE; &apos;<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES FOR
BLIND AND PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED <Organization>INDIVIDUALS</Organization> IN <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> LESLIE
ELDRIDGE; &apos;A MENU OF SUGGESTIONS TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS THAT COULD ENHANCE THE
CAPABILITIES OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> PROFESSIONALS TO SERVE <Organization>DISABLED</Organization> PEOPLE&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> CARMELA RUBY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4075
<Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN <Location>EUROPE</Location>.
     
OVERVIEW OF <Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN <Location>EUROPE</Location> PRESENTING A FRESH PERSPECTIVE <Organization>ON</Organization> US
PRACTICE. THE VERY ANTIQUITY OF THE <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> <Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> PROFESSION HAS SEEN <Organization>ITS</Organization>
CONSTANT TRANSFORMATION IN RESPONSE TO <Organization>CHANGING</Organization> <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
CONDITIONS. EUROPEANS, MORE THAN AMERICANS, <Organization>TRADITIONALLY</Organization> STRESSED THE
ARCHIVIST&apos;S DUAL RESPONSIBILITY AS CUSTODIAN AND INTERPRETER OF THE <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization>
RECORD. <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> ARCHIVISTS SHOULD <Organization>NOT</Organization> SLAVISHLY IMITATE THE PRACTICES OF
<Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COUNTRIES, <Organization>BUT</Organization> RATHER GARNER THE INSIGHTS BROADER THAN AN EXCLUSIVELY
AMERICAN-ORIENTED DISCUSSION CAN PROVIDE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4076
TEACHING THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RESOURCES (TUIR) AND THE SCHOOLS OF
LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
REPLIES TO A SHORT QUESTIONNAIRE SENT TO 18 <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS INDICATE THAT
MOST INCLUDE SHORT OR <Organization>LONG</Organization> UNITS <Organization>ON</Organization> TEACHING THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RESOURCES
(TUIR), OR INTEGRATE TUIR INTO BROADER <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> AREAS. NOTES ARGUMENTS FOR AND
AGAINST TUIR. THE <Organization>FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> MAY LIE IN THE WIDER AREA OF COOPERATION
IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF INDEPENDENT LEARNING SKILLS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4077
<Organization>WORKSHOP ON NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION SCIENCE EDUCATION</Organization>,
<Location>NEWCASTLE</Location> UPON TYNE POLYTECHNIC, 13-16 APRIL 1981.
     
SESSIONS COVERED THE ASPECTS OF <Organization>INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY</Organization> TO BE INCLUDED IN THE
SYLLABUS, <Organization>PRESTEL</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>STAFF DEVELOPMENT</Organization>
AND <Organization>COURSE</Organization> <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> AND EXPECTATIONS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION. REVIEWS
THE WORK OF THE <Organization>MICROELECTRONICS EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMME AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> CENTRE IN
<Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> FOR THE FAMILIARISATION OF SCHOOLCHILDREN WITH COMPUTER TECHNIQUES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4078
THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> TEACHING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
     
ARGUES THAT <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BECOME THE PIVOT OF CHANGE IN <Location>US</Location>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND THAT BECAUSE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization>, A <Organization>NEW</Organization> LEVEL OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN
<Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> CONTROL IS URGENTLY NEEDED. SUGGESTS A
<Organization>NEW</Organization> APPROACH TO TEACHING WHICH WOULD INVOLVE&apos; THE DEVELOPMENT OF TEACHING
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; THE MERGER OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOL <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>; AND THE
NURTURING OF REALISTIC, GOAL ORIENTATED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN A PRACTICAL SETTING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4079
IMPORTANT POINTS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.
     
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> FORMS PART OF THE <Organization>SUBJECT GROUP</Organization> COLLECTIONS/CATALOGUES IN
THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Organization>COURSE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>HUMBOLDT UNIVERSITY</Organization> IN <Location>BERLIN</Location>. THE
<Organization>SUBJECT GROUP</Organization> IS STUDIED IN THE 2ND YEAR AND ORAL EXAMINATIONS IN THESE
SUBJECTS TAKE PLACE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE 4TH AND 6TH SEMESTER. <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
<Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> KNOWLEDGE CONCERNING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS, <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> AND
MAINTENANCE. THE MAIN <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> DIVISIONS ARE&apos; HISTORY OF COLLECTIONS; THEORY OF
COLLECTIONS; ACQUISITION OF COLLECTIONS; <Organization>REVISION</Organization> OF COLLECTIONS; AND CARE AND
MAINTENANCE OF COLLECTIONS. THE HISTORY OF COLLECTIONS CONCENTRATES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>GERMAN</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE BEGINNING OF THE 20TH CENTURY <Organization>THEN</Organization> WORLD WAR II AND
THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>COLLECTION ACQUISITION</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> UP TO THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>.
THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> IS <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> ACQUISITION. STUDENTS <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IN
DEPTH THE <Organization>BASIC ACQUISITION</Organization> PRINCIPLES OF <Organization>TYPICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>&apos; A
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, A DISTRICT <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, A
TOWN AND DISTRICT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND A TRADE UNION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4080
FURNISHING INTRAMURAL STUDENTS WITH KNOWLEDGE, QUALIFICATIONS AND SKILLS IN
THE FIELD OF <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>.
     
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> REPRESENTS THE FOUNDATION OF SYSTEMATIC CATALOGUES AND
PLAYS AN IMPORTANT PART IN <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> FORM RELATING TO CONTENT
AND IDEOLOGY DEPENDS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE LEVEL OF DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> AND SOCIETY
WHICH IT REFLECTS. IT IS NECESSARY TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IT <Organization>FROM</Organization> AN <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> POINT OF
VIEW. <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> STUDYING THE SUBJECTS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> AND <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization>
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> STUDENTS ARE ENABLED TO UNDERSTAND THE METHODOLOGICAL BASIS OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> AND TO EVALUATE IT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A MARXIST-LENINIST POINT OF
VIEW. <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> RELEVANT IN THE CASE OF TERMINOLOGY FOR A <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>
OR A THESAURUS. STUDENTS ARE <Organization>INFORMED</Organization> ABOUT <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>
AND FOLLOW THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE 15TH
CENTURY TO THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> SITUATION IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>. THEY ARE MADE AWARE OF THE
NEED TO INVOLVE THEMSELVES IN THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>CLASSIFICATION SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4081
SELECTING AND PROMOTING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>NETWORKS</Organization> <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> AND KEY WORKS.
     
REPORTS A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> THAT RESULTED IN A <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> PARADIGM AND A 31-ITEM LIST OF
KEY SUPPORTING LITERATURE FOR A 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> <Organization>COURSE</Organization> IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>NETWORKS</Organization>.
THE ASSUMPTION <Organization>UNDERLYING</Organization> THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WAS THAT THERE IS A SYMBIOTIC RELATIONSHIP
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> GOALS AND KEY LITERATURE. THE PARADIGM AND LIST WERE
DEVELOPED EMPLOYING THE HEURISTIC METHOD, A SYSTEMATIC LITERATURE SEARCH,
SELECTED TEACHING STRATEGIES, AND OBSERVATIONS OF STUDENT RESPONSES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4082
SURVEY OF <Organization>ONLINE</Organization> <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> INSTRUCTION IN SCHOOLS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.
     
SUMMARISES THE RESULTS OF A SURVEY OF <Organization>ON-LINE SEARCHING EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
PRACTICES IN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> SCHOOLS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>. THE MAJOR
OBJECTIVE OF THE SURVEY WAS TO OBTAIN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CONCERNING COURSES THAT
COVERED THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ON-LINE TECHNICAL PROCESSING SYSTEMS</Organization> FOR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
SERVICES, <Organization>COURSE</Organization> CONTENT AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS OF CONSCIOUSNESS RAISING
INSTRUCTION AS WELL AS <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> INSTRUCTION, <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>, PHYSICAL
<Organization>FACILITIES</Organization>, AND OPINIONS OF FACULTY REGARDING THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF INSTRUCTION IN
<Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4083
SOUND RECORDINGS AS SOURCES OF MUSICAL HISTORY.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>IAML</Organization> ANNUAL CONFERENCE, 1-7 JULY 79, <Location>SALZBURG</Location>.
<Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> PERSPECTIVE <Organization>ON</Organization> ANALOGIC RECORDING OF ACOUSTICAL PHENOMENA <Organization>FROM</Organization>
EDISON&apos;S PHONOGRAPH TO MODERN HI-FI EQUIPMENT. ONLY THOSE SOURCES WHICH OFFER
A RECORDING OF REAL SOUND <Organization>HAVE</Organization> THE <Organization>SAME</Organization> <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> STATUS AS <Organization>WRITTEN</Organization> OR
PRINTED SOURCES. AS <Organization>SUCH</Organization>, THE EDUCATION OF MUSIC HISTORIANS AND MUSIC
LIBRARIANS SHOULD INCLUDE THE <Organization>SCHOLARLY</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> AND EVALUATION OF RECORDINGS, SO
THAT STUDENTS MAY LEARN <Organization>HOW</Organization> TO DATE RECORDS. ACOUSTICAL KNOWLEDGE OF THE
PRODUCTION, TRANSMISSION AND RECORDING OF SOUND IS INDISPENSABLE KNOWLEDGE FOR
THE MUSICOLOGIST WHO DOES <Organization>NOT</Organization> WISH TO IGNORE MUSIC&apos;S MOST IMPORTANT RECENT
SOURCES-RECORDINGS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4084
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE LATER EMPLOYMENT POSSIBILITIES OF <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> LIBRARIANS IN A UNIVERSITY
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
     
OWING TO THE <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> EXPANSION IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> OF <Organization>STANDARDISED UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CONSISTING OF A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND BRANCHES IN UNIVERSITY
DEPARTMENTS, <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> ARISEN IN THE LAST 10 YEARS CONCERNING THE
<Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>, DIRECTION AND <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROCEDURE <Organization>CORRESPONDING</Organization> TO THE
EXTENDED FUNCTIONS AND DIMENSIONS OF THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE INSTITUTE OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> SHOULD ENSURE THAT <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> LIBRARIANS RECEIVE APPROPRIATE
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> TO ALLOW <Organization>THEM</Organization> TO COPE WITH THE WORK DEMANDED OF <Organization>THEM AT UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> WILL INCLUDE&apos; <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> PROCESSING; WORK WITH <Organization>USERS</Organization>;
PUBLICISING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STOCK, ESPECIALLY <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> HERITAGE COLLECTIONS; ACTIVITY
IN HALLS OF RESIDENCE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; <Organization>COORDINATING</Organization> WORK <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> SECTIONS
OF THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; <Organization>LIBRARY TECHNOLOGY</Organization>; STORAGE AND MAINTENANCE.
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> GRADUATES SHOULD BE CAPABLE OF UNDERSTANDING THE <Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization> CONTENT
OF PRACTICA L PROBLEMS AND FINDING SOLUTIONS TO <Organization>THEM</Organization> WHICH CAN BE CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization>
IN PRACTICE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4085
CERTIFICATE IN LIBRARIANSHIP (USP).
     
PAPER PRESENTED TO THE <Organization>FIJI LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE &apos;MINI CONVENTION&apos;,
WESTERN <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, LAUTOKA, <Location>FIJI</Location>, 29 NOV 80. BRIEFLY <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE
HISTORY OF THE CERTIFICATE IN LIBRARIANSHIP COURSES FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS RUN
<Organization>BY</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> <Organization>PACIFIC</Organization>. <Organization>LOOKS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>FUNDING</Organization> <Organization>FROM FOREIGN AGENCIES</Organization>
AND <Organization>ASSISTANCE</Organization> WITH <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AS WELL AS THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF THE <Location>FIJI</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4086
A SURVEY-QUEBEC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY.
     
AN OUTLINE OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>QUEBEC</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 3 SECTIONS&apos; THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>
REGIME 1608-1760; THE BRITISH REGIME 1760-1867; AND CONFEDERATION 1867-1981.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4087
<Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP&apos; LESSONS FOR <Location>US</Location> IN THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> <Organization>PACIFIC</Organization>.
     
PART OF A REPORT SUBMITTED TO THE <Organization>LEAVE COMMITTEE</Organization>, UNIVERSITY OF THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization>
<Organization>PACIFIC</Organization> AND TO THE <Organization>ASIA FOUNDATION</Organization> WHO FINANCED AND ORGANISED A 10-WEEK <Organization>STUDY</Organization>
TOUR OF <Location>US</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 30 APR-22 JULY 80. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> FINDINGS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE TOUR THAT
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> RELEVANCE TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF THE <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> <Organization>PACIFIC</Organization>,
PARTICULARLY COOPERATION-RESOURCE-SHARING AND NETWORKING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 4088
THE CABINETS DE LECTURE IN <Location>PARIS</Location>, 1800-1850.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY SEMINAR VI &apos;<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> &amp; CULTURE&apos;, <Location>AUSTIN</Location>,
TEXAS, 19-22 MAR 80. <Organization>EXAMINES</Organization> THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF CABINETS DE LECTURE IN THE <Organization>EARLY</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT AND DIFFUSION OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>POPULAR</Organization> LITERATURE IN <Location>PARIS</Location> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1800 TO
