1
I AM INTERESTED IN THE IDENTIFICATION AND EVALUATION OF NOVEL
COMPUTER ARCHITECTURES, FOR INSTANCE, INCREASED PARALLELISM, BOTH
IN SIMD AND MIMD MACHINES.  I AM ALSO INTERESTED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ABOUT
<Organization>ASSOCIATIVE STORES</Organization> OR MEMORIES AND <Organization>ASSOCIATIVE</Organization> PROCESSORS.
COMPUTER ARCHITECTURES, <Organization>ASSOCIATIVE</Organization> PROCESSORS, <Organization>ASSOCIATIVE STORES</Organization>
<Organization>ASSOCIATIVE</Organization> MEMORY. #
2
I WOULD BE INTERESTED TO RECEIVE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> NON-USERS OF LIBRARIES,
INCLUDING <Organization>ANY</Organization> STUDIES OF WHO ARE NON-USERS AND WHY THEY ARE NON-USERS.
I WOULD BE <Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> GRATEFUL FOR PAPERS GIVING THE METHODOLOGICAL
APPROACHES USED IN THESE STUDIES AND THE RESULTS OBTAINED.
NON-USE, LIBRARY <Organization>USE</Organization>, USER STUDIES. #
3
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>COMPUTER DOCUMENTATION SYSTEMS</Organization> FOR CHEMICAL PATENTS.
I WOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> EITHER PUBLICALLY AVAILABLE
<Organization>SYSTEMS OR ON IN-HOUSE SYSTEMS</Organization>. CHEMISTRY, CHEMICAL, PATENTS. #
4
I WOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE <Organization>ANY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF JOURNALS
IN LIBRARIES (<Organization>ANY</Organization> TYPES OF LIBRARY), BOTH CURRENT AND BACK ISSUES.
I AM ALSO INTERESTED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE WAYS IN WHICH LIBRARIES
HAVE COPED WITH CUTS IN PERIODICALS BUDGETS.
PERIODICALS, JOURNALS, LIBRARIES, USER STUDIES, CUTS IN PUBLIC LIBRARIES,
ACADEMIC LIBRARIES, UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES, POLYTECHNIC LIBRARIES,
<Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> LIBRARIES. #
5
MY DISSERTATION IS AN OVERVIEW OF NEWS DATABASES, LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
AVAILABILITY, CONTENT, SCOPE AND USEFULNESS OF WHAT IS CURRENTLY
AVAILABLE.  IT WILL INCLUDE AN EXAMINATION OF USER GROUPS, BOTH AS
PERCEIVED AND IN REALITY.  MORE SPECIFICALLY, I SHALL CARRY OUT A BRIEF
EXAMINATION OF THE HISTORY OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF NEWS DATABASES,
STARTING WITH THE <Organization>NEW YORK TIMES <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> BANK</Organization> AND <Organization>ENDING</Organization> WITH THE MOST
RECENT DEVELOPMENTS <Organization>AT</Organization> REUTERS. NEWS, NEWSPAPERS, NEWS DATABASES, <Organization>REUTERS</Organization>,
NEXIS, TEXTLINE, <Organization>NEW YORK TIMES INFORMATION BANK</Organization>, FINTEL, DATASOLVE,
WORLD REPORTER. #
6
MY DISSERTATION IS <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARY OUTREACH FOR THE <Organization>CHINESE COMMUNITY</Organization>
IN <Location>SHEFFIELD</Location> BUT I WOULD BE INTERESTED IN LIBRARY OUTREACH FOR <Organization>ANY</Organization>
RACIAL OR ETHNIC GROUPS.  LIBRARY OUTREACH, BOOK DEPOSIT COLLECTIONS,
ETHNIC MINORITIES, <Organization>CHINESE</Organization>, RACIAL GROUPS, ETHNIC GROUPS, LIBRARY
SERVICES FOR <Organization>MULTI-CULTURAL SOCIETY</Organization>. #
7
I WOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SECURITY OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
IN DATABANKS OR DATABASES.  SECURITY, PRIVACY, CONFIDENTIALITY,
PROTECTION OF DATA OR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, RIGHTS OF ACCESS. #
8
I AM INTERESTED IN THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>
OF LIBRARIANS, IN PARTICULAR <Organization>ANY</Organization> IN SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AVAILABLE TO
QUALIFIED LIBRARIANS RATHER THAN EDUCATION <Organization>AT</Organization> LIBRARY SCHOOLS.  IN
SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COULD BE GENERAL OR IN ONE PARTICULAR AREA OF
LIBRARIANSHIP, E.G. <Organization>COMPUTERISED RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS</Organization>.  <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
EDUCATION, IN SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>. #
9
I AM INTERESTED IN THE EXTENT TO WHICH LIBRARIES ARE CHARGING FOR
SERVICES.  THIS REFERS TO PUBLIC LIBRARIES IN PARTICULAR THOUGH I WOULD
BE INTERESTED IN OTHER LIBRARIES ALSO.  I WOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE
PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> CHARGING FOR <Organization>ANY SERVICE</Organization> THE LIBRARY OFFERS, <Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> ONLINE
SEARCHING.  I AM INTERESTED IN MANAGEMENT OF CHARGING AND THE PHILOSOPHY
BEHIND IT, I.E. WHETHER ALL THE SERVICES SHOULD BE FREE. CHARGING
POLICIES, FEES FOR SERVICES. #
10
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROVISION OF CURRENT AWARENESS
BULLETINS, <Organization>ESPECIALLY SDI SERVICES</Organization> IN <Organization>ANY</Organization> INSTITUTION, E.G. ACADEMIC
LIBRARIES, INDUSTRY, AND IN <Organization>ANY</Organization> SUBJECT FIELD.  SDI, SELECTIVE
DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, CURRENT AWARENESS BULLETINS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
BULLETINS. #
11
MY DISSERTATION IS CONCERNED WITH A HISTORY OF THE <Location>LIVERPOOL</Location> LYCEUM, A
SUBSCRIPTION LIBRARY.  POSSIBLE <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> TERMS FOR GENERAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>ON</Organization> SUCH LIBRARIES WOULD BE CIRCULATING LIBRARIES, SUBSCRIPTION LIBRARIES
PROPRIETARY LIBRARIES OR UNDER THE NAME OF THE LIBRARY ITSELF, <Location>LIVERPOOL</Location>
LYCEUM. #
12
MY DISSERTATION IS <Organization>ON</Organization> SUBJECT INDEXING FOR AN ORAL HISTORY COLLECTION,
MORE PRECISELY BY SAMPLING FROM THE 350 CASSETTES <Location>SHEFFIELD</Location> <Location>CITY</Location>
LIBRARIES HAVE RECORDED IN THE <Location>CITY</Location>, INTERVIEWING ELDERLY RESIDENTS.
I AM COMPARING THE FEASIBILITY OF A FACETED, MANUAL SCHEME <Organization>ON</Organization> CARDS,
AND AUTOMATED INDEXING, KWIC OR <Organization>ASI</Organization>, <Organization>USING</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY&apos;S PRIME
550 COMPUTER. SUBJECT INDEXING, ORAL HISTORY, AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIALS. #
13
I AM DOING A STUDY OF THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S CHRISTIAN FELLOWSHIP FROM A
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ANGLE. I AM LOOKING FOR LITERATURE WHICH REFLECTS A
DISTINCTLY CHRISTIAN VIEW OF LIBRARIANSHIP, PARTICULARLY PRIOR TO 1973.
ANYTHING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>HISTORICAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S CHRISTIAN
FELLOWSHIP WOULD BE OF INTEREST. ALSO COVERAGE OF THE GROUP IN THE
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL PRESS</Organization> SINCE 1973, INCLUDING THEIR PRONOUNCEMENTS AND VIEWS
OF MEMBERS AND NON-MEMBERS OF CHRISTIAN ACTIVITY AND ATTITUDES IN THE
PROFESSION (<Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> SUBJECTS LIKE ETHICS, CENSORSHIP, SELECTION ETC.).
CHRISTIAN, EVANGELICAL, ETHICS, CENSORSHIP, LIBRARIAN&apos;S CHRISTIAN
FELLOWSHIP, LCF. #
14
I AM INTERESTED IN COGNITIVE MODELS OF LIBRARY <Organization>USE</Organization>. WHAT STUDIES OR
ARTICLES ARE THERE LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> THE PSYCHOLOGY OF LIBRARY AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>, I.E. STRATEGIES OF SEEKING, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND THE <Organization>WAY</Organization>
ITS USEFULNESS IS PERCEIVED. <Organization>USE</Organization> OF LIBRARIES, LIBRARY MATERIALS, USER
BEHAVIOUR, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SEEKING BEHAVIOUR OR <Organization>USE</Organization>, USEFULNESS,
PSYCHOLOGY OF LIBRARY AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>, LIBRARY USER, USER
SATISFACTION. #
15
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>ANY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> SUBSTRUCTURE SEARCHING OF CHEMICAL
FILES, I.E. STRUCTURAL ACCESS TO DATABASES OF CHEMICAL STRUCTURES. I
WOULD BE <Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> INTERESTED IN <Organization>COMPUTERISED SYSTEMS</Organization>. CHEMICAL
STRUCTURES, COMPUTERIZED DATABASES, CHEMISTRY, CHEMICAL, SUBSTRUCTURE. #
16
MY DISSERTATION CONCERNS CONSUMER <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES AND THE PROVISION
OF CONSUMER <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND ADVICE IN THE <Location>SHEFFIELD</Location> AREA. THE
DISSERTATION WILL INCLUDE MONITORING AND EXAMINING TV, RADIO, VARIOUS
PUBLICATIONS IN <Location>SHEFFIELD</Location> AND LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AVAILABLE IN
LIBRARIES, ADVICE CENTRES AND ELSEWHERE. IT DOES NOT INCLUDE OBLIGATORY
DISCLOSURE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (LABELLING, SAFETY ETC.). THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS
EXPECTED TO INCLUDE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN ORDER THAT THE CONSUMER MAY DECIDE
WHICH GOODS AND SERVICES TO BUY, AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> REGARDING PROTECTION
<Organization>AT</Organization> THE POINT OF SALE AND REDRESS AND ENFORCEMENT OF RIGHTS ETC.
CONSUMER <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, CONSUMER PROTECTION, CONSUMER ADVICE, CONSUMER
EDUCATION, MERCHANDISE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. #
17
I AM INTERESTED IN THE ROLE OF OFFICE AUTOMATION IN DECISION-SUPPORT
SYSTEMS, <Organization>MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>, INCLUDING ACCESS TO IN-HOUSE
AND REMOTE TEXT OR BIBLIOGRAPHICAL REFERENCE DATABASES. <Organization>DECISION</Organization> SUPPORT
SYSTEMS, <Organization>MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>, OFFICE AUTOMATION. #
18
I WOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE <Organization>ANY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> TELECOMMUNICATIONS
NETWORKS. THIS COULD INCLUDE BOTH WIDE AREA NETWORKS (MESH) AND LOCAL
AREA NETWORKS (BUS, RING). TELECOMMUNICATIONS, LOCAL AREA NETWORKS,
WIDE AREA NETWORKS, DATA TRANSMISSION, DISTRIBUTED PROCESSING,
DISTRIBUTED ROUTING, PACKET-SWITCHED NETWORKS, MESH, BUS, RING. #
19
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICY, E.G. NATIONAL (INCLUDING THOSE OF
NATIONAL &apos;CENTRES&apos; AND &apos;FOCI&apos;), SCIENTIFIC AND TECHNOLOGICAL (IN
MEDICINE, INDUSTRY, AGRICULTURE). SOURCES MAY INCLUDE VARIOUS
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> BODIES, PARLIAMENTARY COMMITTEES, COUNTERPARTS IN OTHER
COUNTRIES, SUCH AS THE VARIOUS PRESIDENTIAL COMMITTEES IN THE <Location>USA</Location>,
NATIONAL CENTRES, AND, OF COURSE, THOSE OF INTERNATIONAL &apos;CONFERENCES&apos;
AND BODIES SUCH AS <Organization>UNESCO</Organization>. I AM MORE INTERESTED IN IMPLEMENTATION THAN
IN PAPER DECLARATIONS WHICH ARE NOT BACKED UP BY SUFFICIENT RESOURCES.
PLANNING, AIMS AND OBJECTIVES, GOVERNMENT, INTERNATIONAL, POLICY,
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICY, NATIONAL POLICIES, COOPERATION. #
20
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>ANY</Organization> PAPERS <Organization>ON EXPERT SYSTEMS</Organization> OR <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> BASED
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>, <Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>.
<Organization>EXPERT SYSTEMS</Organization>, <Organization>KNOWLEDGE BASED INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>, ARTIFICAL
INTELLIGENCE, MACHINE INTELLIGENCE, <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> BASED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS</Organization>. #
21
MY DISSERTATION IS CONCERNED WITH THE &apos;STATE-OF-THE-ART&apos; OF ONLINE
SEARCHING. THIS WILL INCLUDE EXAMINATION OF <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> STRATEGY FORMULATION,
LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> THE EDUCATION AND EXPERIENCE OF THE SEARCHER IN RELATION TO
STYLE AND PERFORMANCE. ALSO, THE IMPORTANCE OF THE PRE-SEARCH INTERVIEW.
I SHALL BE LOOKING ONLY <Organization>AT</Organization> ONLINE BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATABASES WITH SPECIAL
REFERENCE TO SOCIAL SCIENCE DATABASES. ONLINE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>,
DATABASES. #
22
I WOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE <Organization>ANY</Organization> PAPERS <Organization>ON PARTICIPATIVE MANAGEMENT</Organization>
IN PUBLIC LIBRARIES. THERE HAS BEEN SOME WORK DONE <Organization>ON</Organization> PARTICIPATIVE
MANAGEMENT IN NATIONAL AND ACADEMIC LIBRARIES. MANAGEMENT, PARTICIPATIVE
MANAGEMENT, WORKERS CONTROL, WORKER PARTICIPATION. #
23
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>DECISION SUPPORT SYSTEMS</Organization> (MANAGEMENT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SYSTEMS) BOTH <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> AND NON-COMPUTERISED BUT <Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> IN
THE <Location>UK</Location>. I AM INTERESTED IN CASE STUDIES OF THEIR BEHAVIOURAL,
PSYCHOLOGICAL AND SOCIOLOGICAL IMPACT. <Organization>DECISION SUPPORT SYSTEMS</Organization>,
<Organization>MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>. #
24
I AM INTERESTED IN ALMOST ANYTHING TO DO WITH AUTOMATIC <Organization>DOCUMENT</Organization>
CLASSIFICATION: <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> STRATEGIES FOR HIERARCHICAL AND NON-HIERARCHICAL
CLUSTERS, CLUSTERING ALGORITHMS, THE CREATION OF CLUSTER REPRESENTATIVES,
<Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> EXPERIMENTS <Organization>USING</Organization> CLUSTERED FILES AND MEASURES OF
INTER-DOCUMENT SIMILARITY. RELATED TO THIS IS AN INTEREST IN TERM
CLASSIFICATIONS, THEIR APPLICATION IN <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>, INTER-TERM SIMILARITIES
ETC. AUTOMATIC <Organization>DOCUMENT</Organization> CLASSIFICATION, CLUSTERS, CLUSTERING, TERM
CLASSIFICATIONS. #
25
ONE OF MY STUDENTS IS DOING A DISSERTATION <Organization>ON</Organization> BEST MATCH, OR NEAREST
NEIGHBOUR, <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> ALGORITHMS FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> IN <Organization>DOCUMENT RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS</Organization>.
ALMOST ANYTHING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE CALCULATION OF SIMILARITY COEFFICIENTS OR <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>ASSOCIATIVE</Organization>, I.E. MULTI-KEY, SEARCHING, WHETHER FOR BEST MATCH OR PARTIAL
MATCH, <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> WOULD BE OF <Organization>USE</Organization> HERE.
NEAREST NEIGHBOUR, BEST MATCH, SIMILARITY COEFFICIENTS, PARTIAL MATCH. #
26
MY DISSERTATION TOPIC IS CENTERING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>INTERIOR DESIGN</Organization> OF LIBRARIES
AND HOW THIS AFFECTS THE USERS. IT MAY BE ANGLED TOWARDS CHANGING IDEAS
OF LIBRARY INTERIORS CONNECTED WITH THE CHANGING ROLE OF THE LIBRARY.
I WILL BE LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COLOUR, LIGHTING, VENTILATION,
FURNISHINGS, ETC. LIBRARY BUILDINGS, LIBRARY INTERIORS. #
27
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROVISION IN EDUCATIONAL COMPUTING: A
SURVEY OF TEACHERS <Organization>USING</Organization> MICROCOMPUTERS IN THE CLASSROOM. I AM LOOKING
<Organization>AT COMPUTER EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>ON</Organization> A NATIONAL AND LOCAL BASIS (NORTH
NOTTS. AREA) SO I AM LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> ALL NATIONAL AND LOCAL ORGANISATIONS
THAT ARE PROVIDING SERVICES IN THIS FIELD AND ALSO LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS. TO COMPLEMENT THIS I AM CONDUCTING A POSTAL SURVEY
OF SCHOOLS IN NORTH NOTTS. AND ANALYSING THE RESULTS. MICROCOMPUTERS,
EDUCATION, EDUCATIONAL COMPUTING, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROVISION, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
TECHNOLOGY, SCHOOLS, PRIMARY, SECONDARY, <Organization>MICROELECTRONICS EDUCATION</Organization>
PROGRAMME (MEP), COMPUTER ASSISTED LEARNING (CAL), COMPUTER ASSISTED
INSTRUCTION (CAI), COMPUTER MANAGED LEARNING (CML), COMPUTER
MANAGED INSTRUCTION (CMI). #
28
I WOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE <Organization>ANY</Organization> PAPERS DESCRIBING FREE TEXT
<Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> PACKAGES LIKE CAIRS, ASSASIN, STATUS, DECO OR STAIRS,
<Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> IF THE FEATURES OF DIFFERENT PACKAGES ARE COMPARED, OR IF
THE IMPLEMENTATION AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF A SYSTEM IS DESCRIBED.  I AM <Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization>
INTERESTED IN PACKAGES FOR MINIS AND MICROS AND IN <Organization>ANY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
BETWEEN FREE TEXT <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> PACKAGES AND <Organization>DATABASE</Organization> MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS.
MINICOMPUTERS, MICROCOMPUTERS, <Organization>DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS</Organization>, FREE TEXT
<Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> #
29
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND LESS DEVELOPED COUNTRIES. THIS WOULD
INCLUDE THE PARTICULAR PROBLEMS OF LESS DEVELOPED COUNTRIES NOW, AND
THEIR EXPECTED FUTURE PROBLEMS (SUCH AS ELECTRONIC PUBLISHING). ALSO,
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICIES OF LESS DEVELOPED COUNTRIES AND THE FACTORS
WHICH MAY AFFECT THEIR PRACTICAL IMPLEMENTATION. WHAT ARE THE PRIORITIES
AND SUGGESTED PRACTICAL STAGES IN THE SOLUTION OF PROBLEMS AND
IMPLEMENTATION OF POLICIES. LESS DEVELOPED COUNTRIES, UNDER DEVELOPED
COUNTRIES, DEVELOPING COUNTRIES. #
30
I WOULD BE INTERESTED IN <Organization>ANY INFORMATION ON ONLINE EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
<Organization>USING COMPUTER</Organization> BASED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AIDS FOR ONLINE SEARCHING. I AM ALSO
INTERESTED IN THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF END USERS.
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, EDUCATION, ONLINE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>, COMPUTER ASSISTED
INSTRUCTION, TEACHING PACKAGES, END USERS. #
31
I AM CURRENTLY ENGAGED IN A RESEARCH PROJECT STUDYING CONFLATION
ALGORITHMS FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> PURPOSES AND THE REPRESENTATION
OF WORDS BY CHARACTER SUBSTRINGS. ANYTHING TO DO WITH STEMMING,
ABBREVIATION, TRUNCATION OR SEGMENTATION OF WORDS WOULD BE OF INTEREST,
AS WOULD LINGUISTIC STUDIES OF PREFIXES AND SUFFIXES, DESCRIPTIONS OF
STRING SIMILARITY MEASURES, AND OF DIGRAMS, TRIGRAMS, TETRAGRAMS ETC.
THUS, THIS INVOLVES THE CONFLATION OF MORPHOLOGICALLY SIMILAR WORDS
SO THAT THEY ARE REPRESENTED BY UNIQUE SUBSTRINGS.
CONFLATION ALGORITHMS, CHARACTER SUBSTRINGS, STEMMING, ABBREVIATION,
TRUNCATION, SEGMENTATION, PREFIXES, SUFFIXES, FRAGMENTATION,
MORPHOLOGICAL SEGMENTATION. #
32
I AM INTERESTED IN <Organization>INFORMATION ON ONLINE SEARCH SERVICES</Organization> IN <Organization>ANY</Organization> TYPE OF
ACADEMIC LIBRARY, BUT <Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> POLYTECHNICS. I WOULD BE PARTICULARLY
INTERESTED TO RECEIVE PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> HOW THE SERVICE IS RUN.
POLYTECHNIC, UNIVERSITY, <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>, ACADEMIC LIBRARY, ONLINE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>, <Organization>SEARCH SERVICES</Organization>. #
33
MY DISSERTATION IS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROVISION OF AUDIO-VISUAL RESOURCES IN
POLYTECHNIC LIBRARIES. I INTEND TO SEND A QUESTIONNAIRE TO ALL 30
POLYTECHNICS AND TO VISIT SIX AND BASE MY STUDY <Organization>ON</Organization> THESE SIX.
I WOULD ALSO BE INTERESTED TO RECEIVE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> AUDIO-VISUAL
RESOURCES IN <Organization>ANY</Organization> TYPE OF ACADEMIC LIBRARY, NOT JUST POLYTECHNICS.
POLYTECHNIC, POLYTECHNIC LIBRARIES, ACADEMIC LIBRARIES,
UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES, <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> LIBRARIES, AUDIO-VISUAL, RESOURCE
CENTRES, RESOURCE COLLECTIONS, <Organization>NON-BOOK MEDIA</Organization>. #
34
I SHOULD BE PLEASED TO RECEIVE <Organization>ANY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE EVALUATION
OF PRECIS (PRESERVED CONTEXT INDEXING SYSTEM). #
35
I AM INTERESTED IN ALMOST ANYTHING TO DO WITH OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> AVAILABLE, SUCH AS LIBRARIES. I AM INTERESTED
IN BOTH OCCUPATIONAL NURSES AND OCCUPATIONAL DOCTORS.
HEALTH, OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH, NURSES, DOCTORS, MEDICINE. #
