Document 5850
ULRICH&apos;S REFERENCES TO MICROFORM AVAILABILITY.

ATTEMPTING TO <Organization>USE</Organization> ULRICH&apos;S INTERNATIONAL PERIODICALS DIRECTORY AS A GUIDE TO
THE AVAILABILITY OF MICROFORM OF MANY JOURNALS CAN BE MISLEADING. A QUICK
SURVEY OF 25 TITLES LISTED IN THE GUIDE TO MICROFORMS IN PRINT SHOWS THAT
ULRICH&apos;S LISTED AVAILABILITY FOR ONLY 30.76%. THE SURVEY ALSO BROUGHT OUT THAT
SOME OUTSTANDING <Location>US</Location> GOVERNMENT TITLES ARE NOT LISTED IN ULRICH&apos;S.
********************************************
Document 5851
GOVERNMENT PUBLICATIONS.

ANNOTATED BIBLIOGRAPHY OF <Location>US</Location> GOVERNMENT PUBLICATIONS ON <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> AND HEALTH
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> SEVERAL REVIEWERS. ITEMS INCLUDE 2ALCOHOL <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
WORLD, JOURNAL OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL CANCER INSTITUTE</Organization>, <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> REPORTER,
SCHIZOPHRENIA BULLETIN1, AND 2WORLD <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> FORUM1.
********************************************
Document 5852
A SURVEY OF <Organization>ARCHITECTURE</Organization> <Organization>MAGAZINES</Organization>.

REVIEWS, <Organization>BY</Organization> ACTIVE MEMBERS OF THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>ARCHITECTURE SCHOOL</Organization>
LIBRARIANS AND/OR THE <Organization>ART LIBRARIES SOCIETY</Organization> OF <Location>NORTH AMERICA</Location>, OF 54
<Organization>ARCHITECTURE</Organization> JOURNALS. JOURNALS FALL INTO SEVERAL <Organization>BASIC</Organization> SUBJECT CATEGORIES,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> A <Organization>PRIMARY GROUP</Organization> OF STANDARD PROFESSIONAL JOURNALS, <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> AND
NON-AMERICAN; <Location>US</Location> STATE AND <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>ARCHITECTURE</Organization> PERIODICALS; AND INTERIOR
DECORATION AND DESIGN <Organization>MAGAZINES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5853
THE IMPORTANCE OF ANNOTATIONS AND REVIEWS IN <Organization>BOOK</Organization> SELECTION.

BRIEFLY EXAMINES WHAT <Organization>BOOK</Organization> SELECTION, REVIEWS AND ANNOTATIONS ARE, AND
SUMMARISES THE IMPORTANCE AND SHORTCOMINGS OF ANNOTATIONS AND REVIEWS IN <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
SELECTION.
********************************************
Document 5854
COMPUTER-TO-COMPUTER COMMUNICATION IN THE ACQUISITION PROCESS.

THE WORK OF <Organization>BISAC</Organization> (<Organization>BOOK INDUSTRY SYSTEMS ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization>) IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> AND
<Organization>PROMOTING ON-LINE ACQUISITION VIA DIRECT COMPUTER</Organization>-TO-COMPUTER SYSTEMS AND IN
PRODUCING A STANDARD FORMAT FOR DATA INTERCHANGE IS DESCRIBED.
********************************************
Document 5855
<Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> ORDER <Organization>TRANSMISSION</Organization>.

<Organization>ONLINE COMPUTER LIBRARY CENTER</Organization> (<Organization>OCLC</Organization>) PLANS TO <Organization>USE</Organization> THE <Organization>BISAC</Organization> (<Organization>BOOK</Organization> INDUSTRY
<Organization>SYSTEMS ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization>) DATA <Organization>TRANSMISSION</Organization> PROTOCOL AND FIXED DATA FORMAT
IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> ACQUISITIONS <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. ISBNS WILL BE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO IDENTIFY
<Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> AND STANDARD ADDRESS NUMBERS (<Location>SAN</Location>), DEVELOPED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>BISAC</Organization>, TO IDENTIFY
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> VENDORS, PUBLIC, ACADEMIC AND AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5856
<Organization>ONLINE</Organization> ORDERING. A COMPARISON OF DOCUMENT SUPPLIERS.

DESCRIBES A STUDY <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> TYPES OF DOCUMENTS HAVE BEEN SIMULATANEOUSLY
ORDERED <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> FROM 9 SELECTED DOCUMENT SUPPLIERS. <Organization>CONSIDERABLE</Organization> DIFFERENCES
AS TO COST, SPEED OF DELIVERY AND RELIABILITY OF DELIVERY HAVE BEEN OBSERVED.
THIS IS RELATED TO THE TYPE OF DOCUMENT, THE COUNTRY OF PUBLICATION AND THE
SUBJECT CONTENT OF THE MATERIAL. <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> ORDERING AS A ROUTINE IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ACQUISITION WORK IS DISCUSSED.
********************************************
Document 5857
THE DEUTSCHE STAATSBIBLIOTHEK AS A CENTRE FOR INTER-LIBRARY LOANS AND UNION
CATALOGUING.

IN THE 1970S THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOUNDED A <Organization>SPECIAL INSTITUTE</Organization> TO COPE WITH
INTER-LIBRARY LOANS AND UNION CATALOGUING. THE INSTITUTE&apos;S WORK HAS INCLUDED
ACCELERATING ORDERING PROCEDURES, ORGANISING COPYRIGHT DEPOSIT AND
INTERNATIONAL INTER-LOAN SCHEMES, IMPROVING STAFF QUALIFICATIONS, SOLVING
LEGAL PROBLEMS CONNECTED WITH THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> PROCESSING, KEEPING
<Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> UP TO DATE AND <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> A <Organization>COURIER SERVICE</Organization>. SINCE 1978 STATISTICS
HAVE BEEN COMPILED ON THE 400 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> INVOLVED IN <Organization>TELETEXT SERVICES</Organization>. <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
PROJECTS INCLUDE COMPUTERISATION OF THE <Organization>CENTRAL UNION</Organization> CATALOGUE AND OF THE
INDEX OF FOREIGN PERIODICALS AND SERIALS. THE INSTITUTE PLAYS AN ACTIVE PART
IN INTER-LIBRARY COOPERATION BETWEEN THE COMMUNIST COUNTRIES.
********************************************
Document 5858
TRANSPORT SCHEMES FOR INTERLIBRARY LENDING&apos; THE <Location>UK</Location> EXPERIENCE.

<Organization>WHERE POSTAL SERVICES</Organization> ARE SLOW, UNRELIABLE OR EXPENSIVE, DEDICATED TRANSPORT
SCHEMES FOR INTERLENDING PURPOSES SHOULD BE CONSIDERED; <Organization>THEIR</Organization> USEFULNESS WILL
VARY FROM 1 COUNTRY TO ANOTHER, ACCORDING TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> CIRCUMSTANCES. IN THE <Location>UK</Location>,
FEASIBILITY STUDIES WERE FOLLOWED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SETTING UP OF TRANSPORT SCHEMES IN A
NUMBER OF THE <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> REGIONS, AND A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> SCHEME LINKING THE REGIONS
WAS ENVISAGED. TRANSPORT SCHEMES WERE NOT CONSIDERED WORTHWHILE IN THE LARGER
REGIONS WITH LESS INTERLENDING ACTIVITY. A METHODOLOGY FOR SETTING UP SCHEMES
HAS BEEN DEVISED. THE PRESENT TRANSPORT SCHEMES ARE FINANCIALLY COMPETITIVE
AND LIKELY TO REMAIN SO. <Location>UK</Location> EXPERIENCE MIGHT <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> A FRAMEWORK FOR ASSESSING
POTENTIAL SCHEMES IN OTHER COUNTRIES.
********************************************
Document 5859
ON CHARGING FOR <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>.

COMMENTS ON A REPORT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE DELEGATION FOR <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROVISION&apos; 2<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> ANY PRICE&apos; ON CHARGING FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES1, IN WHICH IT IS SUGGESTED THAT INTERLENDING FROM <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD BE CHARGED <Organization>AT</Organization> A STANDARD RATE PER LOAN, DESPITE THE FACT THAT
CHARGING FOR <Organization>TRADITIONAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> WAS EXCLUDED FROM THE COMMISSION&apos;S
REMIT. 1 REASON FOR CONSIDERING CHARGES NONETHELESS IS THE INCREASING SCOPE
AND COST OF INTERLENDING. ANOTHER IS THE CHANGE IN THE BUDGETING OF
INSTITUTIONS FOR <Organization>TERTIARY EDUCATION</Organization> WHICH HAS TRANSFERRED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ALLOCATIONS
FROM THE STATE TO THE INSTITUTIONS; <Organization>THESE</Organization> ARE TEMPTED TO ACHIEVE SAVINGS
<Organization>THROUGH</Organization> CHARGES ON INTERLENDING. THE REPORT REGARDS INTERLENDING OF LITTLE
IMPORTANCE TO PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IT DOES NOT ATTEMPT TO CALCULATE THE COST OF
INTERLENDING, NOR THE COST OF ADMINISTERING A <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF CHARGES.
********************************************
Document 5860
INTERLIBRARY LENDING IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.

INTERLENDING IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> IS BASED ON A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR THE SUPPLY
OF SCHOLARLY LITERATURE AND A <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR SUPPLYING A WIDER RANGE OF
MATERIAL MAINLY BETWEEN PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. 725,000 REQUESTS WERE MADE IN 1979.
MOST REQUESTS ARE SATISFIED <Organization>THROUGH UNION</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUES OR PRINTED UNION</Organization> LISTS.
IN ADDITION TO THE 12 PROVINCIAL CENTRES, THE 13 <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> SUPPORT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
HAVE A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> ROLE IN THE <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> SUPPLY <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>; THEY RECEIVED 131,708
REQUESTS IN 1980 AND SATISFIED 27%. A <Organization>SINGLE CENTRE</Organization> IN EACH REGION IS
RECOMMENDED. A SURVEY OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> SHOWED THAT 40% OF ALL REQUESTS
<Organization>AT</Organization> THIS LEVEL CAME FROM ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 40% FROM <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND 20%
FROM PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. MOST REQUESTS ARE FOR SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (60%), FOR
ENGLISH LANGUAGE MATERIAL (55% OF ALL REQUESTS; 70% OF REQUESTS FOR JOURNALS),
AND FOR MORE RECENT MATERIAL (65% PUBLISHED IN THE LAST 10 YEARS). THE
SATISFACTION RATE WAS 76% (HIGHER FOR REQ UESTS SENT TO UNION <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>): 1/2
WERE SUPPLIED IN 2 WEEKS, 2/3 IN 3 WEEKS <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> GAPS IN JOURNAL COVERAGE
WERE IDENTIFIED. AN <Organization>ON-LINE NATIONAL UNION</Organization> CATALOGUE WILL BE AVAILABLE IN 1984
AND WILL BE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO DISTRIBUTE REQUESTS MORE EVENLY BETWEEN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
SPECIFIC GRANTS TO SUPPORT THE INTERLENDING FUNCTION IN MAJOR SUPPLYING
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WILL STILL BE NECESSARY, AND CHARGES SHOULD BE MADE. <Organization>IMPROVED UNION</Organization>
<Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> ARE ENVISAGED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> LEVEL ALSO.
********************************************
Document 5861
A PROPOSAL FOR <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AN INTERLENDING <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Location>CAIRO</Location>
<Location>CITY</Location>, <Location>EGYPT</Location>.

(<Organization>PHD DISSERTATION-PITTSBURGH UNIVERSITY</Organization>). A QUESTIONNAIRE SURVEY, INTERVIEWS,
VISITS, AND A LITERATURE ANALYSIS WERE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO EXPOSE THE FACTORS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE PRESENT STATE OF INTERLIBRARY LOAN IN <Location>CAIRO</Location>. A <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR FORMAL
INTERLIBRARY LENDING WHICH CAN BE MODIFIED FOR OTHER <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES IS
PROPOSED.
********************************************
Document 5862
<Organization>PLANNING INTERLENDING SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES.

BASED ON REPORTS DESCRIBING THE EXTENT AND DEVELOPMENT OF INTERLIBRARY LOAN
SYSTEMS IN SEVERAL OF THE <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES, A COMPOSITE IS DRAWN OF THE
DIFFICULTIES AND PROBLEMS WHICH ARISE IN THE <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> STAGES AND EXECUTION OF
<Organization>SUCH SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>THESE</Organization> COUNTRIES. FINANCIAL PROBLEMS, AS WELL AS PROBLEMS OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> POLICY, AND THE REALISTIC POSSIBILITIES CONNECTED WITH THE LITERATURE
SUPPLY AND CORRESPONDING NEED FOR AN INTERLIBRARY LOAN PROGRAMME IN <Organization>THESE</Organization>
COUNTRIES ARE POINTED OUT. ATTENTION IS ALSO GIVEN TO THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. CONSIDERATIONS WHICH SHOULD BE MADE
IN FINDING REALISTIC SOLUTIONS TO <Organization>THESE</Organization> PROBLEMS ON A LONG-TERM BASIS CONCLUDE
THE REPORT.
********************************************
Document 5863
CORE COLLECTIONS OF JOURNALS FOR <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> INTERLENDING PURPOSES.

CENTRALISED <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> PROVISION FOR INTERLENDING PROVIDES A <Organization>BETTER SERVICE</Organization> THAN
DECENTRALISED PROVISION <Organization>BUT</Organization> CAN BE DIFFICULT AND EXPENSIVE TO IMPLEMENT, SO
PARTIAL CENTRALISATION SHOULD BE CONSIDERED. JOURNALS ARE SPECIALLY SUITED TO
<Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> COLLECTIONS. CONCENTRATION OF DEMAND ON A RELATIVELY SMALL NUMBER OF
JOURNALS MEANS THAT COLLECTIONS OF 7,000-8,000 TITLES COULD SUPPLY 80% OF
DEMAND AND 2,000 TITLES 50% IN MANY COUNTRIES. THERE ARE HOWEVER PROBLEMS IN
IDENTIFYING JOURNALS FOR CORE COLLECTIONS. BIBLIOMETRIC METHODS CAN BE SHOWN
TO BE OF LITTLE HELP. ANALYSIS OF DEMAND <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LENDING
DIVISION INDICATES THAT RANK LISTS ARE NOT VERY STABLE OVER TIME; AND VARIOUS
FACTORS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS LANGUAGE OR STAGE OF ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT WILL CAUSE
VARIATIONS THAT MAKE IT DIFFICULT TO APPLY CORE LISTS BETWEEN COUNTRIES
(THOUGH IT MAY BE POSSIBLE TO ALLOW FOR DIFFERENCES, ESPECIALLY IF CORE LISTS
BASED ON <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> DEMAND COULD BE OBTAINED FROM A NUMBER OF <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization>
COUNTRIES). ONCE A CORE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> HAD BEEN SET UP, IT WOULD HAVE TO ATTRACT
SUFFICIENT REQUESTS TO MONITOR DEMAND AND ADJUST ITS CONTENTS ACCORDINGLY. IF
A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS NOT POSSIBLE, LIMITATION TO CERTAIN SUBJECTS HAS
ADVANTAGES. AS COLLECTIONS GROW, ADDITIONAL JOURNALS WILL BE CHEAPER TO
ACQUIRE, THOUGH THE <Organization>UNIT COST</Organization> PER REQUEST WILL STILL BE <Organization>LOWER</Organization> FOR THE JOURNALS
IN HEAVIEST DEMAND. CONCLUDES THAT THE CONCEPT OF CORE COLLECTIONS IS SOUND,
<Organization>BUT FURTHER DATA</Organization> ARE NEEDED <Organization>BEFORE</Organization> THE PRACTICAL PROBLEMS OF SETTING UP <Organization>SUCH</Organization>
COLLECTIONS CAN BE PROPERLY ASSESSED.
********************************************
Document 5864
<Organization>ONLINE INTERLIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>&apos; AN INFORMAL COMPARISON OF FIVE SYSTEMS.

5 <Organization>AUTOMATED NORTH AMERICAN INTERLOAN SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED IN TERMS OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
EFFECTIVENESS FOR LOCATING <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> AND COMMUNICATING REQUESTS. 2 OF THE
SYSTEMS ARE PRIMARILY <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>, 1 OF WHICH, <Organization>ONLINE COMPUTER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
CENTER (<Organization>OCLC</Organization>), HAS A SOPHISTICATED INTERLIBRARY LOAN SUBSYSTEM, AND THE OTHER,
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NETWORK (RLIN), HAS A FORMATTED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MESSAGE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>USED</Organization> TO TRANSMIT INTERLOAN REQUESTS. COMPUTER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SYSTEM INC</Organization>. AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COMPUTER <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> ARE PRIMARILY DESIGNED FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
<Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization>, AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> HAS BEEN EXTENDED FOR RESOURCE SHARING.
UNIVERSITY OF <Location>TORONTO</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTOMATION <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> (UTLAS), IS PROMOTED AS AN
<Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> WITH <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> ACCESS TO A UNION CATALOGUE AND
AVAILABILITY OF AN <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> MAILBOX TO COMMUNICATE REQUESTS.
********************************************
Document 5865
WEEDING: THE PROFESSIONAL PRACTICE OF GETTING RID OF DEAD WOOD IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>.

ATTEMPTS TO GIVE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSIONALS&apos; DEFINITION OF &apos;WEEDING&apos;, DISCUSSES
REASONS FOR AND AGAINST WEEDING OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS, AND SUGGESTS POSSIBLE
SOLUTIONS TO ARGUMENTS AGAINST WEEDING, AND WHAT CAN BE DONE WITH WEEDED STOCK.
********************************************
Document 5866
<Organization>BOOK</Organization> THEFT AND <Organization>BOOK</Organization> MUTILATION IN A <Organization>LARGE URBAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

A QUESTIONNAIRE STUDY OF WHY STUDENTS IN A <Organization>LARGE US URBAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> STEAL AND
MUTILATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BOOKS AND PERIODICALS IDENTIFIED PSYCHOLOGICAL AND
SOCIOLOGICAL MOTIVATIONAL FACTORS IN THE STUDENTS. CIRCUMSTANTIAL REASONS FOR
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> DEVIANT BEHAVIOUR WERE NOT SIGNIFICANT IN THIS STUDY. THE INDIVIDUAL
STUDENT&apos;S PERCEPTIONS OF PRESSURE FOR SOURCES IN THE ACADEMIC WORLD SEEMED TO
MOTIVATE MUTILATION AND THEFT REGARDLESS OF THE QUALITY OF AVAILABLE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE. PEER APPROVAL FOR <Organization>THESE</Organization> BEHAVIOURS WAS NOT APPARENTLY ASSUMED.
********************************************
Document 5867
A SELECTIVE BIBLIOGRAPHY ON THE CONSERVATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIALS.

SELECTION OF ENTRIES IS INTENDED TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THAT IS MOST USEFUL TO
LIBRARIANS AND ARCHIVISTS CONCERNED WITH CONSERVATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND ARCHIVAL
MATERIALS.
********************************************
Document 5868
THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> PRESERVATION PROBLEM AS SEEN <Organization>AT</Organization> HARVARD.

PAPER PRESENTED AS A LECTURE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>TORONTO</Location>, 27 FEB 81.
DESCRIBES WAYS IN WHICH <Organization>HARVARD UNIVERSITY</Organization> LIBRARIANS HAVE TACKLED THE
PROBLEMS OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> PRESERVATION FROM THE 17<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY TO THE PRESENT DAY.
DISCUSSES&apos; THE PROTECTION OF BOOKS FROM PEOPLE; EFFORTS MADE TO PROTECT BOOKS
FROM ENVIRONMENTAL AND NON-HUMAN HAZARDS; REPAIR AND RESTORATION; THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
COOPERATIVE MICROFILMING; THE <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization> AND PUBLICATION OF MICROFILMS; AND
THE ADMINISTRATION OF PRESERVATION ACTIVITIES.
********************************************
Document 5869
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BINDING</Organization> AS A CONSERVATION MEASURE.

EXAMINES THE PROBLEM OF HOW LIBRARIANS CAN CHOOSE SUITABLE BINDINGS FOR BOOKS
MEANT FOR PERMANENT RETENTION IN THE ARCHIVAL <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>. DISCUSSES&apos; THE MAIN
FEATURES OF <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> TYPES OF COMMERCIAL <Organization>BINDING</Organization> CURRENTLY AVAILABLE; <Organization>BINDING</Organization>
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> CATEGORIES OF MATERIAL; <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>BINDING</Organization> OPTIONS WHICH BINDERS CAN
OFFER <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>CUSTOMERS</Organization>; EXAMINING VOLUMES ON <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RETURN FROM <Organization>BINDING</Organization>; AND
IN-HOUSE <Organization>BINDING</Organization> OPTIONS. CONCLUDES THAT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BINDING</Organization> CAN BE A CONSERVATION
MEASURE TO EXTEND THE LIFE OF THE VOLUME AND CONSERVE IT IF METHODS ARE
SENSIBLY SELECTED AND APPLIED, AND INDICATES THE MOST ACCEPTABLE METHODS FROM
A CONSERVATION VIEWPOINT.
********************************************
Document 5870
THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> HOUSE IN LARSBODA.

<Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> WAS THE CONTACT
BETWEEN THE BOOKBINDER, EDVARD HASSLER, AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, WHICH LED IN
1952 TO THE CREATION OF THE <Organization>JOINT BINDING SERVICE</Organization>. HASSLER HAS RECENTLY MOVED
TO <Organization>NEW</Organization> PREMISES IN LARSBODA, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> HIRES 4000 SQ.M. SPACE
FOR THE <Organization>BINDING SERVICE</Organization>. B. SKOLD DESCRIBES THE USES OF THIS SPACE AS STORE,
DISTRIBUTION AREA, OFFICES AND EXHIBITION HALL, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THE WORK OF THE SERVICE
IS DISPLAYED. E. HASSLER DESCRIBES THE HISTORY OF THE BINDERY FROM ITS START
IN 1902 AND ITS COOPERATION WITH THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> SINCE 1952. TODAY IT
BINDS 2.6 MILLION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> VOLUMES AND PREPARES 400,000 <Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization>&apos; VOLUMES.
THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDING IN LARSBODA HOUSES HASSLERBAND, WHICH IS AN UMBRELLA
ORGANISATION FOR 3 BINDERIES&apos; LIBREX, SAMBOK AND KNUT HASSLER.
********************************************
Document 5871
EVALUATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BINDINGS.

REVIEWS THE WORK OF THE <Organization>TESTING LABORATORY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY BINDING INSTITUTE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY</Organization>, WHICH IS THE STANDARD-PRODUCING BODY FOR
THE <Location>USA</Location>. DISCUSSES DECREASING BUDGETS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EFFECTS ON <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BINDING</Organization>
METHODS, ALTERNATIVE BINDINGS, COMPETITION AMONG <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BINDERS, <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
PERFORMANCE <Organization>TESTING</Organization>, <Organization>TESTING</Organization> EQUIPMENT, <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> EVALUATION OF METHODS,
SERVICES TO LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>NEW</Organization> SPECIFICATIONS FOR ALTERNATE <Organization>BINDING</Organization> METHODS.
********************************************
Document 5872
<Organization>BOOK</Organization> THEFTS AND MUTILATION IN <Organization>NIGERIAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

AFTER TRACING REPORTED INCIDENCES OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> THEFTS AND MUTILATION IN ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, DISCUSSES THE MANIFESTATIONS OF THE 2 ACTS IN THE 13 <Organization>NIGERIAN</Organization>
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. A TABLE DEPICTS THE EXTENT OF OCCURRENCE OF <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization>
SECURITY PROBLEMS IN <Organization>NIGERIAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5873
EFFECTIVE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF EXISTING SPACE IN ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION ANNUAL CONFERENCE, JUNE 81. EXAMINES SOME OF THE PROBLEMS
CONCERNED WITH THE EFFECTIVE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF STACK, STUDY AND SERVICE SPACE IN ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. CONSIDERS THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF WEEDING AND MICROFILMING AS WAYS OF
CONTROLLING STACK SPACE, AND SUGGESTS METHODS OF INCREASING UTILISATION OF
FLOOR SPACE. DISCUSSES THE IMPORTANCE OF THE PROVISION OF ADEQUATE STUDY
SPACE, AND DESCRIBES OPPORTUNITY WHICH THE INSTALLATION OF AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
<Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OFFERS FOR INCREASING THE EFFICIENT <Organization>USE</Organization> OF SERVICE
SPACE.
********************************************
Document 5874
<Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY RESERVE</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION AT DEPAUW UNIVERSITY</Organization>.

UNDERTAKEN TO DETERMINE IF THE PATTERN OF <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY RESERVE</Organization> COLLECTIONS
<Organization>FOUND AT OTHER COLLEGE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CONTINUES TO EXIST <Organization>AT</Organization> DEPAUW, THIS STUDY
<Organization>FOUND</Organization> THAT APPROXIMATELY 40% OF ALL THE RESERVE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> ITEMS NEVER
CIRCULATED DURING THE ENTIRE SEMESTER, AND THAT 33% OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
CIRCULATED ONLY 1-5 TIMES DURING THAT PERIOD. IT IS SUGGESTED THAT LIBRARIANS
EXAMINE <Organization>THEIR RESERVE</Organization> COLLECTIONS TO REDUCE THE AMOUNT OF TIME AND EFFORT
EXPENDED ON THEM, AND TO PREVENT THEM FROM DISCOURAGING MORE EXTENSIVE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> TABLES AND REFERENCES ARE PROVIDED. REPORT NOT
AVAILABLE FROM <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5875
<Organization>CIRCULATION SYSTEMS</Organization> PAST AND PRESENT.

REVIEWS THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>CIRCULATION SYSTEMS</Organization> SHOWING 2 AREAS OF CHANGE. THE
LIBRARIAN&apos;S PERCEPTION OF <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> HAS SHIFTED FROM A <Organization>BROAD SERVICE</Organization>
ORIENTATION TO A NARROW RECORD-KEEPING APPROACH AND RECENTLY BACK AGAIN. THE
<Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF <Organization>CIRCULATION SYSTEMS</Organization> HAS EVOLVED FROM MANUAL
SYSTEMS TO THE <Organization>ON-LINE SYSTEMS</Organization> OF TODAY. THE TRADE-OFFS AND DEFICIENCIES OF
<Organization>EARLIER SYSTEMS</Organization> IN RELATION TO THE <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE SERVICES</Organization> MADE POSSIBLE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Organization>ON-LINE COMPUTER</Organization> ARE <Organization>DETAILED</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5876
THE <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> MARKETPLACE&apos; ACTIVE AND HEATING UP.

SURVEYS THE MARKET FOR <Organization>COMPUTERISED CIRCULATION SYSTEMS</Organization> OVER THE PERIOD
1977-81. A FINAL TOTAL OF 11 SYSTEMS ARE COVERED AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS GIVEN FOR
THE NUMBER OF <Organization>CUSTOMERS</Organization> INSTALLING EACH <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, THE RANGE OF SIZES OF
<Organization>INSTALLED SYSTEMS</Organization> AND THE STATUS OF FUNCTIONS OF TURNKEY <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> VENDORS
AS OF 1 OCT, 81.
********************************************
Document 5877
AUTOMATION SUPPORT FOR <Organization>COLLECTION MANAGEMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>CONTROL</Organization>.

DISCUSSES THE AUTOMATION OF <Organization>CIRCULATION SYSTEMS</Organization> AND <Organization>INVENTORY</Organization> MANAGEMENT, WITH
REFERENCE TO EXPERIENCES IN THE DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF AN <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>LISTER HILL NATIONAL CENTER</Organization> FOR BIOMEDICAL
COMMUNICATIONS, <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF MEDICINE, BETHESDA, <Location>USA</Location>. DESCRIBES THE
AREAS OF AUTOMATION SUPPORT THAT WILL BE OF BENEFIT TO <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> MANAGEMENT
AND <Organization>CONTROL</Organization>, AND INDICATES THE EXTENT TO WHICH THIS PARTICULAR <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS
INCORPORATING AND <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> <Organization>THESE</Organization> AREAS.
********************************************
Document 5878
<Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> LOAN <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE STATE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN KOSICE.

SURVEYS THE IMPACT OF AND THE PROBLEMS CONNECTED WITH THE APPLICATION OF
AUTOMATION ON DAY TO DAY WORK <Organization>AT</Organization> THE STATE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (<Organization>SSL</Organization>) IN KOSICE.
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF PUNCHED TAPES FOR THE PREPARATION OF BIBLIOGRAPHIES, REPORTS,
ABSTRACTS AND DOCUMENTS FOR PUBLICATION PROVED VERY USEFUL. <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> TESLA RPP
16S WITH REAL TIME OPERATION IS BEING <Organization>USED</Organization> FOR THE PROCESSING OF LOANS. THE
ORGANISATION OF WORK CONNECTED WITH IT IS DESCRIBED IN DETAIL.
********************************************
Document 5879
<Organization>MICROCOMPUTER</Organization> BACKUP TO <Organization>ONLINE</Organization> <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization>.

<Organization>MICROCOMPUTER BACK-UP SYSTEMS</Organization> TO BE <Organization>USED</Organization> IN EVENT OF FAILURE OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
<Organization>MINICOMPUTER CIRCULATION SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE INVESTIGATED.
********************************************
Document 5880
<Organization>BASIC</Organization> BOOKS V. GNOMON: COPYRIGHT INTERPRETATION &apos;UNREASONABLE&apos;. LIBRARIANS
READ THE SETTLEMENT AS &apos;LAW&apos; AND UNDULY RESTRICT COPYRIGHT <Organization>USERS</Organization>.

DISCUSSES COPYRIGHT ISSUES RAISED IN THE <Location>US</Location> SUIT 2<Organization>BASIC</Organization> BOOKS V. GNOMON1 WITH
IMPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. STATEMENTS <Organization>BY</Organization> THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> HAVE CREATED THE ERRONEOUS IMPRESSION THAT THE TERMS OF THE
2GNOMON1 SETTLEMENT ARE LAW, CONCERNING ILLEGAL PHOTOCOPYING OF DOCUMENTS.
********************************************
Document 5881
LABORATORY NOTEBOOK STORAGE AND RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS.

DESPITE THE GENERAL CONCLUSION THAT LABORATORY NOTEBOOKS CONTAIN <Organization>VALUABLE</Organization> AND
<Organization>OFTEN NEEDED DATA</Organization>, THERE HAS BEEN RELATIVELY LITTLE DISCUSSION IN THE
LITERATURE ON THE DEVELOPMENT OF AN ADEQUATE STORAGE AND RETRIEVAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR
THEM. TO DETERMINE THE VARIOUS POSSIBILITIES OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, A SURVEY OF 83
FOOD SCIENCE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS CONDUCTED. 60% OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> EMPLOYED SOME KIND
OF A <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. 4 <Organization>DIFFERENT SYSTEMS</Organization> WERE IDENTIFIED; AND THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> THAT ALLOWED
ACCESS <Organization>BY</Organization> NOTEBOOK AUTHOR AND NOTEBOOK ACCESSION NUMBER WAS PREDOMINANT.
********************************************
Document 5882
CATALOGUING IN THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; DEVELOPMENT AND TENDENCIES.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO THE GERMAN LIBRARIANS CONFERENCE <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>REGENSBURG</Organization>, 9-13 JUNE 81. FOR ALPHABETICAL CATALOGUING, <Organization>REGENSBURG UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USES THE <Organization>RAK</Organization> RULES FOR ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> STREAMLINING WILL
BE CARRIED OUT HERE BECAUSE THE <Organization>BAVARIAN</Organization> STATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WILL SHORTLY JOIN THE
<Organization>BAVARIAN NEW UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; INTERLOAN <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. KEYWORD <Organization>USE</Organization> IS
STANDARDISED; A KEYWORD INDEX PUBLISHED EVERY 6 MONTHS ASSISTS IN UNIFYING
PRACTICE. ENGLISH KEYWORDS ARE <Organization>USED</Organization> FOR BIOLOGY AND PRE-CLINICAL MEDICINE,
GERMAN FOR OTHER SUBJECTS. <Organization>REGENSBURG UNIVERSITY</Organization>&apos;S OWN <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> SCHEME
IS <Organization>USED</Organization> HERE AND IN OTHER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE INTERLOAN SCHEME. SINCE 1974
<Organization>PRINTED</Organization> CATALOGUE VOLUMES HAVE BEEN REPLACED <Organization>BY</Organization> COM-PROCESS MICROFICHE, WHICH
MAY IN TURN BE REPLACED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> METHODS WHEN <Organization>THESE</Organization> HAVE BECOME CHEAPER.
ACCESS TO OTHER <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKS MAY SOON BE AVAILABLE <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
<Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> PROCESSING.
********************************************
Document 5883
<Organization>UNIT</Organization> TIME/COST STUDY OF THE CATALOGING <Organization>UNIT</Organization>, <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES DIVISION</Organization>,
<Location>TUCSON</Location> PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE 2ND OF 3 REPORTS IN A SERIES TO DETERMINE <Organization>UNIT</Organization> TIME AND COST ESTIMATES FOR
THE MAJOR OPERATIONS OF THE <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES DIVISION</Organization> OF THE <Location>TUCSON</Location> PUBLIC
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>DAILY</Organization> LOGS WERE RECORDED <Organization>BY</Organization> PERSONNEL IN THE CATALOGUING <Organization>UNIT</Organization> IN THE
SPRING OF 1978, AND THE DATA FORMS THE BASIS OF THIS REPORT. CATALOGUING
PROCEDURES ARE DISCUSSED AND A WIDE DIVERGENCE OF COSTS ARE DEVELOPED. ADDED
COPY CATALOGUING DONE PRIMARILY <Organization>BY</Organization> PARAPROFESSIONALS IS COMPARED TO ORIGINAL
CATALOGUING PERFORMED <Organization>BY</Organization> PROFESSIONALS. THE IMPACT OF MULTIPLE COPIES IS
DISCUSSED AS A FACTOR IN REDUCING <Organization>UNIT</Organization> COSTS, AND <Organization>DETAILED</Organization> APPENDICES ALLOCATE
TIME AND COSTS FOR PRINT AND NONPRINT MATERIALS. REPORT NOT AVAILABLE FROM
<Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5884
ALA FILING RULES.

A SHORT DESCRIPTION OF THE 2ALA FILING RULES1 IS GIVEN, TOGETHER WITH
COMMENTS, IN AN <Organization>EARLIER</Organization> ABSTRACT (81/5757).
********************************************
Document 5885
LINKING OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC UTILITIES</Organization> RECOMMENDED IN BATTELLE/CLR STUDY.

THE BATTELLE/CLR STUDY ANALYSED THE ECONOMIC AND SERVICE BENEFITS TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization> OF LINKING NETWORKS FOR 3 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OPERATIONS-SHARED <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
MONOGRAPH CATALOGUING, INTERLIBRARY LOAN, AND REFERENCE SEARCHING. CONCLUDES
THAT THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS, <Organization>OCLC</Organization>, INC., THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
NETWORK AND THE <Location>WASHINGTON</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK SHOULD DEVELOP <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> LINKS USING
AUTOMATIC TRANSLATION OF REQUESTS AND RESPONSES. OTHER RECOMMENDATIONS ARE
ALSO DISCUSSED.
********************************************
Document 5886
DESIGN SPECIFICATION OF THE BARR SMITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>
(BIBLION).

DESCRIBES THE OBJECTIVES AND PRESENTS A SYSTEMS OVERVIEW OF BIBLION-THE
<Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF THE BARR SMITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF
<Location>ADELAIDE</Location>. DISCUSSES&apos; THE LOCATION OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> AND HOLDINGS <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>;
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> NETWORK REFRESHER TAPE <Organization>INPUT</Organization>; THE RECORDING OF
<Organization>DETAILED HOLDINGS</Organization>; <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RETRIEVAL; <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> LIMITATION; AND PERFORMANCE
AND SUPPORT REQUIREMENTS.
********************************************
Document 5887
BIBLION&apos; THE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF THE BARR SMITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

DESCRIBES THE DEVELOPMENT, FEATURES AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF BIBLION-THE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF THE BARR SMITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>ADELAIDE</Location>.
BIBLION IS <Organization>USED</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization> CATALOGUE OF THE UNDERGRADUATE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>,
THE CATALOGUE OF MONOGRAPHS SELECTED FOR STORAGE, AND THE MEANS OF ACCESS TO
<Organization>ABN</Organization> (<Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> NETWORK) FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF ALL <Organization>ABN</Organization> FUNCTIONS
CURRENTLY AVAILABLE.
********************************************
Document 5888
IN LINE TO GET ON LINE.

IN JAN 80, AN AD HOC CONSORTIUM OF SOME 30 SMALL TO MEDIUM-SIZED COLLEGE AND
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS FORMED TO INVESTIGATE THE DEVELOPMENT OF A
REPLICATABLE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> PUBLIC ACCESS CATALOGUE. THE GROUP, CONDOC (CONSORTIUM TO
DEVELOP AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> CATALOG), CAME INTO EXISTENCE BECAUSE MANY SMALLER ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SAW <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> CATALOGUE REQUIREMENTS AS <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> TO THOSE OF
<Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. CONDOC ALLOWED THE POOLING OF EXPERTISE. ITS 1ST
MEETING TOOK PLACE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> MIDWINTER MEETING,
1980. DESCRIBES ITS WORK TO DATE.
********************************************
Document 5889
THESIS/DISSERTATION PROCESSING AND <Organization>OCLC</Organization>.

AS AN EXAMPLE OF THE IMPACT THAT <Organization>OCLC</Organization> CAN HAVE ON CATALOGUING PROCEDURES, AN
EXAMINATION OF THE HANDLING OF THESES AND DISSERTATIONS IN THE UNIVERSITY OF
ILLINOIS <Organization>AT</Organization> URBANA-CHAMPAIGN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DEMONSTRATES THAT <Organization>CONSIDERABLE SAVINGS</Organization>
CAN BE REALISED WITHOUT SACRIFICING OR ELIMINATING SEVERAL <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FILES WHICH
ARE <Organization>USED</Organization> EXTENSIVELY <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STAFF AND PATRONS WHILE MAKING THE MATERIALS
AVAILABLE FOR PATRON <Organization>USE</Organization> MUCH MORE QUICKLY.
********************************************
Document 5890
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKING IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>&apos; THE PAST IS FUTURE.

TAKES A CRITICAL LOOK <Organization>AT</Organization> PROPOSALS <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> TO
PRODUCE A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY NETWORK (<Organization>ABN</Organization>). THE LICENCE FOR A SOFTWARE
PACKAGE, DEVELOPED AND IMPLEMENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>WASHINGTON</Location> STATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, KNOWN AS
THE <Location>WASHINGTON</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK, WAS ACQUIRED IN 1980 AFTER <Organization>CONSIDERABLE</Organization>
<Organization>TESTING</Organization>. PUTS THE PROPOSALS IN THE BROADER CONTEXT IN WHICH THEY ARE SET. THEY
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> HAS 4 MAIN COMPONENTS&apos; <Organization>ON-LINE UNION</Organization> CATALOGUE; <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
SOURCE FILE; CATALOGUE PROCESSING; AND CATALOGUE <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization>. CONCLUDES THAT
THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> WILL NOT SUCCEED FOR ECONOMIC REASONS-IT BUNDLES WITH ITS OFFERINGS
A PROCESSING CAPABILITY WHICH IS ALREADY AVAILABLE ELSEWHERE <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>LOWER COST</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5891
<Organization>ABN</Organization> AND THE <Organization>ART</Organization> OF COST-EFFECTIVE CATALOGUING: THE CHALLENGE IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AUTOMATION FOR THE EARLY EIGHTIES.

THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> HAS RECEIVED PERMISSION TO DEVELOP AN
<Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> NETWORK (<Organization>ABN</Organization>), <Organization>BUT</Organization> NO EXTRA <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> HAVE BEEN
GRANTED FOR IT; THE SERVICE MAY THEREFORE NOT BE ABLE TO SERVE ALL ITS
POTENTIAL PARTICIPANTS AS QUICKLY AS SOME WOULD LIKE. SUGGESTS THAT <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
THE CREATION OF &apos;SERVICE CENTRE&apos; NETWORKS, AND WITHOUT THE NEED FOR A MAJOR
SUPPORTIVE INFRASTRUCTURE FROM THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE BENEFITS OF THE <Organization>ABN</Organization>&apos;S
EXISTENCE CAN BE BROUGHT TO A GREAT MANY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. SUGGESTS WAYS IN WHICH <Organization>ABN</Organization>
MAY BE <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> INTO A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> NETWORK WHICH WILL COORDINATE THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S INITIATIVES AND THE &apos;BOTTOM-UP&apos; DEVELOPMENTS WHICH HAVE ALREADY
TAKEN PLACE AND WILL CONTINUE TO TAKE PLACE.
********************************************
Document 5892
MARC FORMAT SIMPLIFICATION.

(SUMMARY OF A PAPER COMMISSIONED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TASK
FORCE ON <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>CONTROL</Organization>). EXAMINES THE NEED FOR THE MARC FORMAT TO BE
ABLE TO RESPOND TO FUTURE POSSIBLE REQUIREMENTS PARTICULARLY OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
CATALOGUING.
********************************************
Document 5893
ANATOMY OF THE MAIN ENTRY.

<Organization>BASIC</Organization> INTRODUCTION TO THE CONCEPT OF MAIN ENTRY IN CATALOGUING-THE NAME OR
TERM UNDER WHICH THE WORK IS PRIMARILY ENTERED BOTH ON A CATALOGUE CARD AND IN
A BIBLIOGRAPHY. DESCRIBES THE IMPRINT, COLLATION, PAGINATION, ILLUSTRATIONS,
SIZE AND NOTES AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RELATIONSHIP TO THE MAIN ENTRY IN CATALOGUING.
********************************************
Document 5894
THE GENERAL CATALOGUE OF <Organization>PRINTED</Organization> BOOKS, 1881-1981.

ON 30 APR 1881, GEORGE BULLEN, THE KEEPER OF <Organization>PRINTED</Organization> BOOKS, LAID <Organization>BEFORE</Organization> THE
TRUSTEES OF THE BRITISH MUSEUM THE 1ST <Organization>PRINTED</Organization> PART OF THE CATALOGUE OF BOOKS
IN HIS DEPARTMENT. 25 YEARS LATER, ON COMPLETION THE CATALOGUE OF 2 MILLION
ENTRIES BECAME AN ESSENTIAL REFERENCE WORK AS THE MOST <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> RECORD OF
<Organization>PRINTED</Organization> PUBLICATIONS IN <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> LANGUAGES. IN A MODIFIED FORM IT IS STILL IN
<Organization>USE</Organization> IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. PRESENTS A HISTORICAL REVIEW OF THE <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization> AND
DEVELOPMENT OF THE CATALOGUE FROM 1881 TO 1981.
********************************************
Document 5895
THE CARD CATALOG&apos; <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> ISSUES, READINGS AND SELECT BIBLIOGRAPHY.

40 CONTRIBUTIONS AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization> PROVIDING IN-DEPTH COVERAGE FOR LIBRARIANS NEEDING
TO DECIDE ON WHETHER AND WITH WHAT TO REPLACE THE CARD CATALOGUE. INCLUDES
CONSIDERATION OF COSTS, STAFF INVOLVEMENT AND THE EFFECTS ON <Organization>USERS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5896
<Organization>USER EDUCATION</Organization> FOR AN <Organization>ONLINE</Organization> CATALOG&apos; A WORKSHOP APPROACH.

FOR MORE THAN 6 YEARS, THE <Organization>OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE HAD PUBLIC
TERMINALS AVAILABLE FOR SEARCHING <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> (LCS), A FORMER
<Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> THAT IS EVOLVING INTO AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> CATALOGUE. PATRON
INSTRUCTION IN <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> HAS EXPANDED IN PARALLEL WITH THE EVOLUTION
OF LCS, MOVING FROM INFORMAL <Organization>PRINTED</Organization> INSTRUCTIONS TO A STANDARDISED 1 HOUR
WORKSHOP. A YEAR OF EXPERIENCE HAS SHOWN THE WORKSHOP TO BE A <Organization>VALUABLE</Organization> PART OF
THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; USER-EDUCATION PROGRAMME AND A PARTICULARLY SUITABLE APPROACH
FOR <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> CATALOGUE INSTRUCTION.
********************************************
Document 5897
ALIEN IN THE <Organization>READING</Organization> ROOM.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS IS REPLACING ITS CARD CATALOGUE WITH A <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization>
CATALOGUE. DESCRIBES THE REACTIONS OF A REFERENCE LIBRARIAN WHEN A TERMINAL
WAS <Organization>INSTALLED</Organization> IN THE <Organization>READING</Organization> ROOM. SEARCHING WAS SPEEDED UP, WITH THE
POSSIBILITY OF LIMITING SEARCHES TO CERTAIN DATES, LANGUAGES OR PLACES OF
ORIGIN. DISCUSSES THE COMPONENT <Organization>WORD</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> WHICH RESPONDS TO A COMMAND TO
FIND WORDS ANYWHERE IN THE TITLE, SUBJECT <Organization>HEADINGS</Organization>, AUTHOR&apos;S NAME, SERIES, OR
NOTES ON A <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> ENTRY, THUS ENABLING LIBRARIANS TO SOLVE THE PROBLEM
OF INCOMPLETE CITATIONS. IN MAY 77 A <Organization>COMPUTER CATALOGUE CENTRE</Organization> WAS ESTABLISHED
FOR THE PUBLIC NEAR THE MAIN CATALOGUE, WHICH HAS PROVED EXTREMELY POPULAR. A
<Organization>USER</Organization> SURVEY SHOWED THAT COMPUTER-ASSISTED INSTRUCTION IS NEEDED. FUTURE PLANS
ARE OUTLINED.
********************************************
Document 5898
COM CATALOGUE EXPERIENCE <Organization>AT</Organization> ANU.

CHARTS THE HISTORY OF <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> CATALOGUING <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WHICH BEGAN IN 1974. MARC TAPES WERE OBTAINED FROM THE
<Organization>AUSTRALIAN MARC RECORD SERVICE</Organization> AND THE CATALOGUING OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> BOOKS FOR THE LIFE
<Organization>SCIENCES LIBRARY ONTO COMPUTER RECORDS</Organization> WAS SET TO BEGIN IN 1976. FROM 1 JAN 81
ALL CATALOGUING WILL BE IN AACR 2 AND AUSMARC III.
********************************************
Document 5899
COMPARING <Organization>FICHE</Organization> AND FILM&apos; A TEST OF SPEED.

SPEEDS OF SEARCHING MICROFILM AND MICROFICHE COM <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> WERE MEASURED AND
COMPARED. SEARCHING OF MOTORISED MICROFILM CATALOGUED WAS <Organization>FOUND</Organization> TO BE
SIGNIFICANTLY FASTER THAN SEARCHING MICROFICHE FOR INEXPERIENCED <Organization>USERS</Organization>. THE
SLOWEST FILM TIME WAS FASTER THAN MOST <Organization>FICHE TIMES</Organization>. RESULTS SUGGESTED,
HOWEVER, THAT FREQUENT <Organization>USERS MIGHT IMPROVE THEIR SEARCHING TIMES</Organization> AND MAY THEN
BE ABLE TO <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> <Organization>FICHE</Organization> FASTER THAN FILM.
********************************************
Document 5900
<Organization>COLORADO UNION</Organization> CATALOG.

DISCUSSES THE <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization> OF THE <Organization>COLORADO UNION</Organization> CATALOG, WHICH IS BASED ON THE
PROCESSING OF MAGNETIC TAPES FROM A VARIETY OF SOURCES, THE LARGEST OF WHICH
IS THE <Organization>COLORADO</Organization> MULTI-INSTITUTIONAL <Organization>OCLC</Organization> TAPES. CONSIDERS SOME OF THE PROBLEMS
INVOLVED IN THE CREATION OF A MULTI-INSTITUTIONAL PRODUCT, IN PARTICULAR THAT
OF DECIDING WHICH RECORD TO ACCEPT AS THE DEFINITIVE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> DESCRIPTION
OF A TITLE HELD <Organization>BY</Organization> SEVERAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5901
THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> SITUATION AND THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> CATALOGUE, (PART) 2&apos;
THE LONG APPROACH.

THE NEED FOR A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> CATALOGUE FOR PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAS LONG
BEEN FELT <Organization>BY</Organization> REFERENCE LIBRARIANS. THE NEED WAS PARTLY FULFILLED IN 1970 WHEN
THE PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>GREATER</Organization> <Location>COPENHAGEN</Location> PUBLISHED A CATALOGUE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
<Organization>PERIODICAL HOLDINGS</Organization>. IN THE PROVINCES COVERAGE IS VERY UNEVEN AND WITH GROWTH
IN INTERLENDING THE NEED FOR A UNION CATALOGUE IS NOW ACUTE. THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
<Organization>JOINT COMMITTEE</Organization> IS NOW CONSIDERING A PROJECT ON <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A CATALOGUE AND HAS ASKED
THE <Organization>LIBRARY CENTRE</Organization> TO PREPARE AN EDITORIAL PLAN FOR <Organization>INPUT</Organization> OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
<Organization>DATA INTO ITS DATA</Organization> BASE. IT NOW APPEARS THAT <Organization>INPUT</Organization> CANNOT BEGIN FOR FINANCIAL
REASONS UNTIL 1 JAN 84. APPEALS TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INSPECTORATE TO INITIATE A
DEBATE ON THE PRIORITIES WITHIN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY. FOR AN ABSTRACT OF
PART 1 IN 2BIBLIOTEK 701 (4) 1982, 2SEE1 THE FOLLOWING SERIAL NUMBER&apos;-
82/5965.
********************************************
Document 5902
DOBIS-WLN IMPACT STUDY. REPORT.

THE BCUC STUDY TEAM EXAMINED 3 SYSTEMS FOR POSSIBLE APPLICATION TO THE BRITISH
<Organization>COLUMBIA UNION</Organization> CATALOGUE&apos; <Location>WASHINGTON</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK, DOBIS AS IMPLEMENTED <Organization>BY</Organization>
COLLEGE BIBLIOCENTRE AND DOBIS AS IMPLEMENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF
<Location>CANADA</Location>. IT WAS <Organization>FOUND</Organization> THAT NONE OF THE SYSTEMS WOULD BE USABLE <Organization>BY</Organization> BCUC WITHOUT
SOME MODIFICATION. THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> VERSION OF DOBIS WAS SELECTED WITH THE
QUALIFICATION THAT MORE INITIAL WORK WOULD BE NEEDED THAN THE OTHERS TO BRING
IT INTO <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5903
PEOPLE SHOULD BROADEN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OUTLOOK: SOME OBSERVATIONS ON THE &apos;NARROW&apos;
CATCHWORD.

LIBRARIANS STILL COPE BADLY WITH THE PRINCIPLE OF THE NARROW CATCHWORD BECAUSE
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> TERMINOLOGICAL <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> IS STILL INEFFECTIVE. THE NARROW CATCHWORD USES
PRECISE TERMINOLOGY AND SEPARATES RELATED MATERIAL; THE <Organization>BROAD</Organization> CATCHWORD COVERS
WIDE SUBJECT AREAS AND TENDS TO RESULT IN THE FORMATION OF HIERARCHIES OF
SUBORDINATED GROUPS. DIE DEUTSCHE BIBLIOTHEK (GERMAN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>) USES
MAINLY NARROW CATCHWORDS, EQUATING THIS WITH PRECISE SUBJECT <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization>
<Organization>BUT</Organization> OCCASIONALLY DEVIATIONS FROM THIS PRINCIPLE OCCUR. CATCHWORDS IN SOME
SUBJECT AREAS ARE NARROWER THAN IN OTHERS. TERMINOLOGY IS CAREFULLY CONTROLLED
AND THIS IS ESSENTIAL WHEN PRECISE TERMS ARE <Organization>USED</Organization>. IF PRECISE SUBJECT
DEFINITION AND STRICT TERMINOLOGY <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> ARE CLOSELY LINKED THEN IT FOLLOWS
THAT PRECISE SUBJECT DEFINITION CAN ONLY BE CARRIED OUT IN THE <Organization>USER</Organization>&apos;S INTEREST
WHEN SUFFICIENT NUMBERS OF WELL-TRAINED STAFF ARE AVAILABLE.
********************************************
Document 5904
WHAT KIND OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> SHOULD I CHOOSE?.

DISCUSSES THE CHOICE OF <Organization>CLASSIFICATION SYSTEMS</Organization> FOR GENERAL <Organization>BOOK</Organization> COLLECTIONS
DRAWING PARTICULARLY ON EXPERIENCES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE FOLKSAM <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, FACK, <Location>SWEDEN</Location>,
WHICH SPECIALISES IN INSURANCE. ANY <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MUST CAREFULLY CONSIDER THE
ADAPTATION OF SYSTEMS TO COMPUTERISATION. RECOMMENDS THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE
&apos;ALPHABETIC <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>&apos; OF <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization>, WHICH PROVIDES <Organization>BROAD</Organization> AND GENERAL
<Organization>HEADINGS</Organization> FOR A WIDE VARIETY OF SUBJECTS. MAIN <Organization>HEADINGS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> ARE
GIVEN.
********************************************
Document 5905
RUDOLPH FOCKE AND THE THEORY OF THE CLASSIFIED CATALOG.

BETWEEN 1900 AND 1905, RUDOLPH FOCKE PUBLISHED A SERIES OF PAPERS ON
<Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> THEORY AND A DRAFT OF CODE FOR THE CONSTRUCTION OF CLASSIFIED
<Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>. HIS WORK WAS THE <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> RESULT OF THE REFORM OF LIBRARIANSHIP
DURING THE LAST DECADES OF THE 19<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY. THE <Organization>LARGE</Organization> NUMBER OF
<Organization>CLASSIFICATION SYSTEMS</Organization> <Organization>USED BY GERMAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS
SEEN AS AN OBSTACLE TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>NATIONAL SYSTEMS</Organization> OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
<Organization>CONTROL</Organization> AND ACCESS. THE HOPE OF STANDARDISATION CAME TO NOTHING; FOCKE&apos;S CODE
MAY EVEN HAVE HAD THE OPPOSITE EFFECT OF <Organization>PERPETUATING LOCAL SYSTEMS</Organization> WELL INTO
THE 20<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY. HIS WORK WAS INTRODUCED TO LIBRARIANS IN THE <Location>USA</Location> <Organization>AT</Organization> A TIME
WHEN SUBJECT CATALOGUING AND <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> WERE IN TRANSITION. HIS CODE IS
CONSISTENT WITH THE GENERAL PRINCIPLES UNDERLYING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS
<Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization>, WHICH MAY HAVE BEEN MORE INFLUENCED <Organization>BY</Organization> 19<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY GERMAN
<Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> THAN HAS HERTOFORE BEEN RECOGNISED. RE PORT NOT AVAILABLE FROM
<Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5906
<Organization>LC</Organization> <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> KEY&apos; A COMPARISON OF CLASSES A-P WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> Z COUNTERPARTS.

THE BIBLIOGRAPHY SECTION (Z CLASS) OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS <Organization>OFTEN</Organization>
CONFUSING TO REFERENCE LIBRARIANS AND TO <Organization>USERS</Organization>. A KEY HAS BEEN PREPARED
SHOWING A COMPARISON OF THE MAIN CLASSES AND SUBCLASSES FOR A TO P WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
CORRESPONDING Z NUMBERS. THE METHOD FOR PREPARING THIS KEY AND THE PROBLEMS
ENCOUNTERED ARE EXPLAINED.
********************************************
Document 5907
FATE, TIME, OCCASION, CHANCE, AND CHANGE; OR HOW THE MACHINE MAY YET SAVE LCSH.

DESCRIBES SHORTCOMINGS IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS 2LIST OF SUBJECT <Organization>HEADINGS</Organization>1&apos;
OUT OF DATE TERMINOLOGY AND UNHELPFUL 2SEE1 AND 2SEE ALSO1 REFERENCES; <Organization>BROAD</Organization>
<Organization>HEADINGS</Organization> ARE ALL <Organization>BUT</Organization> USELESS AND ACT AS A POOR SUBSTITUTE FOR A KEYWORD TITLE
INDEX; THE INABILITY TO ADAPT TO A CHANGING WORLD AND ITS <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization>
ENVIRONMENT. LISTS IMPROVEMENTS THAT CAN BE MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> COMPUTERISING THE SCHEME,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE POSSIBILITY OF KEYWORD SEARCHING AND THE LIFTING OF SPACE
CONSTRAINTS, AS WELL AS ASPECTS THAT THE MACHINE CANNOT CORRECT-TERMINOLOGY
AND THE ABSENCE OF USEFUL REFERENCES.
********************************************
Document 5908
PRE-AACR2 <Organization>SPECIAL RECORDS</Organization>: CORNELL&apos;S EXPERIENCE WITH A CLOSED CATALOG.

PARTLY BECAUSE OF THE CONFLICTING FORMS OF ENTRY FOR SERIAL AND MONOGRAPH
TITLES IN AACR2, AND DUE TO THE INCREASING DIFFICULTY INVOLED IN MAINTAINING
AN 8 1/2 MILLION CARD CATALOGUE, THE UNION DICTIONARY CATALOG IN CORNELL
UNIVERSITY&apos;S OLIN RESEARCH LIBRARY WAS CLOSED ON 31 DEC 80. <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BEGINNING
OF 1981 A <Organization>NEW</Organization> CATALOGUE-THE SUPPLEMENTAL CATALOG-WAS OPENED, AND SUPPLEMENTAL
CATALOGS ALSO REPLACED OTHER <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> ON THE CORNELL CAMPUS. SERIALS IN THE
SUPPLEMENTAL CATALOGS ARE CATALOGUED ENTIRELY ACCORDING TO AACR2, AND
MONOGRAPHS HAVE AACR2 NAME <Organization>HEADINGS BUT INCLUDE SOME HYBRID RECORDS</Organization> WITH
PRE-AACR2 DESCRIPTIVE ELEMENTS. THE CLOSURE AND <Organization>NEW</Organization> CATALOGUING ARE DESCRIBED
IN DETAIL.
********************************************
Document 5909
SUBJECT THESAURUS PERMUTATED LISTING.

ENTRY TO A <Organization>LARGE</Organization> MULTIDISCIPLINARY THESAURUS CONTAINING BOTH <Organization>SINGLE</Organization> AND
MULTI-WORD DESCRIPTORS PRESENTS PROBLEMS TO THE EXPERIENCED AS WELL AS THE NEW
<Organization>USER</Organization>. THIS PERMUTATED LISTING HAS BEEN PREPARED TO ALLEVIATE <Organization>THESE</Organization> PROBLEMS.
EACH DESCRIPTOR HAS BEEN PERMUTATED ACCORDING TO EACH SIGNIFICANT <Organization>WORD</Organization> IN
<Organization>SINGLE</Organization> AND MULTI-WORD ENTRIES AND LISTED ALPHABETICALLY. THIS TYPE OF LISTING
WILL&apos; (1) <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> THE <Organization>USER</Organization> WITH THE CORRECT THESAURUS ENTRY; AND (2) PERMIT
REVIEW OF GENERICALLY RELATED DESCRIPTORS SEPARATED <Organization>BY</Organization> ALPHABETISATION IN THE
THESAURUS.
********************************************
Document 5910
<Organization>HEALTH CARE</Organization> MICROTHESAURUS&apos; A HIERARCHIAL LIST OF INDEXING TERMS <Organization>USED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.

THE MICROTHESAURUS WAS PREPARED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization> TO HELP <Organization>NTIS DATA</Organization> BASE <Organization>USERS</Organization> RETRIEVE
<Organization>HEALTH CARE</Organization> RELATED REPORTS AND TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> AN INDEXING VOCABULARY FOR THE
<Organization>HEALTH CARE INFORMATION COMMUNITY</Organization>. MORE THAN 1,400 MAIN TERMS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
HIERARCHIES ARE LISTED, <Organization>EXPRESSING HEALTH CARE</Organization> CONCEPTS <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THOSE FOR
<Organization>HEALTH CARE</Organization> COSTS, EDUCATION, DELIVERY, AND OCCUPATIONS. ALSO INCLUDED ARE
TERMS COVERING <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>, MANPOWER, TECHNOLOGY, SERVICES, <Organization>USE</Organization>, AND
LEGISLATION. IN SOME INSTANCES A SHORT DEFINITION HAS BEEN PROVIDED TO CLARIFY
A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF A TERM <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5911
SELECTION AND IMPLEMENTATION OF AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND DOCUMENTATION <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. CASE
STUDY (<Organization>MIRROR NEWSPAPER GROUP</Organization>).

AN ACCOUNT OF THE CIRCUMSTANCES WHICH LED TO THE <Location>LONDON</Location> <Organization>MIRROR</Organization> <Organization>NEWSPAPER</Organization>
GROUP&apos;S SELECTION OF ANCIRS (<Organization>AUTOMATED NEWS</Organization> CUTTING INDEXING RETRIEVAL
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>), AND ITS OPERATION IN THE <Organization>DAILY MIRROR DOCUMENTATION SERVICE</Organization>. DETAILS
ARE GIVEN OF THE NATURE AND SIZE OF <Organization>INFORMATION HOLDINGS</Organization>, AND THE VOLUME OF
QUERIES HANDLED, WHICH LED TO THE DECISION TO REPLACE THE EXISTING
CONVENTIONAL MANUAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. THE ESSENTIAL REQUIREMENTS FOR A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> ARE
OUTLINED AND RELATED TO ANCIRS CAPABILITIES. A BRIEF SKETCH IS GIVEN OF HOW
MATERIAL IS NOW INDEXED AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> DEMANDS HANDLED, AND IN CONCLUSION THE
SUCCESS OF THE CHANGE IS EVALUATED IN TERMS OF SPACE SAVED, INCREASED
EFFICIENCY OF SERVICES, AND REDUCTION OF PERSONNEL REQUIREMENTS.
********************************************
Document 5912
MANAGING <Organization>EXXON</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS.

THE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CONTAINED IN <Organization>EXXON</Organization> REPORTS IS MANAGED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF AN
IN-HOUSE, <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> THAT BUILDS A DATA BASE AND PRODUCES
CURRENT-AWARENESS &apos;REPORT ALERTS&apos;, VARIOUS INDEXES <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> A SUBJECT KWIC,
AN <Organization>ON-LINE DATA</Organization> BASE, AND REPORTS-DISTRIBUTION <Organization>CONTROL</Organization>. KEY ELEMENTS IN THE
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> ARE: (1) A STRUCTURAL REPORT NUMBER THAT INCORPORATES CODES FOR THE
ISSUING <Organization>UNIT</Organization>, MAJOR SUBJECT, AND DATE; (2) NATURAL-LANGUAGE INDEXING SENTENCES
THAT MAKE UP A PSEUDO ABSTRACT; AND (3) CONTROLLED SUBJECT CATEGORIES THAT ARE
A BASE FOR THE &apos;REPORTS ALERTS&apos; <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5913
EVALUATION OF THE EFFECTIVENESS OF <Organization>AUTOMATED INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

CONSIDERS CRITERIA FOR THE EVALUATION OF THE EFFECTIVENESS OF <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND PROCEEDS TO INVESTIGATE IN DETAIL THE
SELECTION EFFECTIVENESS OF THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, I.E. THE RELEVANCE OF ITS OUTPUT, ITS
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> EFFECTIVENESS, AND THE QUALITY, SCOPE AND FORM OF INPUTS AS WELL
AS THE QUALITY OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CONTENT OF DOCUMENTS RETRIEVED.
********************************************
Document 5914
<Organization>TH INTERNATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>ONLINE</Organization> MEETING (IN NORWEGIAN).R

EPORT ON THE MEETING, WHICH WAS HELD IN <Location>LONDON</Location>, DEC 80, WITH BRIEF REVIEWS OF
PAPERS AND PROCEEDINGS.
********************************************
Document 5915
A SURVEY OF <Organization>ON-LINE SEARCH SERVICE</Organization> CENTERS IN <Location>CANADA</Location>.

THIS SURVEY OF <Organization>ON-LINE SEARCH SERVICE</Organization> CENTRES IN <Location>CANADA</Location> WAS CONDUCTED TO
<Organization>PROVIDE DATA</Organization> ON <Organization>THESE</Organization> CENTRES AND, MORE SPECIFICALLY, ON THE CHARACTERISTICS
OF THE <Organization>HUMAN</Organization> <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> INTERMEDIARY, AND TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> AN ACCURATE OVERALL PICTURE
OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> SEARCHING IN <Location>CANADA</Location>. THE SURVEY QUESTIONNAIRES WERE MAILED TO
APPROXIMATELY 765 CANADIAN <Organization>CUSTOMERS</Organization> OF 7 COMMERCIAL <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> VENDORS AND
YIELDED A RESPONSE RATE OF 49.7%. QUESTIONS ON THE SURVEY WERE DIVIDED INTO 2
PARTS&apos; DATA ON THE <Organization>SEARCH SERVICE CENTRE</Organization> ITSELF, AND DATA ON <Organization>SEARCH</Organization>
INTERMEDIARIES. FINDINGS WERE ANALYSED FOR EACH QUESTION USING FREQUENCY
DISTRIBUTIONS, AND CROSS TABULATIONS WERE PERFORMED ON SOME GROUPS OF
QUESTIONS. REPORT NOT AVAILABLE FROM <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5916
EXPERIMENTAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> TERMINALS IN PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE ESTABLISHMENT
OF AN <Organization>ON-LINE INFORMATION RETRIEVAL SERVICE</Organization> IN BEDFORDSHIRE, JAN 80-SEPT 81.

EXAMINES THE 1ST 18 MONTHS OF BEDFORDSHIRE COUNTY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION RETRIEVAL SERVICE</Organization> BASED ON LUTON <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> REFERENCE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. DEALS
WITH THE SETTING UP AND RUNNING OF THE SERVICE WITH EMPHASIS ON STAFF
TRAINING, INTERNAL AND EXTERNAL PROMOTION/PUBLICITY, FINANCE AND OTHER
PROBLEMS.
********************************************
Document 5917
FEASIBILITY STUDY FOR THE UNIVERSITY OF <Organization>LONDON ONLINE REFERRAL CENTRE</Organization>.

INVESTIGATES THE SETTING UP OF A <Organization>REFERRAL CENTRE</Organization> BASED ON AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> FILE OF
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> BEING CARRIED OUT <Organization>AT</Organization> <Location>UK</Location> UNIVERSITIES, POLYTECHNICS AND COLLEGES;
SIMILAR TO THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PUBLISHED IN THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S 2<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN
BRITISH UNIVERSITIES, POLYTECHNICS AND COLLEGES1. REPORT COVERS THE <Organization>REFERRAL</Organization>
CENTRE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>LONDON</Location> AND THE CAFS (CONTENT ADDRESSABLE FILE
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>) AS A MEANS OF <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> STORAGE/RETRIEVAL FOR THE <Organization>REFERRAL DATA</Organization>
BASE.
********************************************
Document 5918
THE <Organization>ABC</Organization>&apos;S OF THE AWLN (<Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> WISSWESSER LINE NOTATION).

THE <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> WISWESSER LINE NOTATION (AWLN) IS A PROPOSED SOLUTION FOR
CHEMISTS AND <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> WHICH TAKES INTO ACCOUNT THE
RECENT DEVELOPMENTS IN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RETRIEVAL.
********************************************
Document 5919
INVESTIGATION OF REQUIREMENTS AND IMPLEMENTATION OF FACILITIES FOR CONNECTING
<Location>UK</Location> HOSTS TO EURONET.

DESCRIBES WORK DONE ON X25 SOFTWARE AND NETWORK MEASUREMENT WITH A NUMBER OF
X25 NETWORKS. INVESTIGATES THE IMPLEMENTATION OF SEVERAL HIGH LEVEL PROTOCOLS
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> TERMINAL, DATA ENTRY, FILE TRANSFER AND REMOTE <Organization>PRINTING</Organization> PROTOCOLS. A
NUMBER OF ACTIVITIES PURSUED IN <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> SUPPORT OF BLAISE CONNECTION TO EURONET
ARE ALSO DESCRIBED.
********************************************
Document 5920
EURONET DIANE-PROS AND CONS&apos; SOME OBSERVATIONS <Organization>BY</Organization> AN OUTSIDER.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 43<Organization>RD</Organization> ASIS ANNUAL MEETING, ANAHEIM, CALIFORNIA, 9 OCT
80. DESCRIBES THE DEVELOPMENT OF EURONET DIANE TO DATE AND DISCUSSES SOME OF
THE ADVANTAGES AND DISADVANTAGES OF THE NETWORK.
********************************************
Document 5921
THE LOST YEARS FOR A <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> REVOLUTION.

FOLLOWING POOR PROGRESS <Organization>BY</Organization> VIEWDATA AND <Organization>TELETEXT</Organization>, THE REASONS FOR A NEW
PROMOTION OF <Organization>THESE SERVICES</Organization> ARE EXAMINED. ACTION <Organization>BY</Organization> THE RENTAL AND RETAIL
COMPANIES, THE <Organization>TREASURY</Organization>, <Organization>BBC</Organization> AND ITV IS DESCRIBED AND FUTURE <Organization>BBC</Organization> AND ITV
INTENTIONS IN THIS FIELD ARE DISCUSSED. THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>TELETEXT</Organization> FOR ADVERTISING IS
CONSIDERED AND THE BRAD UPDATE BRADLINE RECRUITMENT AND MEDIATEL SERVICES FOR
ADVERTISERS ARE EXAMINED. THE GATEWAY METHOD OF ACCESSING A <Organization>PRIVATE COMPUTER</Organization>
USING THE PUBLIC VIEWDATA <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS REVIEWED AND <Organization>TELETEXT</Organization> AND VIEWDATA ARE
COMPARED. PRESTEL&apos;S STRATEGY FOR INCREASING ITS <Organization>USERS</Organization> IS DESCRIBED AND THE
<Organization>PRIVATE SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE CONSIDERED.
********************************************
Document 5922
<Organization>TELEPHONE COMPANIES VERSUS CABLE TV</Organization>.

SUMMARISES THE FINDINGS OF A RECENT <Organization>INTERNATIONAL RESOURCE DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, INC.
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> REPORT. IT ACCUSES BOTH <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization> COMPANIES AND <Organization>CABLE</Organization> TELEVISION
OPERATORS OF &apos;EXCESSIVE TIMIDITY&apos; IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> EXPERIMENTATION WITH
INTERACTIVE CONSUMER SERVICES, <Organization>BUT</Organization> PREDICTS THAT &apos;HIGH-CONSUMER-EXCITEMENT&apos;
PROGRAMMING WILL STIMULATE DEMAND WITHIN THE NEXT 2-3 YEARS. LISTS THE DRIVING
FORCES, CONSTRAINTS AND POSSIBLE NEW SERVICES IDENTIFIED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE REPORT.
********************************************
Document 5923
VIEWDATA-WHAT&apos;S IN IT FOR INDUSTRIAL MARKETERS?.

A BRIEF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> OUTLINE OF VIEWDATA IS PROVIDED AND THE MARKETING VALUE OF
THE TECHNOLOGY IS ASSESSED. IT IS FELT THAT VIEWDATA CAN TAKE THE ROUTINE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> HANDLING LOAD OFF THE <Organization>ENQUIRY DEPARTMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> THE
EFFICIENCY OF THE SALESMAN&apos;S ROLE <Organization>BY</Organization> ENHANCING AND COMPLEMENTING THE PERSONAL
SERVICE OFFERED. THE SIGNIFICANCE OF THE INTERACTIVE QUALITIES OF VIEWDATA AS
OPPOSED TO THE <Organization>PRINTED MEDIA</Organization> IS STRESSED AND BRIEF CONSIDERATION IS GIVEN TO
SECURITY AND COSTS OF A VIEWDATA <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5924
GATEWAY-AN ENHANCEMENT OF PRESTEL.

THE INTRODUCTION OF THE GATEWAY FACILITY IN MAR 82 WILL ENABLE <Organization>USERS</Organization> TO BE
LINKED <Organization>VIA</Organization> PRESTEL AND THE <Organization>PACKET SWITCHED SERVICE</Organization> TO EXTERNAL COMPUTERS,
ALLOWING A RANGE OF NEW SERVICES TO BE OFFERED. EXAMINES THE SIGNALS COMING
FROM THE VIEWDATA INDUSTRY AND POTENTIAL <Organization>USER</Organization> ORGANISATIONS TO ANALYSE THE
DIRECTIONS IN WHICH THIS MORE SOPHISTICATED FORM OF PRESTEL MAY BE CHANNELLED.
OUTLINES&apos; THE BACKGROUND TO GATEWAY&apos;S <Location>UK</Location> INTRODUCTION; HOW THE GATEWAY
FACILITY OPERATES; <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> AND THE INDUSTRIES LIKELY TO BE AFFECTED; AND
GATEWAY&apos;S LONGER TERM INFLUENCE.
********************************************
Document 5925
<Organization>GEC</Organization> CONTRIBUTION TO VIEWDATA.

A DESCRIPTION IS GIVEN OF <Organization>GEC</Organization>&apos;S INVOLVEMENT IN <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT WORK
ON VIEWDATA, FROM THE EARLY 1970S. THE WORK IS CONSIDERED IN SECTIONS WHICH
DESCRIBE THE DEVELOPMENT AND PROGRESS <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> TO THE FIRST <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization> STAGES.
IT IS SHOWN HOW THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> GROUPS WERE LINKED TOGETHER TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> A
<Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> RANGE OF VIEWDATA EQUIPMENT PARTICULARLY FOR THE <Organization>POST OFFICE</Organization>
VIEWDATA <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, PRESTEL.
********************************************
Document 5926
THE FUTURE OF <Organization>VIDEOTEX SYSTEMS</Organization>&apos; A PERSONAL VIEW.

REVIEWS THE TECHNOLOGY OF VIEWDATA, IN <Location>EUROPE</Location> AND THE <Location>UK</Location>, ITS BRIEF HISTORY,
PRESENT PROBLEMS AND POSSIBLE FUTURE. REFERENCE IS MADE TO PANDA (PRESTEL
<Organization>ADVANCED NETWORK DESIGN</Organization> <Organization>ARCHITECTURE</Organization>), PRESTEL&apos;S GATEWAY <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AND PICTURE
PRESTEL. CONCLUDES THAT <Organization>VIDEOTEX</Organization> ON AN INTERNATIONAL SCALE COULD DEVELOP IN 2
DIRECTIONS&apos; <Organization>LOCAL INFORMATION PROVISION BY DISTRIBUTED DATA</Organization> BASE NETWORKS IN
INDIVIDUAL COUNTRIES, AND AS A 1ST ENTRY PORT TO INTERNATIONAL DATA BASES AND
DATA BANKS.
********************************************
Document 5927
<Organization>VIDEOTEX</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE STUDY EXPLORED THE CONCEPT OF INTERACTIVE <Organization>VIDEOTEX</Organization> (VIEWDATA) IN A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SETTING AND THE POTENTIAL USEFULNESS FOR THE <Organization>AUSTRALIAN BUSINESS COMMUNITY</Organization>. IT
WAS FUNDED JOINTLY <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> AND TELECOM <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>
AND UNDERTAKEN <Organization>BY INSEARCH LTD</Organization>. STUDY ALSO UNDERTOOK AN ASSESSMENT OF THE
USEFULNESS OF <Organization>VIDEOTEX SERVICES</Organization> &apos;IN-HOUSE&apos; AS <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES FOR THE
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, FOR PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND AS A VEHICLE FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S
SERVICES AND ANNOUNCEMENTS.
********************************************
Document 5928
A PERSONAL, <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> LITERATURE RETRIEVAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

THE <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> METHOD OF INDEXING AND RETRIEVING DOCUMENTS FROM A PERSONAL
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS DESCRIBED. CONSISTS OF A UNIVAC 1108 WITH <Organization>INPUT</Organization> FROM CARDS AND
OUTPUT <Organization>VIA</Organization> LINE PRINTER. <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> ALLOWS <Organization>INPUT</Organization> OF AUTHOR, TITLE, <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
DETAILS AND KEYWORDS WHILE DOCUMENTS ARE ALLOCATED A NUMBERIC CODE AND STORED
SEQUENTIALLY. 3 TYPES OF OUTPUT ARE PROVIDED; ALPHABETIC KEYWORDS LIST WITH
DOCUMENT REFERENCE NUMBERS, A REFERENCE LIST OF DOCUMENTS TITLES,
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> DETAILS AND AUTHORS, AND OUTPUT FROM SEARCHES ON THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5929
TRANSFER OF TECHNOLOGY&apos; COMPUTER EQUIPMENT SELECTION AND STAFF TRAINING
PROTOCOLS (<Organization>COMPUTERIZED RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS</Organization>).

(ADAPTED FROM A PAPER GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 4<Organization>TH</Organization> INTERNATIONAL CONGRESS ON MEDICAL
LIBRARIANSHIP, WHO/<Organization>UNESCO</Organization>, <Location>BELGRADE</Location>, SEPT 80.) DISCUSSES THE CHOICE OF
EQUIPMENT FOR <Organization>COMPUTERISED RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS</Organization> IN THE LIGHT OF TRAINING
REQUIREMENTS FOR PRESENT STAFF. EMPHASISES THAT THE ACCEPTANCE OF PURCHASED
SYSTEMS IS HIGHLY DEPENDENT ON THE TRAINING EFFORT MADE. ELEMENTS OF SYSTEMS
(NETWORKS, HARDWARE AND SOFTWARE) ARE RELATED TO THE TRAINING TECHNIQUES
NEEDED.
********************************************
Document 5930
<Organization>TOWARDS ON-LINE INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>.

DISCUSSES THE DEVELOPMENT AND POTENTIAL <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SYSTEMS AND PROVIDES A LIST OF <Organization>WORLD-WIDE ON-LINE DATA</Organization> BASES GIVING ACCESS TO
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> OR <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> LITERATURE. THE MAJOR FEATURES OF <Organization>ON-LINE SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE
ENUMERATED.
********************************************
Document 5931
PIRA SEMINAR S13. AN INTRODUCTION TO DATABASE PUBLISHING.

NO ABSTRACT AVAILABLE.
********************************************
Document 5932
PROVIDING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ON <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> WAY OF DATA BASES.

OWING TO DEVELOPMENTS IN THE FIELD OF TELECOMMUNICATIONS, A GREAT VARIETY OF
DATA BASES ARE NOW EASILY ACCESSIBLE TO THE PUBLIC <Organization>BY</Organization> MEANS OF TERMINALS.
REGARDING <Organization>THESE</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS, THE <Organization>NATIONAL COUNCIL</Organization> FOR AGRICULTURAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> DECIDED TO INQUIRE INTO THE OPINIONS OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>
RESEARCHERS <Organization>WORKING</Organization> FOR INSTITUTIONS PARTICIPATING IN THE COUNCIL, ON FREE
ACCESS TO DATA BASES CONTAINING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ON <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN ORDER TO
FIND OUT WHETHER THIS INFLUENCES CONTENTS AND FORMULATION OF PROJECT
DESCRIPTIONS. THE QUESTIONS CONCERNED THE NATURE OF THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
AND THE <Organization>INPUT INTO INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> RESEARCHER IN
QUESTION AND HIS/HER ATTITUDE <Organization>TOWARDS</Organization> FREE ACCESS TO <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN PROGRESS.
********************************************
Document 5933
WHICH DATABASE? AN EVALUATIVE GUIDE TO <Organization>ONLINE</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> DATABASES IN
BUSINESS AND THE SOCIAL <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>.

A GUIDE TO THE RANGE AVAILABLE AND THE FACILITIES AND USES OFFERED, FOR
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROFESSIONALS AND LIBRARIANS WHO <Organization>USE</Organization> THE SERVICES LESS THAN
CONSTANTLY AND WISH TO INCREASE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FREQUENCY OR <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESULTS.
COVERS FACTUAL AND NUMERIC <Organization>AS WELL AS BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA</Organization> BASES. AN ANNUAL
<Organization>UPDATE SERVICE</Organization> IS AVAILABLE ON SUBSCRIPTION FROM THE AUTHOR <Organization>AT</Organization> PRESTON
POLYTECHNIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND LEARNING <Organization>RESOURCES CENTRE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5934
ACOMPLINE&apos; AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> GOVERNMENT.

GIVES AN ACCOUNT OF THE SETTING UP OF ACOMPLINE (ACOMPLIS <Organization>BEFORE</Organization> 1981) <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Organization>GREATER LONDON COUNCIL</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE ORIGINAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, ACOMPLIS (A
<Organization>COMPUTERISED LONDON INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization>), WAS INTRODUCED IN 1973 TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization>
THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH IN-HOUSE FACILITIES; <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> COM INDEXES TO THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S STOCK, <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> INDEXES, BIBLIOGRAPHIES, SDI AND BATCH (OFF-LINE)
SEARCHING. IN 1981, WITH THE <Organization>EUROPEAN SPACE AGENCY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RETRIEVAL
SERVICES (ESRIN) ACTING AS HOST, ACOMPLINE WAS LAUNCHED AS THE 1ST
<Organization>COMPREHENSIVE ON-LINE DATA</Organization> BASE IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> GOVERNMENT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5935
COMPARISON OF RESULTS OBTAINED USING THE <Organization>CHEMICAL ABSTRACTS DATA</Organization> BASE IN
SEARCHES PERFORMED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> DIALOG AND ESA-QUEST.

REPORT OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> CARRIED OUT <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SPANISH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
AND DOCUMENTATION CENTRE (CENIDOC). IDENTICAL SEARCHES WERE PERFORMED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
THE DIALOG AND ESA-QUEST SYSTEMS, USING 2<Organization>CHEMICAL</Organization> ABSTRACTS1 (CA), FOR EQUAL
LENGTHS OF TIME. FULL DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE INITIAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HYPOTHESIS TO
EXPLAIN PREVIOUSLY OBSERVED DIFFERENCES IN REFERENCES RETRIEVED, AND THE
CONSTRUCTION OF THE CA FILE. RESULTS OBTAINED USING A WIDE VARIETY OF <Organization>SEARCH</Organization>
CRITERIA ARE PRESENTED. THE SYSTEMS AGREED ONLY WHEN REGISTRATION NUMBERS OR
<Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> CODES WERE <Organization>USED</Organization>, AND MORE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WAS ALWAYS OBTAINED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
DIALOG USING INDEXING TERMS. THE CONCLUSION REACHED IS THAT <Organization>QUEST</Organization> DOES NOT <Organization>USE</Organization>
THE COMPLETE CA <Organization>SEARCH</Organization>, AND DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF ITS LIMITATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5936
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND COMMUNICATION TECHNIQUES IN SUBJECT COMMUNICATION AND
DOCUMENTATION&apos; ECONOMY, COSTS, FINANCE AND ORGANISATION.

<Organization>ON-LINE SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>SCREEN</Organization> DISCS ARE PROMINENT AMONG <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
DEVELOPMENTS IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location> AND ARE <Organization>USED</Organization> MAINLY <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> HAS RESULTED IN AN ECONOMIC TREND <Organization>TOWARDS</Organization>
COOPERATION BETWEEN SIMILAR FIRMS OR ORGANISATIONS OR BETWEEN COMPLEMENTARY
BRANCHES OF INDUSTRY. THE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> MARKET IS INTERNATIONALLY ORIENTED AND THE
MARKET LEADERS ARE MAINLY FROM ENGLISH-SPEAKING COUNTRIES. THE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MARKET HAS DEVELOPED MORE SLOWLY IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location> THAN IN
NEIGHBOURING COUNTRIES. MEASURES TO COUNTERACT THIS SHOULD INCLUDE&apos; <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICY WITH REGARD FOR ECONOMIC ASPECTS; ENCOURAGING COOPERATION
BETWEEN MANUFACTURERS AND <Organization>USERS</Organization>; AND CONCENTRATING THE RESTRICTED SUPPLY OF
GOVERNMENT MONEY SO AS TO FAVOUR THE GROWTH OF <Organization>PRIVATE ENTERPRISE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5937
QUANTIFIABLE CHARACTERISTICS OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> DATABASES.

(EXTENDED VERSION OF THE LECTURE &apos;QUANTIFIZIERBARE MERKMALE VON DATENBANKEN&apos;,
PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE DEUTSCHER DOKUMENTARTAG, WEST <Location>BERLIN</Location>, 1980.) CONSIDERS THE
QUANTIFIABLE CHARACTERISTICS OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA</Organization> BASES FROM THE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
<Organization>USER</Organization>&apos;S VIEWPOINT. GIVES A BRIEF OVERVIEW OF DATA BASE PROPERTIES WHICH HAVE
BEEN STUDIED QUANTITATIVELY&apos; COVERAGE, CURRENCY, COSTS, ACCURACY, INDEXING AND
RETRIEVAL EFFICIENCY. INDICATES THE VALUE OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> STUDIES TO THE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization>
AND <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> STUDIES WOULD BE USEFUL.
********************************************
Document 5938
BIBLIO-DATA&apos; THE <Organization>DATA BANK</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE GERMAN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

BIBLIO-DATA HAS DEVELOPED SINCE 1975 INTO THE <Organization>BIGGEST LITERATURE DATA BANK</Organization> FOR
<Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> SEARCHING IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>. <Organization>BY</Organization> DEC 81 IT WAS LINKED TO 66 INSTITUTIONS
IN <Location>GERMANY</Location> AND OTHER <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COUNTRIES AND HAD ACCESS <Organization>VIA</Organization> THE STAIRS
RETRIEVAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> TO EURONET DIANE. OVER 900,000 DOCUMENTARY UNITS ARE
AVAILABLE AND 100,000 ARE ADDED ANNUALLY. THE <Organization>DATA BANK</Organization> AIMS TO INCLUDE
REFERENCES TO ALL <Organization>NEW</Organization> GERMAN MONOGRAPHS AND PERIODICALS, ALTHOUGH NOT TO
<Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> ARTICLES, AND RETRIEVAL IS POSSIBLE <Organization>VIA ALL IMPORTANT DATA</Organization>
ELEMENTS. IN SERVICE QUALITY AND QUANTITY BIBLIO-DATA IS AHEAD OF MOST <Organization>PRINTED</Organization>
BIBLIOGRAPHIES; A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FEATURE IS A <Organization>LARGE</Organization> STORE OF DISSERTATIONS FROM BOTH
EAST AND WEST <Location>GERMANY</Location>. CORRECTIONS, HOWEVER, CANNOT YET BE MADE AND SOME
ASPECTS OF CATALOGUING REQUIRE IMPROVEMENT.
********************************************
Document 5939
REFERENCE RETRIEVAL WITHOUT <Organization>USER</Organization> QUERY FORMULATION.

DESCRIBES A COMPUTER PROGRAM FOR THE PURPOSE OF SATISFYING INCOMPLETELY
DEFINED <Organization>USER</Organization> NEEDS <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> A MAN-MACHINE DIALOGUE WHICH DOES NOT REQUIRE A
QUERY FORMULATION <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>USER</Organization>. THE PROGRAM ATTEMPTS TO SATISFY THE <Organization>USER</Organization>&apos;S
NEEDS FROM A MODEL WHICH IT BUILDS OF HIS INTERESTS; A MODEL WHICH IS A SUBSET
OF ITS OWN WORLD MODEL (THE DATA BASE). EXPLORES THE POSSIBILITIES OF THE
PROGRAM CREATING VIRTUAL WORLD MODELS TO PREVENT THE NEED FOR UNNECESSARILY
ACCESSING THE <Organization>WHOLE DATA</Organization> BASE AND INCORPORATING A FORM OF WEIGHTING BASED ON
ASSOCIATION STRENGTHS BETWEEN ITEMS IN THE DATA BASE.
********************************************
Document 5940
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF AUTOMATIC INDEXING FOR AUTHORITY <Organization>CONTROL</Organization>.

THESAURUS-BASED AUTOMATIC INDEXING AND AUTOMATIC AUTHORITY <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> SHARE
COMMON GROUND AS WORD-MATCHING PROCESSES. TO DEMONSTRATE THE RESEMBLANCE, AN
EXPERIMENTAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> UTILISING AUTOMATIC INDEXING AS ITS CORE PROCESS WAS
IMPLEMENTED TO PERFORM AUTHORITY <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> ON A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
RECORDS. DETAILS OF THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> ARE GIVEN AND RESULTS DISCUSSED. THE BENEFITS
OF EXPLOITING THE RESEMBLANCE BETWEEN THE 2 SYSTEMS ARE EXAMINED.
********************************************
Document 5941
THE SUITABILITY OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AND ARTICLE TITLES FOR SUBJECT CATALOGUING.

FOR ECONOMIC REASONS THE VIABILITY OF <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> SUBJECT CATALOGUING USING MAIN
ENTRIES IS <Organization>OFTEN</Organization> CONSIDERED. <Organization>BASIC DATA</Organization> AVAILABLE FOR THIS ARE THE TITLE,
SUB-TITLE AND CIP DATA <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALTHOUGH THE TITLE MAY <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> IT DOES NOT ALWAYS
EXPRESS THE SUBJECT CONTENT ACCURATELY. IN POPULAR LITERATURE THE TITLE MAY BE
EYE-CATCHING RATHER THAN ACCURATE. PROBLEMS CAN ALSO BE CAUSED <Organization>BY</Organization> FOREIGN
LANGUAGES, ABBREVIATIONS, SHORTENED OR LENGTHENED NAMES FOR THE SAME OBJECT,
HOMONYMS AND SYNONYMS, ESPECIALLY IN GEOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL. MANY TITLES ARE
VAGUE AND INCOMPLETE OR EVEN INCOMPREHENSIBLE IF THE SUBJECT OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> IS
NOT ALREADY KNOWN. <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE TITLE IN <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> SUBJECT CATALOGUING WOULD
SAVE WORK TIME <Organization>BUT</Organization> RESULT IN MANY FALSE ENTRIES.
********************************************
Document 5942
WOMEN IN THE COMMUNITY&apos; HUMANITIES PROGRAMMING FOR THE PUBLIC.

MORGANTOWN PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS 1 OF 10 PUBLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO PARTICIPATE IN
<Organization>RADCLIFFE COLLEGE</Organization>&apos;S WOMEN IN THE COMMUNITY PROJECT. A WEEK-LONG TRAINING
SESSION INCLUDED DISCUSSION OF HOW <Organization>NEW</Organization> KNOWLEDGE ABOUT WOMEN IS CHANGING THE
PERCEPTION OF HISTORY AND OTHER ACADEMIC DISCIPLINES. THERE WERE SESSIONS ON
PROGRAMME <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>, OUTREACH, PUBLIC RELATIONS AND FORMATS, AND MORGANTOWN
WILL PLAN AND IMPLEMENT A SERIES OF 4-6 PROGRAMMES ON WOMEN IN SPRING AND
EARLY SUMMER 82. INCLUDED IN PROVISIONAL PLANS ARE A PHOTOGRAPHIC EXHIBITION,
ORAL HISTORY AND REMINISCENCES OF WOMEN FOCUSING ON WAR FROM THE CIVIL WAR TO
<Organization>MODERN TIMES</Organization>. PROGRAMMES WILL DRAW ON THE MANY FORMS OF ARCHIVAL MATERIAL
AVAILABLE IN THE AREA.
********************************************
Document 5943
OPTICAL MEMORIES. 1964-MARCH, 1982 (CITATIONS FROM THE <Organization>NTIS DATA</Organization> BASE).

<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> REPORTS ARE CITED ON EFFORTS <Organization>TOWARDS</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF OPTICAL
MEMORIES FOR DATA STORAGE. PERFORMANCE AND <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> STUDIES OF OPTICAL
STORAGE DEVICES ARE ALSO CONSIDERED, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> HOLOGRAPHIC STORAGE.
********************************************
Document 5944
A BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE <Organization>SAN JOSE COMMUNITY COLLEGE</Organization> DISTRICTS &apos;<Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>&apos;
REGISTRATION <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

THIS DOCUMENT IS A NARRATIVE DESCRIPTION OF AN INTERACTIVE, <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
REGISTRATION <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, WHICH WAS DESIGNED AND WRITTEN FOR THE <Organization>SAN JOSE COMMUNITY</Organization>
COLLEGE DISTRICT. THE DOCUMENT INCLUDES THE MACHINE CONFIGURATION, THE HISTORY
AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, HOW THE OPERATORS AND STUDENTS INTERACT WITH
THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, AND EXAMPLES OF VARIOUS HARD COPY DOCUMENTS THAT ARE ASSOCIATED
WITH THE REGISTRATION <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5945
<Organization>HUMAN</Organization> FACTORS ASPECTS OF VISUAL DISPLAY <Organization>UNIT</Organization> OPERATION.

PRESENTS A BRIEF REVIEW OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND MEDICAL STUDIES ON THE <Organization>HUMAN</Organization> FACTORS
INVOLVED IN THE OPERATION OF VISUAL DISPLAY UNITS.
********************************************
Document 5946
<Organization>HOME</Organization> TELECOMMUNICATIONS IN THE 1980S (PROSPECTUS ONLY).

NO ABSTRACT AVAILABLE.
********************************************
Document 5947
<Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> MAIL&apos; ALSO OF INTEREST TO THE <Organization>PRINTING</Organization> INDUSTRY?.T

HE POSSIBILITIES OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> MAIL ARE EXAMINED AND EXAMPLES ARE GIVEN OF THE
WAYS IN WHICH DATA MAIL IS REPLACING POSTAL AND TELEX SERVICES IN THE <Location>US</Location>. THE
ADVANTAGES OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> MAIL ARE DISCUSSED WITH REFERENCE TO 2 CASE STUDIES
AND THE INCREASED NATIONALISATION OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> MAIL <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>PACKET</Organization> SWITCHING
IS EXAMINED.
********************************************
Document 5948
<Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization> EXCHANGES. JANUARY, 1975-OCTOBER 1981 (CITATIONS FROM THE
<Organization>INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE PHYSICS AND ENGINEERING COMMUNITIES
DATA BASE).

CITATIONS COVER THE PRINCIPLES, DESIGN, DEVELOPMENT, <Organization>TESTING</Organization>, OPERATION, AND
MAINTENANCE OF BOTH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization> EXCHANGES.
********************************************
Document 5949
<Organization>FACSIMILE</Organization> COMMUNICATION. JUNE 1970-1981 (CITATIONS FROM THE <Organization>NTIS DATA</Organization> BASE).

THE BIBLIOGRAPHY CITES REPORTS THAT <Organization>DISCUSS DESIGN</Organization> AND <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> OF
<Organization>FACSIMILE COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS</Organization>. DISCUSSIONS OF SATELLITE AND <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization>
NETWORKS ARE INCLUDED. THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>FACSIMILE COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> BUSINESS,
THE MILITARY, AND GOVERNMENT IS COVERED.
********************************************
Document 5950
<Organization>PACKET</Organization> SWITCHING REVIEWED.

REVIEWS THE PROGRESS OF PUBLIC <Organization>PACKET</Organization> SWITCHED NETWORKS IN <Location>EUROPE</Location> WITH
PARTICULAR EMPHASIS ON THE <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>PSS</Organization> NETWORK.
********************************************
Document 5951
TELECOMMUNICATIONS FOR BUSINESS.

VARIOUS ASPECTS OF RECENT TELECOMMUNICATIONS DEVELOPMENTS ARE DISCUSSED. THEY
COMPRISE THE PROGRESSIVE LIBERALISATION OF <Organization>BRITISH TELECOM</Organization> AND THE COMPANY&apos;S
<Organization>NEW</Organization> POLICIES, FACILITIES OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>BRITISH TELECOM</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS TELEX, TELETEX,
VIEWDATA, <Organization>BT</Organization> GOLD AND THE COMPANY&apos;S DIGITAL <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> NETWORK FOR BUSINESS
<Organization>CUSTOMERS</Organization> AND <Organization>FACSIMILE</Organization> <Organization>TRANSMISSION SERVICES</Organization>; THE LONG TERM REQUIREMENTS OF
THE <Organization>INTEGRATED OFFICE</Organization>; AND A PREVIEW OF NEW AND SIGNIFICANT PRODUCTS THAT WILL
BE ON VIEW <Organization>AT</Organization> THE COMMUNICATIONS 82 EXHIBITION.
********************************************
Document 5952
OUTLINE OF A SOCIETY OF FREELY AVAILABLE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.

TODAY <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> <Organization>INNOVATIONS</Organization> IN MANY FIELDS CAUSE SOCIAL CHANGES ALMOST
<Organization>BEFORE SOCIETY</Organization> HAS BECOME AWARE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EXISTENCE. VERY <Organization>OFTEN</Organization> NEGATIVE
INFLUENCES OF CERTAIN <Organization>INNOVATIONS</Organization> HAVE NOT BEEN THOROUGHLY INVESTIGATED
BEFOREHAND. THIS HAS LED TO THE GROWTH OF MANY COUNTER MOVEMENTS IN SOCIETY.
IT IS NECESSARY TO FIND COMMON GROUND BETWEEN REPRESENTATIVES OF &apos;ESTABLISHED&apos;
AND &apos;ALTERNATIVE&apos; STYLES OF LIVING, IN ORDER TO ENSURE THE CONTINUATION OF
INNOVATION IN SOCIETY. INITIATIVE, CREATIVITY AND COOPERATION, THE VITAL
FACTORS FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC INNOVATION, ARE EVIDENT IN BOTH GROUPS,
ONLY OPINIONS AS TO THE BEST MEANS OF EMPLOYING THEM DIFFER. TODAY A NEW
<Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NETWORK IS GRADUALLY LINKING MANKIND. THE WORLD IS
BECOMING A &apos;GLOBAL VILLAGE&apos; <Organization>AT</Organization> LEAST ON THE LEVEL OF <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization>
COMMUNICATIONS STRUCTURES. THIS NETWORK MAY ENABLE <Location>US</Location> TO PROGRESS TO A
RATIONAL WORLD MODEL IN WHICH EVERYONE WILL HAVE A CHANCE IN  LIFE.
********************************************
Document 5953
FUNDAMENTAL PRINCIPLES FOR <Organization>CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.

THE <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> MUST REFLECT THE EDUCATIONAL MILIEU, AND RESPOND TO IT.
ACCORDINGLY CONSIDERS IN TURN THE RELEVANCE OF SOCIAL FACTORS, THE PROCESS OF
<Organization>HUMAN DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, THE NATURE OF LEARNING, AND THE NATURE OF KNOWLEDGE,
SHOWING THE INFLUENCE OF EACH OF <Organization>THESE</Organization>. ONLY AFTER <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AN ANALYSIS IS IT
POSSIBLE TO FORM A VIABLE <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5954
AUTHORS VERSUS BOOKS.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 54<Organization>TH</Organization> ASLIB ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Organization>OXFORD UNIVERSITY</Organization>, 22-25
SEPT 81. A DISCUSSION ON THE EFFECTS OF THE <Organization>NEW COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES</Organization> ON
THE FLOW OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND THE CONCEPT OF AUTHORSHIP.
********************************************
Document 5955
<Organization>TOWARDS</Organization> A <Organization>READING SOCIETY</Organization>.
