Document 5627
<Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> A <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO ETHNIC MINORITIES.

A <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IS ONLY LIKELY TO HAVE TO CATER FOR ETHNIC MINORITIES
IN URBAN AREAS. AFTER THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> ETHNIC MINORITIES HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED A
REASONABLE STOCK OF BOOKS IN THE <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization> LANGUAGES MUST BE INCLUDED
BEARING IN MIND THAT SEVERAL ETHNIC MINORITIES ARE ENGLISH-SPEAKING E.G. WEST
INDIANS. STOCKS OF BOOKS FOR ETHNIC MINORITIES MUST PERFORCE BE LIMITED SINCE
ETHNIC MINORITIES <Organization>ALSO</Organization> READ BOOKS ORIGINATING <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE DOMINANT CULTURE&apos; A
SURFEIT <Organization>WOULD</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> ALIENATE THE NON-ETHNIC MINORITY USERS. THE PROBLEM OF
STOCK SELECTION OF FOREIGN LANGUAGE BOOKS CAN BE OVERCOME BY USING ETHNIC
MINORITY <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5628
<Organization>SWEDISH PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR IMMIGRANTS AND LINGUISTIC MINORITIES.

THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PARLIAMENT HAS ESTABLISHED THAT THE GOALS OF <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> IMMIGRATION
POLICY SHOULD BE EQUALITY, FREEDOM OF CHOICE AND COOPERATION. <Organization>THESE</Organization> AIMS APPLY
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR IMMIGRANTS AND ETHNIC MINORITIES. TODAY, <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE OVER A MILLION BOOKS IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> 80 LANGUAGES. DESCRIBES THE
FINANCING OF <Organization>SUCH SERVICES</Organization>, SOURCES OF SUPPLY, PURCHASING AND <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>,
MEDIA SELECTION, NEWSPAPERS AND MAGAZINES, <Organization>AV MEDIA</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> GRANTS FOR BOOKS AND <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5629
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> CHILDREN IN <Location>DENMARK</Location>.

SINCE THE MIDDLE OF THE 1970S THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN OF FOREIGN CITIZENS HAS
INCREASED HEAVILY AS THE RELATIVES OF FOREIGN WORKERS WERE GIVEN ENTRY
PERMITS. <Organization>DISCUSSES EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>HEALTH CARE</Organization>, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORGANISATIONS,
ORGANISATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIAL, STOCKTAKING AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ASPECTS OF PROVISION
FOR <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> CHILDREN.
********************************************
Document 5630
<Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.

IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> THERE ARE NOW MORE THAN 250,000 <Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
RELATIVES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE POORER <Location>MEDITERRANEAN</Location> COUNTRIES TOGETHER WITH A <Organization>FURTHER</Organization>
200,000 <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE FORMER <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> COLONIES. FOR A NUMBER OF YEARS BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN AREAS WITH LARGE NUMBERS OF <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> RESIDENTS HAVE PROVIDED MATERIAL IN
THE IMMIGRANTS&apos; NATIVE LANGUAGES. <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LEVEL THE NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK
EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>) SET UP A
<Organization>COMMITTEE ON PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR <Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> IN JAN 78. THE
REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE PUBLISHED IN 1979 <Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
COORDINATION OF THE PROVISION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR IMMIGRANTS AND THE
APPOINTMENT OF A STAFF-MEMBER <Organization>AT</Organization> THE NBLC WITH SPECIAL RESPONSIBILITY FOR
SERVICES TO IMMIGRANTS.
********************************************
Document 5631
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR IMMIGRANTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>MEDITERRANEAN</Location> COUNTRIES&apos; PLANS <Organization>AT</Organization>
UTRECHT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

IN 1981 A <Organization>NEW</Organization> POST WITH SPECIAL RESPONSIBILITY FOR SERVICES TO FOREIGN WORKERS
AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES WAS CREATED <Organization>AT</Organization> UTRECHT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.
UTRECHT HAS ALMOST 20,000 IMMIGRANTS, MAINLY <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE POORER <Location>MEDITERRANEAN</Location>
COUNTRIES AND THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> POST WAS THE RESULT OF A REPORT PUBLISHED IN 1980 <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
PROVISION OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> WORKERS. THE REPORT RECOGNISED THE
DIFFICULTIES IN <Organization>PROVIDING SUCH SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> ENLISTING THE <Organization>AID</Organization> OF
<Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> IN SELECTING, OBTAINING AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> MATERIAL FOR THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. TO PUBLICISE <Organization>ITS SERVICES</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS ENDEAVOURING TO CONTACT
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> ORGANISATIONS CONCERNED WITH THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> WELFARE OF
<Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> FAMILIES AND TO GIVE PRESENTATIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SERVIVES <Organization>AT</Organization>
MEETINGS OF <Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5632
NON-USE AND LOSER STUDIES IN <Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>,
JULY 80. ARGUES THAT <Organization>USE</Organization> AND <Organization>USER</Organization> STUDIES HAVE NOT BEEN WIDELY ADOPTED, OR
BEEN INFLUENTIAL IN <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization> PRIMARILY BECAUSE WE DO NOT YET
HAVE A GOOD <Organization>UNDERSTANDING</Organization> OF THE CONTEXT IN WHICH THEY SHOULD BE INTERPRETED.
<Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> THAT AN <Organization>UNDERSTANDING</Organization> OF THE RELEVANT ASPECTS OF THE SOCIOLOGY OF THE
COMMUNITY IS ESSENTIAL TO THE DESIGN OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, POLICIES AND GOALS,
AND TO THE MEANINGFUL INTERPRETATION OF STUDIES OF <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> AND <Organization>USER</Organization>
PATTERNS. DESCRIBES BRIEFLY AN INTELLIGENCE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>
DESIGNED TO PROVIDE <Organization>THIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5633
A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE BEHAVIOUR OF USERS OF THE SERVICES OF A SPECIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

REPORT OF AN INVESTIGATION CARRIED OUT <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> NUCLEAR ENERGY
<Organization>RESEARCH INSTITUTE</Organization> (INSTITUTO DE PESQUISAS ENERGETICAS E NUCLEARES) IN 1979,
TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> REASONS FOR LOW <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE SCIENTIFIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION SERVICES</Organization>, FOR <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND REORGANISATION PURPOSES. A
PRELIMINARY REVIEW OF RECENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> STUDIES IS PRESENTED.
DATA WAS COLLECTED BY QUESTIONNAIRE AND <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>STATISTICAL RECORDS</Organization>. RESULTS ARE
REPORTED IN FULL, <Organization>GIVING</Organization> DETAILS OF <Organization>USER</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS; HABITS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
FREQUENTATION; <Organization>USE</Organization> OF SERVICES; <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PUBLICATIONS; AND THE INFLUENCE
OF <Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HABITS. THE INITIAL HYPOTHESES, THAT SERVICES WERE
NOT GEARED TO <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> HABITS <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> ADEQUATE FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> NEEDS, AND
THAT PREVIOUS <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> INCREASED <Organization>USE</Organization>, WERE BORNE OUT. THE NEED TO PROMOTE
SERVICES IS EMPHASISED IN CONCLUSION.
********************************************
Document 5634
EVALUATING COLLECTIONS BY <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>,
<Location>NEW YORK</Location>, JULY 80. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> METHODS OF EVALUATING A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
IN TERMS OF THE VOLUME AND TYPE OF <Organization>USE</Organization> IT RECEIVES. DESCRIBES THE FINDINGS OF
SEVERAL STUDIES OF CIRCULATION PATTERNS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> DERIVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> MACHINE
<Organization>READABLE RECORDS</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE APPLICATION, AND RELATIVE ADVANTAGES AND
DISADVANTAGES OF 2 TYPES OF STUDIES OF <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> USE-DOCUMENT DELIVERY TESTS,
AND SHELF AVAILABILITY STUDIES. INDICATES <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE PROBLEMS AND LIMITATIONS
ASSOCIATED WITH <Organization>SUCH</Organization> STUDIES, AND POINTS OUT THAT A CONSIDERABLE ADVANCE WILL
BE MADE WHEN THE METHODOLOGIES NOW APPLIED TO ONE-TIME EVALUATIONS ARE
MODIFIED SO THAT THEY CAN BE <Organization>USED</Organization> IN CONTINUOUS MONITORING OF PERFORMANCE.
********************************************
Document 5635
THE EFFECTIVENESS OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO USERS&apos; THE CASE OF THE <Organization>POLYTECHNIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, IBADAN.

(<Organization>MLS</Organization> THESIS). ATTEMPTS TO MEASURE THE EFFECTIVENESS OF THE SERVICES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>POLYTECHNIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>AT</Organization> IBADAN (<Location>NIGERIA</Location>), TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> USERS AND EMPLOYING <Organization>READER</Organization>
SATISFACTION AS THE TEST OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EFFECTIVENESS VIA A QUESTIONNAIRE
TECHNIQUE.
********************************************
Document 5636
AROUSING AN INTEREST OR LOVE IN READERS, LITERARY CHILDREN AND YOUTH.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> WAYS IN WHICH TO MAKE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MORE APPEALING. THE NEED TO TALK
TO CHILDREN AND DISCOVER <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INTERESTS IS STRESSED. A LACK OF INTEREST IN
BOOKS IS OFTEN A RESULT OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> DIFFICULTIES IN THE CHILD&apos;S OWN READING
ABILITIES. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> SURVEYS DONE <Organization>ON</Organization> WHAT READING MATTER APPEALS MOST TO
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>AGE</Organization> GROUPS.
********************************************
Document 5637
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>: THE LITERACY PLACE.

BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A SPEECH GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>OTTAWA LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> CONFERENCE, OCT 81.
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>ONTARIO</Location> WERE CONTACTED IN ORDER TO INVESTIGATE CHILDREN&apos;S
LITERACY PROJECTS. SPECIAL PROGRAMMES WERE FOUND <Organization>AT</Organization> ETOBICOKE, NORTH <Location>YORK</Location> AND
<Location>LONDON</Location>. <Location>WINDSOR</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SPECIALISES IN READING TO CHILDREN. <Organization>SOME</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OFFER PRACTICAL WORKSHOPS; DO THEY HELP LITERACY? AUTHOR SUSAN
GLAZER SPECIFIES 7 LANGUAGE EXERCISES&apos; LISTENING; WRITING; ACTING; PLAYING;
CONSTRUCTING; READING; THINKING. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD SUPPLY <Organization>ALL</Organization> SITUATIONS
CONDUCIVE TO <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, E.G. STORY HOURS, BOOK MAKING, DRAMA GROUPS,
CRAFTS. OBSERVATION OF THE CHILDREN AND OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ATTENTION AND <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization>, AND
CONTACT WITH PARENTS, ARE ADVISED.
********************************************
Document 5638
BIBLIOTHERAPY&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN THE TREATMENT OF THE SICK.

AN INTRODUCTION TO BIBLIOTHERAPY-THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF BOOKS AND <Organization>RELATED</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN THE
TREATMENT OF THE SICK. <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> SELECTED ACTIVITY INVOLVING PLANNED, CONDUCTED,
CONTROLLED READING, BIBLIOTHERAPY MAY BE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO DEAL WITH EMOTIONAL AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
PROBLEMS. DESCRIBES THE <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization> IN WHICH BIBLIOTHERAPY MAY BE <Organization>USED</Organization>, AND
THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S ROLE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE TREATMENT TEAM WITHIN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AN INSTITUTION.
********************************************
Document 5639
LOTKA&apos;S TEST.

PRESENTS A STEP-BY-STEP PROCEDURE FOR TESTING IF A GIVEN SET OF AUTHOR
<Organization>PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization> CONFORMS TO LOTKA&apos;S LAW. THE STEPS <Organization>PROPOSED</Organization> ARE&apos; <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
OF DATA; DETERMINATION OF THE SLOPE +N; CALCULATION OF THE CONSTANT +C; AND
APPLICATION OF KOLMOGOROV-SMIROV ONE SAMPLE GOODNESS-OF-FIT TEST TO
EXPERIMENTAL AND CALCULATED DATA.
********************************************
Document 5640
NORDINFO COURSE IN BIBLIOMETRICS, 1981-10-26-29, HANASSARI, <Location>HELSINKI</Location>,
<Organization>SWEDISH-FINNISH CULTURAL CENTRE</Organization> (IN <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>).

DESCRIBES THE DISCIPLINE OF BIBLIOMETRICS WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO A NORDINFO COURSE
ATTENDED IN <Location>HELSINKI</Location>. DEFINES BIBLIOMETRICS AS QUANTITATIVE MEASUREMENT OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TECHNIQUES. BIBLIOMETRIC METHODS CAN BE <Organization>USED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A GLOBAL SCALE, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
THEY CAN <Organization>ALSO</Organization> BE A TOOL TO CALCULATE THE BEST <Organization>USE</Organization> OF AN INDIVIDUAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S
RESOURCES. AMONG THE EMPIRICAL LAWS DEVELOPED, <Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S LAW IS THE MOST
APPLICABLE. DESCRIBES THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> LAW TO OBTAIN A GRAPH WITH AN
EXPONENTIALLY INCREASING PART, A SO-CALLED <Location>BRADFORD</Location> GRAPH. <Organization>THIS</Organization> CAN SHOW THE
RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> AUTHORS AND NUMBER OF ARTICLES, ARTICLES AND QUOTATIONS
AND CAN HELP TO DETERMINE THE <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> OF OBSOLESCENCE OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN A
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> BIBLIOMETRIC LAWS ARE THOSE OF LOTKA AND ZIPF. THE METHODS ARE
USEFUL IN ACQUISITION, <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> OF SPACE ALLOCATION, WITHDRAWALS, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>,
AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREAS OF <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5641
COMPUTER PROGRAMS FOR ANALYSIS OF BIBLIOMETRIC DISTRIBUTIONS.

(<Organization>MSC DISSERTATION-CITY UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>LONDON</Location>). A SUITE OF COMPUTER PROGRAMS IS
GIVEN FOR THE ANALYSIS OF AUTHOR AND JOURNAL <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization>. THE PROGRAMS
WERE WRITTEN USING SUBPROGRAMS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> PACKAGE FOR THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
SCIENCES, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization>, AND USING THE FORTRAN PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE. THE
AUTHOR <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization> PROGRAMS 1ST <Organization>PROCESS RAW AUTHOR PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization>
(CONSISTING OF AUTHOR CODES AND ARTICLE NUMBERS). THEN THE WEIBULL, NEGATIVE
BINOMIAL AND 2 FORMS OF THE LOTKA DISTRIBUTION ARE COMPARED WITH THE OBSERVED
DISTRIBUTIONS OF AUTHOR <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization>, USING THE CHI SQUARED AND
KOLMOGOROV-SMIRNOV GOODNESS-OF-FIT TESTS. THE JOURNAL <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization> PROGRAMS
<Organization>ALLOW RAW JOURNAL PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization> (CONSISTING OF JOURNAL CODES AND ARTICLE
NUMBERS) TO BE <Organization>PROCESSED</Organization>. THE <Organization>PROCESSED DATA</Organization> IS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO PLOT <Location>BRADFORD</Location>, YIELD
FORMULA AND NARANAN <Organization>GRAPHS BY COMPUTER</Organization>. REASONS FOR CHOOSING <Organization>THESE</Organization> AUTHOR AND
JOURNAL <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization> DISTRIBUTIONS ARE G IVEN, AND APPLICATIONS OF THE
PROGRAMS IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREAS OF BIBLIOMETRICS ARE EXAMINED. FINALLY, USEFUL
DEVELOPMENTS TO THE SUITE OF PROGRAMS ARE CONSIDERED.
********************************************
Document 5642
<Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S LAW OF BIBLIOGRAPHIC SCATTER.

ANALYSES THE AMBIGUITY INHERENT IN <Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S LAW, AND ATTRIBUTES <Organization>THIS</Organization> TO THE
INCONSISTENCIES <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE VERBAL AND GRAPHICAL FORMS OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> EXPRESSION.
DEMONSTRATES HOW BRADFORD&apos;S LAW CAN BE REWRITTEN SO THAT THEORY AND EMPIRICAL
RESULTS WILL CORRESPOND EXACTLY. TO EXTEND THE PRACTICAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A
MATHEMATICAL MODEL, INTRODUCES THE CONCEPTS OF NORMAL SITUATION AND
NORMALISATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, AND USES ZIPF&apos;S 2ND LAW TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> A MODEL VALID
FOR NORMAL SITUATIONS <Organization>BUT</Organization> WITH WIDER APPLICATION AND GREATER OBJECTIVITY THAN
<Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S.
********************************************
Document 5643
THE SCATTER OF ARTICLES ACCORDING TO BRADFORD&apos;S LAW OF SCATTER&apos; A BIBLIOMETRIC
ANALYSIS.

REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> CARRIED OUT TO VERIFY BRADFORD&apos;S LAW IN A PARTICULAR CASE
AND COMPILE AS <Organization>COMPLETE</Organization> A BIBLIOGRAPHY AS POSSIBLE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> BRADFORD&apos;S
LAW. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF HOW THE REFERENCES WERE COLLECTED, USING <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>
COLLECTIONS IN THE <Organization>SAO PAULO UNIVERSITY</Organization>, AND CALCULATIONS PRESENTED IN FULL.
THE RESULTS OBTAINED WERE IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE LAW.
********************************************
Document 5644
COMIC STRIPS AND COMICS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>?.

THE BAVARIAN SECTION OF THE VEREIN DER BIBLIOTHEKARE AN OFFENTLICHEN
BIBLIOTHEKEN (ASSOCIATION OF LIBRARIANS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) HELD AN ADVANCED
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SESSION IN MAR 82 <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMICS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> STORIES IN PICTURE
FORM IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. SUBJECTS DISCUSSED INCLUDED&apos; THE HISTORY OF COMICS IN THE
<Location>USA</Location>, <Location>FRANCE</Location> AND GERMANY; TERMINOLOGY; MARKETING AND PRODUCTION; PURCHASING;
AND THE USES OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> TYPE OF MATERIAL FOR ADULTS, YOUNG CHILDREN AND TEENAGERS
IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. POPULAR THEMES IN COMICS INCLUDE ADVENTURE, TRAVEL,
ANIMALS AND MEN AND SUPERMAN INVOLVED IN THE CONQUEST OF EVIL. WHILE A
REGRETTABLE TENDENCY TOWARDS VIOLENT AND AGGRESSIVE MATERIAL IS APPARENT, THE
TENDENCY IS OFTEN LESS STRONG HERE THAN IN <Organization>OTHER MEDIA</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5645
<Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> ACCESS TO <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION ANNUAL CONFERENCE, JUNE 81. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE PROBLEMS
CONCERNED WITH THE SUCCESSFUL IDENTIFICATION AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> OF <Location>US</Location> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
PUBLICATIONS. DESCRIBES AN &apos;IDEAL&apos; <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> ACCESS TO <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
PUBLICATIONS, AND OUTLINES AN <Organization>ACTION</Organization> PROGRAMME FOR ACHIEVING <Organization>THIS</Organization>. HIGHLIGHTS
THE IMPORTANCE OF&apos; ASSESSING THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS OF POTENTIAL CLIENTELE;
PUBLICISING AND ENCOURAGING THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>; OBTAINING SUFFICIENT
RESOURCES; <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>; <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> THE COMPREHENSIVENESS AND SIMPLICITY OF
THE SYSTEMS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO ACCESS THE PUBLICATIONS; AND MAINTENANCE OF THE
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5646
OFFICIAL <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS AND BIBLIOGRAPHIC WORK <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
PARLIAMENTARY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

ARTICLE PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ANNUAL MEETING OF IFLA, <Organization>GENERAL RESEARCH COUNCIL</Organization>,
1981. BRIEFLY DESCRIBES THE HISTORY OF THE 2ANNUAL BIBLIOGRAPHY OF <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
OFFICIAL PUBLICATIONS1 WHICH 1ST APPEARED IN 1934 COVERING THE YEARS 1931-33.
IT WAS FOLLOWED BY ANNUAL VOLUMES COMPILED BY THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PARLIAMENTARY
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WHICH RECEIVED A DEPOSIT COPY OF EVERY PRINTED OFFICIAL DOCUMENT. THE
2ANNUAL BIBLIOGRAPHY1 HAS ALWAYS BEEN <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> IN A <Organization>CONVENTIONAL</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization>. HOWEVER
AN <Organization>AUDIT GROUP</Organization> IS INVESTIGATING WHETHER IT SHOULD BE INSERTED INTO THE LIBRIS
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, <Organization>USED</Organization> BY <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5647
THE LUMLEY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; A SUPPLEMENTARY CHECKLIST.

PRESENTS <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> 89 PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF JOHN, LORD
LUMLEY (1534-1609), GLEANED SINCE THE PUBLICATION OF THE 1609 <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> OF THE
LUMLEY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> GIVEN IN THE NOTES FALLS INTO 4 CATEGORIES&apos;
ADDITIONAL BOOKS AND MANUSCRIPTS BEARING LUMLEY&apos;S OWNERSHIP INSCRIPTION
IDENTIFIED SINCE THE 1956 PUBLICATION OF THE <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>; 5 ITEMS, NOT YET
LOCATED, WHICH ARE LISTED IN THE <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>OLD</Organization> ROYAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OR IN
BURBRIDGE AS OF CRANMER PROVENANCE; <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, CHIEFLY RELATING TO
PROVENANCE, ABOUT LUMLEY BOOKS ALREADY LISTED; AND NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> RECENTLY CHANGED
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHELF-MARKS. DETAILED NOTES ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF THE 89 WORKS,
AND OF 7 OTHERS NOT LISTED IN THE 1609 <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5648
THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF TURKISH PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE. THE
BEGINNINGS OF OTTOMAN <Organization>PRINTING</Organization> (PART 1).

A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> MARKING THE CENTENARY OF THE BIRTH OF KEMEL ATATURK. A DETAILED
ACCOUNT IS GIVEN OF THE VISITS MADE BY TURKISH LEADERS TO THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> COURT IN
THE LATE 17TH AND EARLY 18TH CENTURIES, WHICH RESULTED IN THE ESTABLISHMENT OF
THE 1ST <Organization>PRINTING PRESS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN CONSTANTINOPLE IN 1727, WITH THE
OBJECTIVE OF ENCOURAGING A TURKISH CULTURE INDEPENDENT OF ARAB INFLUENCE.
INCLUDES A DETAILED DESCRIPTIVE LIST OF 17 <Organization>TITLES PRODUCED AT THIS PRESS</Organization>, HELD
IN THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5649
THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF TURKISH PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE. THE
BEGINNINGS OF OTTOMAN <Organization>PRINTING</Organization>. PART 2.

CONCLUSION OF AN ARTICLE BEGUN IN REVUE DE <Location>LA</Location> BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE I (I)
(SEE PRECEDING ABSTRACT), DESCRIBING 17 NOTABLE PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
CONSTANTINOPLE IN THE EARLY 18TH CENTURY BY THE PRINTER MUTEFERRIKA. DETAILS
ARE GIVEN OF SUBJECT MATTER, AUTHORS, AND HISTORICAL BACKGROUND, WITH
BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE BIBLIOGRAPHIC DETAILS. <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> WITH A BRIEF
DISCUSSION OF THE ACHIEVEMENTS OF KEMAL ATATURK IN <Organization>PROMOTING EDUCATION</Organization> AND THE
EUROPEANISATION OF <Location>TURKEY</Location>, WITH A SKETCH OF MODERN BOOK PRODUCTION AND THE
AVAILABILITY OF RARE EDITIONS.
********************************************
Document 5650
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AND REGIONAL COLLECTIONS.

<Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF A 1978 CONFERENCE PAPER DISCUSSING ORGANISATION AND MANAGEMENT
POLICIES. CONSIDERS FIRSTLY THE <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> CONSTITUTING A <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IN
RELATION TO GEOGRAPHICAL RELEVANCE AND CRITERIA FOR SELECTION&apos; WORKS BY <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
AUTHORS, <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> BY <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> PRINTERS, OR DEALING WITH <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> SUBJECTS, ARE
CONSIDERED, AS WELL AS OFFICIAL ADMINISTRATIVE PUBLICATIONS AND EPHEMERA. THEN
PROBLEMS OF EXPLOITATION AND CONSERVATION ARE EXAMINED, IN AN ATTEMPT TO
RECONCILE ARCHIVAL RESPONSIBILITIES WITH <Organization>USER</Organization> NEEDS&apos; THE RANGE OF POTENTIAL
USERS, <Organization>FROM</Organization> SCHOLARLY RESEARCHERS TO INTERESTED NON-SPECIALISTS, IS DISCUSSED
IN RELATION TO PREPARATION OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> TOOLS PERMITTING MULTIPLE ACCESS
TO THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> TO CATER FOR VARIED APPROACHES; BASIC COMMONSENSE
PRECAUTIONS ARE SUGGESTED FOR MINIMISING DAMAGE TO BOOK <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, AND SPECIAL
MEASURES FOR MINOR DOCUMENTS <Organization>PROPOSED</Organization>. EMPHASISES THAT <Organization>EACH</Organization> LIBRARIAN MUST
EVOLVE HIS OWN POLICY TO MEET HIS OWN PARTICULAR SITUATION.
********************************************
Document 5651
STANDARDS OF PROVISION FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> STUDIES. REPORT &amp; POLICY STATEMENT.

REPORT OF A <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization>, OF THE LANCASHIRE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, TO EXAMINE <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS
OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> STUDIES AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> HISTORY WITHIN THE COUNTY.
********************************************
Document 5652
TOOLS OF THE <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> TRADE.

ANNOTATED BIBLIOGRAPHY, BY VARIOUS REVIEWERS, OF ITEMS RELATING TO <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>
LIBRARIANSHIP. ITEMS FALL INTO THE FOLLOWING MAIN CATEGORIES-COLLECTION
DEVELOPMENT-LIBRARIES; <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>-PERIODICALS; <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>;
PRESENTATION; AND SERIAL PUBLICATIONS-BIBLIOGRAPHY.
********************************************
Document 5653
A QUANTITATIVE AND QUALITATIVE EVALUATION OF THE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IN THE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>SAO PAULO</Location>.

REPORT OF A PILOT <Organization>STUDY</Organization> CARRIED OUT IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>SAO
PAULO</Location> INSTITUTE OF BIOMEDICAL SCIENCES, AS A PRELIMINARY TO A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization>
INVESTIGATION OF PERIODICAL RESOURCES THROUGHOUT THE UNIVERSITY, PRIOR TO THE
INTEGRATION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE <Organization>UNIVERSITY LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE
INSTITUTE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN RELATION TO PARTICULAR CHARACTERISTICS RENDERING IT
ATYPICAL OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AS A WHOLE. THE OBJECTIVES, METHODOLOGY, DATA
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> PROCEDURES, CALCULATIONS AND RESULTS OF THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> ARE PRESENTED IN
FULL, WITH ACCOMPANYING TABLES AND DIAGRAMS. MODIFICATIONS NECESSARY FOR
APPLYING THE PILOT PROCEDURES TO THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> ARE NOTED, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
<Organization>ALL</Organization> CIRCUMSTANCES AND CONDITIONS, <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization>, HUMAN, AND FINANCIAL, OBSERVED
DURING THE COURSE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> TESTING PHASE.
********************************************
Document 5654
EVALUATION OF THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PERIODICAL <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF RIO GRANDE DO SUL.

REPORT, PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A CONFERENCE IN 1979, BY A <Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> SET UP TO
INVESTIGATE PERIODICAL COLLECTIONS THROUGHOUT THE <Organization>FEDERAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> OF RIO
GRANDE DO SUL, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF DATA <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> PROCEDURES, AND
<Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND ANALYSIS TECHNIQUES. THE RESULTS SHOWED THAT THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> DID NOT ADEQUATELY MEET <Organization>USER</Organization> NEEDS. CONCLUDING
RECOMMENDATIONS COVER THE POINTS REQUIRING IMMEDIATE ATTENTION, AND LISTS OF
CRITERIA ARE PRESENTED FOR EVALUATING INDIVIDUAL PERIODICAL <Organization>USE</Organization> AND THE STATE
OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AS A WHOLE, TO PERMIT <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> EVALUATION.
********************************************
Document 5655
<Organization>PERIODICALS SUPPORTING LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE BLIND AND PHYSICALLY
HANDICAPPED.

ANNOTATED BIBLIOGRAPHY OF <Organization>PERIODICALS SUPPORTING LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE BLIND
AND PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED. ITEMS FALL INTO THE FOLLOWING MAIN CATEGORIES&apos;
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization>; FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> PROVIDERS; AND FOR PRINT HANDICAPPED READERS.
********************************************
Document 5656
ROLE OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS IN SCI-TECH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>).S

PECIAL <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO THE ROLE OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS IN <Location>US</Location> SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. FOR ABSTRACTS OF THE INDIVIDUAL ARTICLES, 2SEE1 THE
FOLLOWING SERIAL NUMBERS&apos;-.
********************************************
Document 5657
THE TRUE FACTS ABOUT CENSORSHIP?.

REPLY TO AN ARTICLE BY E.J. GROESKAMP IN BIBLIOTHEEK EN SAMENLEVING 9 (12) DEC
81, 333-337 (FOR AN ABSTRACT OF WHICH 2SEE1 82/4167), IN WHICH ATTENTION WAS
DRAWN TO THE HIDDEN CENSORSHIP PRACTISED BY <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. GROESKAMP&apos;S
DEFINITION OF CENSORSHIP SHOULD MORE PROPERLY BE TERMED &apos;REJECTION <Organization>ON</Organization> ETHICAL
GROUNDS&apos;. BECAUSE OF LACK OF SPACE AND FINANCIAL RESOURCES, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CANNOT
PURCHASE <Organization>ALL</Organization> BOOKS PUBLISHED AND SELECTION IS NECESSARY TO OBTAIN A BALANCED
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF MATERIAL. THE FACTS <Organization>ON</Organization> WHICH GROESKAMP&apos;S ARGUMENTS ARE BASED
INCLUDE 2 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SURVEYS, OF WHICH 1 <Organization>CONTAINED INSUFFICIENT DATA</Organization> TO DRAW ANY
FIRM CONCLUSIONS, WHILE THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> RESULTS IN CONFLICT WITH
GROESKAMP&apos;S DEDUCTIONS. FOR FINANCIAL REASONS IT IS TO BE EXPECTED THAT IN A
COMMUNITY OF 1 RELIGIOUS PERSUASION FEW BOOKS OF A <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> PERSUASION ARE
LIKELY TO BE FOUND IN THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5658
INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE 2ND INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE OF TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>STOCKHOLM</Location> 1981 INCLUDED
PAPERS, LECTURES, WORKSHOPS, AN EXTENSIVE TOY EXHIBITION, AND VISITS TO
HOSPITALS, <Organization>DAY</Organization> NURSERIES, CLINICS, PRESCHOOLS AND TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. APART <Organization>FROM</Organization>
LOANING TOYS, A TOY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AIMS TO ADVISE AND STIMULATE <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> PLAY,
PARTICULARLY TO DEPRIVED FAMILIES. VISITS (IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>) ARE BY APPOINTMENT AND
DOCTOR&apos;S REFERRAL. TOYS ARE SELECTED ACCORDING TO THE CHILD&apos;S <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> NEEDS.
SIBLINGS ARE INVOLVED. COUNTRIES ESPECIALLY SUPPORTING TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> INCLUDE
<Location>DENMARK</Location>, <Location>SWEDEN</Location>, <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>, <Location>ICELAND</Location>, <Location>UK</Location> AND ITALY. <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE
RARELY INVOLVED.
********************************************
Document 5659
TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>. A REPORT WITH SPECIAL ATTENTION TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE IN
SERVICES FOR YOUNG HANDICAPPED CHILDREN AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES.

THE GROWTH OF TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> HAS BEEN RAPID AND EXTENSIVE DURING
THE 70S AND TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE BEEN ESTABLISHED IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> STATES AND TERRITORIES.
HOWEVER, EVIDENCE POINTS TO A LACK OF AWARENESS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PART OF LAY PEOPLE AND
PROFESSIONALS ABOUT THE PURPOSES AND FUNCTIONS OF TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; ESPECIALLY IN
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE OF SERVING HANDICAPPED CHILDREN AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES. THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> IS TO HELP OVERCOME <Organization>THIS</Organization> LACK OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND BE OF ASSISTANCE TO
POLICY MAKERS AND THOSE <Organization>DEVELOPING SERVICES</Organization> WHICH IMPINGE <Organization>ON</Organization> AREAS IN WHICH
TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE PRESENTLY INVOLVED.
********************************************
Document 5660
<Organization>AUDIOVISUAL</Organization> AIDS IN THE <Location>FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF GERMANY</Location>.

IN THE PAST 10 YEARS <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> AIDS HAVE BECOME AN ESSENTIAL PART OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SUPPLIES</Organization> OFFERED IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>. <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SAME TIME THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>AID</Organization>
MEDIA HAVE DEVELOPED IN <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> DIRECTIONS. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> AIDS
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN <Organization>SOUND RECORDING MEDIA</Organization>, VIDEO AND SLIDES AND FILMS. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> MENTIONS
THE SERVICES OF THE EINKAUFSZENTRALE FUR OFFENTLICH BIBLIOTHEKEN REVIEWING AND
READING DEPARTMENTS AND THE DIFFICULTIES OF <Organization>CATALOGUING SOUND RECORDING MEDIA</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5661
<Organization>NATIONAL SERVICE</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>AUDIOVISUAL MEDIA</Organization>. THE
SITUATION IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENTS IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> WHICH HAVE LEAD TO THE INCLUSION
OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA</Organization> IN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>CENTRAL SERVICES</Organization> TO
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD. MENTIONS PROBLEMS REGARDING THE INCLUSION OF
<Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE EFFECTS OF THE 1975 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> WHICH MADE PROVISION FOR <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, THE WORK OF THE
NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
CENTRE) AND <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> PRODUCTION <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF THE <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA SERVICE</Organization>.
SINCE 1981 THE NBLC HAS PROVIDED A <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization> SUPPLY OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>THIS SERVICE</Organization> HAS ENABLED <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO IMPROVE
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> STOCK.
********************************************
Document 5662
SERVICES AND <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR THE HANDICAPPED&apos; AN INSTITUTE FOR SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MEDIA PROFESSIONALS (DEKALB, ILLINOIS, AUGUST 12-17, 1979).

CONTAINS A NARRATIVE AND 2 EVALUATIONS OF A <Organization>WEEK-LONG INSTITUTE ON MEDIA</Organization>
SERVICES FOR HANDICAPPED STUDENTS WHICH WAS HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> NORTHERN ILLINOIS
UNIVERSITY. PURPOSES OF THE INSTITUTE WERE TO&apos; (1) EXTEND THE ABILITIES OF
<Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA</Organization> PROFESSIONALS TO PROVIDE MEDIA SERVICES TO HANDICAPPED
CHILDREN; (2) SUPPLY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> SOURCES OF <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> ESPECIALLY PERTINENT
FOR THE HANDICAPPED; (3) PROVIDE PARTICIPANTS WITH THE EXPERTISE NECESSARY TO
<Organization>PRESENT</Organization> IN-SERVICE SESSIONS FOR <Organization>TEACHERS ON SERVICE</Organization> TO THE HANDICAPPED; (4)
HELP PARTICIPANTS COMMUNICATE WITH PARENTS OF HANDICAPPED CHILDREN ABOUT
<Organization>AVAILABLE SERVICES</Organization>; AND (5) STIMULATE GREATER INITIATIVE AND INVOLVEMENT IN
<Organization>THIS</Organization> ASPECT OF <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA SERVICES</Organization>. PARTICIPANTS IN THE INSTITUTE
WERE PROFESSIONALS INVOLVED IN THE APPLICATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY MEDIA SERVICES</Organization> AND
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN RELATION TO SPECIAL EDUCATI <Organization>ON</Organization>. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5663
<Location>U.S.</Location> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> <Organization>AUDIOVISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>.

<Location>US</Location> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> OFFER A VALUABLE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
RESOURCE WHICH IS OFTEN OVERLOOKED BY LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS. THE
LIBRARIAN WHO IS KNOWLEDGEABLE ABOUT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> AVAILABILITY WILL BE ABLE TO BRING
<Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> TO THE ATTENTION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PATRONS TO WHOM THEY
COULD BE USEFUL. KNOWLEDGE OF THE INDEXES AND LISTS WHICH HAVE BEEN SPECIALLY
COMPILED FOR <Organization>THESE</Organization> RESOURCES WILL MAKE THEM AS ACCESSIBLE AS THE MORE FAMILIAR
PRINT <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DOCUMENTS.
********************************************
Document 5664
MICROGRAPHICS AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. A GRADUATE COURSE.

THE <Organization>COMPLETE</Organization> SYLLABUS FOR A 15-SESSION COURSE IN MICROGRAPHICS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
ACQUISITION, HANDLING, INTERPRETATION, AND UTILISATION IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS
PRESENTED. SEMINAR TOPICS COVER THE SELECTION OF EQUIPMENT, MICROFORM
STANDARDS, COM, RESOURCES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> MICROFORM, MICROPUBLISHING, RECORDS
MANAGEMENT LABORATORIES, BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL OF MICROFORMS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
INDUSTRY, AND THE CREATION AND EVALUATION OF THE MICROFORM ENVIRONMENT. REPORT
NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5665
CONVERSION OF <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> PAPER TO MICROFORM.

EXAMINES THE ADVANTAGES TRADITIONALLY ASCRIBED TO MICROFORMAT <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS
COST AND SPACE SAVING, PERMANENCE, AND EASE OF HANDLING, IN THE LIGHT OF NEW
COST COMPARISONS, CONTINUED <Organization>USER</Organization> RESISTANCE AND THE UNCERTAIN RESULTS OF
PERMANENCE STUDIES.
********************************************
Document 5666
VIDEOCASSETTE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> MORGANTOWN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

DESCRIBES THE VIDEOCASSETTE MOVIE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> MORGANTOWN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
WEST <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization>, WITH DETAILS OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> MOST POPULAR ITEMS. DURING <Organization>ITS</Organization> 1ST
YEAR THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> GREW TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> TARGET OF 100 CASSETTES, AND THE CORE
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS EXPANDING <Organization>FURTHER</Organization>. CIRCULATION FIGURES HAVE RISEN STEEPLY.
MOVIES ARE RATED BEFORE SCREENING, AND THERE ARE <Organization>SOME</Organization> RESTRICTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>
BORROWING, WITH CHECKS <Organization>ON</Organization> PATRONS COPYING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S VIDEOCASSETTES AND
SWITCHING COPIES WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN.
********************************************
Document 5667
THE <Organization>VIDEOGRAM</Organization> REPORT-PUBLISHED TOO LATE?.

THE <Organization>VIDEOGRAM COMMISSION</Organization>&apos;S REPORT <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD BE
DISTRIBUTION CENTRES FOR A BROAD SUPPLY OF GOOD QUALITY VIDEO RECORDINGS, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
VIDEO HAS ALREADY BECOME A MASS MARKET ARTICLE <Organization>SUPPLIED THROUGH INTERNATIONAL</Organization>
DISTRIBUTION CHANNELS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE LITTLE CHANCE OF MAKING AN IMPACT. A
<Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> OF REPRESENTATIVES OF <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization>, THE VIDMO-GROUP,
WAS FORMED ALREADY IN 1973; IT HOPED TO START EXPERIMENTS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH
PRODUCTION AND SHOWING OF VIDEOGRAMS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> TRADE UNION OPPOSITION MEANT THAT
THE <Organization>SWEDISH BROADCASTING CORPORATION</Organization>&apos;S PROGRAMMES COULD NOT BE <Organization>USED</Organization>. <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
REPORTS HAVE APPEARED POINTING TO THE ADVANTAGES OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS DISTRIBUTORS
OF VIDEO, <Organization>BUT WITHOUT STATE FINANCIAL</Organization> SUPPORT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WILL NEVER BE
ABLE TO FULFIL <Organization>THIS</Organization> ROLE. <Organization>SOME</Organization> AREAS ARE, HOWEVER, OPEN TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, PROVIDED
THEY COOPERATE WITH <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ORGANISATIONS&apos; VIDEOGRAMS FOR THE
DEAF AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> HANDICAPPED; VIDEOGRAMS <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization>  DIRECTLY FOR THE MEDIUM BY
ARTISTS AND MEDIA WORKSHOPS; VIDEOGRAMS FOR CHILDREN; FOR EDUCATION IN
COOPERATION WITH THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL RADIO</Organization> AND THE <Organization>AV CENTRE</Organization>; AND LOCALLY <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization>
MATERIAL FOR VIDEO.
********************************************
Document 5668
THE IMPACT OF <Organization>USER</Organization> FRUSTRATION OF HUMANITIES <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.

REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> TO PROVIDE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE CONSEQUENCE OF <Organization>USER</Organization>
FRUSTRATION AMONG HUMANITIES FACULTIES CAUSED BY <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> INADEQUACY <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>VIRGINIA POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE</Organization> AND STATE UNIVERSITY. RESULTS INDICATE THAT
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> FRUSTRATION DOES EXIST, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE LACK OF A STRONG HUMANITIES <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS
NOT DEEMED TO BE AN UNSURMOUNTABLE IMPEDIMENT TO <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. THE FREEDOM AND
ENCOURAGEMENT TO TRAVEL TO PRIMARY SOURCES AND A COMFORTABLE WORK ENVIRONMENT
WITH <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization>, <Organization>EFFECTIVE SERVICES</Organization> IS MOST IMPORTANT.
********************************************
Document 5669
THE VISNEWS FILM <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

VISNEWS IS 1 OF THE WORLD&apos;S <Organization>LEADING NEWSFILM AGENCIES</Organization> AND <Organization>SUPPLIES</Organization> MATERIAL TO
TV STATIONS. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>LONDON</Location> IS HELD TO BE THE LARGEST AND MOST
<Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> KIND. IT HAS A UNIQUE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF NEWSFILM <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF
WHICH DATES BACK TO 1896&apos; BESIDES <Organization>ITS</Organization> OWN <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IT OWNS 5 <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization>
CINEMA NEWSREEL COLLECTIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PAST. AN EXTENSIVE CARD INDEX <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>
THE COLLECTIONS UNDER A VARIETY OF HEADINGS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS SUBJECT, LOCATION,
PERSONALITIES ETC. MUCH OF THE <Organization>OLD NITRATE HOLDINGS</Organization> ARE NOW <Organization>ON</Organization> VIDEO <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PREFERS TO KEEP MATERIAL <Organization>ON</Organization> FILM. VIEWING FACILITIES ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> AND
COMPILATION OF ANY VISNEWS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIAL IS POSSIBLE <Organization>ON</Organization> PAYMENT.
********************************************
Document 5670
THE MANAGEMENT AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>&apos; AN INTERDISCIPLINARY
CROSS-CITATION ANALYSIS.

A METHOD IS <Organization>PROPOSED</Organization> FOR MEASURING INTERDISCIPLINARY RELATIONS IN SCIENTIFIC
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> CROSS CITATION AMONG CORE JOURNALS EMPIRICALLY SELECTED <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE BASIS OF <Organization>USE</Organization> AND IMPORTANCE. THE METHOD IS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO TEST HYPOTHESES DERIVED
<Organization>FROM</Organization> A BIBLIOMETRIC DEFINITION OF INTERDISCIPLINARITY AMONG THE MANAGEMENT AND
<Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> LITERATURES. THE RESULTS REVEAL THAT THE MANAGEMENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
IS DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> SCIENCES, THAT IS MORE DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THEM THAN VICE
VERSA, AND THAT IT IS MORE DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THEM THAN THEY ARE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5671
<Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COMMUNITIES INFORMATION-HOW TO TRACK IT DOWN AND KEEP PACE WITH IT,
PART 2.

CONTINUATION OF A PREVIOUS ARTICLE (2SEE1 81/5645) WHICH LOOKED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization>
SOURCE <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> RELATING TO THE <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COMMUNITIES. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> BRIEFLY&apos;
SCIENTIFIC, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> PUBLICATIONS; COMMERCIAL <Organization>ABSTRACTING</Organization>
SERVICES; <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>; GRANTS AND <Organization>LOAN</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>; DATA SYSTEMS; <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>
GUIDES; AND <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CENTRES AND DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5672
ABIDING BY THE LAW&apos; LEGAL <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

INCREASINGLY, LAW <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> ARE NEEDED BY AN EVER-WIDENING RANGE OF PEOPLE,
AND SINCE THE SOURCE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MOST READILY <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>AVERAGE</Organization>
PERSON IS THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD BE THE MOST CONVENIENT
LOCATION FOR LEGAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. EXAMINES THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> RIGHT OF ACCESS TO
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WITH REGARD TO INDIVIDUAL LEGAL PRACTICE AND THE ATTITUDES OF
LAWYERS, AND <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> BASIC LEGAL TEXTS FOR A CORE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>. HINTS ARE
GIVEN <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ORGANISATION OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, AND THE MORE IMPORTANT
BIBLIOGRAPHIC AIDS ARE CITED.
********************************************
Document 5673
PICK A TITLE 2&apos; A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF MEDIA ABOUT THE HANDICAPPED.

THE LISTING OF BOOKS, FILMS, <Organization>SOUND</Organization> CASSETTES, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MEDIA ABOUT THE
HANDICAPPED IS DIVIDED INTO 3 INTEREST LEVEL AREAS; PRE-SCHOOL AND PRIMARY,
MIDDLE OR INTERMEDIATE, AND YOUNG ADULT AND ADULT. A SECTION FOR PARENTS
CONTAINS INSTRUCTIONAL <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> IN THE HOME. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> INCLUDED IS A
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> SECTION FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> BY <Organization>TEACHERS</Organization>, SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PEOPLE INVOLVED WITH HANDICAPPED STUDENTS. <Organization>EACH</Organization> CITATION INCLUDES
A PRICE AND A SHORT CONTENT <Organization>SUMMARY</Organization>; THE ADDRESSES OF PUBLISHERS CITED ARE
GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE BIBLIOGRAPHY. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5674
DIACHRONOUS <Organization>VS</Organization>. SYNCHRONOUS <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF OBSOLESCENCE.

(PHD THESIS-UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS <Organization>AT</Organization> URBANA-CHAMPAIGN). A COMPARISON OF 2
WAYS OF MEASURING OBSOLESCENCE WITHIN THE SUBJECT OF HUMAN AND <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
GENETICS. SYNCHRONOUS STUDIES (WHICH ARE MADE <Organization>ON RECORDS</Organization> OF <Organization>USE</Organization> OR
BIBLIOGRAPHIC REFERENCES MADE <Organization>AT</Organization> 1 POINT IN TIME AND COMPARE THE <Organization>USE</Organization> AGAINST
THE <Organization>AGE</Organization> DISTRIBUTION OF THE MATERIAL <Organization>USED</Organization> OR CITED) ARE MORE EASILY APPLIED
AND PRODUCE EQUIVALENT RESULTS TO THE APPARENTLY MORE THEORETICALLY DESIRABLE
DIACHRONOUS STUDIES (WHICH FOLLOW THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF PARTICULAR ITEMS <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
SUCCESSIVE OBSERVATIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> DATES).
********************************************
Document 5675
CITATION ANALYSIS AND BIBLIOMETRIC CHARACTERISTICS OF CORE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>.

A REPORT OF THE PRELIMINARY STAGES OF A SPANISH STATE SPONSORED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
PROJECT. THE ANALYSIS COVERS CITATIONS OF PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> ANTINEOPLASTIC SUBSTANCES
IN 2CANCER <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>1 <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1976-79. A TOTAL OF 7,815 REFERENCES TO 576
<Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> CARRIED IN 284 PAPERS WAS OBTAINED, AND THE <Location>BRADFORD</Location> TECHNIQUE
APPLIED TO ASCERTAIN THE CORE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> RECEIVING AN <Organization>AVERAGE</Organization> OF 1 CITATION
PER MONTH. A COMPARISON WAS THEN MADE <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> CORE AND NON-CORE PERIODICAL
THEMATIC COVERAGE OF 8 ANTINEOPLASTIC SUBSTANCES; AND THE QUANTITATIVE
DIFFERENCE IN DISTRIBUTION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE 2 SETS OF <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> FOR <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND
SPECIFIC THEMATIC DISTRIBUTION ESTABLISHED. FULL DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>ALL</Organization>
CALCULATIONS MADE, AND RESULTS TABULATED. THE RESULTS OBTAINED SHOW THAT ONLY
THE CORE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> CAN SATISFY THE BIBLIOGRAPHIC REQUIREMENTS OF THE FIELD,
AS REGARDS THEMATIC COVERAGE AND CITATION FREQUENCY.
********************************************
Document 5676
ANALYSIS OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> PRODUCTION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>UFMG VETERINARY MEDICINE SCHOOL</Organization>,
<Location>BRAZIL</Location>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1973 TO 1977.

EXTRACT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A POSTGRADUATE DISSERTATION PRESENTED <Organization>AT UFMG LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
<Location>BRAZIL</Location>. THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WAS UNDERTAKEN TO INVESTIGATE THE DIRECTIONS OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
INTERESTS. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE ORGANISATION AND PERSONNEL OF THE SCHOOL.
<Organization>ALL</Organization> PERIODICAL ARTICLES PUBLISHED BY <Organization>STAFF</Organization> WERE ANALYSED BY PLACE OF
PUBLICATION; LANGUAGE; SINGLE AND MULTIPLE AUTHORSHIP; AND SUBJECT
DISTRIBUTION. RESULTS SHOWED THAT THE SCHOOL&apos;S <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROGRAMMES SUPPORTED
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>, STATE AND UNIVERSITY OBJECTIVES.
********************************************
Document 5677
BIBLIOMETRIC STUDIES <Organization>ON</Organization> A PROTEIN-RICH CROP: THE COWPEA.

2 BIBLIOGRAPHIES <Organization>ON</Organization> COWPEAS, ONE COVERING THE PERIOD 1888-1949 AND THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
1950-1973, WERE ANALYSED TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> VARIOUS CHARACTERISTICS OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
RESULTS SHOWED THAT GROWTH OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> HAS BEEN EXPONENTIAL, DOUBLING
EVERY 20 YEARS, WITH THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE ACCOUNTING FOR OVER 87% OF THE
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. THOUGH THE PERIODICAL WAS THE MOST POPULAR PUBLISHING MEDIUM,
FORMAT CHANGES WERE EVIDENT AND BRADFORD DISTRIBUTIONS OF THE 2 GROUPS
RESULTED IN A THIRD <Location>BRADFORD</Location> DISTRIBUTION WHEN MERGED.
********************************************
Document 5678
THE EXAMINATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TRENDS BY ANALYSIS OF PUBLICATION NUMBERS.

DESCRIBES A METHOD <Organization>USED</Organization> TO EXAMINE TRENDS IN <Organization>TEXTILE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> OVER THE PERIOD
1960-79. THE METHOD CONSISTED OF A COUNT OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PAPERS AND PATENTS, IN
SPECIFIC SUBJECT AREAS, USING 2WORLD <Organization>TEXTILE</Organization> ABSTRACTS1, 2CHEMICAL ABSTRACTS1,
2JOURNAL OF THE <Organization>TEXTILE INSTITUTE</Organization>1 AND 2<Organization>TEXTILE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> JOURNAL1 AS SOURCES
OF DATA. THE <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> PROCEDURES <Organization>USED</Organization> TO <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> THE DATA ARE BRIEFLY
INDICATED.
********************************************
Document 5679
THE WORK OF THE <Location>GERMAN DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC</Location>&apos;S BRANCH OF THE INTERNATIONAL
ASSOCIATION OF MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, MUSIC ARCHIVES AND MUSIC <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CENTRES.

THE BRANCH, FOUNDED IN 1959, HAS 27 CORPORATE MEMBERS <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> MUSIC
DEPARTMENTS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, MUSIC <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> CENTRES AND
COLLEGES, SCORE AND RECORD ARCHIVES. THE BRANCH&apos;S TASKS INCLUDE <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>, <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> STANDARDS OF
MUSIC LIBRARIANSHIP, <Organization>PROMOTING</Organization> EXCHANGE AND <Organization>LOAN</Organization> OF MUSIC DOCUMENTS,
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> MUSIC BIBLIOGRAPHY, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND PROTECTING THE
MUSICAL HERITAGE. WORK IS CARRIED OUT <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL LEVELS <Organization>ON</Organization>
MUSICOLOGY, LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>, COOPERATION WITH <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>&apos;S
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization> IN THE PRODUCTION OF THE BIBLIOGRAPHIC
WORK <Organization>REPERTOIRE INTERNATIONAL</Organization> DES SOURCES MUSICALES AND THE QUARTERLY
<Organization>ABSTRACTING SERVICE REPERTOIRE INTERNATIONAL</Organization> DE LITTERATURE MUSICALE BEING
PARTICULARLY IMPORTAN T.
********************************************
Document 5680
MUSIC AND THEATRE COLLECTIONS IN <Location>MADRID</Location> MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS DESCRIBED AS A &apos;HIDDEN JEWEL&apos; IN THE <Organization>OLD</Organization> CITY OF <Location>MADRID</Location>. IT WAS
FOUNDED IN 1876 AND SINCE 1930 HAS SHARED A <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> WITH THE MUNICIPAL
MUSEUM. IT HOUSES THE RICHEST <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF SPANISH MUSIC TO BE FOUND
ANYWHERE, AND MANY <Organization>OLD</Organization> MANUSCRIPTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> HISTORIC <Location>MADRID</Location> THEATRES. THERE ARE
8,430 VALUABLE LIBRETTI AND SCORES, MAINLY OF THE PERIOD 1750-1890, TOGETHER
WITH COLLECTIONS OF MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS, OPERAS AND PLAYS. A <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> WAS
PUBLISHED IN 1965.
********************************************
Document 5681
MURDER IN THE FISHER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>SYDNEY</Location>&apos;S FISHER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HOLDS A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF CRIME FICTION
THAT RANKS 3RD OR 4TH IN SIZE IN THE WORLD-NEARLY 18,000 VOLUMES. DESCRIBES
THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, STARTED IN THE EARLY 1970S. <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization>
MATERIAL <Organization>ON</Organization> THE GENRE HAS BEEN OBTAINED TO <Organization>FACILITATE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
VALUES OFFERED BY CRIME FICTION.
********************************************
Document 5682
REGIONAL COLLABORATION IN THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
<Location>SWEDEN</Location>&apos;S <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE BASICALLY OPERATED BY THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES. THE
STATE CAN PROVIDE GRANTS TO LEVEL OUT STANDARDS <Organization>BUT</Organization> DOES NOT INTERFERE IN THE
RUNNING OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND SWEDEN HAS NO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. MUNICIPAL
AUTHORITIES THEMSELVES DECIDE THE OBJECTIVES, SCALE AND STRUCTURE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. <Organization>ALL</Organization> OF <Location>SWEDEN</Location>&apos;S 279 MUNICIPALITIES PROVIDE MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES. CERTAIN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FUNCTIONS <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE TOO EXPENSIVE TO <Organization>OPERATE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A
PURELY MUNICIPAL BASIS-IT IS THEREFORE RATIONAL AND <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> TO TRANSFER
<Organization>THESE</Organization> TO THE REGIONAL OR SUPRAMUNICIPAL-THAT IS, COUNTY-LEVEL.
********************************************
Document 5683
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization> A <Organization>WAGON LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>SR-</Organization>6 STATE RAILWAY NETWORK, RIO
GRANDE DO SUL, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.

A PROJECT PRESENTED TO THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> RAILWAY BORAD IN 1980, BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> PREVIOUS
EXPERIENCE WITH <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE <Organization>WAGON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>WOULD</Organization> CIRCULATE THROUGHOUT
THE NETWORK HOOKED UP TO A PASSENGER TRAIN; THE POTENTIAL BENEFITS IN
<Organization>PROMOTING</Organization> READING ARE DISCUSSED, AND DETAILS GIVEN OF THE ESTIMATED <Organization>STAFF</Organization>,
STOCK, AND EQUIPMENT REQUIRED. PROCEDURES FOR EVALUATING AND CONTROLLING THE
SERVICE ARE OUTLINED, AND A VARIETY OF ADDITIONAL EXTENSION <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> WHICH
COULD <Organization>OPERATE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>WAGON</Organization> AS A BASE SUGGESTED.
********************************************
Document 5684
INVISIBLE COLLEGES AS A BASIS FOR <Organization>PLANNING SPECIAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. A REVIEW
OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.

EXPLAINS HOW INVISIBLE COLLEGES <Organization>FACILITATE</Organization> TRANSMISSION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AMONG
MEMBERS OF SCIENTIFIC COMMUNITIES, CITING PUBLISHED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AS EVIDENCE.
THERE IS NO EVIDENCE IN THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> TO SHOW THAT LIBRARIANS HAVE
CAPITALISED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> PHENOMENON. PROPOSES THAT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES IDENTIFY THE
INTERESTS OF <Organization>USER</Organization> COMMUNITIES AND KEEP FILES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>,
DISSEMINATING <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS PART OF <Organization>THEIR REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5685
WHICH <Organization>WAY</Organization> FOR SCHOOL MEDIA SERVICES TO TURN?.

IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> THERE HAS BEEN MUCH DISCUSSION IN RECENT YEARS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
TRANSFER OF <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO THE
RESPONSIBILITY OF THE <Organization>LOCAL EDUCATION</Organization> AUTHORITIES. IN THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> SITUATION OF
CUTBACKS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FINANCES THERE IS CONSIDERABLE SUPPORT FOR <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A
TRANSFER. HOWEVER, SCHOOL LIBRARIANS EMPLOYED BY THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AUTHORITIES, ARE AS MUCH A PART OF THE SCHOOL &apos;SUPPORT&apos; <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AS <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
PSYCHOLOGISTS AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> WORKERS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> FOUND IN SCHOOLS. LIBRARIANS EXPERIENCED
IN THE PROVISION OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> ARE IN THE BEST POSITION TO
<Organization>ORGANISE SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> GROWING COLLECTIONS OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AS WELL AS <Organization>THEIR</Organization> BOOKSTOCK.
********************************************
Document 5686
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK IN THE <Organization>SLOVAK</Organization> SOCIALIST REPUBLIC AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.

THE RECENT <Organization>COMMUNIST PARTY</Organization> CONGRESS AND REQUIREMENTS OF THE 7TH 5-YEAR-PLAN
(1981-85) HAVE GIVEN A <Organization>NEW</Organization> IMPETUS TO THE WHOLE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK IN <Location>SLOVAKIA</Location>.
SINCE 1 JAN 82, A SPECIAL SECTION OF MATICA SLOVENSKA, BASED IN <Location>BRATISLAVA</Location>,
HAS BEEN IN OPERATION. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> HAVE TO WATCH, <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> AND CONTROL BOTH SHORT-
AND LONG-TERM <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THEY WILL <Organization>ALSO CARE</Organization> FOR COORDINATION
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND CENTRES OF SCIENTIFIC, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. CONTACTS WITH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE CZECH SOCIALIST REPUBLIC AS WELL
<Organization>AS INTERNATIONAL</Organization> CONNECTIONS WILL <Organization>ALSO</Organization> BE FURTHERED. THE OVERALL
RESPONSIBILITY FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, HOWEVER, RESTS UPON THE <Organization>SLOVAK MINISTRY</Organization> OF
CULTURE. FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PART, THE MINISTRY&apos;S OFFICIALS WILL MAKE EVERY EFFORT
TOWARDS UNIFICATION AND/OR STANDARDISATION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP BOOK COLLECTIONS, RECORDS, STATISTICS AND THE LIKE.
AMONG <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PROBLEMS WHICH MUST BE TACKLED IN  THE FORSEEABLE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> ARE
COMPUTERISATION, MERGERS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization>,
AND INCORPORATION OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> INTO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5687
NETWORKS.

REVISED VERSION OF A PAPER PRESENTED TO A MEETING <Organization>ON</Organization> REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
COOPERATION IN DEVENTER, 19 NOV 81. IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> COOPERATION AMONGST
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES HAS COME UNDER CLOSE EXAMINATION AS A RESULT OF THE
INCLUSION OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>PROPOSED PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. THE
CONCEPT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKS DATES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE EARLY 1900S WHEN THE NEED FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO SHARE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESOURCES WAS RECOGNISED. THE MOST <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
NETWORKS ARE THOSE NETWORKS WHICH <Organization>OPERATE THEIR SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A FINANCIAL BASIS.
IN ADDITION, THE COORDINATION OF ACQUISITION POLICIES, <Organization>CATALOGUING SERVICES</Organization>
AND <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization> AMONGST MEMBERS OF A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK REQUIRES THE
MOST UP-TO-DATE TELECOMMUNICATION AND COMPUTER EQUIPMENT. WITHIN <Organization>EACH</Organization> NETWORK
A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD BE DESIGNATED TO <Organization>ACT</Organization> AS A CLEARING-HOUSE FOR THE
TRANSFER OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5688
EXTRA-MURAL FUNCTIONS OF UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

FOR OVER 10 YEARS <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE BEEN BUYING MORE ACADEMIC <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
THAN BEFORE AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OFFERING THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FACILITIES TO
PEOPLE OUTSIDE THE UNIVERSITY. <Organization>THIS</Organization> EXTRA-MURAL WORK MUST NOT BE REDUCED
BECAUSE OF FINANCIAL PROBLEMS; THE OBVIOUS NEED FOR ACADEMIC MATERIAL MUST BE
SATISFIED AND INTER-LIBRARY LOANS AND PURCHASING SCHEMES MUST RESULT IN A
<Organization>BETTER</Organization> COORDINATED AND MORE ECONOMICAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP OF
UNION <Organization>CATALOGUES USING ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND OF DECENTRALISED
MICROFICHE AND SCREEN <Organization>TEXT SERVICES</Organization> WILL EASE THE <Organization>DEMAND ON UNIVERSITY</Organization> SPECIAL
COLLECTIONS. ISOLATION OF UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WILL NOT IMPROVE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
IMAGE AND COULD PROVE COSTLY.
********************************************
Document 5689
THE WORK OF THE <Organization>STUDY GROUP</Organization> OF DIRECTORS OF UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>, THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Location>BERLIN</Location>,
<Location>DRESDEN</Location>, GREIFSWALD, HALLE, JENA, <Location>LEIPZIG</Location> AND ROSTOCK PLAY AN IMPORTANT PART
IN INTER-LIBRARY <Organization>LOAN</Organization> SCHEMES AND IN THE ACQUISITION OF SPECIALISED STOCKS. IN
1980 <Organization>THESE</Organization> UNIVERSITIES OWNED TOTAL STOCKS OF 18 MILLION ITEMS. THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization>
GROUP PROVIDES ADVICE <Organization>ON</Organization> ORGANISATION, WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THE UNIFIED <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF A <Organization>CENTRAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH
ASSOCIATED BRANCHES AND PROMOTES EXCHANGES AND ANALYSES OF EXPERIENCE. THE
GROUP IS CURRENTLY CONCENTRATING <Organization>ON</Organization> INTER-LIBRARY COOPERATION WITHIN SUBJECT
NETWORKS, WITH A VIEW TO IMRPOVING PURCHASING POLICY. IMPROVEMENTS MUST <Organization>ALSO</Organization>
BE MADE IN THE COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES
AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, IN <Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND IN THE APPLICATION OF TECHNOLOGY.
********************************************
Document 5690
THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK.

A FULL PRESENTATION OF THE ORGANISATION AND OPERATION OF THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN</Organization>
INTER-UNIVERSITY <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, SHOWING HOW IT WAS CREATED TO INTEGRATE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization>
INITIATIVES AND IMPLEMENT A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICY OF COOPERATION AND
RESOURCE SHARING. THE NETWORK&apos;S STRUCTURE IS DESIGNED TO MAXIMISE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> RESOURCES <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>, REGIONAL AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> LEVELS; DETAILS ARE GIVEN
OF MEMBERSHIP AND ADMINISTRATION. 16 PROGRAMMES CURRENTLY IN <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization> ARE
OUTLINED; <Organization>THESE</Organization> INCLUDE PROJECTS FOR A <Organization>NATIONAL UNION</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>,
<Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LOAN</Organization>, DUPLICATES EXCHANGE, COOPERATIVE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>
IN PUBLICATION, PREPARATION OF DIRECTORIES AND GUIDES, AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF BOTH
PERSONNEL AND USERS.
********************************************
Document 5691
INTERACTION WITHIN THE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS COMMUNITY.

THERE IS A GROWING INTERDEPENDENCE AMONG THE <Organization>MAJOR US FEDERAL</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
REPORTS <Organization>PROCESSING AGENCIES</Organization>, THE <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>/TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
CENTRES AND COMMERCIAL SERVICES WITH WHICH THEY INTERACT. IN <Organization>THIS</Organization>
INTERCONNECTED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NETWORK, THE PARTICIPANTS BOTH FEED AND <Organization>USE</Organization> THE
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> TO FULFIL <Organization>THEIR</Organization> MISSIONS IN REGARD TO TRANSFERRING <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
AND DEVELOPMENT RESULTS. COOPERATIVE ARRANGEMENTS AMONG THE PARTICIPANTS AND
SHARING OF RESOURCES ARE BECOMING INCREASINGLY IMPERATIVE IN ORDER TO LOWER
<Organization>COSTS</Organization> AND INCREASE EFFICIENCY. RECENT STEPS TAKEN TOWARDS <Organization>THESE</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED.
********************************************
Document 5692
BACKGROUND TO THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN</Organization> LAW 11 OF 5 MARCH 1979 &apos;RECOGNISING THE PROFESSION
OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND REGULATING <Organization>ITS</Organization> EXERCISE&apos;.

DESCRIBES THE PREPARATION AND PRESENTATION OF EARLY VERSIONS OF THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN</Organization>
LAW NOW IN FORCE. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE PROJECTS PRESENTED IN 1963, 1964,
AND 1971, FOLLOWING DISCUSSION BY THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS, TO REGULARISE
THE LEGAL BASIS OF LIBRARIANSHIP, TO ACCORD WITH <Organization>ITS</Organization> STATUS AS A UNIVERSITY
SUBJECT, AND EXPANDING RECRUITMENT. THE <Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF THE LAW IS APPENDED.
********************************************
Document 5693
DRAFT OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL&apos; <Organization>AMPUTATED CENTRAL ADMINISTRATION</Organization> AND MANY
POSSIBILITIES OF DISPENSATION.

<Organization>THIS</Organization> DRAFT, <Organization>ISSUED</Organization> BY THE <Organization>DANISH MINISTRY</Organization> OF <Organization>CULTURAL AFFAIRS</Organization> IN APR 81, TO
BECOME LAW <Organization>AT</Organization> THE EARLIEST JAN 83, OPERATES WITH A COMPLICATED <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
ADMINISTRATION, CONSISTING OF A CHIEF ADMINISTRATOR PRESIDING OVER A <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND A <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY DIRECTORATE</Organization>, <Organization>EACH</Organization> WITH A <Organization>LIBRARY BOARD</Organization>. <Organization>SOME</Organization>
LARGE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> UNDER A <Organization>DIFFERENT MINISTRY</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
MINISTRY OF CULTURE, WILL REMAIN OUTSIDE THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> CONTROL, <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS TO BE CENTRALLY
ADMINISTERED. THERE WILL BE NO <Organization>DIRECT STATE FINANCIAL</Organization> SUPPORT FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> SPECIFIED <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> WILL RECEIVE
STATE GRANTS. THE JOINT APPROPRIATION IS TO REMAIN AND WILL INCLUDE THE
<Organization>PRESENT DISPENSATION FUND</Organization>. DATES ARE SET FOR THE INTRODUCTION OF FULL TIME
SERVICE AND OF MUSICAL MATERIAL IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5694
IN CONVERSATION WITH THE MINISTER FOR CULTURE, <Organization>RECREATION</Organization> AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AFFAIRS,
HANS DE BOER.

<Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF AN INTERVIEW WITH HANS DE BOER, MINISTER FOR CULTURE, <Organization>RECREATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>SOCIAL AFFAIRS</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>. DE BOER FIRMLY SUPPORTS THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
SERVICES <Organization>ACT</Organization> WHICH WILL DECENTRALISE RUNNING OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> LEVEL. DE BOER BELIEVES
THAT INVOLVEMENT OF THE <Organization>LOCAL COMMUNITY</Organization> IN THE RUNNING OF <Organization>THESE SERVICES</Organization> IS
THE BEST GUARANTEE FOR <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> THE QUALITY OF THE SERVICE. PLANS FOR
EXTENDING THE <Organization>AGE</Organization> LIMIT FOR <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEMBERSHIP <Organization>FROM</Organization> 16 TO 18 YEARS
OF <Organization>AGE</Organization> HAVE BEEN ABANDONED BY DE BOER BECAUSE OF FINANCIAL CUTBACKS IN
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> SUPPORT. THE ALTERNATIVE, DE BOER BELIEVES, <Organization>WOULD</Organization> HAVE BEEN A
REDUCTION IN THE STANDARD OF SERVICE.
********************************************
Document 5695
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE 10TH ANNIVERSARY OF <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM
(<Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>)&apos; THE CHAIRMAN&apos;S TURN TO SPEAK
(PART) 2.

<Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF AN INTERVIEW WITH DR. J.J. POSTMA, CHAIRMAN OF THE NBLC <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 10TH
ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF THE CENTRE. POSTMA BELIEVES THAT LIBRARIANS IN
<Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> SHOULD NOW COME TO TERMS WITH THE <Organization>NEW PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>,
WHICH WILL REPLACE THE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. BY REFUSING TO ACCEPT
THE <Organization>ACT</Organization> LIBRARIANS ARE IN DANGER OF BEING LEFT OUT IN THE COLD. IN POSTMA&apos;S
VIEW THE DANGER OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> LIES IN THE DEVOLUTION OF RESPONSIBILITY FOR
THE <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>. IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES, HE ADDS, TOWN FESTIVALS MAY RECEIVE
GREATER PRIORITY THAN THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. THE NBLC MUST CONVINCE THE
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> OF THE NEED FOR AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> WHICH INCLUDES THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. (FOR AN ABSTRACT OF PART 1, 2SEE1 82/5007).
********************************************
Document 5696
<Organization>LIBRARY-INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> EVALUATION&apos; A <Organization>CASE-HISTORY FROM PHARMACEUTICAL</Organization> R
AND D.

DESCRIBES A 19-WEEK PROJECT TO EXAMINE AND EVALUATE THE <Organization>LIBRARY-INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICE <Organization>AT SYNTEX RESEARCH CENTRE</Organization>, RICCARTON, <Location>EDINBURGH</Location>, A PHARMACEUTICAL R
AND <Organization>D CENTRE</Organization>. AREAS LOOKED <Organization>AT</Organization> WERE&apos; <Organization>STOCK-USE RECORDS</Organization>; INTERLOAN REQUESTS; <Organization>USE</Organization>
OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> TIME AND THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> AWARENESS BULLETIN. 36 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS,
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SCIENTISTS, WERE INTERVIEWED, AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>DEMAND</Organization> FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES IS DESCRIBED. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE VALIDITY OF INDIVIDUAL
<Organization>LIBRARY-INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> EVALUATION TESTS AND PROBLEMS AND ATTRACTIONS OF
EVALUATING A <Organization>COMPLETE LIBRARY-INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> &apos;IN THE ROUND&apos;.
********************************************
Document 5697
STUDIES IN <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization> VOLUME SEVEN.

COLLECTED PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> VARIOUS ASPECTS OF <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization> DIVIDED INTO 3 MAIN
SECTIONS&apos; (1) INCLUDES A NUMBER OF <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> TOPICS, AUTHORITATIVELY TREATED; (2)
INCLUDES STUDIES OF THE &apos;VALUE&apos; OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> IN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND (3) PRESENTS MORE SPECIALISED STUDIES OF INTEREST TO LIBRARIANS
AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOL STUDENTS.
********************************************
Document 5698
<Organization>MANAGING MULTISITE POLYTECHNIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.

OUTLINES MANAGERIAL PROBLEMS COMMON TO MULTISITE <Organization>POLYTECHNIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
<Organization>THESE TIMES</Organization> OF ECONOMIC STRINGENCY. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>&apos; STYLES OF MANAGEMENT;
ALLOCATION OF RESOURCES; RATIONALISATION OF SYSTEMS; <Organization>STAFF</Organization> ALLOCATION;
MANAGEMENT OF GROWTH; <Organization>STAFF DEVELOPMENT</Organization>; AND <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> PROBLEMS.
********************************************
Document 5699
DISCUSSION AND <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN THE HOOGEVEEN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

IN 1971 A SCHEME OF WORKER <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization> WAS INTRODUCED <Organization>AT</Organization> HOOGEVEEN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>. <Organization>PREVIOUSLY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MEETINGS WERE RESTRICTED TO
ADMINISTRATIVE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> ONLY. UNDER THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>WEEKLY</Organization> MEETINGS WERE HELD <Organization>AT</Organization>
WHICH THE CHIEF LIBRARIAN AND HEADS OF THE ADULT AND CHILDREN&apos;S DEPARTMENTS
WERE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>. REPORTS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> MEETINGS WERE CIRCULATED TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> HEADS OF
DEPARTMENTS. IN 1975 FOLLOWING THE OPENING OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> WAS REORGANISED INTO 8 DEPARTMENTS AND A <Organization>NEW</Organization> STRUCTURE OF
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> MEETINGS WAS INTRODUCED. IN ADDITION TO THE MEETINGS ATTENDED BY
ADMINISTRATIVE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND HEADS OF DEPARTMENTS, <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF THE INTERNAL
SERVICES MEET EVERY 3 WEEKS, WHILE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF THE <Organization>EXTERNAL SERVICES</Organization> MEET <Organization>EACH</Organization>
WEEK. THE PURPOSE OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> MEETINGS IS TO IMPROVE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MOTIVATION AND THEREBY
THE QUALITY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SERVICES.
********************************************
Document 5700
CENTRALISATION AND DECENTRALISATION&apos; ONE POINT OF VIEW.

EXAMINES THE DEBATE <Organization>ON</Organization> CENTRALISATION AND DECENTRALISATION IN RELATION TO&apos; THE
HISTORICAL ASPECTS, SHOWING HOW IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> THE <Organization>LATIN AMERICAN UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> DEVELOPED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE ORIGINAL <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> PATTERN; THE
INSTITUTIONAL ASPECTS, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THE NECESSITY FOR UNIVERSITIES TO FULFIL <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
RESPONSIBILITIES DICTATES ADMINISTRATIVE STRUCTURES, IN TURN GOVERNING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ORGANISATION; THE TECHNICAL-ADMINISTRATIVE ASPECTS, OUTLINING THE ESSENTIAL
CHARACTERISTICS OF <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization>, PARTIALLY DECENTRALISED, AND DECENTRALISED
SYSTEMS; AND GEOGRAPHICAL FACTORS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> LEADS TO THE CONCLUSION THAT
THE PARTICULAR CIRCUMSTANCES OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> PARTICULAR CASE SHOULD DETERMINE
ADMINISTRATIVE AND ORGANISATIONAL STRUCTURES.
********************************************
Document 5701
THE <Organization>METHODOLOGICAL CENTRE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION SERVICES</Organization> OF THE MINISTRY FOR UNIVERSITY AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COLLEGE
AFFAIRS.

THE CENTRE ASSISTS IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> SUBJECT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND SUBJECT
NETWORKS AND PROMOTES THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>. GIVES ESTIMATES AND OPINIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>
INVESTMENT PROJECTS, DRAFT VERSIONS OF NEW REGULATIONS, ORGANISATIONAL
GUIDELINES; STANDARDS AND STATISTICS ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization>. THE MAIN <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS INCLUDE&apos; A CLASSIFICATION FOR SUBJECT <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN
ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; THE <Organization>FURTHER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> FOR
<Organization>USE</Organization> IN <Organization>LOAN SYSTEMS</Organization>, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES; THE EXPANSION OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> WORK IN UNIVERSITIES; THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF FOREIGN
<Organization>MAGNETIC TAPE SERVICES</Organization>. THE CENTRE REPRESENTS <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> IN THE WORK OF THE
INTERNATIONAL CENTRE FOR SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN <Location>MOSCOW</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5702
ADVISORY BODIES IN LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EFFECTIVENESS.

ADVISORY BODIES AND COMMITTEES DEALING WITH LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Location>SLOVAKIA</Location> ARE
LISTED. AMONG THE PROBLEMS TACKLED ARE NOT ONLY <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, BIBLIOGRAPHY AND
PRESERVATION OF BOOK COLLECTIONS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> STANDARDISATION, <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
STATISTICS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>AS WELL AS CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> OF LIBRARIANS.
SPECIAL COMMITTEES ATTEND TO THE RUNNING OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>. THE ENTIRE NETWORK IS HEADED BY THE
<Organization>SLOVAK LIBRARY COUNCIL</Organization> ESTABLISHED IN THE 1950S. THE MAIN OBJECTIVE OF THE
COUNCIL&apos;S ANNUAL PLANS IS TO MEET THE TARGETS SET BY THE <Organization>SLOVAK MINISTRY</Organization> OF
CULTURE. FOLLOWING A CAREFUL AND THOROUGH EXAMINATION IN THE COURSE OF THE
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> 5 YEAR PLAN (1981-85), MEASURES WILL BE TAKEN TO ENSURE UNIFICATION OF
<Organization>ALL</Organization> ADVISORY <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> AND TO INCREASE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> IMPACT <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5703
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK AMONG ADULTS.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>. A
COUNTRY WITH A RICH PUBLICATION OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SHOULD <Organization>ALSO</Organization> HAVE
WELL-APPOINTED AND FLOURISHING CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE
EXISTED IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location> FOR 70 YEARS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> NOT UNTIL THE 1970S, WITH GREAT
<Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> REFORMS, WAS PRIORITY ACCORDED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> FOR CHILDREN.
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE LATE 1970S, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONSULTANTS&apos; POSTS HAVE BEEN ESTABLISHED <Organization>AT</Organization>
ALMOST <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE COUNTY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. DESCRIBES THE CONSULTANT&apos;S ROLE IN RELATION
TO THAT OF OTHERS CONCERNED WITH CHILD WELFARE.
********************************************
Document 5704
ZZZZ.

IN BOTH <Location>NORWAY</Location> AND SWEDEN, COMMITTEES HAVE BEEN APPOINTED TO LOOK INTO THE
FINANCING OF SERVICES IN <Organization>PUBLICLY FUNDED UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> A MEETING IN <Location>OSLO</Location> <Location>IN</Location> FEB 81, <Organization>AT</Organization> WHICH THE SECRETARY OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
COMMITTEE TALKED ABOUT THAT COMMITTEE&apos;S <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, AND ARGUED THE CASE BOTH
FOR AND AGAINST CHARGING THE <Organization>USER</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5705
STUDIES IN CREATIVE PARTNERSHIP. FEDERAL <Organization>AID</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> DURING THE
<Organization>NEW</Organization> DEAL.

7 ARTICLES EXAMINING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF THE <Location>US</Location> WORK PROJECTS
ADMINISTRATION (W.P.A., CREATED IN 1935 AS THE WORK <Organization>PROGRESS ADMINISTRATION</Organization>)
DURING THE 2ND &amp;H OF THE GREAT DEPRESSION: &apos;ALMOST A BOON...&apos; FEDERAL RELIEF
PROGRAMS AND THE ENOCH PRATT <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, 1933-1943, BY JOHN CALVIN COLSON;
THE <Location>CLEVELAND</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE W.P.A.&apos; A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IN CREATIVE PARTNERSHIP,
BY DANIEL F. RING; THE <Location>CHICAGO</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> W.P.A. OMNIBUS PROJECT, BY ALEX
LADENSON; THE W.P.A. AND THE <Location>NEW YORK</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BY MARGOT KARP AND RHODA
GAROOGIAN; THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> DEAL WORK PROJECTS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>MILWAUKEE</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BY
DANIEL F. RING; THE <Location>MINNEAPOLIS</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE W.P.A. EXPERIENCE&apos;
COLLABORATION FOR COMMUNITY NEED, BY JOHN FRANKLIN WHITE; AND THE W.P.A. AND
<Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BY FAY M. BLAKE.
********************************************
Document 5706
<Organization>ALL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> SHOULD BE <Organization>FREE</Organization> OF CHARGE.

IN THE BILL FOR A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>, WHICH WILL SHORTLY BE TABLED IN THE
FOLKETING, THE CLAUSE REGARDING A <Organization>FREE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> WILL, IT SEEMS, BE
RETAINED. QUESTIONS WHETHER THE PARTIES WHO BELIEVE THAT A CHARGE SHOULD BE
LEVIED FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> WILL MANAGE TO INFLUENCE THE FINAL FORM OF THE <Organization>ACT</Organization>. IF
THE PRINCIPLE OF A <Organization>FREE SERVICE</Organization> GOES BY THE BOARD, EVERY IDEA OF AN EQUAL
SERVICE TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> WILL GO BY THE BOARD WITH IT, WITH THE CONSEQUENT BAD EFFECT <Organization>ON</Organization>
PUBLISHING HOUSES, BOOKSHOPS AND AUTHORS.
********************************************
Document 5707
FAIR PLAY WITH THE CAKE, YOU KNOW?&apos;.D

ISCUSSES THE ECONOMIC CUTS AS THEY AFFECT THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. THE
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>&apos;S SAVINGS CIRCULAR <Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> THAT <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES CUT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EXPENDITURE TO 185 KR PER CAPITA, AS, IT WAS ARGUED, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOWED
SIGNS OF UNCONTROLLED GROWTH. THE LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION HAS, HOWEVER, CALCULATED
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; REAL GROWTH IN 1980 AS WITHIN THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization>
3%; <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS SUPPORTED BY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INSPECTORATE. THE FIGURES FOR 1981
INDICATE AN <Organization>AVERAGE</Organization> FALL IN REAL GROWTH OF 1.4%. THE LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION HAS
EXAMINED THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> EFFECTS OF CUTS AND FOUND THAT <Organization>FRINGE SERVICES</Organization> LIKE
OUTREACH <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> ARE WORST HIT AND THAT <Organization>STAFF</Organization> APPOINTMENTS ARE FROZEN. THE
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>&apos;S TECHNOCRATS HAVE DRAWN UP MODELS FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SECTOR, <Organization>BUT</Organization> LIBRARIANS&apos; ANSWER MUST BE THAT THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PART OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> SECTOR IS NOT A <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> MATTER ONLY, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THAT <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
ASPECTS ARE EQUALLY IMPORTANT.
********************************************
Document 5708
GANGS OF SAVERS IN A DANCE OF CRANES.

4 MEMBERS OF THE LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION&apos;S <Organization>WORKING PARTY ON SAVINGS</Organization> WERE ASKED TO
EVALUATE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SITUATION IN VIEW OF THE CUTS IN EXPENDITURE. THEY
DISCUSSED THE FIGURES RELATING TO RUNNING <Organization>COSTS</Organization>, <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND MATERIAL <Organization>COSTS</Organization>
<Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> BY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INSPECTORATE AND THE EFFECTS OF CUTS <Organization>ON</Organization> WORK LOADS AND
LOANS. VIEWS DIFFERED AS TO WHETHER MINIMUM NORMS SHOULD BE LAID DOWN. THEY
AGREED THAT THE UNION AS A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> ORGANISATION COULD DO LITTLE TO GIVE
GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>ACTION</Organization> IN <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> SITUATIONS. <Organization>SOME</Organization> THOUGHT MEMBERS SHOULD REFUSE
TO TAKE PART IN <Organization>LOCAL WORKING GROUPS ON SAVINGS</Organization> SET UP TO GIVE PRIORITIES TO
CUTS IN <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> AREAS, AS <Organization>THIS</Organization> WAS TANTAMOUNT TO CONDONING CUTS, OTHERS
THOUGHT USEFUL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> COULD BE GAINED <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization> AND THAT <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
LIBRARIANS SHOULD <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> POLITICANS WITH WELL ARGUED BUDGET PROPOSALS AND
OUTLINE EFFECTS OF PARTICULAR CUTS.
********************************************
Document 5709
CABLE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> RESULTS.

<Organization>PUBLIC SERVICE</Organization> SATELLITE CONSORTIUM CONDUCTED A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
IN 1980, TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Organization>THEIR DATA COMMUNICATIONS</Organization> NEEDS AND SERVICES. &apos;CABLE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; (CATVLIB) WERE IDENTIFIED AS <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CONNECTED TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> CABLE
COMPANIES. A 2ND <Organization>STUDY</Organization> AIMED TO DETERMINE TO WHAT EXTENT A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> SATELLITE
CABLE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK MIGHT ALREADY BE IN <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> EXISTENCE; HOW MANY
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE PRESENTLY CONNECTED TO COOPERATIVE CABLE COMPANIES WITH
SATELLITE HARDWARE AND EXCESS SATELLITE RECEIVER CAPACITY AND OF THAT NUMBER,
HOW MANY CABLE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE INTERESTED IN PARTICIPATING IN
<Organization>SATELLITE-ASSISTED LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>TELECONFERENCING</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5710
COMPUTER TECHNOLOGY AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; AN INTRODUCTION.

A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> INTRODUCTION TO THE VARIOUS FORMS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTOMATION, DESCRIBING
HARDWARE AND SOFTWARE, MODES OF COMPUTER OPERATION (<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> AND
BATCH <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>), NETWORKS, AND PROSPECTS FOR THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5711
AUTOMATION: A CHALLENGE TO THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> FUNCTION OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
CHARACTER OF THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization>?.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE IDEAS OF COBABUS AND THIEM <Organization>ON</Organization> THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
AUTOMATION AND&apos; (1) <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization>; (2) PRODUCT QUALITY; (3) <Organization>STAFF</Organization>
QUALIFICATIONS AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, AND THE EFFECTS OF GOVERNMENTAL RESTRICTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>
EXPENDITURE UPON <Organization>THESE</Organization> RELATIONSHIPS. AUTOMATION IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TENDS TO LAG
BEHIND AUTOMATION IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> FIELDS <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT DEMANDS CHANGES IN <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>,
INTELLECTUALISATION OF PRODUCTION WORK AND A <Organization>NEW</Organization> RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
AND ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. PROCESSES <Organization>PREVIOUSLY</Organization> SEPARATED CAN BE INTEGRATED BY
AUTOMATION. BEFORE AUTOMATION THERE WAS A TENDENCY TOWARDS RIGIDITY IN THE
<Organization>HIGHER</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> GRADES; NOW AUTOMATION REQUIRES CHANGES IN THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> HIERARCHY
AND THE <Organization>OLD</Organization> IDEA OF THE &apos;CLASSICAL LIBRARIAN&apos;.
********************************************
Document 5712
THE REITERATE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE AUTOMATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>, <Organization>THIS</Organization> TIME
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> PRACTICAL RESULTS.

AN ANALYSIS AND EVALUATION OF THE DEVELOPMENT AND <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> SITUATION IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AUTOMATION IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location> ARE PRESENTED, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> A BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF
<Organization>MAJOR</Organization> TRENDS. DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> 14 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH HAVE ATTAINED CERTAIN PRACTICAL
RESULTS IN USING COMPUTERS TO ASSIST THEM IN SPECIFIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OPERATIONS AND
PROCESSES ARE SET OUT IN THE TABLE.
********************************************
Document 5713
IS AUTOMATION NECESSARY?.

IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> SUPPORTERS OF THE INTRODUCTION OF <Organization>AUTOMATED SYSTEMS</Organization> IN
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> POINT TO THE <Organization>COMPUTERISED LOANS SYSTEMS</Organization> ALREADY IN OPERATION
IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>ROTTERDAM</Location>, <Location>AMSTERDAM</Location> AND ELSEWHERE, AND TO THE GROWING NUMBER
OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MAKING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> NETWORKS. OPPONENTS OF
AUTOMATION POINT TO THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> IMPLICATIONS OF THE REPLACEMENT OF MAN BY
MACHINES. A <Organization>FURTHER GROUP</Organization> <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> THAT THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF AUTOMATION IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
DEPENDS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE NATURE OF THE WORK TO BE DONE AND ASSERTS THAT CERTAIN
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AIDS, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS THE TELEPHONE AND THE PHOTOCOPIER, ARE REGARDED AS
ESSENTIAL TO A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SERVICES. IN SPITE OF UNEMPLOYMENT IT IS BECOMING
INCREASINGLY DIFFICULT TO ATTRACT AND RETAIN <Organization>STAFF</Organization> FOR CERTAIN TASKS IN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> CASES AUTOMATION CAN BE OF GREAT ASSISTANCE.
********************************************
Document 5714
STATE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Location>USSR</Location>. AUTOMATION OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROCEDURE AS A MEANS OF RAISING EFFICIENCY OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CONFERENCE OF COOPERATIVE LIBRARIANS &amp; <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>
OFFICERS, <Location>MOSCOW</Location>, OCT 80. SINCE 1976 AN <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> HAS BEEN UNDER
DEVELOPMENT IN THE STATE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Location>USSR</Location>,
COVERING <Organization>ALL</Organization> BASIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROCEDURES, <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization> TO SUBSCRIBER
SERVICES. IT IS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> PLANNED TO AUTOMATE THE MAINTENANCE OF A CARD INDEX OF
READERS, AND CARD INDEXES OF PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> SOLUTIONS. IT IS FELT THAT
THE AUTOMATION WILL SUBSTANTIALLY INCREASE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S EFFICIENCY.
********************************************
Document 5715
THE NETWORKING OF WEST <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization>&apos; A WORKSHOP <Organization>SUMMARY</Organization>.

REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> 2 WEST <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization> NETWORKING WORKSHOPS HELD IN JULY AND AUG 80. THE
HIGHLIGHT OF BOTH MEETINGS WAS A PRESENTATION BY VINOD CHACHRA OF <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization>
<Organization>POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE</Organization> AND STATE UNIVERSITY, WHO HAS BEEN INVESTIGATING THE
STATE OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY TECHNOLOGY</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> IMPLICATIONS FOR THE
DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization>, <Organization>EFFICIENT LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> IN WEST <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization>. THE
PRESENTATION IS SUMMARISED IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> DETAIL.
********************************************
Document 5716
ISSUES AND APPLICATIONS OF MICROCOMPUTERS FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION ANNUAL CONFERENCE, JUNE 81. EXAMINES THE IMPACT OF MICROCOMPUTERS
<Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND ARGUES THAT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INTRODUCTION REPRESENTS A <Organization>CRITICAL</Organization> POINT
FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROFESSIONALS. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE APPLICATIONS OF MICROCOMPUTERS AS
PART OF A <Organization>REFERENCE SERVICE MANAGEMENT</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS</Organization>,
AND FOR <Organization>EXTERNAL</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> ACCESS.
********************************************
Document 5717
THE <Organization>AGE</Organization> OF MICRO-INFORMATICS.

A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> DISCUSSING THE USES OF MICROPROCESSORS IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>. A BRIEF
EXPLANATION IS GIVEN OF HOW MICROPROCESSORS WORK AND <Organization>COSTS</Organization> INVOLVED ESTIMATED.
THEN THE 2 MAIN TENDENCIES GOVERNING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>THIS NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> ARE EXAMINED&apos;
DECENTRALISATION, AS IN THE <Location>USA</Location>; AND <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTIVE SYSTEMS</Organization> AS IN
<Location>FRANCE</Location> AND THE <Location>UK</Location>. EXAMPLES ARE GIVEN ILLUSTRATING VARIOUS APPLICATIONS IN
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> COUNTRIES. SURVEYS <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> USES OF MICROPROCESSORS IN PERFORMING
TRADITIONAL AND INNOVATORY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TASKS, AND <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> SPECIALISED
<Organization>COMMUNICATION SERVICES</Organization>. IN CONCLUSION CONSIDERS BRIEFLY <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS IN
<Organization>DATA BASE MANAGEMENT</Organization>, SELF-EDUCATION, AND COMMUNICATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5718
MINICOMPUTERS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 1981-82&apos; THE <Organization>ERA</Organization> OF <Organization>DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS</Organization>.

ATTEMPTS TO DEAL WITH THE NUMEROUS QUESTIONS POSED BY READERS OF THE EARLIER
BOOK, 2MINICOMPUTERS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>1 1979-1980. A SECTION DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>PROCESS</Organization>
OF <Organization>SYSTEM DEVELOPMENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS FOLLOWED BY 1 DESCRIBING HARDWARE AND
SOFTWARE FOR <Organization>DISTRIBUTED</Organization> COMPUTING. A 3RD SECTION GIVES <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> APPLICATIONS. A LARGE DIRECTORY OF <Organization>INSTALLED SYSTEMS</Organization> IS
INCLUDED.
********************************************
Document 5719
MICRO-INFORMATICS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.

A BRIEF <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> DESCRIBING HOW <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CAN CAPITALISE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE OPPORTUNITIES
OFFERED BY THE AVAILABILITY <Organization>AT</Organization> LOW COST OF MICROCOMPUTERS. DETAILS ARE GIVEN
OF HOW MICROCOMPUTERS WORK AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> POTENTIAL APPLICATIONS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SITUATIONS; PROGRAMS FOR <Organization>MANAGING</Organization> LOANS, <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization>, AND PERIODICAL
COLLECTIONS ARE DISCUSSED; AND THE ADVANTAGES OF <Organization>ACCESSING ON-LINE DATA</Organization> BASES
CONSIDERED.
********************************************
Document 5720
LEARNING BY <Organization>MICROCOMPUTER</Organization>&apos; THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

EXAMINES THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>MICROCOMPUTER</Organization> IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF A COLLEGE OF
EDUCATION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE EXPERIENCES OF THE AUTHOR WITH THE
COMPUTER IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>STRANMILLIS COLLEGE</Organization>, <Location>BELFAST</Location>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>&apos; REASONS
FOR INSTALLING A COMPUTER IN A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; CHOOSING A <Organization>SUITABLE COMPUTER</Organization>; <Organization>ITS</Organization>
OPERATION AND PROGRAMING; <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> TYPES OF COMPUTER ASSISTED LEARNING
PROGRAMS; AND BIBLIOGRAPHIC <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> PROGRAMS. GIVES <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
VARIOUS PRODUCERS OF <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> PROGRAMS FOR MICROCOMPUTERS, AND NOTES THE
STEPS WHICH HAVE BEEN TAKEN TOWARDS <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> CONTROL OF
<Organization>THIS</Organization> SOFTWARE.
********************************************
Document 5721
QUALIFICATIONS REQUIRED OF <Organization>STAFF MEMBERS AT UNIVERSITY</Organization> OF TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO EDUCATION FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK. GIVES A SHORT HISTORICAL REVIEW OF FORMAL QUALIFICATIONS
REQUIRED OF APPLICANTS TO QUALIFIED LIBRARIANS&apos; POSTS IN <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. SHOWS HOW <Organization>NEW</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS IN EDUCATION AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AS WELL AS IN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TECHNIQUES HAVE AFFECTED CONDITIONS OF WORK IN A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>NEW</Organization> TASKS
HAVE BEEN ADDED TO THE TRADITIONAL ONES, AND IT IS NECESSARY TO FIND WAYS OF
RECONCILING THE <Organization>NEW DEVELOPMENT</Organization> WITH <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPERTISE, AND TO FIND A
COMMON DOMINATOR WHICH WILL WORK TOWARDS AN INTEGRATION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> TASKS IN A
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS FOUND IN THE OVERALL AIMS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK&apos; TO MEET THE NEEDS
OF THE CUSTOMER. INSTRUCTION AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> HOW BEST TO MEET THE USERS&apos; NEEDS
SHOULD THEREFORE FORM AN IMPORTANT PART OF <Organization>ALL EDUCATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
Document 5722
STAFFING IN <Organization>NIGERIAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

DESCRIBES A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> UNDERTAKEN TO ASCERTAIN TO WHAT EXTENT ACADEMIC LIBRARIANS
IN <Location>NIGERIA</Location> SATISFY THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> REQUIREMENTS OF
SCHOLARSHIP AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, AND WHETHER THE INSTITUTIONAL SETTINGS IN WHICH
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> WORK ARE CONDUCIVE TO <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL SERVICE</Organization>. AMONG <Organization>MAJOR</Organization>
ELEMENTS EXAMINED WERE THE LIBRARIANS&apos; PERCEPTIONS OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESPONSIBILITIES;
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> ACADEMIC AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> BACKGROUNDS; WORK ENVIRONMENTS; JOB
SATISFACTION AND OPPORTUNITIES FOR <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT. IT WAS FOUND THAT <Organization>PROFESSIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> HAS BEEN HINDERED
BY THE INABILITY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ADMINISTRATORS TO CONCEPTUALISE THE PROPER
ROLE OF A LIBRARIAN; RIGID BUREAUCRATISATION IN THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; FAILURE TO
SEPARATE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NON-PROFESSIONAL DUTIES; AND BY LIMITED INCENTIVES
AND OPPORTUNITIES FOR <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> GROWTH.
********************************************
Document 5723
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> JUNIOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN A <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. SHORTAGE OF SENIOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE RADCLIFFE <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, OXFORD
UNIVERSITY (<Location>UK</Location>) HAS NECESSITATED THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF JUNIOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN THE BASIC
PRINCIPLES OF ASSISTING READERS. THE METHODS <Organization>USED</Organization> ARE <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO THE
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> STOCK, <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>, BIBLIOGRAPHIC SOURCES, AND <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> WORKS IN
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE PLAN OF LECTURES IN THE 18-HOUR <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSE IS OUTLINED
AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> ELEMENTS DESCRIBED. THE COURSE EFFECTIVENESS TESTS ARE OUTLINED.
********************************************
Document 5724
INTRA-REGIONAL <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> AND COOPERATION WORKSHOP.

<Organization>ON</Organization> 6 MAY 81, AN IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>DAY</Organization> WAS HELD FOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MEMBERS AND
VOLUNTEERS <Organization>WORKING</Organization> WITHIN THE MIRACLE VALLEY REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, WEST
<Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> PURPOSE WAS TWOFOLD&apos; (1) TO ACQUAINT <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND VOLUNTEERS IN
ORDER TO PROMOTE <Organization>BETTER</Organization> INTRA-REGIONAL <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> AND COOPERATION; AND (2)
TO PROVIDE PRACTICAL WORKSHOP EXPERIENCE FOR NON-PROFESSIONAL <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. THE
KEYNOTE ADDRESS AND PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE WORKSHOP ARE SUMMARISED. THE <Organization>DAY</Organization>
WAS SO SUCCESSFUL, IT IS HOPED TO MAKE THE WORKSHOP AN ANNUAL EVENT.
********************************************
Document 5725
THE REPORT OF THE LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION 1979-80.

INCLUDES THE ACCOUNTS OF THE LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION FOR 1979, THE EXECUTIVE
COMMITTEE&apos;S BUDGET PROPOSALS FOR 1981, REPORT OF THE LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION&apos;S
<Organization>ACTION FUND</Organization> FOR 1979-80, REPORT OF THE LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION FOR 1979-80, REPORT
OF THE UNION&apos;S GROUP FOR STATE EMPLOYED LIBRARIANS 1979-80, REPORT OF THE
UNION&apos;S GROUP FOR PRIVATELY EMPLOYED LIBRARIANS 1979-80, AND REPORTS OF THE
FOLLOWING SPECIAL GROUPS&apos; THE GROUP FOR BRANCHES AND <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE
GROUP FOR CHILDREN&apos;S AND YOUNG PEOPLE&apos;S LIBRARIANS, THE GROUP FOR OUTREACH
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, AND THE GROUP &apos;<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND EDUCATION&apos;.
********************************************
Document 5726
IN CASE OF UNIONS, <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION ANNUAL CONFERENCE, JUNE 81. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF UNIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>
CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND ADVISES <Organization>LIBRARY BOARD</Organization> MEMBERS <Organization>ON</Organization> DEALING WITH UNIONS.
HIGHLIGHTS THE NEED FOR BOARD MEMBERS TO BE FAMILIAR WITH THE REQUIREMENTS OF
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> PROVINCES&apos;S LABOUR CODE, AND FOR CHIEF LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ASSISTANTS
TO BE WELL TRAINED IN <Organization>CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION</Organization>. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> CONSIDERS BARGAINING AND
NEGOTIATING TACTICS.
********************************************
Document 5727
UNION-LIBRARY RELATIONSHIP.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION ANNUAL CONFERENCE, JUNE 81. EXAMINES THE IMPACT OF UNIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>
CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND PRESENTS THE RESULTS OF A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>
ORGANISATIONS IN ANGLOPHONE <Location>CANADA</Location>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> HOW <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MANAGERS CAN TRY TO
ENSURE THAT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ABILITY TO MANAGE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> REMAINS AS UNIMPAIRED AS
POSSIBLE AFTER UNIONISATION. ARGUES THAT THE SERVICE FUNCTION IS THE ASPECT OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OPERATIONS MOST ENDANGERED BY THE IMPACT OF UNIONS, AND URGES THOSE
RESPONSIBLE TO ENSURE THAT THE SERVICE GOAL OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> REMAINS AS UNFETTERED
AS POSSIBLE BY A <Organization>COLLECTIVE</Organization> AGREEMENT.
********************************************
Document 5728
THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> STATE OF LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR ASSISTANT LIBRARIANS.

IN RECENT YEARS <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> GRADES HAS UNDERGONE A
FUNDAMENTAL REFORM. THE NUMBER OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> GRADUATES <Organization>WORKING</Organization> IN ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAS NOW INCREASED. FORMERLY, <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES POSSESSED UNIVERSITY</Organization> DEGREES, FEW OF THEM POSSESSED QUALIFICATIONS
IN LIBRARIANSHIP. IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, BY CONTRAST, MOST SENIOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> HAVE
LIBRARIANSHIP QUALIFICATIONS. THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> SITUATION HAS BEEN CAUSED BY LEGAL
CHANGES, THE FINAL RESULTS OF WHICH CANNOT BE PREDICTED WITH CERTAINTY. <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>PRESENT</Organization> THERE IS A WIDE VARIETY OF COURSES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>; THE BEST BALANCE OF
THEORETICAL AND PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> MUST BE CHOSEN. <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> CONSIDERATION MUST
BE GIVEN TO THE JOINT <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF LIBRARIANS AND DOCUMENTALISTS AND TO THE
SALARIES OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5729
THE STATUS OF LIBRARIANS IN <Location>HONG KONG</Location>.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE STATUS, SALARIES AND QUALIFICATIONS OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN
ACADEMIC, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, SPECIAL AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>HONG KONG</Location>. OUTLINES REASONS
FOR A LACK OF MILITANCY AMONGST ASSISTANT LIBRARIANS IN ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> COUNTERPARTS IN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SECTOR, IN A WEAKER POSITION WITHOUT
POST-GRADUATE QUALIFICATIONS, HAVE FORMED THE ASSOCIATION OF ASSISTANT
LIBRARIANS TO PROTECT AND <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INTERESTS. DESCRIBES THE DIPLOMA
COURSE IN LIBRARIANSHIP WHICH HAS BEEN RECENTLY INTRODUCED AND IS AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization>
ASSISTANT LIBRARIANS IN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SECTOR AND A <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSE FOR
TEACHER-LIBRARIANS. <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> WITH THE ROLE OF THE <Location>HONG KONG</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION IN PROTECTING THE INTERESTS OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> MEMBERS.
********************************************
Document 5730
THE <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARIANS ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND ASSOCIATION CREDIBILITY.

CONTRIBUTION TO A SPECIAL FEATURE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF ASSOCIATIONS. <Organization>NLA</Organization> WAS
FOUNDED IN 1975 TO MEET A LONG-FELT NEED IN MANY LIBRARIANS FOR A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATION</Organization> WHICH <Organization>WOULD</Organization> CONCERN ITSELF EXCLUSIVELY WITH LIBRARIAN
ISSUES RATHER THAN WITH THE ENTIRE GAMUT OF ISSUES <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
SOCIETY. <Organization>NLA</Organization> IS SMALL, NEW AND NOT WELL UNDERSTOOD. THE <Location>USA</Location> HAS 100,000
LIBRARIANS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>NLA</Organization> HAS ONLY 500 MEMBERS. NO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PUBLICATION HAS REPORTED
<Organization>ON</Organization> OR EVALUATED <Organization>NLA</Organization>&apos;S POSITION PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>NATIONWIDE</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF CERTIFICATION
FOR LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> WELFARE. <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS TEND TO IGNORE
<Organization>NLA</Organization>&apos;S OFFERS TO PROVIDE SPEAKERS OR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>. IN MANY WAYS <Organization>NLA</Organization>
HAS ACHIEVED A GREAT DEAL, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT STANDS <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>CRITICAL</Organization> POINT IN <Organization>ITS</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT. IT MAY BE THAT DIRECTLY ADDRESSING &apos;BREAD AND BUTTER&apos; ISSUES WILL
PROVIDE THE IMPETUS <Organization>NLA</Organization> NEEDS TO REGAIN <Organization>ITS</Organization> MOVEMENT TOWARD BECOMING A <Organization>MAJOR</Organization>
<Organization>NATIONAL ASSOCIATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIA <Organization>NS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5731
A <Organization>NEW</Organization> CONCEPT OF <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE SCHEME, WHOSE <Organization>TEXT</Organization> IS INCLUDED, WAS DEVISED BY DAS ZENTRALINSTITUT FUR
BIBLIOTHEKSWESEN (<Organization>CENTRAL INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>) IN 1981. <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> PROBLEMS IS PROVIDED TOGETHER WITH VARIOUS
TYPES OF SPECIALIST MATERIAL AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FOR MANAGEMENT. THE COURSE
INCLUDES LECTURES, DISCUSSIONS AND VISITS TO VARIOUS <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; <Organization>USE</Organization>
IS MADE OF FACILITIES IN LARGE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> ORGANISATIONS AND IN SMALL BRANCH
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE EXPERIENCE GAINED <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES ALREADY <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN
POTSDAM AND ERFURT HAS PROVED VALUABLE. <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN MUNICIPAL
AND RURAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> WILL HAVE A REGULAR <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PROGRAMME; IN
<Organization>SOME</Organization> AREAS A <Organization>TRAINING CENTRE</Organization> HAS BEEN CREATED TO SERVE SEVERAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5732
IN-SERVICE QUALIFICATION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>WAB</Organization>(B) POTSDAM.

IN MANY LARGE MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> THERE ARE UNQUALIFIED <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN SPECIALIST
POSTS WHO HAVE BEEN UNABLE FOR VARIOUS REASONS TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> FOR <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
QUALIFICATIONS. SINCE 1979 POTSDAM <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS ORGANISED SPECIAL
IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES FOR THEM, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> SURVEYS OF
LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN PARTICULAR AND SPECIALIST <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN
THE WORK OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN DEPARTMENTS. <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE 12 MONTHS&apos; COURSE <Organization>EACH</Organization>
STUDENT RECEIVES A CERTIFICATE OF <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization>. IT IS ESSENTIAL FOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> TO
HAVE PRELIMINARY DISCUSSIONS WITH PROSPECTIVE STUDENTS TO GIVE THEM
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ABOUT THE COURSE AND TO GET <Organization>FROM</Organization> THEM A PROMISE TO WORK HARD.
EXPERIENCE HAS SHOWN THAT MOST STUDENTS FIND THE COURSE HELPFUL. <Organization>THIS</Organization> TYPE OF
COURSE CAN ONLY BE PROVIDED IN A LARGE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5733
<Organization>WOMEN</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A SPECIAL <Organization>ISSUE</Organization>.

SPECIAL <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO PROBLEMS FACED BY <Organization>WOMEN</Organization> EMPLOYED IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
WRITTEN AND EDITED BY MEMBERS OF THE <Organization>WOMEN</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES GROUP</Organization>. THE FOLLOWING
ARTICLES ARE INCLUDED; THE PROBLEMS FACED BY <Organization>WOMEN</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, BY SHERRY
JESPERSEN; CENSORSHIP OR SELECTION? LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CONTENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, BY JANE LITTLE; FEMINISM IN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BY JANE ALLEN;
FEMINIST BOOKS&apos; A <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> CHOICE, BY FRAN DEVINE; THE LOWEST OF THE LOW&apos;
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, BY JACKIE TAYLOR; <Organization>WOMEN WORKERS</Organization>, UNION
POWER AND POSITIVE <Organization>ACTION</Organization>, BY JANE ALLEN; <Organization>WOMEN</Organization> IN MANAGEMENT, BY ANNE KNOX;
JOB-SHARING&apos; A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization> TO WORK, BY HELEN SUNDERLAND; JOB-SHARING&apos; A <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization>
ACCOUNT, BY SARAH CARTER AND FRANCES HINTON; JOB-SHARING IN A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
BY MAUREEEN WADE; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AUTOMATION AND <Organization>WOMEN</Organization>, BY MARY NEWTON.
********************************************
Document 5734
THE REMOVAL AND EQUIPPING OF AN INDUSTRIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>DE VOORST HYDRAULICS LABORATORY</Organization> IN THE NOORDOOSTPOLDER IN
<Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> BEGAN WITH A SMALL <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF DOCUMENTS IN 1963. BY 1980
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>CONTAINED</Organization> OVER 20,000 DOCUMENTS, ANNUAL LOANS TOTALLED ALMOST
10,000 AND THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> HAD LONG OUTGROWN THE ORIGINAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization>. IN
1975 PLANS HAD ALREADY BEEN DRAWN UP FOR A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH A <Organization>WORKING</Organization> AREA OF
200 SQ.M. TOGETHER WITH A <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> 200 SQ.M. OF UNDERGROUND STORAGE AREA FOR
ARCHIVAL MATERIAL. THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND BOOKSTACK AREAS WERE PLANNED TO
PROVIDE THE MOST <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> LAYOUT FOR READERS AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND REMOVAL OF THE
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> TO THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS CAREFULLY PLANNED IN ADVANCE TO MINIMISE
DISRUPTION TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SERVICES.
********************************************
Document 5735
IFLA AND LIBER SEMINARS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS.

REPORT OF 2 SEMINARS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS. THE 1ST, WHICH TOOK PLACE IN
<Location>DENMARK</Location>, WAS ORGANISED BY IFLA AND TOOK AS <Organization>ITS</Organization> THEME <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INTERIORS; THE
2ND, ORGANISED BY LIBER WAS HELD IN <Location>HEIDELBERG</Location> <Location>IN</Location> NOV 80, AND WAS ENTITLED
&apos;<Organization>NEW</Organization> PROBLEMS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARCHITECTURE&apos;. PAPERS AND DISCUSSION ARE REVIEWED.
********************************************
Document 5736
HENRY THOMAS HARE 1860-1921. AN EDWARDIAN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARCHITECT AND HIS
WORK.

(M.A. THESIS). HENRY THOMAS HARE WAS A SUCCESSFUL COMPETITION ARCHITECT,
INITIALLY FOR MUNICIPAL BUILDINGS <Organization>BUT</Organization> LATER FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. AN ACCOUNT
IS GIVEN OF THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND ARCHITECTURAL HISTORY OF THE PERIOD
FOLLOWED BY AN OUTLINE OF HARE&apos;S CAREER AS AN ARCHITECT WITH AN EXAMINATION OF
HIS VIEWS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND DESIGN OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS. PARTICULAR
ATTENTION IS PAID TO HIS &apos;LARGE HALL OR ROOM&apos; CONCEPT WHICH POINTED THE <Organization>WAY</Organization> TO
OPEN PLAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5737
FOUR <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> LIBRARIES-PRESENTATION AND COMMENTS.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
INTRODUCTION TO 4 <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>AT</Organization> NORA, SJOBO, VARBERG AND
OREBRO, <Organization>GIVING DESIGN</Organization> SPECIFICATIONS, FLOOR-PLANS AND DETAILS OF ORGANISATION.
SECTIONS ARE INCLUDED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE URBAN ENVIRONMENT AND <Organization>ON</Organization> THE BOOK
ROOM OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF THE 4 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5738
<Organization>FROM</Organization> BARRACKS TO <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> PALACE.

A LIGHT-HEARTED DESCRIPTION OF THE <Organization>WORKING</Organization> OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WHICH
OPENED IN JAN 80 IN <Organization>FROLUNDA CULTURAL CENTRE</Organization>, <Location>GOTEBORG</Location>. APART <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
OF 2750 SQ.M., THE 15,000 SQ.M. LARGE <Organization>BUILDING CONTAINS SECONDARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
SPORTSHALL, SWIMMING POOL, CAFETERIA, EXHIBITION HALL AND HALL FOR THEATRE AND
CINEMA. THE MOVE TO THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SAW AN INCREASE OF LOANS OF 50%, THE STOCK
IS NOW 120,000 VOLUMES, 600 <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> AND 65 NEWSPAPERS. BUMS TERMINALS HAVE
BEEN <Organization>INSTALLED</Organization>. IN STEP WITH INCREASED RESOURCES THE READERS&apos; <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
SERVICES HAS INCREASED, AND VISITS TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARE PAID BY MANY <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization>
GROUPS. PROGRAMMES FOR CHILDREN AND ADULTS HAVE EXPANDED.
********************************************
Document 5739
<Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE ARCHITECT AND THE LIBRARIAN.

EXAMINES THE RESPECTIVES ROLES OF THE ARCHITECT AND THE LIBRARIAN IN THE
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization> OF A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization>. <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> THAT, <Organization>WHATEVER DESIGN</Organization> A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS
TO TAKE, <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE LIBRARIAN AND THE ARCHITECT IS AN
ESSENTIAL INGREDIENT FOR GREATER SUCCESS AND MORE POSITIVE RESULTS.
********************************************
Document 5740
ENERGY CONSERVATION IN THE CONSTRUCTION OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS.

<Organization>AT</Organization> A TIME OF <Organization>RAPIDLY RISING ENERGY COSTS ENERGY</Organization>-CONSCIOUSNESS HAS BECOME A
NECESSITY IN THE CONSTRUCTION OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS. <Organization>AT</Organization> MIERLO IN <Location>THE
NETHERLANDS</Location> A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS OPENED IN NOV 81. BY THE INSERTION OF
EXTRA INSULATION IN THE FLOOR, WALLS AND ROOF, AND THE MOST <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
HEAT GENERATED BY THE ARTIFICIAL LIGHTING IT IS EXPECTED THAT HEATING <Organization>COSTS</Organization>
FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WILL BE 1/3 OF THE NORMAL AMOUNT FOR BUILDINGS OF SIMILAR
DIMENSIONS. IN ADDITION, THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF PREFABRICATED PARTS IN THE CONSTRUCTION OF
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ENABLED THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> TO BE COMPLETED IN 22 WEEKS WITH A CONSEQUENT
SAVING IN LABOUR <Organization>COSTS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5741
AN ENERGY-CONSCIOUS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> IN KATWIJK.

<Organization>ON</Organization> 14 DEC 80, A <Organization>NEW</Organization> BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS OPENED <Organization>AT</Organization> KATWIJK IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.
DURING THE <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> STAGES IT WAS FELT THAT A <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> WITH A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> FUNCTION,
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, SHOULD SET AN EXAMPLE IN ENERGY SAVING. TO MAXIMISE
<Organization>NATURAL ENERGY</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE SUN THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> HAS BEEN CONSTRUCTED WITH A LARGE
AREA OF GLASS IN THE SOUTH-EAST WALL; THE WARMTH GENERATED BY <Organization>THIS</Organization> MEANS IS
RETAINED IN THE STONE NORTH WALL AND THE FLOOR. THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> IS EQUIPPED WITH
TRIPLE-GLAZING AND HEAT-INSULATING BLINDS WHICH CLOSE AUTOMATICALLY <Organization>AT</Organization> NIGHT
AND REOPEN <Organization>EACH</Organization> MORNING. IT IS EXPECTED THAT THE SAVINGS IN ENERGY <Organization>COSTS</Organization> WILL
BE IN THE REGION OF 50%. IT IS TO BE HOPED THAT <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>THE
NETHERLANDS</Location> WILL FOLLOW <Organization>THIS</Organization> EXAMPLE.
********************************************
Document 5742
POINTS TO THE CONSIDERED IN RELATION TO THE <Organization>PHYSICAL DESIGN</Organization> OF A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

A BRIEF <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> COVERING POINTS THAT MIGHT BE OVERLOOKED IN DESIGNING A
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. BASIC REQUIREMENTS TO BE CONSIDERED INCLUDE THE NEED FOR
FLEXIBILITY OF INTERIOR SPACE TO <Organization>ALLOW</Organization> FOR INCREASE OF READERS AND SERVICES,
AND THE CREATION OF AN AGREEABLE ATMOSPHERE. A PRELIMINARY ANALYSIS, BY THE
LIBRARIAN AND ARCHITECT IN COLLABORATION, OF <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> TO BE ACCOMMODATED
PERMITS CLASSIFICATION OF THE SPACE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN RELATION TO REQUIREMENTS, FOR
EXAMPLE, FOR BOOKS, READERS, ADMINISTRATION, AND ARCHIVES. DETAILS ARE GIVEN
OF PROCEDURES FOR <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> INCORPORATION OF ESSENTIALS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS SHELVING SPACE,
<Organization>READER</Organization> ACCOMMODATION, ILLUMINATION, <Organization>SOUND</Organization> INSULATION, <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> CHANNELS,
<Organization>CLEANING SERVICES</Organization>, AND PROVISION OF EQUIPMENT.
********************************************
Document 5743
WHY GO TO DENMARK?.

EDITED <Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF A PAPER GIVEN TO THE JOINT CONFERENCE (OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION OF <Location>IRELAND</Location> AND THE NORTHERN <Location>IRELAND</Location> BRANCH OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION), BLARNEY, COUNTY <Location>CORK</Location>, MAY 80. DESCRIBES THE TOUR OF <Organization>DANISH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH WAS UNDERTAKEN IN 1979 BY A GROUP OF LIBRARIANS, ARCHITECTS
AND COUNTY MANAGERS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE REPUBLIC OF <Location>IRELAND</Location>. THE BASIC OBJECTIVE OF THE
TOUR WAS TO SEE A RANGE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS, VEHICLES AND EQUIPMENT WHICH
MIGHT PROVIDE INSPIRATION FOR <Organization>FUTURE IRISH LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, AND THE
JUTLAND AREA OF <Location>DENMARK</Location> WAS CHOSEN AS IT SEEMED TO REPRESENT THE MOST <Organization>SUITABLE</Organization>
EXAMPLE FOR IRISH NEEDS. GIVES BRIEF DETAILS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN THE
MUNICIPALITIES OF <Location>AARHUS</Location>, RANDERS AND HABRO, AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>&apos; <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
LAW; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS; STAFFING; AND BOOK SELECTION.
********************************************
Document 5744
ATTRACTION OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> READERS BY <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> REGIONAL AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

<Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>BULGARIA</Location>, AS ELSEWHERE, HAVE TO COMPETE WITH MASS
MEDIA, IN PARTICULAR WITH TELEVISION. MIGRATION OF YOUNG PEOPLE TO TOWNS
HAMPERS EXPANSION OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN RURAL AREAS. PEOPLE BUY MORE BOOKS AND <Organization>USE</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> LESS THAN IN THE PAST. IN SPITE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> AS WELL AS <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
NEGATIVE FACTORS, INTEREST IN READING HAS INCREASED RECENTLY AND THE
POPULATION&apos;S LEISURE TIME <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> HAVE BECOME MORE BALANCED. THUS THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization>
IN <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE TO PLAN CAREFULLY TO
ATTRACT <Organization>NEW</Organization> READERS. <Organization>ALL</Organization> AGES AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> GROUPS MUST BE CATERED FOR. IN
ADDITION TO BOOKS, SPECIAL PRINTED MATERIAL, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS SHEET-MUSIC AND
REPRODUCTION OF PAINTINGS, MUST BE MORE FULLY <Organization>USED</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5745
THE DYNAMIC <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

A PRACTICAL DISCUSSION OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S ROLE AS AN AGENT FOR <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND
<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> IMPROVEMENT IN THE COMMUNITY. TO ATTRACT READERS, THE LIBRARIAN MUST
DESIGN SERVICES TO MEET <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> NEEDS AND INTERESTS; HERE, CONTACT WITH <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
COMMUNITY LEADERS IS ESSENTIAL. TO PROJECT A DYNAMIC IMAGE, SERVICES MUST BE
MANIFESTLY RELEVANT AND <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization>, AND GEARED NOT ONLY TO <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> USERS <Organization>BUT</Organization>
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> TO NON-USERS. EMPHASISES THAT THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S PRIORITY IS TO COUNTERACT
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> APATHY BY BOLD INITIATIVES; <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> VARIOUS STRATEGIES FOR
DRAWING <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> ATTENTION, AND <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> WITH A DETAILED PLAN FOR ORGANISING A
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WEEK, ALONG THE LINES OF THE <Organization>LATIN</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BOOK
WEEK, TO HIGHLIGHT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> AND SERVICES.
********************************************
Document 5746
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DISPLAYS.

IDEAS AND HINTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DESIGN AND PRESENTATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DISPLAYS, READING
AREAS, GAMES AND BULLETIN BOARDS ARE PRESENTED BY MEANS OF ILLUSTRATIONS AND
NOTES.
********************************************
Document 5747
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INDUSTRY IN THE YEAR 2000.

COMPARES THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> STATE OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INDUSTRY TO THAT IN 1960; <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THAT COMPARISON <Organization>SOME</Organization> PREDICTIONS ARE MADE FOR THE NEXT 20-YEAR PERIOD. THE
<Organization>FURTHER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INDUSTRY WILL BE DETERMINED BY 3
FACTORS&apos; <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> INNOVATION, SOCIO-ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENTS AND THE ABILITY
OF INDUSTRY TO PRODUCE <Organization>VIABLE SYSTEMS</Organization>. PREDICTS A TREND TOWARDS UNIFICATION OF
COMPONENTS OF THE INDUSTRY, TOGETHER WITH ONE OF ELIMINATION OF INTERMEDIARIES
IN THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FLOW.
********************************************
Document 5748
GUIDEBOOK TO THE FREEDOM OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND PRIVACY ACTS.

A COMPILATION OF <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> VARIOUS SOURCES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Location>US</Location> FREEDOM OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> AND PRIVACY <Organization>ACT</Organization>, EXPLAINING THEM AND DETAILING HOW TO OBTAIN
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> UNDER THEM. INCLUDES THE FULL TEXTS OF BOTH ACTS,
SECTION-BY-SECTION ANALYSIS, AND COURT DECISIONS.
********************************************
Document 5749
<Organization>SOME THOUGHTS ON INFORMATION SYSTEMS DESIGN</Organization>.

REPORTS AN INTERVIEW WITH BENJAMIN A. SALTZER, <Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> AND
TECHNOLOGIES PROJECT MANAGER <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>NAVAL OCEAN SYSTEMS CENTER</Organization>, SYSTEMS
DEVELOPMENT BRANCH IN <Location>SAN DIEGO</Location>, <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization>. <Organization>SUMMARISES</Organization> SALTZER&apos;S VIEW <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; THE
NATURE OF <Organization>INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY</Organization>; GOALS FOR <Organization>GOVERNMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>;
AND AREAS IN WHICH EFFORT HAS TO BE EXPENDED IN THE CREATION AND
IMPLEMENTATION OF <Organization>EFFECTIVE INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>. PRESENTS HIS PHILOSOPHY OF
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> ESTABLISHMENT.
********************************************
Document 5750
AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AGENDA FOR THE 1980S.

PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A COLLOQUIUM, 17-18 JUNE 80. THE FOLLOWING PAPERS WERE
PRESENTED&apos; AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AGENDA FOR THE 1980S, BY CARLTON C. ROCHELL;
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>&apos; THE ULTIMATE FRONTIER, BY LEWIS M. BRANSCOMB; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
IMPLICATIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY</Organization>, BY LEWIS M. BRANSCOMB; HUMAN VALUES IN
THE <Organization>INFORATION SOCIETY</Organization>, BY DOUGLASS CATER; SHIFTING BOUNDARIES IN THE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MARKETPLACE, BY BENJAMIN M. COMPAINE; A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AGENDA FOR THE
1980S, BY ROBERT WEDGEWORTH; <Organization>COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY</Organization> AND THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
BY MARTIN M. CUMMINGS; A POSTSCRIPT TO AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AGENDA FOR THE 1980S, BY
DAN LACY.
********************************************
Document 5751
WHAT SHOULD USERS EXPECT <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> STORAGE AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> SYSTEMS OF THE
1980&apos;S.

<Organization>THESE</Organization> PROCEEDINGS CONCERN AN AGARD <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PANEL SPECIALISTS&apos;
MEETING HELD IN <Location>MUNICH</Location> <Location>IN</Location> SEPT 81. THE SESSIONS WERE AS FOLLOWS. SESSION 1&apos;
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> STORAGE AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> SCENE IN THE BEGINNING OF THE 80S (A
RETROSPECT OF SIGNIFICANT DEVELOPMENTS IN THE LAST DECADE AND A REVIEW OF THE
PROSPECTS AHEAD). SESSION 2 ADDRESSED <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> FACTORS WHICH WILL BE
INFLUENTIAL IN THE 80S, AND SESSION 3 WAS CONCERNED WITH <Organization>USER</Organization> EXPECTATIONS.
THE FINAL SESSION OF THE MEETING WAS A FORUM DISCUSSION IN THE FORM OF A
<Organization>USER</Organization>/SUPPLIER DIALOGUE.
********************************************
Document 5752
THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>EUROPEAN COMMISSION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ENVIRONMENT.

REPORT BY THE DIRECTOR <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MARKET AND INNOVATION,
COMMISSION OF THE <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COMMUNITIES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE COMMISSION&apos;S ROLE IN THE <Organization>EEC</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INDUSTRY.
********************************************
Document 5753
NCLIS <Organization>STUDY</Organization> URGES SEPARATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ROLES <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND PRIVATE
SECTORS.

PRESENTS THE CONCLUSIONS OF A 2-YEAR <Organization>STUDY</Organization> UNDERTAKEN BY A TASK FORCE
APPOINTED BY THE <Organization>US NATIONAL COMMISSION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IN
RECOGNITION OF THE CONFLICT OVER THE ROLES OF THE 2 SECTORS IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
GENERATION, <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>, AND DISSEMINATION. THE TASK FORCE HAS
FORMULATED PRINCIPLES FOR FEDERAL POLICY AND RECOMMENDATIONS FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
IMPLEMENTATION. IT IS IN FAVOUR OF&apos; OPEN ACCESS TO FEDERAL <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>; RELIANCE UPON <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE PRIVATE SECTOR TO MAKE <Organization>THIS</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> READILY <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>; A LEADERSHIP (RATHER THAN MANAGEMENT) ROLE FOR
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>; AND LIMITING <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> INTERVENTION IN THE MARKETPLACE.
********************************************
Document 5754
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PROBLEMS OF LIBRARIANSHIP PRACTICE.

THE 1ST SECTION DEALS WITH THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> APPARATUS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS REPRESENTED BY 4 COMPONENTS&apos; DOCUMENTOGRAPHIC AIDS, I.E. INDEXES
AND <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>; FACTOGRAPHIC PUBLICATIONS; TERTIARY SOURCES AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
FACTOGRAPHIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ABOUT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES; AND FACTOGRAPHIC NOTES
CONCERNING READERS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INTERESTS. THE 2ND SECTION LOOKS INTO THE
CREATIVE APPROACH TO THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> APPARATUS, AND THE 3RD
EXAMINES THE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> APPARATUS IN CONNECTION WITH
<Organization>READER SERVICES</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF POLITICAL <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5755
<Organization>MANAGING</Organization> THE <Organization>BELL LABORATORIES</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL REPORT SERVICE</Organization>.

THE <Organization>TECHNICAL REPORT SERVICE</Organization> (<Organization>TRS</Organization>) OF <Organization>BELL LABORATORIES (USA)</Organization> USES A
COMPUTER-DRIVEN, MICROFICHE-BASED <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> TO MANAGE <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORT
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND SERVICES. PRESENTS AN OVERVIEW OF <Organization>TRS SYSTEMS</Organization> AND SERVICES,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> METHODS OF ACQUIRING, ANNOUNCING AND DISTRIBUTING <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
REPORTS, AND <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> SPECIALISED <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> SERVICES TO A
LARGE, <Organization>SOPHISTICATED USER COMMUNITY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5756
COUNCIL OF <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> LIBRARIANS.

PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 19TH ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>MIAMI</Location> BEACH, 2-5 MAR 79.
TOPICS COVERED INCLUDE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> USES OF <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, SERVICES FOR
CITIZENS AND COMMUNITY GROUPS, GRANTSMANSHIP FOR <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> LIBRARIANS AND
MAINTAINING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES FOR THE SMALL <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5757
COUNCIL OF <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> LIBRARIANS.

PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 20TH ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, 11-14 APR 80.
TOPICS COVERED INCLUDE NEIGHBOURHOOD DEMOGRAPHY, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> ALTERNATIVE
MODES OF URBAN TRANSIT AND TRANSFER OF ENERGY CONSERVATION <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> LEVEL TO THE FEDERAL LEVEL (AND VICE-VERSA).
********************************************
Document 5758
ESTABLISHING AN ENVIRONMENTAL <Organization>INFORMATION CENTER</Organization>&apos; A GUIDE TO ORGANIZATION AND
OPERATION.

THE CENTER FOR ENVIRONMENTAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (CEI) WAS ESTABLISHED TO SERVE THE
<Location>ROCHESTER</Location>, <Location><Location>NY</Location></Location> METROPOLITAN REGION AS A CLEARING-HOUSE FOR ENVIRONMENTAL
CONCERNS. SINCE <Organization>ITS</Organization> INCEPTION, CEI HAS BEEN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> INTO A <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICE</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE CENTRE</Organization>. PRESENTS DETAILED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OF CEI&apos;S (1) EARLY HISTORY; (2)
ADMINISTRATION AND MANAGEMENT; (3) PROGRAMMES AND SERVICES; (4) MEMBERSHIP AND
CLIENTELE; AND (5) FINANCES, BUDGETS, AND FUND RAISING. THE POSSIBILITY OF
USING <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SUPPORT FOR A <Organization>COMMUNITY-BASED CENTRE</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS
CEI IS EXPLORED.
********************************************
Document 5759
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND IMPLEMENTING <Organization>SOCIAL SERVICE INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>&apos; A GUIDE FOR
MANAGEMENT AND USERS.

DEALS WITH THE DESIGN OF A <Organization>SOCIAL SERVICE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. IDENTIFIES
<Organization>CRITICAL</Organization> ELEMENTS, <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> STRATEGIES, AND POTENTIAL PITFALLS IN THE
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization>, IMPLEMENTATION, AND UTILISATION OF <Organization>SUCH SYSTEMS</Organization>. THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS
INTENDED TO HELP ADMINISTRATORS AND USERS <Organization>ESTABLISH SUCCESSFUL SOCIAL SERVICE</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>, ANTICIPATE AND AVOID PROBLEMS ALREADY FACED BY SIMILAR
AGENCIES, AND MAXIMISE THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> SYSTEMS.
********************************************
Document 5760
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS MUNICIPAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES; THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> EXPERIENCE.

TALK GIVEN TO THE 14TH NORDIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEETING HELD IN <Location>STOCKHOLM</Location> AUG 80. THE
<Organization>DANISH LOCAL AUTHORITY</Organization> REFORMS OF 1970 AND THE <Organization>LOCAL AUTHORITY</Organization> <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> OF
1977, WHICH EXTENDED THE DEMOCRATIC PRINCIPLE, INTENSIFIED THE <Organization>DEMAND</Organization> FOR A
MORE <Organization>EFFICIENT PUBLIC INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization>. TO SATISFY <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>DEMAND</Organization> THE STATE
<Organization>INFORMATION OFFICE</Organization> FOR DISTRIBUTION OF <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WAS SET UP IN
1977 AND COOPERATION WITH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ESTABLISHED. THE REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> &apos;<Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
PARTICIPATORY DEMOCRACY&apos; STIMULATED THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE &apos;KOMMUNE-INFORMATION&apos; <Organization>AT</Organization> THE TOWN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF
LYNGBY-TAARBAEK WAS SET UP IN 1977. IT IS PLACED CLOSE TO THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> ROOM
AND STAFFED BY 1 FULL-TIME LIBRARIAN. CLOSE COOPERATION WITH THE TOWN HALL
EXISTS AND CONTACT PERSONS IN <Organization>EACH DEPARTMENT</Organization> WERE APPOINTED. <Organization>ALL</Organization> MATERIAL
AUTOMATICALLY SENT TO KOMMUNE-INFORMATION IS CATALOGUED AND DISPLAYED AND <Organization>SOME</Organization>
MAY BE BORROWED. AN INFORMATIO N INDEX OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> ITEMS IS BEING BUILT UP.
AROUND 400 ENQUIRIES A MONTH ARE DEALT WITH, <Organization>SOME</Organization> BY <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE RELEVANT
DEPARTMENT, OTHERS DIRECTLY, CONCERNING&apos; DECISIONS MADE, RIGHTS AND DUTIES,
ON-GOING PROJECTS, <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> GROUPS AND SOCIETIES. DESPITE THE NEED FEW <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES HAVE FOLLOWED <Organization>THIS</Organization> EXAMPLE.
********************************************
Document 5761
THE BUSINESS DECADE.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE MAIN DEVELOPMENTS IN THE <Location>UK</Location> BUSINESS <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCENE
DURING THE PAST DECADE. BRIEFLY REVIEWS&apos; THE ESTABLISHMENT OF THE <Location>CITY</Location>
BUSINESS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; THE GROWTH OF <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> OFFERED BY COMMERCIAL
FIRMS; THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>ON-LINE DATA</Organization> BASES; THE WORK DONE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> AREA BY
THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> SPECIAL AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SECTION, AND THE
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5762
TRANSFER AND EXPLOITATION OF SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>&apos; PROCEEDINGS
OF THE SYMPOSIUM HELD IN <Location>LUXEMBOURG</Location>, 10 TO 12 JUNE 1981.

(THE SYMPOSIUM COORDINATOR WAS J. MICHEL GIBB, AND THE SYMPOSIUM SECRETARY,
DENIS NICOLAY). PAPERS ARE GROUPED BY SESSION-(1) INTRODUCTION; (2) THE NEEDS
OF THE ECONOMY AND OBSTACLES TO TRANSFER; (3) EXPLOITATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>; (4)
TECHNOLOGY TRANSFER AND INDUSTRIAL PROPERTY; (5) TOWARDS <Organization>BETTER</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>
AND TRANSFER; AND (6) CONCLUSIONS-TASKS FOR THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>. THE SYMPOSIUM WAS HELD
BY THE COMMISSION OF THE <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COMMUNITIES, DIRECTORATE-GENERAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
MARKET AND INNOVATION.
********************************************
Document 5763
<Organization>INFORMATION MANAGEMENT</Organization>. 4TH REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF THE COMMITTEE FOR
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY OF THE <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization>
COMMUNITIES (1978-80).

THE FIRST 3 REPORTS OF THE COMMITTEE ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> AS EUR 5177, EUR 5597 AND
EUR 6158 RESPECTIVELY. THE 1ST 3-YEAR PLAN OF <Organization>ACTION</Organization> WAS 1975-77 AND <Organization>THIS</Organization>
FORMED THE BASIS OF THE 2ND 3-YEAR PLAN OF <Organization>ACTION</Organization> (1978-80), THE <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF
WHICH ARE DESCRIBED IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> REPORT.
********************************************
Document 5764
SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> INFORMATION-A PRE-CONDITION OF SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization>.

IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>, CENTRES OF SCIENTIFIC, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
ARE <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> IN OPERATION NOT ONLY IN DESIGN CENTRES AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
INSTITUTES, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> LARGER FACTORIES. THE CORE OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A CENTRE IS THE
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. IN MOST <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> AND MONOGRAPHS STILL
PREVAIL, <Organization>BUT</Organization> LATELY PATENTS, STANDARDS, DISSERTATIONS, <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> REPORTS, TRADE
<Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> AND DOCUMENTARY FILMS ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>. THE CENTRES&apos; <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>
DEPEND, OF COURSE, VERY MUCH <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND EQUIPMENT. <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP DATA AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> BASES, UNDER EXPLORATION OF INTERNAL AND <Organization>EXTERNAL</Organization> RESOURCES, IS
OF PRIMARY IMPORTANCE. TRANSLATIONS, ESPECIALLY THOSE <Organization>FROM</Organization> FOREIGN LANGUAGES
INTO <Organization>SLOVAK</Organization> AND CZECH ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> USERS ARE TAUGHT TO <Organization>USE</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES MORE EFFICIENTLY AND EFFECTIVELY. IN ADDITION TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
RELEVANT <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING THEIR OWN CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENT ISTS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> SHOULD ENGAGE IN THEORETICAL STUDIES AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>,
THE RESULTS OF WHICH SHOULD BE PUBLISHED WHEREVER POSSIBLE.
********************************************
Document 5765
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENT&apos; TOWARDS A
POLICY OF <Organization>ACTION</Organization>.

ANALYSES THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF ORGANISING THE DIFFUSION OF SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE EFFECTIVENESS OF THE
<Organization>ALSACE REGIONAL AGENCY</Organization> FOR SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (ARIST) IN
MEETING THE NEEDS OF SMALL BUSINESSES. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE VARIOUS
ORGANISATIONS AND <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization> IN THE REGION INVOLVED IN SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, SHOWING THE TENDENCY TO OVERLAP
AND DUPLICATE SERVICES, AND THE FAILURE TO PROVIDE 2A PRIORI1 <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO
ASSIST USERS TO ANTICIPATE DEVELOPMENTS. PROPOSALS ARE THEN PRESENTED FOR
<Organization>IMPROVING SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> LINKING THE VARIOUS ORGANISATIONS CONCERNED, SO
THAT BY POOLING <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, DEVELOPMENTS CAN BE
PREDICTED, AND PROGRAMMES OF STRATEGIC INTERVENTION DEVELOPED FOR BUSINESS
INTERESTS AFFECTED.
********************************************
Document 5766
THE DIFFUSION OF SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN <Location>FRANCE</Location>. EXAMPLES OF
INITIATIVES UNDERTAKEN BY THE <Organization>ALSACE REGIONAL AGENCY</Organization> FOR SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (ARIST).

AN ACCOUNT OF THE VARIOUS TYPES OF SERVICES TO INDUSTRY PROVIDED BY ARIST
SHOWING KINDS OF PROBLEMS ENCOUNTERED AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> STRATEGIES EVOLVED TO
SOLVE THEM. A PRELIMINARY EXPLANATION IS GIVEN OF THE ORGANISATION OF THE
<Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. 4 LEVELS OF
INTERVENTION ARE DESCRIBED WITH SPECIFIC EXAMPLES&apos; THE READY-REFERENCE TYPE
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization>; PROVISION OF SPECIALISED SCIENTIFIC, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>, AND
ECONOMIC DOCUMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A GIVEN SUBJECT; PREPARATION OF ANALYTICAL REPORTS
SUMMARISING <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF A PARTICULAR PROBLEM, INVOLVING CONSULTATION WITH
SPECIALISTS AND SPECIAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>; AND A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE SERVICE</Organization> TO ASSIST FIRMS
IN DIVERSIFICATION AND DEVELOPMENT. INVITES CRITICISM OF THE TECHNIQUES
DESCRIBED SO THAT SERVICES CAN BE IMPROVED.
********************************************
Document 5767
IMPLEMENTATION OF A <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY (<Organization>S&amp;T</Organization>) <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> DELIVERY
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IN NEBRASKA, A LEGISLATIVE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS ESTABLISHED, AND AN
IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PROGRAMME WAS DEVELOPED WITH <Organization>EMPHASIS ON S&amp;T</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
FOR THE LEGISLATIVE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. TO ADDRESS THE DELIVERY OF <Organization>S&amp;T</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
INTO THE LEGISLATIVE <Organization>PROCESS</Organization>, <Organization>PROTOTYPE DATA BASES ON CERTAIN S&amp;T</Organization> TOPICS WHICH
RECEIVED SPECIAL LEGISLATIVE ATTENTION WERERE CREATED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
<Organization>EXISTING COMPUTER</Organization> COMPATIBILITY.
********************************************
Document 5768
EXCHANGE OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROGRAM ANNUAL REPORT, FISCAL YEAR 1980.

ANNUAL REPORT OF THE EXCHANGE OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (EMI) PROGRAMME FOR 1980.
ESTABLISHED BY <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LAW 89785, THE PROGRAMME&apos;S PURPOSE IS TO FUND AND
SUPPORT PILOT PROJECTS AIMED <Organization>AT STRENGTHENING VETERANS ADMINISTRATION</Organization> (VA)
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> FACILITIES LOCATED IN REMOTE AREAS BY <Organization>PROMOTING</Organization> CONSULTATION AND
CO-OPERATION WITH <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> PERSONNEL <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> TEACHING CENTRES AND LARGER
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> FACILITIES INSIDE AND OUTSIDE THE <Organization>VA HOSPITAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5769
STRATEGIES FOR <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> REVIEWS AND GREY <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.

AS A RESULT OF THE CRAIG REPORT (2SEE1 80/4557) AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> FOLLOW-UP (2SEE1
81/3454) THE IMPORTANCE OF, AND THE NEED TO DEVELOP <Organization>BETTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>
FOR, NON-CONVENTIONAL <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND REVIEWS WAS HIGHLIGHTED. THE OBJECTIVES
OF THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WERE TO <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> A COMMENTARY <Organization>ON</Organization> GREY <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND REVIEWS IN
<Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>UK</Location> AND TO PROVIDE AN INDEPENDENT ASSESSMENT OF
THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> NEEDS IN THE AREA AND MAKE SPECIFIC RECOMMENDATIONS FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
IMPLEMENTATION.
********************************************
Document 5770
CONTRIBUTIONS TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES WITHIN THE IRON AND STEEL
INDUSTRY 1961-1981.

(STATEMENT OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ACHIEVEMENT SUBMITTED FOR FELLOWSHIP OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION). AN ACCOUNT OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE AUTHOR&apos;S ACHIEVEMENTS OR CONTRIBUTIONS
TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES IN THE <Location>UK</Location> IRON AND STEEL INDUSTRY OVER 20
YEARS.
********************************************
Document 5771
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> IN THE CONSTRUCTION INDUSTRY-A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
NEED AND PROVISION.

THERE IS AMPLE RECORD THAT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> HANDLING OCCUPIES A <Organization>HIGH</Organization> PERCENTAGE OF
PRODUCTION TIME AND THAT POOR PERFORMANCE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD IS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ROOT OF MANY
OF THE INDUSTRY&apos;S PROBLEMS. <Organization>SUCH</Organization> PROBLEMS FALL INTO 2 MAIN CATEGORIES. THE 1ST
RELATES TO BUILDINGS THEMSELVES AND CONCERNS <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> (COLLAPSE, FIRE, LEAKS,
CONDENSATION) AND SPATIAL (SHORT LIFE, TIGHT FIT, <Organization>HIGH ENERGY</Organization>) FAILURE. THE
2ND CATEGORY CONCERNS ORGANISATIONAL FAILURES. CLEARLY IMPROVEMENTS IN BOTH
<Organization>THESE</Organization> CATEGORIES COULD BE BENEFICIAL.
********************************************
Document 5772
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TRANSFER&apos; A CONCEPTUAL MODEL FOR LIBRARIANSHIP, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MANAGEMENT WITH IMPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO EDUCATION FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK. TRADITIONALLY, THERE ARE 5 BASIC FUNCTIONS WHICH THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
LIBRARIANSHIP PERFORM FOR SOCIETY-ARCHIVAL, <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>, <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>,
RECREATIONAL AND INFORMATIONAL. UNFORTUNATELY, <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>, WHILE <Organization>GIVING</Organization>
LIP-SERVICE TO THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> FUNCTIONS, HAS REMAINED PREOCCUPIED WITH THE ARCHIVAL
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>. PROPOSES A THEORETICAL MODEL OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TRANSFER. THE
RESPECTIVE ROLES OF LIBRARIANS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
MANAGERS ARE IDENTIFIED WITHIN <Organization>THIS</Organization> MODEL IN THE CONTEXT OF THE 5 FUNCTIONS
DISCUSSED ABOVE. IMPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>CURRICULUM DESIGN</Organization> ARE DISCUSSED.
RECOMMENDATIONS FOR PROGRAMMES OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization> BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A COMMON CORE, <Organization>BUT</Organization> WITH
DISTINCT AREAS OF SPECIALISATION FOR STUDENTS <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR THE 3 <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
FIELDS, ARE PRESENTED.
********************************************
Document 5773
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS A COMMODITY&apos; THERE&apos;S NO <Organization>SUCH</Organization> THING AS A <Organization>FREE</Organization> HUNCH.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization> ACADEMIC AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> LIBRARIANS MEETING <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE <Organization>CALIFORNIA LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, 14 DEC
81. IN THE <Location>USA</Location> AMIDST AN ABUNDANCE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THERE ARE GROWING
RESTRICTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AVAILABILITY AND <Organization>USE</Organization>. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS BECOMING A
MARKET COMMODITY, THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RESOURCE BASE ITSELF SHIFTING <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> TO THE PRIVATE SECTOR WHICH SETS TO MAINTAIN PROPRIETARY CONTROL OF <Organization>ITS</Organization>
PRODUCTS AND SERVICES <Organization>LEADING</Organization> TO INCREASING RESTRICTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> ACCESS. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS A COMMODITY IN <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> AND IN <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5774
THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> CONSEQUENCES FOR THE <Organization>INFORMATION SOCIETY</Organization>&apos; A PANORAMA OF THE ACTUAL
SITUATION.

1ST OF A PROJECTED SERIES REVIEWING <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> AND POLICY DEVELOPMENTS IN
THE <Organization>INFORMATION SOCIETY</Organization> THROUGHOUT THE WORLD COVERING OFFICIAL REPORTS
RECENTLY PUBLISHED IN <Location>FRANCE</Location>, <Location>USA</Location> AND THE <Location>UK</Location>. THE 1978 <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> REPORT BY NORA
AND MINC IS DISCUSSED FULLY WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> COVERAGE OF
DEVELOPMENTS IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS, THE QUESTION OF RELATIONS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> AND COMMERCIAL INTERESTS, THE ROLE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN
ADMINISTRATION, AND THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> ISSUES INVOLVED. RECENT <Location>US</Location>
CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> PREDICTING <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS IN THE
<Organization>INFORMATION SOCIETY</Organization> ARE SURVEYED, AND <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> VIEWPOINT.
CONSIDERS THE SITUATION IN <Location>SPAIN</Location> AND WHAT KIND OF POLICY SHOULD BE ADOPTED IN
THE LIGHT OF INITIAL FINDINGS, AND IN CONCLUSION EXAMINES THE QUESTION OF
SECURITY OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO DATA BASES AND DECOMOCRATISATION.
EMPHASISES THE NECESSITY FOR A GLOBAL VIEW IN POLICY <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND THE NEED FOR
AN OFFICIAL REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> SPAIN&apos;S ACTUAL AND POTENTIAL SITUATION.
********************************************
Document 5775
THE ROLE OF COMMUNICATIONS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RESOURCES IN <Location>CANADA</Location>.

EXAMINES THE ENTIRE RANGE OF COMMUNICATIONS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MATTERS IN TERMS
OF UNDERLYING POLITICAL, ECONOMIC AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> FORCES IN <Location>CANADA</Location> WITH SPECIAL
<Organization>EMPHASIS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> CANADA&apos;S 3 MAIN CONCERNS&apos; UNITY, ECONOMIC VIABILITY AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
IDENTITY. IT IS INTENDED TO SERVE AS A BASE FOR <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> EXAMINATION OF
<Organization>US-CANADIAN COMMUNICATIONS</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RELATIONSHIPS.
********************************************
Document 5776
PERFORMANCE MEASUREMENT AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ARRANGEMENT.

DESCRIBES AN ATTEMPT BY ASLIB TO DEVELOP A CHECKLIST FOR THE EVALUATION OF
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES COVERING CURRENT AWARENESS SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>RETRIEVAL SERVICES</Organization>, DOCUMENT DELIVERY AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MISCELLANEOUS EVALUATION
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>. THERE WAS LITTLE SUPPORT <Organization>FROM</Organization> PRACTITIONERS FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF
GUIDELINES RELATING TO SPECIFIC ITEMS IN THE CHECKLIST <Organization>BUT</Organization> CHOOSING <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> AN
<Organization>IN-HOUSE DATA</Organization> BASE AND RELIANCE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>EXTERNAL</Organization> <Organization>SUPPLIES</Organization> WAS SEEN AS AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> OF
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> SIGNIFICANCE. <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> THE NEED FOR A &apos;USER-FRIENDLY&apos; PACKAGE BRINGING
TOGETHER THE BEST OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> PERFORMANCE MEASUREMENT TO ENCOURAGE
<Organization>ITS</Organization> WIDESPREAD ADOPTION.
********************************************
Document 5777
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> CHALLENGES TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MANAGERS.

STRESSES THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS AN ECONOMIC PRODUCT AND EMPHASISES
<Organization>ITS</Organization> VITAL ROLE IN SOCIETY. SINCE THE VALUE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO SOCIETY IS
INCREASING, <Organization>ITS MANAGEMENT</Organization> SHOULD BE STRENGTHENED-THIS IS A CHALLENGE TO
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MANAGERS, PARTICULARLY IN BALANCING REDUCTION OF RESOURCE
INVESTMENTS AND INCREASES IN THE VALUE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ASSETS. AN ANALYSIS OF
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CYCLE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> RESPECT IS GIVEN AND A PLEA IS MADE FOR
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MANAGERS TO CONTRIBUTE SIGNIFICANTLY TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE
<Organization>FUTURE OFFICE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5778
INCREASING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF DATA TELECOMMUNICATIONS CALLS FOR STRONG PRIVACY PROTECTION
AND IMPROVED ECONOMIES.

THE <Organization>US GENERAL ACCOUNTING OFFICE</Organization> HAS CONCLUDED THAT INCREASING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF DATA
TELECOMMUNICATIONS CALLS FOR STRONG PRIVACY PROTECTION AND IMPROVED ECONOMIES,
AFTER CONDUCTING A REVIEW OF <Organization>CIVIL AGENCY</Organization> DATA TELECOMMUNICATIONS NETWORKS AND
<Organization>RELATED</Organization> PRIVACY ISSUES. THE OFFICE HAS <Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> TO THE <Organization>SENATE COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE JUDICIARY AND HOUSE COMMITTEE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> OPERATIONS THAT CONGRESS
REVISE &apos;WIRETAP&apos; LAWS TO STRENGTHEN PROTECTIVE PROVISIONS; AND THAT THE
DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF MANAGEMENT AND BUDGET <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> EXTRA EXECUTIVE LEVEL
PROTECTIVE POLICIES AND GUIDELINES FOR DATA TRANSMISSIONS OF <Organization>PERSONAL DATA</Organization>,
AND MAKE A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TO PROVIDE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO CONGRESS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
MERITS AND PROBLEMS OF IMPLEMENTATING A <Organization>COMMON-USER DATA</Organization> TELECOMMUNICATIONS
NETWORK FOR THE <Organization>CIVIL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5779
SURVEYS <Organization>ON</Organization> PRIVACY AND BIG BUSINESS, BANKING, AND INSURANCE.

THE SURVEYS, CONDUCTED BY THE <Organization>SURVEY RESEARCH LABORATORY</Organization>, UNIVERSITY OF
ILLINOIS, SOUGHT TO DETERMINE THE EXTENT TO WHICH POLICIES SAFEGUARDING
<Organization>PERSONAL</Organization>, FINANCIAL AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> HAVE BEEN IMPLEMENTED. RESULTS
INDICATE THAT <Organization>SOME</Organization> LARGE <Location>US</Location> INDUSTRIAL CORPORATIONS HAVE INADEQUATE POLICIES
TO PROTECT SENSITIVE EMPLOYEE DATA <Organization>FROM</Organization> POSSIBLE ABUSE; THE IDEA THAT A
PERSON&apos;S FINANCES ARE A PRIVATE MATTER <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> HIM AND HIS BANKER IS NO LONGER
TRUE; AND THAT MOST INSURANCE COMPANIES HAVE ADOPTED MANY PROTECTIONS
<Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> BY THE <Organization>US PRIVACY PROTECTION STUDY COMMISSION</Organization> AFTER AN
INVESTIGATION INTO THE INSURANCE INDUSTRY&apos;S RECORD-KEEPING PRACTICES.
********************************************
Document 5780
<Organization>COMPUTER-BASED NATIONAL INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>. TECHNOLOGY AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> POLICY
ISSUES.

PRESENTS THE RESULTS OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMPUTER TECHNOLOGY IN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> AND <Organization>RELATED</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> POLICY ISSUES. THE PURPOSE OF THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization>
WAS TO PROVIDE&apos; A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> INTRODUCTION TO <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SYSTEMS; A FRAMEWORK FOR <Organization>UNDERSTANDING COMPUTER</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICY ISSUES; A
STATE OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF COMPUTER AND <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TECHNOLOGIES/INDUSTRIES; AND A
FOUNDATION FOR <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>RELATED</Organization> STUDIES.
********************************************
Document 5781
HYSTERIA IS UNNECESSARY&apos; OBSERVATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR OF THE <Location>USA</Location>.

THE TOUR WAS MADE IN CONNECTION WITH PLANS FOR <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> GERMAN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> SERVICES. MANY <Location>US</Location> DEVELOPMENTS COULD NOT BE TRANSFERRED
DIRECTLY TO EUROPE SINCE THEY <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE UNSUITABLE FOR A SMALL MARKET. IN THE
<Location>USA</Location> A WIDE RANGE OF <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization> IS INVOLVED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> DISSEMINATION, IN
CONTRAST WITH THE SMALLER, GOVERNMENT-BASED ORGANISATION PLANNED FOR <Location>WEST
GERMANY</Location>. THE <Location>US</Location> ECONOMIC CLIMATE LENDS ITSELF TO EXPERIMENT <Organization>BETTER</Organization> THAN THE
<Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization>. THE <Location>US</Location> MARKET FOR <Organization>LITERATURE REFERENCE DATA</Organization> BASES HAS REACHED
SATURATION POINT AND THE MAIN GROWTH AREAS ARE IN FACTOGRAPHIC AND FULL <Organization>TEXT</Organization>
DATA BASES. <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> TRENDS ARE AGAINST THE SUPERMARKET APPROACH TO SELLING. A
WIDE RANGE OF <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> EXPERIMENTS ARE BEING CARRIED OUT. MANY PEOPLE
CONSIDER THAT THE CLOSE LINK WITH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS RETURNING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT.
********************************************
Document 5782
A <Organization>DOCUMENTATION FRANCAISE SERVICE</Organization>&apos; THE POLITICAL AND <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> AFFAIRS
<Organization>INFORMATION BANK</Organization> (B.I.P.A.).

<Organization>SUMMARY</Organization> OF A PRESENTATION DELIVERED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>FRENCH LIBRARIANS ASSOCIATION</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARIES GROUP</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> SESSION IN JAN 81. B.I.P.A. IS A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> ARCHIVE
FOR POLITICAL, ECONOMIC AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, IN RELATION TO
ADMINISTRATIVE, POLITICAL, PRESS, AND PHOTOGRAPHIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>; AND DIFFUSION
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> ACCESS TO DATA, MICROFICHE
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, AND PUBLICATIONS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> AND INDEXES.
********************************************
Document 5783
<Organization>MEDICAL INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>&apos; APPLICATIONS AND EVALUATION. 1973-APRIL, 1982
(CITATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE ENGINEERING INDEX DATA BASE).

BIBLIOGRAPHY CONTAINS CITATIONS CONCERNING THE APPLICATIONS OF COMPUTER BASED
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> IN HOSPITALS, CLINICS, LABORATORIES, AND DOCTORS&apos; OFFICES
FOR DATA RECORDING AND REPORTING OF PATIENT <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> AND ACCOUNTING RECORDS.
<Organization>MICROCOMPUTER SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE DISCUSSED.
********************************************
Document 5784
THE DEVELOPMENT OF COMPUTER SYSTEMS IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PRACTICE.

(<Organization>MSC</Organization> THESIS). IN RECENT YEARS IT HAS BEEN INCREASINGLY REALISED THAT
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> HANDLING IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PRACTICE IS INADEQUATE FOR <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> A <Organization>HIGH</Organization>
STANDARD OF <Organization>HEALTH CARE</Organization>, PARTICULARLY IN PREVENTIVE MEDICINE AND CHRONIC
DISEASE SURVEILLANCE. THE <Organization>CONVENTIONAL PATIENT RECORDS</Organization> HAVE BEEN PARTICULARLY
CRITICISED. A QUESTIONNAIRE SENT TO <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PRACTITIONERS INTERESTED IN
<Organization>MICROCOMPUTER-BASED INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> REVEALED THAT WITHIN 3 YEARS MOST OF
THE GROUP <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE OPERATING <Organization>SUCH SYSTEMS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5785
A TEXTBOOK OF <Organization>CRITICAL THINKING-PRODUCED BY TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization>-NEEDED BY
PATRON&apos;S SERVICES.

BRIEFLY DESCRIBES THE TEACHING OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> TO PATRONS OF THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
SECTION OF THE DAUGHTERS OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> REVOLUTION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND STUDENTS OF
THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> OF <Organization>GEORGETOWN UNIVERSITY</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PYRAMID WITH FACT AS <Organization>ITS</Organization> BASE, OPINION AS THE MIDSECTION AND VALUE
JUDGMENT AS THE CAPSTONE. LIBRARIANS SHOULD <Organization>AIM</Organization> TO FILL THE MISSING LINK
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> BASIC LITERACY SKILLS AND <Organization>CRITICAL</Organization> THINKING.
********************************************
Document 5786
THE TRAVELLING WORKSHOPS EXPERIMENT IN <Organization>LIBRARY USER EDUCATION</Organization>.

FOR AN ABSTRACT 2SEE1 82/1797.
********************************************
Document 5787
THE IMPORTANCE OF TEACHING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

INTRODUCTION TO AN OCCASIONAL SERIES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> INSTRUCTIONS IN ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. BIBLIOGRAPHIC INSTRUCTION IS TEACHING STUDENTS HOW TO FIND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> EFFICIENTLY AND EFFECTIVELY IN THE MODERN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. INSTITUTING
BIBLIOGRAPHIC INSTRUCTION PROGRAMMES PERMITS STUDENTS TO DO <Organization>BETTER</Organization> WORK, TO BE
MORE INDEPENDENT IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK AND TO HAVE MORE MOTIVATION. <Organization>THIS</Organization> ALLOWS
ASSIGNMENTS TO BE MORE VARIED AND EXPECTATIONS CAN BE <Organization>HIGHER</Organization>. BIBLIOGRAPHIC
INSTRUCTION <Organization>ALSO</Organization> HELPS TO INSURE THAT THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS WELL USED-AN IMPORTANT
ARGUMENT WHEN COST EFFECTIVENESS IS A PRIME CONSIDERATION IN <Organization>ALL</Organization>
ADMINISTRATIVE DECISIONS.
********************************************
Document 5788
BIBLIOGRAPHIC INSTRUCTION...AGAIN.

DESCRIBES <Organization>SOME</Organization> RECENT INNOVATIONS IN BIBLIOGRAPHIC INSTRUCTION IN ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN COLORADO. <Organization>THESE</Organization> INCLUDE&apos; A NEW 2 HOUR INSTRUCTION PROGRAMME <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO WHICH AIMS TO TEACH STUDENTS HOW TO DEVELOP <Organization>SEARCH</Organization>
STRATEGIES; THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> AS AN INSTRUCTIONAL TOOL; THE
COMPILATION OF A DIRECTORY OF BIBLIOGRAPHIC INSTRUCTION IN COLORADO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>;
AND THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A CLEARINGHOUSE FOR IDEAS AND <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> DEALING WITH
BIBLIOGRAPHIC INSTRUCTION.
********************************************
Document 5789
<Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> APPROACH.

A DISCUSSION RELATING RECENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN ENGLISH AND SPANISH TO THE
<Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> SITUATION, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD HAS BEEN LARGELY NEGLECTED. THE MAIN
OBJECTIVE OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> PROGRAMMES IS TO TRAIN CHILDREN HOW TO <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND
ACQUAINT THEM WITH THE SERVICES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>; HERE THE ROLE OF THE LIBRARIAN IN
PRESENTING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS A PLACE FOR BOTH LEISURE AND <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IS CRUCIAL.
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PROGRAMMES ARE PRESENTED, FOR BOTH <Organization>NEW</Organization> USERS AND OLDER CHILDREN, AND
TEACHING METHODS WHICH CAN BE INTEGRATED INTO THE SCHOOL <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> SUGGESTED.
FINALLY, SURVEYS TECHNIQUES FOR EVALUATING <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization> AND IN CONCLUSION
EMPHASISES THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR THE CHILD&apos;S <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENT.
********************************************
Document 5790
<Organization>USER EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Organization>SECONDARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE SCHOOL LIBRARIAN SHOULD TAKE THE INITIATIVE IN THE TEACHING OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SKILLS TO PUPILS WITHOUT SUBJECT BIAS. GETTING TO KNOW PUPILS IS
IMPORTANT SO THAT THE <Organization>APPROPRIATE SERVICE</Organization> CAN BE OFFERED. REGULAR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
VISITS FOR 1ST-YEAR PUPILS ARE ESPECIALLY VALUABLE AND ARE BEST DONE BY
TIMETABLING A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LESSON THAT IS NOT ATTACHED TO A PARTICULAR SUBJECT
AREA. THEREAFTER VISITS CAN BE ORGANISED AS REQUIRED <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE NEED FOR A MORE
STRUCTURED APPROACH IS OFTEN FELT BY THE START OF THE 4TH YEAR. IT IS
IMPORTANT TOO THAT THE TEACHING <Organization>STAFF</Organization> HAVE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SKILLS AND
<Organization>THESE</Organization> CAN BE DEVELOPED BY THE LIBRARIAN.
********************************************
Document 5791
TEACHING TECHNIQUES FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

SCHOOL CHILDREN NEED TO LEARN HOW TO <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND WHAT IS <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN A
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. SURVEYS WERE CARRIED OUT TO FIND OUT WHAT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> CHILDREN READ.
BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE RESULTS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> SURVEYS A COURSE FOR TEACHING CHILDREN
TECHNIQUES FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS DEVELOPED. THE COURSE CONSISTED OF
CLASSWORK&apos; ANALYSING FAVOURITE BOOKS, DISCOVERING THE CONTENTS LIST, PREFACE,
TITLE, PUBLISHER ETC. AND VISITS TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. DURING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> VISITS THE
CHILDREN WORKED IN GROUPS WITH GIVEN TASKS. <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> ASKING LIBRARIANS AND
OTHERS THEY WERE TO DISCOVER VARIOUS MEANS OF FINDING BOOKS. THEY WERE <Organization>ALSO</Organization>
ENCOURAGED TO FIND OUT HOW A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS ORGANISED, WHAT <Organization>LENDING</Organization> CONDITIONS ARE
AND WHAT <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> A LIBRARIAN NEEDS. THE GROUPS COMPARED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESULTS IN
CLASSWORK.
********************************************
Document 5792
BOOKS AND SCI-TECH STUDENTS AND ACADEMICS.

LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>WAY</Organization> IN WHICH <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY STUDENTS AND LECTURERS <Organization>USE</Organization>
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> METHODS OF <Organization>PROMOTING</Organization> <Organization>BETTER</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> BY <Organization>THESE</Organization> GROUPS
<Organization>THROUGH USER EDUCATION</Organization>. <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> SUBJECT KNOWLEDGE IS VERY IMPORTANT IN
ESTABLISHING ACADEMIC LIBRARIANSHIP IN THE EYES OF ACADEMICS.
********************************************
Document 5793
EVALUATION OF BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> IN <Location>CURITIBA</Location>.

REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> CONCERNING <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> PRODUCTION OF <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> AND BIBLIOGRAPHIES
IN <Location>CURITIBA</Location>, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>. EXAMINES THE EXTENT TO WHICH PUBLISHERS COMPLY WITH LEGAL
DEPOSIT REGULATIONS, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN PUBLICATION PROJECTS, AND THE NATIONALLY
<Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> PUBLISHING STANDARDS. DATA COLLECTED BY THE UNIVERSITY OF PARANA
<Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> WAS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO ANALYSE COVERAGE BY BIBLIOGRAPHIES AND UNION
<Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization> PUBLISHED OVER THE DECADE 1970-80; RESULTS SHOWED THAT <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
LIBRARIANS WERE CHIEFLY RESPONSIBLE FOR THE CREATION OF BIBLIOGRAPHIC TOOLS,
WHILE PUBLISHERS GENERALLY DISREGARDED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OBLIGATIONS. RECOMMENDS STRICTER
ENFORCEMENT OF LEGAL DEPOSIT AND GREATER ENCOURAGEMENT FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5794
BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL&apos; A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.

A LIST OF REFERENCES COVERING <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> AND FOREIGN <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL PUBLISHED <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 1970-80. PRELIMINARY DETAILS ARE GIVEN
OF SOURCES <Organization>USED</Organization> FOR COLLECTING MATERIAL AND THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF ARRANGEMENT. THE
REFERENCES ARE DIVIDED INTO 12 SECTIONS&apos; BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL; <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SYSTEMS; INTERNATIONAL <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> CODES; LEGAL DEPOSIT; <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
BIBLIOGRAPHIES; INTERNATIONAL BIBLIOGRAPHIES; COOPERATIVE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>; UNION
<Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>; <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN SOURCE; SIMPLIFIED <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>; <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization>
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>; AND <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5795
<Organization>HMSO</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS&apos; A <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> ACCOUNT.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE DEVELOPMENTS IN <Organization>HMSO CATALOGUING SERVICES</Organization> THAT HAVE
TAKEN PLACE SINCE THE AUTHOR TOOK OVER AS HEAD OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL SERVICES</Organization> IN
1979. DESCRIBES BRIEFLY&apos; IMPROVEMENTS THAT HAVE BEEN MADE IN THE TIMETABLING
OF <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>; THE INTRODUCTION OF THE <Organization>DAILY PRESTEL INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization>; AND
THE COMPUTERISATION OF <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>. LISTS <Organization>ALL</Organization> PUBLICATIONS CURRENTLY <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization>
UNDER <Organization>HMSO</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> PROGRAMME, AND CONSIDERS THE POSSIBILITY OF <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>CATALOGUE RECORDS</Organization> BEING MADE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> IN THE NEAR <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5796
BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IN <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.

A DESCRIPTIVE ACCOUNT STRESSING THE NEED FOR <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL
TO AVOID DUPLICATION OF PUBLICATION AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> BRIEFLY THE
FACTORS INFLUENCING THE GENERATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THE
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IS INCREASING <Organization>RAPIDLY</Organization>. <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHIC TOOLS, WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO PROJECTS INITIATED
BY THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (IBICT),
AS WELL AS BIBLIOGRAPHIC PUBLICATIONS <Organization>ISSUED BY RESEARCH INSTITUTES</Organization> AND
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS. THE BIBLIOGRAPHIC RELEVANCE OF THESES, PERIODICAL
<Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>, AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> DIRECTORIES IS EXAMINED, AND IN CONCLUSION EMPHASISES
THE NEED TO COORDINATE INITIATIVES IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD FOR MORE RATIONAL COVERAGE.
********************************************
Document 5797
RETROSPECTIVE BIBLIOGRAPHIC SEARCHING IN SPANISH HISTORY.

A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Location>MADRID</Location> CONFERENCE IN 1981 TO DEMONSTRATE THE SPANISH
INSTITUTE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> SCIENCES AND
HUMANITIES (ISOC) APPROACH TO RETROSPECTIVE SEARCHING WHEN THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF
THE SUBJECT IS MAINLY IN SPANISH. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE SPECIFIC SUBJECT
SELECTED, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> SUITABILITY AS A SAMPLE TOPIC DISCUSSED, IN RELATION TO
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> DIFFICULTIES FOR THE SEARCHER AND APPLICABILITY OF TECHNIQUES EMPLOYED
TO THE HUMANITIES FIELD IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>. RESULTS OBTAINED USING 4 DATA BASES AND 2
SPANISH INDEXES ARE PRESENTED AND ANALYSED IN TERMS OF OVERLAP, DATE OF
PUBLICATION, COUNTRY OF ORIGIN, AND TYPE OF PERIODICAL. IN CONCLUSION A
COMPARISON IS MADE SHOWING THE ADVANTAGES OF <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> OVER MANUAL SEARCHING.
A PROFILE OF THE TYPICAL ISOC <Organization>USER</Organization> IS PRESENTED, AND FINALLY RECOMMENDATIONS
ARE MADE CONCERNING <Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, PRICING OF <Organization>SEARCH SERVICES</Organization>, AND AUTOMATION
PROGRAMMES.
********************************************
Document 5798
THE TREATMENT OF &apos;REGIONAL <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>&apos; IN DATA BASES <Organization>ON</Organization> URBAN STUDIES AND LAW.

REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>MADRID INSTITUTE</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> IN
THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> SCIENCES AND HUMANITIES (ISOC). FULL DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE
OBJECTIVES, METHODOLOGY AND RESULTS. THE INVESTIGATION COVERED&apos; COMPARISON OF
JOURNAL COVERAGE BY THE DATA BASES SELECTED; OVERLAP IN REFERENCES RECOVERED;
DISTRIBUTION BY COUNTRY OF ARTICLES CITED; DISTRIBUTION BY JOURNAL OF
REFERENCES OBTAINED; THE IMPORTANCE OF &apos;REGIONAL <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>&apos; WITHIN THE FIELD OF
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization> IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>; AND THE IMPORTANCE OF <Location>SPAIN</Location> AS A SOURCE OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
REGIONAL <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>. THE DATA BASES INVESTIGATED WERE BOTH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND
INTERNATIONAL IN COVERAGE, MULTI-DISCIPLINARY AND SPECIALISED.
********************************************
Document 5799
A <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL DATA</Organization> BASE IN <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY FOR <Location>LATIN
AMERICA</Location> AND THE CARIBBEAN.

DESCRIBES THE ORIGIN AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>AGRINTER DATA</Organization> BASE (<Organization>ADB</Organization>) <Organization>FROM</Organization>
1965-80. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF EARLY <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND EXPERIMENTATION, SELECTION OF
A <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> IMPLEMENTATION. THE ROLE OF <Organization>ADB</Organization> IN THE INTERNATIONAL
CONTEXT, AS A COMPLEMENT TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>AGRICULTURAL DATA</Organization> BASES <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS AGRIS AND
AGRICOLA, IS EXAMINED. THE PRODUCTS AND SERVICES TO BE DERIVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ADB</Organization> ARE
OUTLINED, WITH SPECIAL <Organization>EMPHASIS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> INDEX FOR <Location>LATIN AMERICA</Location>
AND THE CARIBBEAN, AND GENERATION OF HARD COPY MATERIAL AND <Organization>MAGNETIC</Organization> TAPES.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND PROMOTIONAL <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO THE DEVELOPMENT AND
<Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ADB</Organization> AND <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> WITH A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF PLANS FOR <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> EXPANSION AND
DEVELOPMENT OF THE BASE <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> INCREASED ACTIVE COOPERATION AND <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE COUNTRIES PRIMARILY SERVED.
********************************************
Document 5800
THE EFFECT OF THE INTRODUCTION OF COMPUTERS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.

DESCRIBES THE CONVERSION OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS CONGRESSIONAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
SERVICE&apos;S <Organization>CURRENT AWARENESS SERVICE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> A MANUAL TO AN <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> MODE,
EMPHASISING THE EFFECTS OF AUTOMATION UPON <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND CLIENTELE. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization>
INITIALLY THE CONVERSION WAS ATTENDED BY VARIOUS <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND EQUIPMENT PROBLEMS,
FULL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IMPLEMENTATION WAS HIGHLY SUCCESSFUL. AUTOMATION <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> NO
SAVING IN EITHER TIME OR <Organization>STAFF</Organization>; RATHER THE CONTRARY. HOWEVER THE TRUE BENEFITS
OF AUTOMATION APPEAR AS A MULTIPLICITY OF <Organization>PREVIOUSLY UNOBTAINABLE SERVICES</Organization> AND
PRODUCTS OF FAR-RANGING UTILITY TO <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> USERS.
********************************************
Document 5801
SELECTIVE DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

PRESENTS A HISTORICAL REVIEW OF SELECTIVE DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS A
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> AWARENESS <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, THE NEED FOR IT, AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> PRACTICAL SUGGESTIONS FOR
<Organization>ITS</Organization> INSTIGATION. EXAMPLES ARE DRAWN <Organization>FROM</Organization> BOTH SPECIAL AND ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
ATTEMPTS TO DRAW UP BLUEPRINTS FOR A <Organization>CURRENT AWARENESS SERVICE</Organization> IN KASHIM
IBRAHIM LIBRARY, <Organization>AHMADU BELLO UNIVERSITY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5802
A COMPARISON OF FIVE <Organization>PHYSICAL EDUCATION</Organization> INDEXING/<Organization>ABSTRACTING SERVICES</Organization>.

PRESENTS A CAREFUL ANALYSIS OF 5 OF THE 7 INDEXING/<Organization>ABSTRACTING SERVICES</Organization>&apos;
2COMPLETED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN HEALTH1; 2<Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> EDUCATION AND <Organization>RECREATION</Organization>1; 2SPORT
AND <Organization>RECREATION</Organization> INDEX1; 2<Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> EDUCATION INDEX1; AND 2<Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization>
EDUCATION/SPORTS INDEX1. <Organization>EVALUATES COMPARATIVE DATA</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SCOPE, ARRANGEMENT,
INDEXING LANGUAGE, JOURNAL COVERAGE, SUBJECT ACCESS, SPECIAL FEATURES AND <Organization>USER</Organization>
AIDS.
********************************************
Document 5803
INFORMATIVE ABSTRACTS <Organization>ON</Organization> AGRICULTURE&apos; A PIONEER PROJECT IN <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.

A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> ACCOUNT OF THE 2RESUMOS INFORMATIVOS1 PROJECT, INITIATED BY
THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> (EMBRAPA). THE ABSTRACTS ARE
INTENDED TO PROMOTE DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>,
<Organization>FACILITATE</Organization> ACCESS TO PRIMARY DOCUMENTS, AND PREVENT DUPLICATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
THE SEQUENCE OF STAGES IN COMPILING THE ABSTRACTS IS DESCRIBED, <Organization>FROM</Organization> INITIAL
DATA <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, SELECTION AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> TO DISTRIBUTION AND ARRANGEMENTS FOR
RETRIEVING ORIGINAL DOCUMENTS. THE STRUCTURE OF THE BIBLIOGRAPHY AND THE
SUMMARIES IS OUTLINED, WITH DETAILS OF PROCEDURES FOR COMPOSING SUMMARIES. IN
CONCLUSION THE IMPORTANCE OF INVOLVING <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> SPECIALISTS IN THE
PREPARATION OF THE SUMMARIES IS EMPHASISED, AND THE POTENTIAL BENEFITS OF THE
ABSTRACTS TO USERS BRIEFLY DISCUSSED.
********************************************
Document 5804
THREE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORT PRINTED INDEXES&apos; A COMPARATIVE <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.

COMPARES 3 <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Location>US</Location> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORT INDEXES&apos; 2<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> REPORTS
ANNOUNCEMENTS AND INDEX1; 2ENERGY <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ABSTRACTS1; AND 2SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AEROSPACE REPORTS1. PRIMARILY <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> DUPLICATION IN COVERAGE AND
ALPHANUMERIC LISTINGS OF REPORT NUMBERS <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization>&apos; THE AVAILABILITY OF
REPORT SERIES LISTED IN THE INDEXES; THE SUBJECT AREAS <Organization>EACH</Organization> INDEX COVERS; AND
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> WITHIN THE INDEXES, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS PATENT LISTINGS AND
PERIODICAL REFERENCES.
********************************************
Document 5805
THE SPANISH HUMANITIES INDEX (IEH): A DESCRIPTION AND ANALYTIC <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.

AN EXPLANATION OF THE FORMAL STRUCTURE OF THE INDICE ESPANOL DE HUMANIDADES
(SPANISH HUMANITIES INDEX) <Organization>GIVING</Organization> DETAILS OF SUBJECT COVERAGE IN RELATION TO
<Organization>OTHER INDEXING SERVICES</Organization>, SPANISH AND FOREIGN. DATA <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE 1ST 3 ISSUES
(1975-76) WAS ANALYSED TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> SUBJECT DISTRIBUTION; DISTRIBUTION OF
<Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> BY PUBLISHER; GEOGRAPHICAL DISTRIBUTION OF PUBLISHERS;
DISTRIBUTION OF <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> BY PROVINCE; AND DISTRIBUTION OF PAPERS BY
PROVINCE. FINALLY A QUANTITATIVE ANALYSIS OF NUMBER OF PAPERS, <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>,
AND ENTRIES, IS PRESENTED. SAMPLE PAGES ARE REPRODUCED IN THE APPENDIX.
********************************************
Document 5806
THE <Organization>LATIN</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> INDEX MEDICUS&apos; AN EXAMPLE OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COOPERATION AMONG
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES.

A BRIEF INTRODUCTORY <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF BIOMEDICAL <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN <Location>LATIN AMERICA</Location> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> COVERAGE IS PRESENTED, THEN THE ROLE AND <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF BIREME
(BIBLIOTECA REGIONAL DE MEDICINA) ARE DESCRIBED IN FULL, IN RELATION TO <Organization>ITS</Organization>
POSITION AS THE NUCLEUS OF THE <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NETWORK COVERING THE ENTIRE
<Organization>LATIN</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> CONTINENT. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>
SERVICES, COVERING PUBLICATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LATIN</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> COUNTRIES; THE 2INDEX
MEDICUS LATINO-AMERICANO1 THUS ENCOURAGES THE <Organization>LATIN AMERICAN MEDICAL COMMUNITY</Organization>
TO RELY <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RESOURCES RATHER THAN TURNING TO FOREIGN
LANGUAGE PUBLICATIONS. THE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> PROCESSES <Organization>USED</Organization> IN COMPILING THE INDEX ARE
DESCRIBED, AND IN CONCLUSION SIMILAR PROJECTS NOW UNDER CONSIDERATION BY <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES IN <Location>AFRICA</Location>, SOUTH WEST <Location>ASIA</Location> AND CHINA, USING THE INDEX AS
A MODEL, ARE OUTLINED.
********************************************
Document 5807
CAPTURE AND ANALYSIS OF <Organization>LATIN</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY FOR 2AQUATIC SCIENCES AND
FISHERIES ABSTRACTS1 (ASFA).

AN ACCOUNT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL INDEPENDENT UNIVERSITY</Organization> OF <Location>MEXICO</Location>&apos;S CENTRE FOR
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN THE SCIENCES AND HUMANITIES (CICH), DESIGNATED IN 1978 AS
RESPONSIBLE FOR COVERING <Organization>LATIN</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> SOURCES FOR 2AQUATIC SCIENCES AND
FISHERIES ABSTRACTS1 (ASFA). PRELIMINARY DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE ORIGINS OF
THE PUBLICATION AND THE AQUATIC SCIENCES AND FISHERIES <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>
WHICH SPONSORS IT. DESCRIBES THE VOLUME OF ENTRIES CONTRIBUTED, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
TO DISTRIBUTION OF JOURNALS BY COUNTRY; PROCEDURES FOR CAPTURING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> IDENTIFICATION OF MATERIAL, ACQUISITION AND INDEXING; AND THE
ANALYSIS OF DOCUMENTS OBTAINED, COVERING THE ENTIRE <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> OF BIBLIOGRAPHIC
LISTING, <Organization>ABSTRACTING</Organization>, INDEXING, AND DESPATCH TO THE EDITOR, WITH DETAILS OF
PERSONNEL REQUIRED AND <Organization>COSTS</Organization>. <Organization>RELATED</Organization> ASFIS <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AND
INTERNATIONAL LEVELS TO COORDINATE PARTICIPANT OPERATIONS ARE OUTLINED. TH E
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> NOW <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> CICH USING ASFA MATERIAL ARE DESCRIBED
BRIEFLY.
********************************************
Document 5808
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> CORRESPONDENCE REFERRAL PROGRAM.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND ADULT <Organization>SERVICES DIVISION COOPERATIVE</Organization>
<Organization>REFERENCE SERVICE COMMITTEE</Organization> PROGRAMME <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, 29 JUNE 81. DESCRIBES THE SETTING UP OF A
COOPERATIVE REFERRAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> TO ANSWER WRITTEN <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> ENQUIRIES SENT TO THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS. AS AN EXPERIMENT, ENQUIRIES OF A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> NATURE, NOT
SPECIFICALLY NEEDING AN ANSWER <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS, WERE PASSED ONTO
OREGON STATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO IMPROVE EFFICIENCY AND SPEED UP REPLIES. LATER <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
STATE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> JOINED THE SCHEME. <Organization>SUGGESTS FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
INTERNATIONAL LEVEL, REFERRAL <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE BOTTOM UP AS WELL AS THE <Organization>TOP</Organization> DOWN, AND
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> MAIL.
********************************************
Document 5809
RESOURCES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>TOP</Organization>&apos; ANSWERS AND REFERRALS-PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE RASD
<Organization>COOPERATIVE REFERENCE SERVICE COMMITTEE</Organization> PROGRAM <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ALA ANNUAL CONFERENCE
IN <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, JUNE 29, 1981.

SPECIAL SECTION DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND ADULT SERVICES DIVISION
<Organization>COOPERATIVE REFERENCE SERVICE COMMITTEE</Organization> PROGRAMME <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, 29 JUNE 81. FOR ABSTRACTS OF THE
INDIVIDUAL PAPERS, 2SEE1 THE FOLLOWING SERIAL NUMBERS&apos;-.
********************************************
Document 5810
<Organization>NATIONAL-LEVEL COOPERATIVE REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization>&apos; A REACTION.

PAPER PRESENTED AS A REACTION TO PREVIOUS SPEECHES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND ADULT
<Organization>SERVICES DIVISION COOPERATIVE REFERENCE SERVICE COMMITTEE</Organization> PROGRAMME <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, 29 JUNE 81.
PUTS THE POINT OF VIEW OF OREGAN STATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> REGARDING <Organization>ITS</Organization> INVOLVEMENT IN
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> CORRESPONDENCE REFERRAL PROGRAMME (2SEE1
82/5808) AND BRIEFLY <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE SERVICES PROVIDED BY THE SLAVIC <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
SERVICE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS (2SEE1 82/5812) AND THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>LENDING DIVISION</Organization>. <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> THAT IF A <Organization>NATIONAL-LEVEL</Organization> REFERRAL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS NOT TO
BE OVERLOADED WITH INAPPROPRIATE REQUESTS THAT UNNECESSARILY INCREASE THE
<Organization>COSTS</Organization>, THERE MUST BE ADEQUATE <Organization>LOCAL REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Location>US</Location>
RESIDENTS AND A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AWARENESS OF <Organization>THESE LOCAL SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5811
INFOPASS&apos; <Organization>SOME</Organization> ORGANIZATIONAL CONCERNS OF A <Organization>LOCAL COOPERATIVE</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
PROGRAM.

A 3-MONTH TRIAL OF THE DEARBORN AREA <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> INFOPASS <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> (DALIS), A
<Organization>LOCAL LIBRARY COOPERATIVE</Organization> PROGRAMME COORDINATING THE <Organization>REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization> OF 6
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (SPECIAL, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, AND ACADEMIC), <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> THAT <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IS
WARRANTED TO DEVELOP <Organization>COST BENEFIT DATA</Organization>. ANALYSIS INDICATES THAT DOCUMENT
DELIVERY AND TELECOMMUNICATION <Organization>USE</Organization> SHOULD BE INVESTIGATED TO OVERCOME LOW
PROGRAMME ACCEPTANCE BY PATRONS. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5812
RESOURCES FOR COOPERATIVE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>&apos; THE UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS SLAVIC
<Organization>REFERENCE SERVICE</Organization> AS A MODEL.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND ADULT <Organization>SERVICES DIVISION COOPERATIVE</Organization>
<Organization>REFERENCE SERVICE COMMITTEE</Organization> PROGRAMME <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
ANNUAL CONFERENCE, 29 JUNE 81, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>. DESCRIBES THE SLAVIC <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
SERVICE DEVELOPED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO PROVIDE A <Organization>FREE</Organization>
SERVICE TO INDIVIDUALS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OFFERING HELP WITH UNLOCATED ITEMS OR
DIFFICULT <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> QUESTIONS IN THE SLAVIC AND EAST <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> FIELDS. LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND ACCESS TO IT, THE DEMONSTRATED NEED FOR THE SERVICE,
INSTITUTIONAL SUPPORT AND CONTACTS AND COOPERATION AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>DAILY</Organization>
OPERATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5813
QUANTITATIVE EVALUATION OF THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>PROCESS</Organization>.

THE QUANTITATIVE EVALUATION OF THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> IS DISCUSSED. A
DISTINCTION IS MADE <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE BEHAVIOURAL OUTCOMES OF THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>PROCESS</Organization>,
AND THE CAUSAL FACTORS THAT INHIBIT THE DELIVERY OF <Organization>REFERENCE SERVICE</Organization>. DATA
ARE PRESENTED <Organization>ON</Organization> 16 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> THAT PARTICIPATED IN A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ECONOMICS. DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> BEHAVIOURAL AND CAUSAL ASPECTS ARE COLLECTED AND ANALYSED
SEPARATELY; GROUP OR COMPOSITE VALUES FOR THE PERFORMANCE PARAMETERS ARE
PRESENTED. <Organization>THESE</Organization> ARE TRANSFORMED TO PROVIDE INDEPENDENT MEASURES OF THE
PERFORMANCE OF THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, AND THE PATRONS. GROUP VALUES,
TOGETHER WITH THE RANGE AND MEDIANS, ARE PRESENTED. THE QUESTION OF HOW THE
LIBRARIAN&apos;S PERCEPTION OF SUCCESS IS <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO THE PATRON&apos;S PERCEPTION, AND
TO THE VALIDITY OF THE ANSWERS PROVIDED, IS DISCUSSED BRIEFLY.
********************************************
Document 5814
INTERNATIONAL SEMINAR <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> DOCUMENT SUPPLY.

REPORT OF AN INTERNATIONAL SEMINAR <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> DOCUMENT SUPPLY, HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>LENDING DIVISION</Organization>, SEPT 80, AND ARRANGED BY IFLA AND THE
BRITISH COUNCIL. THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> WAS TO DISCUSS DOCUMENT SUPPLY AS A PART OF THE
<Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> AVAILABILITY OF PUBLICATIONS PROGRAMME.
********************************************
Document 5815
UAP AND THE <Organization>NEW INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES</Organization>.

<Organization>SOME</Organization> RECENT APPLICATIONS OF ELECTRONICS TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND TRANSFER
ARE BRIEFLY DESCRIBED AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RELEVANCE TO THE PROBLEMS OF <Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization>
AVAILABILITY OF PUBLICATIONS DISCUSSED. THE DEVELOPMENTS MENTIONED INCLUDE
FACSIMILE TRANSMISSION, <Organization>VIDEODISC TECHNOLOGY</Organization>, <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> PUBLISHING, WORD
<Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> IN VARIOUS FORMS AND TELETEXT OR VIDEOTEXT. <Organization>ALL</Organization> ARE BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
MANIPULATION OF <Organization>TEXT</Organization> AND GRAPHICAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN A DIGITISED OR
MACHINE-READABLE FORM, WHICH ALLOWS A RANGE OF OPTIONS FOR THE DISTRIBUTION OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO THE CONSUMER.
********************************************
Document 5816
ANALYSIS OF DOCUMENT AVAILABILITY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE PROF. <Organization>LUIS DE BESSA CENTRE</Organization> FOR
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>.

<Organization>SUMMARY</Organization> OF A DISSERTATION PREPARED FOR <Organization>UFMG LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>. THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization>
<Organization>USED</Organization> KANTOR&apos;S MATHEMATICAL AVAILABILITY ANALYSIS MODEL, WHICH IS PRESENTED IN
DETAIL. AN ACCOUNT IS GIVEN OF THE ORGANISATION OF THE PROF. LUIS DE BESSA
CENTRE FOR <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARY HOLDINGS</Organization>, AND <Organization>USER</Organization> HABITS. RESULTS
ARE REPORTED IN FULL, AND ANALYED TO SHOW CAUSES OF FAILURE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SHELF. THE
PROBABLE RATE OF <Organization>USER</Organization> SATISFACTION CALCULATED WAS 70%.
********************************************
Document 5817
<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

A PRACTICAL DISCUSSION BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> PUBLISHED MATERIAL, CONVERSATION WITH
LIBRARIANS, AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> VISITS. CONSIDERS THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> FOR <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> VALUES, AND THE METHODS AND
TECHNIQUES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>; THE OBJECTIVES IN RELATION TO <Organization>CONVENTIONAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>; <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> PROCEDURES, WITH A FULL GUIDE FOR IMPLEMENTING A
PROGRAMME; THE HUMAN, MATERIAL, ECONOMIC AND INSTITUTIONAL RESOURCES REQUIRED;
EVALUATION TECHNIQUES, TO BE MODIFIED AS CIRCUMSTANCES DICTATE; AND PROGRAMMES
FOR ADULTS, CHILDREN, AND YOUNG PEOPLE, <Organization>GIVING</Organization> A WIDE RANGE OF SUGGESTED
<Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> FOR <Organization>EACH GROUP</Organization>. FINALLY EXAMINES THE REASONS WHY LATIN <Location>AMERICA</Location> HAS
LARGELY FAILED TO DEVELOP PROGRAMMES IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD, AND GIVES EXAMPLE OF
PROJECTS SUCCESSFULLY INITIATED IN <Location>COLOMBIA</Location> <Organization>AT</Organization> 3 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5818
PROGRAMMING IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A DISSENTING VIEWPOINT.

THE ORIGINAL PURPOSE OF PROGRAMMING (THE OFFERING <Organization>ON</Organization> NON-BOOK <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> IN
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) HAS BEEN FORGOTTEN BY MANY LIBRARIANS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> HAS BEEN
JUSTIFIED IN SEVERAL WAYS. ADVOCATES THAT THE COMMONEST METHOD IS NOT TO
JUSTIFY IT <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization>; IN MANY CASES PROGRAMMING IS INEFFECTIVE, AND LITTLE
RIGOROUS EVALUATION HAS EVER BEEN UNDERTAKEN TO PROVE THAT PROGRAMMING CAN
SUCCEED. QUESTIONS THE COMMON UNTHINKING ACCEPTANCE OF THE NEED FOR
PROGRAMMING, AND CITES ANNUAL REPORTS AND STUDIES WHICH INDICATE THE NEED FOR
<Organization>BETTER</Organization> EVALUATION THAN HAS HERETOFORE BEEN THE PRACTICE.
********************************************
Document 5819
SUMMER READING CLUBS COVER CABELL COUNTY.

CABELL COUNTY <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SUMMER READING PROGRAMME &apos;SUMMER OF FUN&apos; AND
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> PROGRAMMES, ORGANISED WITH THE COOPERATION OF <Location>HUNTINGTON</Location>&apos;S <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
TELEVISION STATION, WPBY, REACHED OVER 500 YOUNG PEOPLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> PRE-SCHOOL <Organization>AGE</Organization> TO
YOUNG ADULTS IN 1981. YOUNG PEOPLE SHOWED A WILLINGNESS TO BE GUIDED AND
SUSTAINED BY <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> INTEREST RATHER THAN INDUCEMENTS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS AWARDS OR
CERTIFICATES. IT WAS EVIDENT THAT READING CAN LEAD TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
SKILLS, AS WELL AS BEING STIMULATING IN ITSELF. EVALUATION OF THE 1981
PROGRAMME WILL BE <Organization>USED</Organization> IN THE <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> OF THE 1982 FORMAT.
********************************************
Document 5820
COOPERATIVE LINKS MADE BY LEIPZIG MUNICIPAL MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

PUBLICITY WORK PLACES GREAT DEMANDS UPON A SPECIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Location>LEIPZIG</Location> MUSIC
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORKS CLOSELY WITH MUSIC PUBLISHERS, SCHOOLS, YOUTH CLUBS, THE
UNIVERSITY AND THE <Organization>NATIONAL ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF COMPOSERS AND MUSICOLOGISTS AND IS
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> LINKS WITH THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> THEATRE AND MUSIC SCHOOLS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> RESULTS IN
COOPERATIVE ORGANISATION AND FINANCE FOR MUSICAL <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, JUSTIFIED BECAUSE
OF THE VALUE OF LIVE PERFORMANCES AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF A WIDE RANGE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIAL. THERE IS GOOD PUBLICITY FOR THE MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S STOCK OF
140,000 ITEMS <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> VALUABLE 1ST EDITIONS. AGREEMENTS WITH COMPOSERS
AND PUBLISHERS RESULT IN THE PROVISION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> PUBLICATIONS AND
1ST PERFORMANCES AND IN A RATIONAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF MONEY. PUBLICATION EXCHANGES ARE
ESPECIALLY USEFUL. <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> COOPERATION WITH THE UNIVERSITY, MUSIC
LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> CAN BE PROVIDED FOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5821
<Organization>SOME</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>TECHNICAL REPORT PROCESSING BY FEDERAL</Organization> AGENCIES.

<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS ARE A VALUABLE RESOURCE OF SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WHICH HAS BEEN ALLOWED TO SLIP INTO LESS THAN MAXIMUM UTILITY.
WHILE THE <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> OF MORE TRADITIONAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES HAS PROGRESSED
AND REMARKABLY IMPROVED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> MECHANISMS AS SHARED <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND
<Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> ACCESS TO HUGE FILES OF <Organization>CATALOGUING DATA</Organization>, THE CORRESPONDING <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>
OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS HAS REMAINED RELATIVELY STAGNANT. <Organization>SOME</Organization> EFFORTS <Organization>AT</Organization>
COORDINATING THE <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> OF REPORTS HAVE BEEN MADE BY THE 4 <Organization>US FEDERAL</Organization>
AGENCIES RESPONSIBLE FOR THE LARGEST REPORT COLLECTIONS. ADDITIONAL EFFORTS
SUGGESTED INCLUDE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF A COMMON REPORT FORMAT, MORE EXTENSIVE SHARED
<Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> OF FEDERAL DOCUMENTS AND INCREASED EFFORTS TOWARDS COOPERATION IN
THE FEDERAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK.
********************************************
Document 5822
<Organization>CENTRAL SERVICE</Organization> OF <Organization>AUDIOVISUAL MEDIA</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.

BIBLIOTEKSTJANST (BTJ) IS THE <Organization>SWEDISH NATIONAL CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> AND
IS OWNED BY THE <Organization>SWEDISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> (<Organization>SAB</Organization>) AND THE <Organization>SWEDISH ASSOCIATION</Organization>
OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES . BTJ WORKS IN THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> AS WELL AS IN THE
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> FIELD. IN THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> FIELD THE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND THE
<Organization>CENTRALISED BINDING SERVICES</Organization> ARE THE MOST IMPORTANT OF BTJ&apos;S <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>. IN
THE SECTION FOR <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization> BINDING THE DEPARTMENT FOR <Organization>AUDIOVISUAL MEDIA</Organization>
PROVIDES 3 TYPES OF SERVICES&apos; TALKING BOOKS, MUSIC AND FILMSTRIPS, SLIDE
SERIES, LANGUAGE COURSES ETC. IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> 3 FIELDS THE EDITORIAL <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF
BTJ IS SUPPORTED BY A COMMITTEE OF SPECIALISTS AND EXPERIENCED LIBRARIANS
CHOSEN BY THE <Organization>SWEDISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND THE <Organization>SWEDISH ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
AUTHORITIES.
********************************************
Document 5823
OVERVIEW OF THE COST OF ACQUIRING, CATALOGING, AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>TUCSON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

A SYNOPSIS OF 3 STUDIES CONDUCTED IN THE <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization> AREA OF THE <Location>TUCSON</Location>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> JAN 77-JUNE 80, <Organization>THIS</Organization> REPORT PRESENTS ESTIMATED <Organization>COSTS</Organization> OF
ACQUIRING, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> PRINT AND NONPRINT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>.
AN <Organization>AVERAGE COST</Organization> OF $7.00 PER BOOK COPY AND $12.20 PER NON-PRINT COPY IS
DEVELOPED, AND IT IS DEMONSTRATED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> A RANGE OF <Organization>COSTS</Organization> THAT ORDERING
PATTERNS (I.E., SINGLE COPIES, MULTIPLE COPIES, <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>TITLES</Organization>, ADDED <Organization>TITLES</Organization>) MAKE
A SIGNIFICANT IMPACT <Organization>ON</Organization> UNIT <Organization>COSTS</Organization>. AN ORGANISATIONAL CHART SHOWING STAFFING
LEVELS, AN OUTLINE OF <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF THE 3 SECTIONS OF THE <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization>
AREA, AND A <Organization>SUMMARY</Organization> OF <Organization>AUTOMATED SYSTEMS</Organization> BEING <Organization>USED</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>TUCSON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARE INCLUDED. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5824
UNIT TIME/COST <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> UNIT, <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES DIVISION</Organization>,
<Location>TUCSON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. REVISED EDITION.

THE 1ST OF 3 REPORTS IN A SERIES TO DETERMINE UNIT TIME AND COST ESTIMATES FOR
THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> OPERATIONS OF THE <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES DIVISION</Organization> OF THE <Location>TUCSON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. MEMBERS OF THE <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> UNIT RECORDED <Organization>DAILY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> FOR A 4-WEEK
PERIOD AND <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>THESE</Organization> LOGS <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> <Organization>COSTS</Organization> WERE DEVELOPED. <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>
PROCEDURES ARE OUTLINED AND TIME AND COST ALLOCATIONS MADE, WITH A <Organization>SUMMARY</Organization>
TABLE ITEMISING <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>COSTS</Organization> IN THE DIVISIONS OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> BOOKS, NONPRINT ITEMS, AND
MENDING. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5825
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> TRENDS IN LIBRARIANSHIP WITH SPECIAL <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE BRITISH
SITUATION.

PART 2 OF A 3-PART ARTICLE. FOR AN ABSTRACT OF PART 1, 2SEE1 2LISA1 JAN 83.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE LATEST DEVELOPMENTS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTOMATION AND MEDIA STUDIES
BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE AUTHOR&apos;S <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization> IN AN OVERSEAS LIBRARIANS COURSE <Organization>AT</Organization> LEEDS
<Organization>POLYTECHNIC SCHOOL</Organization> OF LIBRARIANSHIP IN 1979. EXAMINES THE ADVANTAGES AND
DISADVANTAGES OF THE <Organization>LOCKHEED</Organization> DIALOG <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AND COMMENTS FAVOURABLY <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> CIRCULATION CONTROL. VARIOUS TYPES OF <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>
NETWORKS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS BLAISE AND MASS ARE DISCUSSED. <Organization>MULTI MEDIA</Organization> RESOURCE CENTRES
ARE BEING DEVELOPED <Organization>AT</Organization> MANY <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> INSTITUTES IN THE <Location>UK</Location> AND CAN BE
CONSIDERED AS WORTHWHILE LONG-TERM INVESTMENTS <Organization>BUT</Organization> THERE ARE NUMEROUS PROBLEMS
ASSOCIATED WITH THE <Organization>NEW MEDIA</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS POOR BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL AND SELECTION
AND ORGANISATIONAL DIFFICULTIES.
********************************************
Document 5826
CLASSIFICATION POLICIES IN <Location>DENMARK</Location>.

AIMS TO GIVE <Organization>SOME</Organization> IDEAS OF CLASSIFICATION AND INDEXING POLICIES IN <Organization>DANISH</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS WELL AS A STATE-OF-THE-ART REPORT OF <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SEARCHING. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE INFLUENCE OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> AND THE
POSSIBILITIES OF <Organization>UTILISING DATA</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS SUBJECT ENTRIES <Organization>FROM</Organization> MARC TAPES FOR
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, AND PREDICTS A DEVELOPMENT WITHIN THE NEXT 10 YEARS TOWARDS
<Organization>ON-LINE INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> IN 1 OR BOTH OF THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SECTORS, EITHER
<Organization>AS LARGE SHARED SYSTEMS</Organization> OR, PERHAPS MORE LIKELY, <Organization>AS SMALLER LIBRARY DATA</Organization> BASES
IN NETWORKS.
********************************************
Document 5827
THE SUITABILITY OF THE CARIBBEAN SITUATION FOR ESTABLISHING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKS.

TRANSLATED BY CARLOS GIL. ANALYSES THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCCESSFULLY
IMPLEMENTING <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKS IN THE CARIBBEAN, IN RELATION TO THE
ACTUAL <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>, POLITICAL AND ECONOMIC CIRCUMSTANCES. THE DISCUSSION COVERS THE
ROLE OF TECHNOLOGY IN <Organization>PROMOTING DEVELOPMENT</Organization>; THE NEED FOR AND LIKELIHOOD OF
COOPERATION AMONG THE CARIBBEAN STATES; THE PROBABLE IMPACT OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization>
<Organization>IMPORTED</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE DEVELOPED WORLD; AND THE ABILITY OF CARIBBEAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO
IMPLEMENT <Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> PROGRAMMES AND ADAPT TO THEM. <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> THAT THE <Organization>OCLC</Organization> TYPE
NETWORK MODEL IS NOT <Organization>SUITABLE</Organization> FOR THE CARIBBEAN SITUATION, REQUIRING TOO GREAT
AN INVESTMENT WITHOUT CONCRETE EVIDENCE THAT THE <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization>, POLITICAL AND
<Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> OBSTACLES TO COOPERATION COULD BE OVERCOME. RECOMMENDS INSTEAD A
DETAILED INVESTIGATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND TELECOMMUNICATION RESOURCES, WITH A VIEW
TO <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> AN INDIGENOUS NETWORK.
********************************************
Document 5828
THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>IMPORTED DATA</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

REPORT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>, <Location>CANBERRA</Location>, WITH SPECIAL <Organization>EMPHASIS</Organization>
<Organization>ON ITS DATA</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>IMPORTED</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>USA</Location> (-<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>WASHINGTON</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
NETWORK).
********************************************
Document 5829
INTEGRATING AUTOMATION <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization> TECH.

DESCRIBES THE DEVELOPMENT OF AN INTEGRATED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
CAROL M. NEWMAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>VIRGINIA POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE</Organization> AND STATE
UNIVERSITY. THE <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization> TECH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> (VTLS) WILL EVENTUALLY
INCORPORATE CIRCULATION CONTROL, <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization>, AND <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> CONTROL, AS WELL AS
AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>. MENTIONS <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> LINKAGE WITH <Organization>OCLC</Organization> AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF MARC
RECORDS.
********************************************
Document 5830
<Organization>CHINESE</Organization> MARC&apos; <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> STATUS AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DEVELOPMENT.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE INTERNATIONAL WORKSHOP <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CHINESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTOMATION,
<Location>TAIPEI</Location>, <Location>TAIWAN</Location>, 14-19 FEB 81. <Location>TAIWAN</Location>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY AUTOMATION PLANNING COMMITTEE</Organization>
ESTABLISHED THE <Organization>CHINESE MARC WORKING GROUP</Organization> IN MAY 80, ASSIGNING IT THE TASK OF
DESIGNING A <Organization>CHINESE</Organization> MARC FORMAT WHICH <Organization>WOULD MEET INTERNATIONAL</Organization> REQUIREMENTS,
<Organization>FACILITATE AUTOMATIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> OF <Organization>CHINESE</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, AND PROMOTE
INTERNATIONAL RESOURCE SHARING AND EXCHANGE OF <Organization>CHINESE</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>. OUTLINES THE
UNDERLYING PRINCIPLES, SCOPE, AND CHARACTERISTICS OF THE RESULTANT FORMAT,
COMPARES <Organization>CHINESE</Organization> MARC WITH UNIMARC (THE FORMER FOLLOWS THE FRAMEWORK OF THE
LATTER AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE), LISTS THE ACHIEVEMENTS MADE, AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> PLANS
FOR <Organization>FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5831
COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> CLANN &amp; ABN.

EXPLORES THE ROLE OF CLANN, THE NETWORK OF 20 COLLEGE, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
SPECIAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>NEW</Organization> SOUTH WALES, IN RELATION TO THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF
<Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>&apos;S EMERGING AUSTRALIAN BIBLIOGRAPHIC NETWORK (ABN) <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. THE
<Organization>PROPOSED SERVICE</Organization> FOR ACCESS TO <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> DATA CONFORMING TO <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
STANDARDS IS ESSENTIAL TO THE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT OF THE NATION&apos;S
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT SHOULD BE OPERATED IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A MANNER AS TO ENCOURAGE, MAINTAIN
AND SUPPORT VARIOUS NETWORKS AND SERVICES, BOTH THOSE ALREADY <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> AND
THOSE THAT MAY BE ESTABLISHED IN THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>, IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY COMMUNITY</Organization> AND IN
THE PRIVATE SECTOR. CLANN&apos;S ROLE SHOULD BE FOCUSSED <Organization>ON</Organization> MAKING THE OPERATION OF
THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AND OF <Organization>LOCAL SERVICES</Organization> AS <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> AS POSSIBLE IN MEETING
THE NEEDS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> SOUTH WALES.
********************************************
Document 5832
AN INVESTIGATION OF THE <Organization>COSTS</Organization> AND BENEFITS OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> HANDLING.

FOR AN ABSTRACT 2SEE1 82/3825.
********************************************
Document 5833
<Organization>OCLC SERIALS ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization> MEETINGS.

IN 1980, <Organization>OCLC REACTIVATED ITS SERIALS ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization>, AFTER A 3-YEAR
HIATUS. THE GROUP OF ABOUT 20 MEMBERS REPRESENTING NETWORKS <Organization>FROM</Organization> ACROSS THE
<Location>USA</Location> MET 3 TIMES IN 7 MONTHS. <Organization>ALL</Organization> INDICATIONS ARE THAT <Organization>OCLC</Organization> INTENDS TO IMPROVE
THE <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> CONTROL SUBSYSTEM AND MAKE IT A <Organization>VIABLE</Organization> OPTION TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> METHODS OF
<Organization>SERIALS MANAGEMENT</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS IN THE SUBSYSTEM <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS 2 NEW
VARIABLE FIELDS IN THE <Organization>LOCAL DATA RECORD-THE SUMMARY COPY HOLDINGS</Organization> AND <Organization>SUMMARY</Organization>
<Organization>INSTITUTIONS HOLDINGS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5834
THE <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF THE DEPARTMENT OF PRINTED BOOKS IN THE 1870S.

WILLIAM BRENCHLEY RYE SUCCEEDED TO THE POST OF KEEPER <Organization>AT</Organization> THE DEPARTMENT OF
PRINTED BOOKS OF THE BRITISH MUSEUM <Organization>FROM</Organization> THOMAS WATTS IN 1869, AND CONTINUED
IN OFFICE UNTIL 1875. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> DESCRIBED AS COMPETENT, WITHOUT MUCH
INITIATIVE, HE LEFT USEFUL REPORTS WHICH GIVE A GOOD PICTURE OF THE DEPARTMENT
OF PRINTED BOOKS AFTER THE PANIZZI PERIOD. <Organization>SUMMARISES HOLDINGS</Organization> BY GEOGRAPHICAL
AREA, <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization> BY DATE, AND BOOK FUNDS BY YEAR.
********************************************
Document 5835
<Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization> IN THE SPECIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

ARTICLE BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A PAPER GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ANNUAL MEETING OF THE SOCIETY FOR
SCHOLARLY PUBLISHING, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, 2 JUNE 81. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN BUSINESS AND
INDUSTRY ARE SERVICE-ORIENTED. THEY ARE LESS INTERESTED IN THE <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization>
PACKAGE THAN IN THE CURRENCY OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND THE SPEED WITH WHICH IT
CAN BE DELIVERED.
********************************************
Document 5836
PROBLEMS AND STRATEGIES FOR EAST ASIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE 1980&apos;S.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 33RD ANNUAL MEETING, ASSOCIATION FOR ASIAN STUDIES,
INC., <Location>TORONTO</Location>, <Location>CANADA</Location>, 13-15 MAR 81. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE MEANING OF <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT IN THE 1980S AND THE FISCAL ADVERSITIES FACING EAST ASIAN
COLLECTIONS IN THE <Location>USA</Location> (INFLATION, BUDGET CUTS, DRAMATIC INCREASES IN <Organization>COSTS</Organization> OF
EAST ASIAN BOOKS AND POSTAGE RATES, ND INCREASED DANGER OF CUTS IN
UNDER-UTILISED COLLECTIONS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS THOSE SPECIALISING IN <Location>EAST ASIA</Location>). <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization>
STRATEGIES (SPECIALISATION, COOPERATION, SHARING CHECKLISTS OF UNIQUE
HOLDINGS, REDUCTION OF DUPLICATION, AND OPTIMAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization>) AND
DESCRIBES THE PREPARATIONS FOR <Organization>FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> MADE BY THE EAST ASIAN
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF THE HOOVER INSTITUTION, <Organization>STANFORD UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5837
BACK VOLUME MISCELLANY.

PRESENTS A MODERN HISTORICAL PERSPECTIVE <Organization>ON</Organization> SERIAL BACK VOLUMES, WITH COMMENTS
<Organization>ON</Organization> PRICING/VALUES, A GLIMPSE <Organization>AT</Organization> HOW THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF BACK VOLUMES STARTED IN
THE EARLY 1960S, AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> INSIGHTS INTO THE WORKINGS OF DEALER OPERATION.
********************************************
Document 5838
SOURCES AND ACQUISITION PROBLEMS OF <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> IN <Organization>NIGERIAN</Organization> ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
WITH SPECIFIC <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO ALVAN <Organization>IKOKU COLLEGE</Organization> OF EDUCATION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, OWERRI.
<Location>NIGERIA</Location>.

(<Organization>MLS</Organization> THESIS). A REVIEW OF THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> IN <Organization>NIGERIAN</Organization> ACADEMIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE SOURCES OF <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> <Organization>USED</Organization> BY <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS FOLLOWED
BY A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ACCOUNT OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE PROBLEMS WHICH CAN CROP UP IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
ACQUISITION. <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PROBLEMS INCLUDE BUDGETARY CONTROL, COST OF <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>,
INTERNAL ADMINISTRATIVE PROBLEMS, CENSORSHIP. SPECIFIC PROBLEMS IN ACQUISITION
OF FOREIGN AND DOMESTIC <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED.
********************************************
Document 5839
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> MAP SOURCES: <Organization>BARGAINS FROM VARIOUS AGENCIES</Organization>.

REVIEWS <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE CARTOGRAPHIC <Organization>BARGAINS</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM VARIOUS US AGENCIES</Organization>
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> THAN THE COMMONLY <Organization>USED NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC SOCIETY</Organization>, AND CONTENDING THAT
IN WEST <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization> A CORE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> MAPS MAY BE ACQUIRED FOR $50.00 OR
LESS. AGENCIES INCLUDE THE DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS, WEST <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization> GEOLOGICAL
AND ECONOMIC <Organization>SURVEY</Organization>, AND THE DEPARTMENT OF <Organization>NATURAL</Organization> RESOURCES.
********************************************
Document 5840
UNIT TIME/COST <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization> UNIT, <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES DIVISION</Organization>,
<Location>TUCSON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

IN THE 3RD AND FINAL REPORT OF A SERIES DESIGNED TO DEVELOP UNIT TIME AND
<Organization>COSTS</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> OPERATIONS OF THE <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES DIVISION</Organization> OF THE
<Location>TUCSON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization> UNIT&apos;S <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> ARE ANALYSED BY
MEANS OF SELF-RECORDED <Organization>DAILY</Organization> LOGS. ORDERING, ACCOUNTING, AND RECEIVING ARE
PERFORMED IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> AREA, AND THOSE FUNCTIONS ARE DETAILED BOTH IN NARRATIVE
FORM AND A SERIES OF TABLES. SELECTION <Organization>COSTS</Organization> ARE NOT INCLUDED IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> REPORT.
A <Organization>SUMMARY</Organization> OF UNIT <Organization>COSTS</Organization> IS PRESENTED IN WHICH SINGLE AND MULTIPLE COPY
ORDERING VARIATIONS ARE <Organization>USED</Organization> AS EXAMPLES. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5841
THE PURCHASING <Organization>KEY</Organization>&apos; A METHOD FOR PROGRAMMING AND CONTROLLING <Organization>COLLECTIVE</Organization>
PURCHASING.

SINCE THE 1960S THE CENTRALISATION OF STOCK <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND ADVISORY WORK <Organization>ON</Organization>
BOOK SELECTION HAS DEMANDED RATIONALISATION METHODS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORGANISATION.
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF PURCHASING <Organization>KEY</Organization> CODES IN <Location>DRESDEN</Location>&apos;S LARGE MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS
DESCRIBED. IN A <Organization>COLLECTIVE</Organization> PURCHASING DECISION <Organization>EACH</Organization> PARTICIPANT CAN <Organization>USE</Organization> THE
<Organization>KEY</Organization> TO MAKE DECISIONS FOR THE WHOLE NETWORK; THUS INDIVIDUAL RESPONSIBILITY
FOR <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> PROVISION BECOMES GREATER. USING A <Organization>KEY</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> ENSURES BALANCED
STOCK PROPORTIONS THROUGHOUT THE WHOLE NETWORK AND TAKES INTO ACCOUNT DEMANDS
FOR TIME SAVING AND FOR IMPROVED STOCK QUALITY, THUS OFFERING AN OPTIMAL
SOLUTION FOR UNIFYING STOCKS IN A TERRITORIAL NETWORK.
********************************************
Document 5842
PURCHASING KEYS&apos; METHODS OF CARRYING OUT IDEAS <Organization>ON</Organization> STOCK-BUILDING.

MUCH ATTENTION IS BEING PAID <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> TO STOCK-BUILDING PROBLEMS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>
THE DISTRIBUTION OF MATERIAL WITHIN A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK. <Organization>WORKING</Organization> OUT
STOCK-BUILDING PRINCIPLES CAN BE TIME-CONSUMING AND <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS ONLY ONE ASPECT OF
STOCK-BUILDING, EVEN IF IT IS THE MOST IMPORTANT. A PURCHASING <Organization>KEY</Organization> IS A CODING
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR THE PRACTICAL APPLICATION OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> PRINCIPLES; EXPERIENCES IN
MAGDEBURG HAVE PROVED THE <Organization>KEY</Organization> TO BE A USEFUL RATIONALISATION METHOD. <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
THE CODING SYMBOLS THE LIBRARIAN CAN SEE QUICKLY WHAT TYPES OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> ARE
IN WHICH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE NETWORK. THE SYMBOLS ARE FLEXIBLE AND CAN EASILY BE
KEPT UP TO DATE. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> STOCK-BUILDING CRITERIA ARE LITERARY MERIT, SPECIALIST
<Organization>DEMAND</Organization>, FUNCTIONS OF INDIVIDUAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE NETWORK, NUMBERS OF READERS,
SPACE AND MONEY.
********************************************
Document 5843
THE INTERRELATEDNESS OF BOOK SELECTION AND CENSORSHIP IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH
SPECIAL <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE POSITION IN THE REPUBLIC OF <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>.

(M.A. THESIS). THE INVESTIGATION AS TO WHETHER OR NOT THERE IS ANY
INTERRELATEDNESS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> BOOK SELECTION AND CENSORSHIP IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS
CARRIED OUT. A REVIEW OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CENSORSHIP IN <Location>UK</Location>,
<Location>USA</Location> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COUNTRIES WAS FOLLOWED BY AN EXPLORATORY, EMPIRICAL
INVESTIGATION OF THE POSITION IN <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>. THE SELECTION POLICIES OF THE 4
PROVINCIAL AND 10 AUTONOMOUS MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE EXAMINED. <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> THAT
LIBRARIANS SOMETIMES CENSOR AND THAT THERE IS AN INTERRELATEDNESS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> BOOK
SELECTION AND CENSORSHIP.
********************************************
Document 5844
A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE INTERACTION IN BOOK SELECTION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> PROVINCIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SYSTEMS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> AFFILIATED <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>.

(M.A. THESIS). EXAMINED <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> METHODS OF BOOK SELECTION IN RURAL, PROVINCIAL
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, IN <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>, WITH A VIEW TO ESTABLISHING WHETHER THEY ARE THE
MOST <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> POSSIBLE. RESULTS SHOWED THAT RELATIVELY LITTLE CHANGE HAD
TAKEN PLACE IN THE ORGANISATIONAL STRUCTURES OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> BOOK
SELECTION METHODS SINCE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INCEPTION AND THAT INVOLVEMENT OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
LIBRARIANS IN BOOK SELECTION WAS NEGLIGIBLE. RURAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN COUNTRIES
OUTSIDE <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location> WERE REVIEWED IN ORDER TO OBTAIN A MODEL AGAINST WHICH TO
MEASURE THE PERFORMANCE OF SOUTH AFRICAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5845
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SELECTION AND ACQUISITION.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO THE GERMAN LIBRARIANS CONFERENCE,
REGENSBURG, 9-13 JUNE 81. <Organization>AT REGENSBURG UNIVERSITY</Organization> A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>ACQUISITIONS</Organization>
DEPARTMENT COORDINATES ORDERS RECEIVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> AND SUBJECT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
AND CONTROLS <Organization>ALL</Organization> PRE-ACCESSION WORK, FINANCE AND BUDGETING. A BALANCE OF
<Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization> AND DECENTRALISED TASKS PROVES SUCCESSFUL. THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>ACQUISITIONS DEPARTMENT</Organization> FINDS <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> DOMESTIC AND FOREIGN <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
AND SENDS <Organization>THIS</Organization> TO THE SUBJECT LIBRARIANS. <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SELECTION IS MADE JOINTLY
BY THE SUBJECT LIBRARIANS AND THE FACULTIES. THE SUBJECT LIBRARIAN TRACES
MISSING BIBLIOGRAPHIC DETAILS FOR THE <Organization>ACQUISITIONS DEPARTMENT</Organization>. GERMAN LANGUAGE
MATERIAL IS BOUGHT <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> BOOK-SELLERS, FOREIGN MATERIAL <Organization>FROM</Organization> A VARIETY OF
SOURCES; GIFTS, EXCHANGES AND DEPOSIT COPIES <Organization>ALSO</Organization> PROVIDE USEFUL MATERIAL.
<Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> ARE OBTAINED MAINLY <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> ORDERING.
********************************************
Document 5846
<Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> POLICIES.

A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF ARTICLES AND REPORTS <Organization>PRODUCED BY COLLEGE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
ORGANISATIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SUBJECT OF <Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> POLICIES. THE
ORGANISATIONS SELECTED WERE <Organization>ALL</Organization> CHOSEN <Organization>FROM</Organization> THOSE INVOLVED WITH <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> RELATING TO <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> DEVELOPMENT.
********************************************
Document 5847
THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>&apos;S REVIEWS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; BOOK PURCHASES.

FACED WITH CUTS IN BOOK BUDGETS, LIBRARIANS HAVE TO CHOOSE TO WHICH GROUPS OF
USERS THEY SHOULD GIVE PRIORITY&apos; THOSE WHO <Organization>USE</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MOST, I.E. THOSE
WITH <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>, OR THE MINORITY FOR WHOM THE NEED FOR MEANINGFUL
<Organization>ACTIVITIES BEYOND TV</Organization> AND <Organization>WEEKLY</Organization> MAGAZINES IN A TIME OF UNEMPLOYMENT IS GREAT.
FEARS THAT CUTS ARE MADE, NOT IN THE PULP ENTERTAINMENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>BUT</Organization> IN
BOOKS BY QUALITY AUTHORS. INSTEAD OF DEFENDING WHAT IS CULTURALLY VALUABLE,
LIBRARIANS GIVE IN TO POPULAR <Organization>DEMAND</Organization> IN ORDER TO ACHIEVE <Organization>HIGH</Organization> <Organization>LOAN</Organization> FIGURES.
THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>&apos;S REVIEWS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PURCHASES
DEMONSTRATES <Organization>THIS</Organization>&apos; WELL REVIEWED QUALITY BOOKS ARE BOUGHT IN SMALL NUMBERS,
WHEREAS MULTIPLE COPIES ARE BOUGHT OF ENTERTAINMENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, DESPITE
LUKEWARM REVIEWS.
********************************************
Document 5848
<Organization>MODELING COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> BEHAVIOUR&apos; A PRELIMINARY STATEMENT.

DESCRIBES A MODEL FOR <Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITHIN BOTH
SPECIFIC COLLECTIONS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEMS AS A WHOLE AND SEEKS TO DEMONSTRATE
THE FULL RANGE AND COMPLEXITY OF RELEVANT FACTORS. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> THE MODEL
PRESENTED IS NOT NOW QUANTIFIABLE IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> DIMENSIONS, <Organization>ITS</Organization> ANALYSIS IS SEEN
AS <Organization>LEADING</Organization> TOWARDS <Organization>BETTER</Organization> MODELS FOR <Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, WHICH IN TURN
WILL <Organization>ALLOW</Organization> MORE USEFUL PLANS AND PROJECTIONS.
********************************************
Document 5849
SELECTION OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AND ACQUISITION POLICY&apos; <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
PROBLEMS.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE SITUATION IN <Location>LATIN AMERICA</Location>&apos;S UNDERDEVELOPED COUNTRIES, WITH
PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. EXAMINES THE STATE OF EDUCATION
IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, <Organization>WHERE HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> HAS BEEN DEVELOPED USUALLY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE EXPENSE
OF THE ELEMENTARY STAGES; <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> HAS BENEFITED ACCORDINGLY, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
<Organization>ALTHOUGH SOME UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE ADEQUATELY RESOURCED, RATIONALISATION
AND <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> OF <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> POLICIES IS ESSENTIAL TO MAXIMISE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF RESOURCES.
HENCE LIBRARIANS SHOULD DEVELOP DEFINITE SELECTION AND ACQUISITION POLICIES
USING THE ADVICE OF SPECIALISTS, AND DISREGARDING RESTRICTIONS OF RESOURCES BY
AUTHORITIES UNAPPRECIATIVE OF THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>PROMOTING</Organization> CULTURE
AND SCIENTIFIC KNOWLEDGE.
********************************************
