Document 2501
<Organization>IMPACT</Organization> OF OPTICAL MEMORIES (VIDEODISCS) <Organization>ON</Organization> THE COMPUTER AND IMAGE <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>
INDUSTRIES.
     
THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF <Organization>VIDEODISC SYSTEMS</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 1970 AND 1980 IS CONSIDERED. THE
TECHNOLOGIES WHICH <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>, JAPANESE, <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> AND <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> COMPANIES ARE WORKING
<Organization>ON</Organization> ARE EXAMINED, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO APPLICATIONS IN DATA AND IMAGE <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>
<Organization>USING</Organization> THE READ-WRITE DISCS WHICH ARE CONTINUALLY BEING DEVELOPED. THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
OF <Organization>OPTICAL DISC TECHNOLOGY</Organization> IS DISCUSSED AND CONSIDERATION IS GIVEN TO THE
APPLICATIONS AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE READ-ONLY DISCS IN THE EDUCATIONAL,
INSTITUTIONAL AND ENTERTAINMENT MARKETS. FINALLY, THE NEWS AND PLANS OF THE
FOLLOWING <Organization>USERS</Organization>, SUPPLIERS AND INDUSTRY SPOKESMEN ARE PRESENTED&apos; BANTEC, <Location>US</Location>
DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE, ENERGY CONVERSION DEVICES, HARRIS, <Organization>HONEYWELL</Organization>, MEMOREX,
<Organization>SRI INTERNATIONAL</Organization> AND XEROX.
********************************************
Document 2502
<Organization>INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY</Organization>.
     
OUTLINES FACTORS THAT MAKE THE <Organization>VIDEODISC</Organization> SO ATTRACTIVE AS AN IMAGE AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STORAGE</Organization> MEDIUM; DISCUSSES THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>VIDEODISC</Organization>
TECHNOLOGY; AND SPECULATES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2503
GUIDELINE FOR INSPECTION AND QUALITY <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> FOR <Organization>ALPHANUMERIC COMPUTER</Organization>-OUTPUT
MICROFORMS. CATEGORY&apos; HARDWARE. SUBCATEGORY&apos; MEDIA.
     
THE <Organization>STANDARD</Organization> DESCRIBES OPERATIONAL AND QUALITY-CONTROL GUIDELINES FOR
<Organization>ALPHANUMERIC COMPUTER</Organization>-OUTPUT MICROFILM (COM) RECORDERS AND MICROFORMS. IT IS
LIMITED TO IMAGES OF LINE PRINTER EQUIVALENT OUTPUT ONLY, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS THOSE USED
FOR BUSINESS AND <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> RECORDS.
********************************************
Document 2504
<Organization>ONLINE</Organization> MICROFILM RECORDERS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LOS</Organization> <Organization>ALAMOS NATIONAL LABORATORY</Organization>.
     
THE <Organization>LOS ALAMOS COMPUTING DIVISION</Organization> HAS DEVELOPED A SATELLITE GRAPHICS OUTPUT
STATION (PAGES). <Organization>THIS</Organization> STATION ACCEPTS <Organization>USER</Organization> REQUESTS FOR OUTPUT <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> A <Organization>LARGE</Organization>
COMPUTER <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> (THE <Organization>ICN</Organization>). THE SYSTEM TRANSLATES A <Organization>STANDARD</Organization> METAFILE <Organization>INTO</Organization> A
DEVICE-SPECIFIC FORMAT AND EFFICIENTLY GENERATES THE REQUESTED OUTPUT. <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>SAME</Organization> <Organization>TIME</Organization>, PAGES PROVIDES <Organization>SOME</Organization> GRAPHICS <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization>, PREVIOUSLY <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Organization>LARGE</Organization> SUPERCOMPUTERS.
********************************************
Document 2505
COLLECTING <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PRODUCTION OF AUDIO, VISUAL
AND <Organization>MICROFORM</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>PAPER</Organization> <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> ACTIVITIES FOR THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> PRODUCTION
DATA OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AND MICROFORMS AND PRESENTS <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> APPROACHES
TO THE TASK. <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> HAS FOR <Organization>SOME</Organization> YEARS <Organization>COLLECTED DATA</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PRODUCTION OF
PRINTED <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> WHILE RECOGNISING THE NEED FOR COLLECTING <Organization>SIMILAR</Organization>
<Organization>STATISTICS ON NONPRINT MEDIA</Organization>, IT HAS NOT YET DONE SO. IF <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> WERE TO
UNDERTAKE THE TASK, IT <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE <Organization>NECESSARY</Organization> TO ENLIST THE <Organization>AID</Organization> OF INTERNATIONAL
ASSOCIATIONS AND THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS OF PRODUCERS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>.
REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2506
PROLEGOMENA TO THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF INTERNATIONAL LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
IN THE CLOSING DECADES OF THE 20<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>CENTURY</Organization>, THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF INTERNATIONAL
LIBRARIANSHIP IS STILL LARGELY UNCHARTED TERRITORY. DISCUSSES EVIDENCE OF
INTEREST IN INTERNATIONAL LIBRARIANSHIP (WHICH IS DISTINGUISHED <Organization>FROM</Organization>
COMPARATIVE LIBRARIANSHIP), THE <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> AND SCOPE OF INTERNATIONAL
LIBRARIANSHIP, HYPOTHESES UNDERLYING <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> INVESTIGATION, SOURCES OF THE
<Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE FIELD, AN AGENDA FOR <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> SCHOLARSHIP, AND USES OF THE
<Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF INTERNATIONAL LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
Document 2507
THE PARETO PRINCIPLE <Organization>AT</Organization> NEWCASTLE.
     
EDITED <Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF THE PRESIDENTIAL ADDRESS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>JOINT</Organization> CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION OF <Location>IRELAND</Location> AND THE NORTHERN <Location>IRELAND</Location> BRANCH OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION, <Location>NEWCASTLE</Location>, <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> DOWN, 12-16 MAY 81. <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> SURVEYS THE WORK OF
THE ASSOCIATIONS IN THE LAST <Organization>YEAR</Organization>. SUGGESTS THAT WE SHOULD LOOK CAREFULLY <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>HOW</Organization> WE <Organization>USE</Organization> OUR <Organization>TIME</Organization>&apos; THE PARETO PRINCIPLE STATES THAT THE MOST TRIVIAL 20% OF
ACCOMPLISHMENT USUALLY CONSUMES 80% OF YOUR <Organization>TIME</Organization> WHILST THE MOST VITAL
RECEIVES ONLY 20%. ARGUES FOR 10% VAT TO BE REMOVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> BOOKS; VAT TOGETHER
WITH THE POOR COMPARISON OF THE PUNT TO STERLING, LIMITS <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> PURCHASING
POWER. COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROBLEMS OF PHOTOCOPYING AND COPYRIGHT.
********************************************
Document 2508
THE ROAD AHEAD FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; POLITICISATION AND QUALIFIED DEFENCE.
     
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROAD AHEAD FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
GROUP OF CHIEF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND <Organization>HELD</Organization> IN FEB 81. THE PLIGHT OF AUTHORS AND
BOOKSELLERS WAS DEALT WITH <Organization>BY</Organization> A PUBLISHER AND AN AUTHOR IN TALKS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
POSSIBILITIES AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PRODUCTION OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> IN RELATION TO THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
OF THE 80S. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECTS</Organization> COVERED <Organization>BY</Organization> CIVIL SERVANTS IN <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES
WERE&apos; CONDITIONS FOR AND CLAIMS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SENIOR CIVIL SERVANT IN THE 80S;
COOPERATION AND <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> CIVIL SERVANTS AND POLITICIANS, AND
CIVIL SERVANTS&apos; RIGHT OF FREE EXPRESSION. A SURVEY OF <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN
<Location>DENMARK</Location> SINCE 1909 WAS GIVEN <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. R. LYSHOLT HANSEN WAS RESIGNED TO
THE FACT THAT THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> DID NOT WISH TO ENTER <Organization>INTO</Organization> A <Organization>JOINT</Organization>
DIRECTORATE, <Organization>BUT</Organization> ARGUED THAT <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization> OF SECURING FAIR <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> DISTRIBUTION
SHOULD BE FOUND. THE FINAL <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> OF DISCUSSION WAS&apos; PROVISION AND MANAGEMENT
IN THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF TOMORROW, WHEN THE  RIGHT BALANCE <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> CENTRALISATION,
<Organization>NECESSARY</Organization> IN A <Organization>TIME</Organization> OF CUTS, AND INDIVIDUALITY WAS DEBATED.
********************************************
Document 2509
OUR TASKS.
     
THE <Organization>OFFICIAL</Organization> 1977-<Organization>UNESCO</Organization> <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization> SHOW THAT, AS FAR AS NUMBERS OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
AND <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, AND ALSO ANNUAL ACQUISITIONS PER HEAD OF POPULATION, ARE
CONCERNED, <Location>BULGARIA</Location> LIES IN THE 7<Organization>TH</Organization> AND 4<Organization>TH</Organization> PLACES RESPECTIVELY IN THE WORLD.
HOWEVER, <Location>BULGARIA</Location> TAKES THE 14<Organization>TH</Organization> AND 19<Organization>TH</Organization> PLACES IN LOANS AND IN TURNOVER OF
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> COLLECTIONS. THUS, <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> EFFICIENCY REQUIRED IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> FIELDS OF
THE NATION&apos;S LIFE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE RECENT 12<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>BULGARIAN COMMUNIST PARTY</Organization>
MUST ALSO BE AIMED FOR IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES. <Organization>GREAT</Organization> ATTENTION
MUST BE PAID IN <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> TO <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH
NEED TO COPE NOT ONLY WITH THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> EXPLOSION, <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO WITH
SOARING PRICES OF <Organization>WESTERN</Organization> PUBLICATIONS AND BULGARIA&apos;S LIMITED <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> CURRENCY
RESOURCES. AMONGST <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PROBLEMS ARE THE EDUCATION AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, THE NEEDS IN <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS, MECHANISATION, <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>, AND
UPDATING OF <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization>. THE CYRIL AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, NOT
ONLY AS KEEPER OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LITERARY HERITAGE, <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO AS THE MOST
<Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRE IN THE WHOLE COUNTRY, IS, IN ITSELF,
A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> CASE. IT SHOULD BE RELIEVED OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> PROBLEMS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE OCCASION
OF THE 1300<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNIVERSARY OF THE <Organization>BULGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2510
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>INDIA</Location>-PERSONAL IMPRESSIONS).
     
STARTING WITH THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>CALCUTTA</Location> OUTLINES THE STRUCTURE,
ORGANISATION, WORK, AND THE NATURE AND EXTENT OF COLLECTIONS OF <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> INDIAN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Location>DELHI</Location>, <Location>BOMBAY</Location> AND MADRAS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
NETWORKS OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> ARE FOLLOWED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE 3
CITIES. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL INSTITUTES</Organization> AND <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
ARE ALSO OUTLINED. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ASPECTS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LIFE IN <Location>INDIA</Location> COVERED INCLUDE
THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, FOUNDED IN <Location>MADRAS</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1928, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION, <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>, BIBLIOGRAPHICAL WORK, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK WITH
CHILDREN, AND <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2511
A CONVERSATION WITH MALACHI BEIT-ARIE.
     
AN INTERVIEW WITH DR. MALACHI BEIT-ARIE, DIRECTOR OF THE <Organization>JEWISH</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>JERUSALEM</Location>. COVERS THE MOVE OF THE <Organization>HEBREW UNIVERSITY</Organization> TO
MOUNT SCOPUS, THE SCOPE OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, THE INSTITUTE FOR
<Organization>HEBREW</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY, THE INSTITUTE OF MICROFILMED <Organization>HEBREW</Organization> MANUSCRIPTS,
PRESERVATION OF <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION, PARTICULARLY WITH
<Location>EGYPT</Location>.
********************************************
Document 2512
EFFICIENCY, TAYLORISM, AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN PROGRESSIVE <Location>AMERICA</Location>.
     
THE <Organization>SAME</Organization> INTENSE SENSE OF URGENCY THAT SURROUNDED THE WORD &apos;ENERGY&apos; IN THE
LATE 1970S WAS FELT IN CONNECTION WITH THE WORD &apos;EFFICIENCY&apos; IN THE LATE 19<Organization>TH</Organization>
AND EARLY 20<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURIES. EFFICIENCY WAS FELT TO BE THE <Organization>KEY</Organization> TO PUTTING <Organization>INTO</Organization>
ORDER THE CHAOS RESULTING <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization>/<Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> REVOLUTION. THE
PUBLICATION OF FREDERICK W. TAYLOR&apos;S 2PRINCIPLES OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC MANAGEMENT</Organization>1 IN
1911 IS OFTEN ERRONEOUSLY CITED AS THE BEGINNING OF THE EFFICIENCY CRAZE.
DISCUSSES THE PRINCIPLES PROPOUNDED <Organization>BY</Organization> TAYLOR, THE EFFICIENCY CRAZE, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
EFFECTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2513
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> OVER THE WORLD TO MEET IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location> FOR THE 47<Organization>TH</Organization> CONFERENCE
OF THE IFLA&apos;S <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ASSEMBLY.
     
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 17-22 AUG 81 THE 47<Organization>TH</Organization> CONFERENCE OF THE IFLA&apos;S <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ASSEMBLY WILL
TAKE PLACE IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>. THE MAIN THEME OF THE CONFERENCE WHICH WAS SUGGESTED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> WILL BE &apos;<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
ORGANISATIONS&apos;. <Organization>THIS</Organization> THEME IS CONSIDERED TO BE OF <Organization>GREAT</Organization> IMPORTANCE <Organization>ON</Organization> AN
INTERNATIONAL LEVEL AS IT PROVIDES AN OPPORTUNITY TO DEAL WITH <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> ASPECTS
OF <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE EFFICIENCY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORGANISATIONS, <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> METHODICAL
CENTRES AND <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> SERVICE FACILITIES FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. ABOUT 1,200 PEOPLE ARE
EXPECTED TO ATTEND THE CONFERENCE WHICH WIL BE THE LARGEST <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> EVENT YET
IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>. MANY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND MUSEUMS IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location> WILL BE ORGANISING
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> EXHIBITIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>TIME</Organization> AND A SEMINAR FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
COUNTRIES WILL BE <Organization>HELD</Organization> IN THE WEEK PRECEDING THE CONFERE NCE.
********************************************
Document 2514
<Organization>BOOK</Organization> <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> IN FIVE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> JOURNALS&apos; A COMPARATIVE ANALYSIS.
     
PRESENTS A COMPARATIVE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE SIGNED <Organization>BOOK</Organization> <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> PUBLISHED DURING
1979 IN&apos; 2AUST. LIBR. J1.; 2AUST. ACAD. RES. LIBR1.; 2LIBR. <Organization>ASS</Organization>. REC1.; 2J.
LIBRARIANSHIP1; AND 2LIBR. Q1. DESCRIBES AND <Organization>COMPARES</Organization> THE <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> IN <Organization>THESE</Organization>
JOURNALS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE POINT OF VIEW OF&apos; COVERAGE; DUPLICATION PATTERNS; BIASES OF
THE <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization>; LANGUAGE AND SOURCE OF PUBLICATION; LENGTH; <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> <Organization>THEY</Organization> ARE
FAVOURABLE; AND THE FORMAT OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> <Organization>REVIEW</Organization> SECTION. ATTEMPTS TO EVALUATE
THE <Organization>CONTENT</Organization> OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2515
THE 20<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNIVERSARY OF AZ ORVOSI KONYVTAROS (<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN).IN 195
     
6, THE &apos;<Organization>REVIEW</Organization> OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP&apos; WAS PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization>
<Organization>MEDICAL DOCUMENTATION CENTRE</Organization> (SUCCEEDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>MEDICAL INFORMATION CENTRE</Organization>).
ONLY 2 ISSUES APPEARED, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> SUCCESSOR AZ ORVOSI KONYVTAROS WAS ESTABLISHED
IN 1961. NOW, 20 YEARS LATER, 80 ISSUES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> APPEARED, CARRYING 834 ARTICLES.
ANALYSES THE CONTENTS AND PHILOSOPHY BEHIND THE PRODUCTION OF THE JOURNAL.
********************************************
Document 2516
STANDARDISATION IN THE FIELDS OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND BIBLIOGRAPHY&apos; THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
SITUATION AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PROSPECTS.
     
STANDARDS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> AN <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> ROLE IN THE <Organization>IMPLEMENTATION</Organization> OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> AND
THE <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> OF ECONOMIC EFFICIENCY. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RELEVANCE IN LIBRARIANSHIP
<Organization>INCLUDES IMPROVING READER SERVICES</Organization>, MAXIMISING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF RESOURCES, ACCOUNTING
PROCEDURES AND INTERLIBRARY COOPERATION. IN 1976-78 <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> STANDARDS
RELATING TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE REVISED AND COORDINATED AND A LONG-TERM PROGRAMME
OF STANDARDISATION COVERING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK, LIBRARIANSHIP AND PUBLISHING WAS
<Organization>INITIATED</Organization>. ASPECTS OF LIBRARIANSHIP AFFECTED <Organization>BY</Organization> STANDARDS INTRODUCED SINCE
THEN INCLUDE&apos; THE BIBLIOGRAPHICAL DESCRIPTION OF <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> AND MAPS, <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
BOOKS IN SERVICE POINTS, BASIC TERMS AND DEFINITIONS IN <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
WORK, AND A SINGLE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> SYSTEM OF INTER-LIBRARY LOANS.
********************************************
Document 2517
<Organization>BULGARIAN</Organization> PERIODICALS AS AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCE <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
ONE OF THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHIES PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE CYRIL AND METHODIUS
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>SOFIA</Location> COVERS <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP, BIBLIOGRAPHY AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE. <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1967-76, 4330 HEADINGS WERE LISTED. MORE THAN 90%
WERE ARTICLES AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> PAPERS, AND ONLY THE REMAINING 10% INCLUDED BOOKS.
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> DAILIES AS WELL AS <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> PAPERS ALSO PAID ATTENTION TO
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>THEY</Organization> EMPHASISED, HOWEVER, <Organization>MOSTLY</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ISSUES OR TOPICS OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
INTEREST AND TIMING FREQUENCY AS WELL AS STANDARDS VARIED CONSIDERABLY. SINCE
1954, 2BIBLIOTEKAR1 HAS BEEN ALMOST THE ONLY STABLE PERIODICAL FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
AND HAS SO FAR REMAINED THE ONLY <Organization>BULGARIAN</Organization> PERIODICAL OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> KIND KNOWN AND
ABSTRACTED ABROAD. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> LACKED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
PERIODICAL. THE <Organization>GAP</Organization> HAS BEEN PARTLY FILLED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE EFFORT OF THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>BULGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMY OF SCIENCES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2518
MAKING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS PAY.
     
EXAMINES <Organization>GOOD</Organization> (EVEN SOPHISTICATED) PRACTICE IN THE FIELD OF FINDING AND <Organization>USING</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS, COVERING PATTERNS OF <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>, THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SEARCH,
HANDLING SEARCH RESULTS, PROBLEMS, BUILDING <Organization>ON</Organization> PREVIOUS <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, AND
STRATEGIES FOR <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2519
A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>READER</Organization> AND <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> GUIDE.
     
A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF ESSAYS AIMING&apos; TO STIMULATE MORE INTEREST IN THE PURSUIT OF
SYSTEMATIC INQUIRY PERTAINING TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE; TO HELP
<Organization>POTENTIAL RESEARCH WORKERS</Organization> GAIN A CLEARER UNDERSTANDING OF SELECTED STRATEGIES
FOR THE CONDUCT OF STUDIES, THE ANALYSIS OF <Organization>EMPIRICAL DATA</Organization>, AND THE EVALUATION
OF COMPLETED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS; TO ACQUAINT <Organization>READERS</Organization> WITH <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization>
CONSIDERATIONS FOR PLANNING STUDIES AND OBTAINING FUNDS TO UNDERTAKE PROJECTS;
AND TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> USEFUL LISTS OF ADDITIONAL SOURCES OF PUBLISHED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
ABOUT <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> METHODS. <Organization>INCLUDES</Organization> PAPERS <Organization>BY</Organization>&apos; CHARLES
H. BUSHA, LAUREL GROTZINGER, JEFFREY KATZER, CAROL MCCOMBS, STEPHEN B. WALTER,
AND CAROLYN GRADDICK TEAL, WITH A BIBLIOGRAPHY COMPILED <Organization>BY</Organization> CHARLES H. BUSHA.
********************************************
Document 2520
THE EVOLUTION OF THE INTERNATIONAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SYSTEM <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN
DOCUMENTATION (ISORID).
     
A READING OF THE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> DOCUMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INTERNATIONAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SYSTEM
<Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN DOCUMENTATION (ISORID), A <Organization>JOINT</Organization> <Organization>UNESCO</Organization>-FID OPERATION, REVEALS
THAT THE SYSTEM HAS MET AS YET UNRESOLVED STRESSES THAT HINDER THE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization>
CONTRIBUTION TO THE WORLD COMMUNITY THAT <Organization>THIS</Organization> SYSTEM WAS EXPECTED TO MAKE. A
QUANTITATIVE COMPARISON WITH THE US-BASED 2<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES
TODAY1 (LIST) IS NOT KIND TO ISORID AND REFLECTS THE DEGREE OF DIFFICULTY THAT
ISORID HAS WITH <Organization>ITS ESSENTIALLY COOPERATIVE</Organization> BASIS FOR <Organization>GATHERING DATA</Organization>. THE
THEORETICAL BASIS FOR AN INTERNATIONAL REGISTER APPEARS SOUND, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
PRACTICALITIES ARE HINDERING <Organization>ITS</Organization> EFFECTIVENESS TO THE FIELDS OF DOCUMENTATION,
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE, AND LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
Document 2521
THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE IN <Location>QUEBEC</Location>&apos; SURVEY
RESULTS.
     
IN ORDER TO FULFILL ONE OF THE ELEMENTS OF THE MANDATE CONFERRED UPON IT IN
JUNE 79, THE <Organization>RESEARCH COMMITTEE</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP CONDUCTED A SURVEY TO FIND
<Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> <Location>QUEBEC</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE RESEARCH-MINDED. THE 203 QUESTIONNAIRES
RECEIVED, STUDIED AND ANALYSED, GIVE WITNESS TO <Organization>SOME</Organization> INTERESTING PROJECTS AND
REALISATIONS. <Organization>BUT</Organization> GIVEN THE <Organization>TIME</Organization> AND FINANCIAL CONSTRAINTS AND THE
PSYCHOLOGICAL CLIMATE, ONE QUESTION REMAINS UNANSWERED&apos; WHAT IS THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Location>QUEBEC</Location>?.
********************************************
Document 2522
LIFE AND WORK OF PROFESSOR ARNTZ. AN <Organization>FID</Organization> TRIBUTE.
     
<Organization>PAPER</Organization> <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> AN ADDRESS DELIVERED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>FID</Organization> <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> BANQUET, <Organization>HELD</Organization> IN
<Location>COPENHAGEN</Location> 21 AUG 80. HIGHLIGHTS THE CONTRIBUTIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS OF
PROFESSOR H. ARNTZ IN THE FIELD OF DOCUMENTATION AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE AND
TRACES HIS EARLY CAREER AND INTEREST IN MICROFILMS AND REPROGRAPHY. <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization>
THE ACTIVITIES OF <Organization>FID</Organization> WHEN PROFESSOR ARNTZ WAS PRESIDENT AND PAYS TRIBUTE TO
HIS WORK AND ACHIEVEMENTS WITHIN THE FEDERATION.
********************************************
Document 2523
CARLOS E. CASTANEDA&apos;S RENDEZVOUS WITH A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; THE LATIN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, 1920-1927-THE FIRST PHASE.W
     
HILST CARLOS EDUARDO CASTANEDA ACHIEVED DISTINCTION AS A 1<Organization>ST</Organization> RATE HISTORIAN OF
THE SOUTHERN BORDERLANDS OF THE <Location>USA</Location>, MANY ARE UNAWARE OF THE CONTRIBUTIONS HE
MADE TO THE PROFESSIONS OF <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE. DESCRIBES THE PERIOD
<Organization>FROM</Organization> 1920, WHEN CASTANEDA 1<Organization>ST</Organization> HEARD THAT THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS WAS TO
ACQUIRE &apos;THE FINEST AND MOST EXTENSIVE <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> AND LITERARY <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF
<Location>MEXICO</Location>&apos;, TO 1927, WHEN HE BECAME LIBRARIAN OF THE BENSON LATIN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
********************************************
Document 2524
CARMEN DIANA DEARDEN&apos; EDITOR AND <Organization>EXECUTIVE</Organization> DIRECTOR OF THE VENEZUELAN BANCO
DEL LIBRO.
     
AN INTERVIEW WITH THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> DIRECTOR OF THE CHIEF <Organization>PRIVATE</Organization> VENEZUELAN
ORGANISATION CONCERNED WITH SCHOOL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND EDUCATIONAL
PUBLISHING. A BRIEF SUMMARY IS GIVEN OF HER PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE WITH BANCO DEL
LIBRO IN ORGANISING A <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. THE DISCUSSION COVERS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMMES AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>IMPLEMENTATION</Organization> <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> COOPERATION;
ACTIVITIES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE INTERNATIONAL LEVEL; AND PUBLISHING PROJECTS UNDER THE
SPONSORSHIP OF EKARE, THE BANCO DEL LIBRO PUBLISHING HOUSE.
********************************************
Document 2525
FRANCES NEWMAN&apos; LIBRARIAN AND NOVELIST.
     
BRIEF BIOGRAPHY OF FRANCES NEWMAN, (BORN IN <Location>ATLANTA</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1888), WHO WAS BOTH
LIBRARIAN AND NOVELIST. DISCUSSES HER WRITING AS A REFLECTION OF THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE OF THE PERIOD UP TO HER DEATH IN 1928.
********************************************
Document 2526
AZARIAH SMITH ROOT AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFORM AT OBERLIN COLLEGE</Organization>.
     
AZARIAH SMITH ROOT WAS BORN IN MIDDLEFIELD, MASSACHUSSETTS, IN 1862. IN 1885,
<Organization>HAVING</Organization> GAINED MA AND BA DEGREES, HE ASSUMED A TEMPORARY POSITION <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> OBERLIN COLLGE. IN 1887 HE WAS ELECTED COLLEGE
LIBRARIAN, A POSITION WHICH HE <Organization>HELD</Organization> UNTIL HIS DEATH 40 YEARS LATER. DISCUSSES
ROOT&apos;S <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> PHILOSOPHY, THE COLLEGE AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> HISTORIC COMMITMENT TO REFORMIST
NOTIONS, (IN 1835 IT ADMITTED BLACK STUDENTS, AND IN 1837 BECAME THE <Location>USA</Location>&apos;S 1<Organization>ST</Organization>
<Organization>COEDUCATIONAL COLLEGE</Organization>), AND THE INTERPLAY <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> ROOT AND HIS OBERLIN
COLLEAGUES.
********************************************
Document 2527
OSCAR G.T. SONNECK: ARCHITECT OF THE &apos;<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>&apos;.
     
DISCUSSES THE WORK OF OSCAR GEORGE THEODORE SONNECK, (BORN IN <Organization>NEW</Organization> JERSEY IN
1873), WHO AS CHIEF OF THE <Organization>MUSIC DIVISION</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization>, PRODUCED A
<Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> SCHEME FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> COLLECTIONS, ASSEMBLED A VAST
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> COLLECTIONS, AND MAY JUSTLY BE DESCRIBED AS
THE FATHER OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
Document 2528
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION OF <Location>INDIA</Location> <Organization>AT</Organization> CROSS ROADS.
     
TRACES THE GENESIS AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION IN <Location>INDIA</Location> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
1924 WHEN <Organization>MADRAS UNIVERSITY</Organization> CREATED A LIBRARIAN&apos;S <Organization>POST</Organization> WITH A STATUS AND
SALARY SCALE WORTHY OF A PROFESSION. DISCUSSES THE STATUS AND PRESTIGE OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSIONALS AND MAKES A COMPARATIVE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF SALARY SCALES IN 1959
AND 1969. DISCUSSES THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCIENCE EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>TECHNIQUES</Organization> AND SUGGESTS MEANS <Organization>BY</Organization> WHICH THE STATUS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION
<Organization>CAN</Organization> BE RAISED.
********************************************
Document 2529
EDUCATING THE <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> SELF-CENSOR.
     
A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>IMPACT</Organization> OF AN EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE DEVOTED TO CENSORSHIP <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE <Organization>SELECTION</Organization> BEHAVIOUR OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE AND EDUCATION MAJORS.
********************************************
Document 2530
DRAMATIC RISE IN THE NUMBER OF CENSORSHIP CASES.
     
INTERVIEWS JUDITH F. KRUG, LEADER OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S OFFICE
FOR <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> FREEDOM. <Organization>ITS</Organization> WORK IS <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FIRST AMENDMENT OF THE <Location>U.S.</Location>
CONSTITUTION AND <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ALA&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL OF RIGHTS. IT BEGAN AS THE
<Organization>INTELLECTUAL FREEDOM COMMITTEE</Organization> IN 1940. UNTIL RECENTLY ALMOST <Organization>ALL</Organization> CASES CAME
<Organization>FROM SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> SINCE THE <Organization>REAGAN ADMINISTRATION TOOK OFFICE</Organization> THE
MOST <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> CASES ORIGINATE WITH THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE OFFICE, HOWEVER,
DOES NOT CONFINE ITSELF TO TAKING UP CASES WITHIN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SECTOR, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT
KEEPS <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> INFORMED OF THE IMPORTANCE OF THE FIRST
AMENDMENT, ISSUES PUBLICATIONS, AND HOLDS SEMINARS. MANY ATTEMPTS <Organization>AT</Organization>
CENSORSHIP COME <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE MORAL MAJORITY MOVEMENT. THE OFFICE FINDS IT EASIER
TO DEAL WITH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> A CLEARLY FORMULATED <Organization>SELECTION</Organization> POLICY, AND
IN VERY <Organization>FEW</Organization> CASES DOES IT RECOMMEND REFUSAL TO ACQUIRE A <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization>. THE
LEGAL SIDE OF ALA IS DEALT WITH <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>SEPARATE</Organization>,  <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>RELATED</Organization> BODY, THE FREEDOM
TO READ FOUNDATION.
********************************************
Document 2531
THE YOUNG <Organization>ADULT</Organization> AND <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> FREEDOM IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. A SELECTIVE
BIBLIOGRAPHY AND CRITICAL <Organization>REVIEW</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
     
DESIGNED FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS PLANNING COMMUNITY</Organization> ORIENTED PROGRAMMES, <Organization>THIS</Organization> ANNOTATED
BIBLIOGRAPHY CRITICALLY <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> DEFENDING THE YOUNG <Organization>ADULT</Organization>&apos;S RIGHT
TO <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> FREEDOM. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2532
ANNUAL <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> AS INDICATORS OF THE <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> STRUCTURE OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>
DISCIPLINES.
     
(<Organization>PHD</Organization> THESIS-UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND.) EXAMINES THE 2ANNUAL <Organization>REVIEW</Organization> OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY1 <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1966-75, FOR EVIDENCE OF THE
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> STRUCTURE OF THE DISCIPLINE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE.
<Organization>THIS</Organization> STRUCTURE IS VIEWED AS BEING COMPOSED OF THE CONCEPTS WHICH FORM THE
<Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> TERRITORY OF THE DISCIPLINE AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ORGANISATION <Organization>INTO</Organization> TOPICS
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AREAS AND SUB-FIELDS. A <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> FUNCTION OF <Organization>REVIEW</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IS SEEN
TO BE THE MAPPING OF THE <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> STRUCTURE OF THE DISCIPLINE. EXAMINES
CONCEPTS UNDERLYING AUTHORS&apos; <Organization>NATURAL</Organization> LANGUAGE. ATTEMPTS TO PRODUCE A MODEL OF
THE LIFE CYCLE OF A <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> DISCIPLINE, AND SUGGESTS A NUMBER OF FOLLOW-UP
STUDIES.
********************************************
Document 2533
<Organization>MEASUREMENT</Organization> IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE&apos; OBJECTIVE AND SUBJECTIVE METRICAL SPACE.
     
IT IS ARGUED THAT IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE WE <Organization>HAVE</Organization> TO DISTINGUISH PHYSICAL,
OBJECTIVE, OR DOCUMENT SPACE <Organization>FROM</Organization> PERSPECTIVE, SUBJECTIVE, OR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SPACE. <Organization>THESE</Organization> 2 SPACES ARE LIKE MAPS AND LANDSCAPES&apos; EACH IS A SYSTEMATIC
DISTORTION OF THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization>. HOWEVER, TRANSFORMATIONS <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE EASILY MADE ONCE THE
2 SPACES ARE DISTINGUISHED.
********************************************
Document 2534
MYSTERIES OF THE DEEP&apos; MODELS OF THE UNIVERSE OF KNOWLEDGE.
     
EVIDENCE OF THE <Organization>USE</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> SCHOLARS AND OTHERS, OF MENTAL CONSTRUCTS OR MODELS OF
SPATIAL AND TEMPORAL <Organization>RELATIONSHIPS</Organization> IS PRESENTED TO ILLUSTRATE A NON-VERBAL
KNOWLEDGE STRUCTURE. THE RELATIONSHIP OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> KIND OF STRUCTURE TO EFFORTS TO
CONSTRUCT MODELS OF THE UNIVERSE OF KNOWLEDGE IS STATED, NOTING THE DANGER IN
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> MODELS.
********************************************
Document 2535
AN EXTRAPOLATION APPROACH TO THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
     
DISCUSSES THE ANALYSIS OF THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WITHIN THE FRAMEWORK OF
THE TRIAD &apos;DATA-INFORMATION-KNOWLEDGE&apos; AND STRESSES THE IMPORTANCE OF
EXTRAPOLATION IN RELATION TO THE KNOWLEDGE ASPECT OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> CONCEPT. SHOWS THE
VARIETY OF FORMS WHICH EXTRAPOLATION MAY TAKE WHEN OBTAINING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> ASPECTS OF HUMAN KNOWLEDGE.
********************************************
Document 2536
THE CONCEPTION OF <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization>, <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> AND TERTIARY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE POINT
OF VIEW OF THE THEORY OF REFLECTION OF SYMBOLS.
     
<Organization>USING</Organization> THE <Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> MODEL OF TRANSFORMATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
STRUCTURE OF DATA <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE POINT OF VIEW OF THE THEORY OF REFLECTION, THE
SIMILARITIES AND DIFFERENCES <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization>, <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> AND TERTIARY
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ARE OUTLINED. ACCORDING TO <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> THE SYMBOL IS A REFLECTION OF
PHENOMENA OR A REFLECTION OF A SYMBOL (SIGN), <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> ORDERS OF THE REFLECTION
ARE RECOGNISED, I.E. THE ORDER OF THE SYMBOL REFLECTION. THUS <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS A REFLECTION OF A PHENOMENON DEPOSITED WITHOUT A SIGN/MARK,
<Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS A REFLECTION OF THE DEPOSITED SIGNS, ETC. THE
STATEMENT GIVING THE SPACE AND <Organization>TIME</Organization> IN WHICH A PHENOMENON IS VALID IS CALLED
THE ADDRESS.
********************************************
Document 2537
THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIAN.
     
THE CAREER OF A LIBRARIAN SHOULD COMBINE THE PRACTICAL SIDE OF LIBRARIANSHIP
WITH <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> KNOWLEDGE AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. NOWADAYS <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE
IS USUALLY CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> IN TEAMS RATHER THAN <Organization>BY</Organization> INDIVIDUALS. <Organization>MODERN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> TO POSSESS A <Organization>WIDE</Organization> RANGE OF KNOWLEDGE COVERING MANY FIELDS AND IT IS NO
LONGER USUAL FOR A LIBRARIAN TO BE AN EXPERT IN ONLY 1 <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization>. TEACHERS <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS ARE OFTEN PART-TIME <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> STUDENTS WITH AN
UNDERSTANDING OF DAILY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITY, WHICH PREVENTS COURSES <Organization>FROM</Organization> BECOMING
MERELY THEORETICAL. THE CHANGING STRUCTURE OF <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS REFLECTED
IN THE SYLLABUSES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS WHICH DEVOTE MORE <Organization>TIME</Organization> TO <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>SUBJECTS</Organization> THAN BEFORE.
********************************************
Document 2538
ARCHIVIST AND COMPREHENSIVIST.
     
RECENT DEVELOPMENTS IN TECHNOLOGY <Organization>HAVE</Organization> VASTLY EXPANDED THE ARCHIVAL REALM. THE
ARCHIVIST RISKS BEING <Organization>OUT</Organization> OF TUNE WITH THE NEEDS OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC TIMES</Organization>. TODAY
THE &apos;COMPLETE&apos; ARCHIVIST IS REQUIRED TO PLAY AN EVER WIDENING
INTERDISCIPLINARY ROLE. THE <Organization>SPECIALIST</Organization> MUST NOW BECOME THE COMPREHENSIVIST WHO
<Organization>CAN</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> THE <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization> HARDWARE WITH <Organization>ALL</Organization> HIS WITS AND SENSES.
********************************************
Document 2539
IFLA DURING THE PRESIDENCY OF GUSTAV HOFMANN (1958-1963).
     
IN 1958 GUSTAV HOFMANN WAS ELECTED PRESIDENT OF IFLA IN <Location>MADRID</Location>. HE WAS THE
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> DIRECTOR OF THE BAVARIAN <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. DURING HIS PERIOD OF OFFICE
AS PRESIDENT OF THE IFLA <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1958-63 HOFMANN PROMOTED AND CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> A GREAT
DEAL OF STRUCTURAL REORGANISATION <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE GROUNDWORK FOR THE REVISION OF
THE ARTICLES AND THE CONSTITUTION OF IFLA. THE ASSOCIATION GREW RAPIDLY DURING
<Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>TIME</Organization> AND IT WAS <Organization>NECESSARY</Organization> TO <Organization>ORGANISE</Organization> IT ALONG FEDERAL LINES WITH
VICE-PRESIDENTS RESPONSIBLE FOR <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> GEOGRAPHICAL AREAS. HOFMANN
SUCCESSFULLY ENGAGED PEOPLE IN IFLA PROJECTS AND CONTRIBUTED ACTIVELY HIMSELF.
********************************************
Document 2540
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS&apos; <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE AND UTILITY IN THE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMME
OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.
     
DISCUSSES THE ROLE OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS AND <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> THE CONTRIBUTION
OF THE <Organization>UK LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION. HIGHLIGHTS THE EDUCATION ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS IN <Location>INDIA</Location>. REVEALS THAT MOST OF THE CERTIFICATE COURSES IN <Location>INDIA</Location>
ARE RUN <Organization>BY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS. CONCLUDES THAT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS IN COLLABORATION
WITH UNIVERSITIES AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES SHOULD TRY TO IMPROVE THE PROFESSION
<Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>STANDARD</Organization> METHODS OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2541
JOHN HARRIS&apos; <Location>NZ</Location>&apos;S GIFT TO NIGERIAN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.
     
<Organization>NEW</Organization> ZEALANDER JOHN HARRIS (1903-80) ARRIVED IN <Location>NIGERIA</Location> IN 1948 TO BE LIBRARIAN
OF THE <Organization>FLEDGELING UNIVERSITY COLLEGE</Organization>, IBADAN. HE ALMOST SINGLE-HANDEDLY
CREATED <Location>NIGERIA</Location>&apos;S <Organization>PREMIER ACADEMIC PRESS</Organization> AND, WITH HIS WIFE, <Organization>ITS</Organization> 1<Organization>ST</Organization>
UNIVERSITY BOOKSHOP. HE PLAYED A <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> ROLE IN FORMING THE <Organization>WEST</Organization> AFRICAN
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND <Organization>INITIATED</Organization> THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>FORMAL LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> COURSE IN
<Location>NIGERIA</Location>. THANKS LARGELY TO HIM, THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> IN <Location>NIGERIA</Location>, THE
INSTITUTE OF LIBRARIANSHIP, WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1959 WITH A <Organization>GRANT</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
<Organization>CARNEGIE CORPORATION</Organization>-THIS IN THE FACE OF COMPETITION <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>WEST</Organization> AFRICAN
STATES WISHING TO ESTABLISH <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A BODY.
********************************************
Document 2542
EVEN AFTER 8 YEARS WITHIN THE COLLEGES OF TECHNOLOGY, LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
IS STILL A CRISIS AREA.
     
ALTHOUGH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> GUIDELINES WERE DRAWN UP <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, EACH
<Organization>WEST</Organization> <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> IS RESPONSIBLE FOR <Organization>ITS OWN EDUCATION</Organization> SYSTEM, THEREFORE
CONSIDERABLE VARIATIONS STILL EXIST CONCERNING LEGAL STATUS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOLS, ENTRY REQUIREMENTS, CURRICULA FOR COMPULSORY AND OPTIONAL <Organization>SUBJECTS</Organization>
AND ORGANISATION OF COURSES FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECTS</Organization>
ARE NOT TAUGHT <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> SCHOOLS AND GENERALLY <Organization>RELATED</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECTS</Organization> ARE SPLIT
UP TOO MUCH. MANY LECTURERS PLACE TOO MUCH EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>FORMAL</Organization> LECTURES&apos; MANY
STUDENTS ARE UNINTERESTED IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> STUDIES. <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES MUST DEVELOP
STUDENTS&apos; CRITICAL FACULTIES, ENCOURAGE CREATIVITY AND PROMOTE ACTIVE
<Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> WITH <Organization>READERS</Organization> AND COOPERATION WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> INSTITUTIONS; <Organization>BETTER</Organization>
ORGANISATION AND MORE UNIFICATION AMONG <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS ARE REQUIRED.
********************************************
Document 2543
STUDENTS CRITICISE THE SITUATION CONCERNING <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> STUTTGART <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOL.
     
REPORT OF DISCUSSION <Organization>AT</Organization> A WEEKEND SEMINAR, <Location>STUTTGART</Location>, JAN 81. MANY STUDENTS
<Organization>HAVE FINANCIAL</Organization> PROBLEMS AND DIFFICULTIES IN FINDING ACCOMMODATION <Organization>BUT</Organization>,
COMPARED WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COURSES, <Organization>FEW</Organization> DROP <Organization>OUT</Organization> AND STUDENT-STAFF <Organization>RELATIONSHIPS</Organization> ARE
<Organization>GOOD</Organization>. LIBRARIANSHIP STUDIES SHOULD DEVELOP CRITICAL FACULTIES AND THE ABILITY
TO MAKE CONTACT WITH <Organization>READERS</Organization>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MUST BECOME A <Organization>COMMUNICATION CENTRE</Organization>,
UP TO DATE AND OPEN TO OUTSIDE INFLUENCES. <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> NEEDS SHOULD BE EMPHASISED
RATHER THAN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> STANDARDISATION. LIBRARIANSHIP COURSES SHOULD CONTAIN NEW
FIELDS OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization>, LIKE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>. <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>FORMAL</Organization> LECTURES
SHOULD BE <Organization>REPLACED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>SMALL</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> GROUPS, EXAMINATION PROCEDURES SHOULD BE
<Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> AND <Organization>BETTER</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> MADE OF PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PERIODS.
********************************************
Document 2544
AN EXPERIMENT IN M LIB SC TEACHING.
     
PRESENTS AN ANALYTICAL VIEW OF THE M LIB SC COURSE WHICH IS BEING OFFERED <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>BOMBAY UNIVERSITY</Organization>. <Organization>COMPARES</Organization> THE COURSE <Organization>CONTENT</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>THIS</Organization>
COURSE WITH THOSE <Organization>AT DELHI UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>BENARAS</Organization> <Organization>HINDU UNIVERSITY</Organization>. ANALYSES
IN DETAIL THE METHOD OF TEACHING, EXAMINATION PATTERN AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>RELATED</Organization>
ASPECTS OF <Organization>BOMBAY UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>COMPARES</Organization> THEM WITH THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> UNIVERSITIES
OFFERING M LIB SC COURSES. CONCLUDES THAT THE <Organization>BOMBAY UNIVERSITY</Organization> COURSE HAS
STARTED A <Organization>NEW</Organization> EXPERIMENT WHERE REGULAR CLASSES ARE NOT REQUIRED AND NO
FULL-TIME TEACHERS ARE <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2545
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE EXTENSION <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
     
SUMMARISES THE <Organization>OPPORTUNITIES</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FOR EXTENSION <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN
<Location>HUNGARY</Location> SINCE 1963. APART <Organization>FROM</Organization> LECTURES AND COURSES, EXTENSION <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> MAY
ALSO TAKE THE FORM OF <Organization>STUDY TOURS</Organization>, THESES FOR DOCTORATES AND INDIVIDUAL
STUDIES FOR THE <Organization>COMPLEMENTARY COLLEGE</Organization>-LEVEL <Organization>STATE</Organization> EXAMINATIONS. DESCRIBES THE
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> ORGANISATIONS AND THE CONTRIBUTION <Organization>THEY</Organization> MAKE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD&apos;
THE CENTRE FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE AND METHODOLOGY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> SZECHENYI
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (OSZK KMK); <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND
THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WHICH HELPS THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE
PROFESSION WITH <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> DEBATES AND WITH <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WORK CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> WITHIN
<Organization>ITS</Organization> SECTIONS. PROPOSES THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A UNIFORM SYSTEM OF EXTENSION
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> WITHIN THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND THE OSZK KMK.
********************************************
Document 2546
THE APPLICATION OF KNOWLEDGE GAINED DURING <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
STUDIES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE PHILOSOPHICAL FACULTY OF <Organization>CHARLES UNIVERSITY</Organization> IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
PRACTICE.
     
THE THEORETICAL KNOWLEDGE GAINED DURING STUDIES IN THE 4-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> COURSE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE PHILOSOPHICAL FACULTY OF <Organization>CHARLES UNIVERSITY</Organization> IN
<Location>PRAGUE</Location> IS COMPARED WITH THE AUTHOR&apos;S 20 YEARS PRACTICAL EXPERIENCE OF WORKING
IN AN <Organization>INFORMATION CENTRE</Organization> IN A BRANCH OF THE TEXTILE INDUSTRY. THE DEMANDS
PLACED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE STUDENT FALL <Organization>INTO</Organization> 3 CATEGORIES&apos; KNOWLEDGE OF THE METHODOLOGY AND
<Organization>TECHNIQUES</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK (THE SYLLABUS OF THE <Organization>SUBJECTS</Organization> FORMING THE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CORE IS PRESENTED IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> DETAIL); KNOWLEDGE OF <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> LANGUAGES;
<Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> KNOWLEDGE (<Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> SPECIALISATION). LISTS THE AREAS IN WHICH <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THEORY HAS HELPED IN PRACTICAL WORK.
********************************************
Document 2547
WHEN THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> WANTS TO ALTER <Organization>ITS</Organization> ROAD-MAP.
     
REACTIONS OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> TO RECENT PROPOSALS (TAKING ACCOUNT OF THE 1976-77
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> ELEVATION TO UNIVERSITY STATUS) FOR A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> IN
THE <Organization>NORWEGIAN STATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>. POINTS COVERED INCLUDE THE PROPOSED 2-<Organization>YEAR</Organization>
<Organization>COMMON</Organization> COURSE, WITH SPECIALISATION IN THE 3<Organization>RD</Organization> <Organization>YEAR</Organization> (GENERALLY APPROVED);
METHODS <Organization>SUBJECTS</Organization> (BIBLIOGRAPHY IS CONSIDERED <Organization>NECESSARY</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> CONSIDER
COMPUTER STUDIES NOWADAYS EQUALLY ESSENTIAL); <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND SOCIETY (THOUGHT
TO MERIT MORE ATTENTION, ESPECIALLY CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, POPULAR <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>,
AND SERVICES TO HANDICAPPED AND IMMIGRANTS); <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE (SHOULD BE
INCLUDED IN 2 OR EVEN 3 YEARS); ADMINISTRATION (CONSIDERED ABSOLUTELY
ESSENTIAL); PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> (SHOULD PROBABLY BE EXTENDED); EVALUATION OF
STUDENTS&apos; WORK (<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> OPINION FAVOURS THE RETENTION OF MARKING TOGETHER WITH
CONTINUOUS EVALUATION); LECTURING <Organization>STAFF</Organization> (<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPERIENCE IS PREFERRED TO
<Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> SPECIALISATION); INTAKE OF STUD ENTS (AS FAR AS <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> SHOULD COVER
THE WHOLE COUNTRY). <Organization>BETTER LIAISON ON EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN SCHOOL</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
PROFESSION IS FELT DESIRABLE, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THERE SEEMS NO <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> DISAGREEMENT <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
THE <Organization>CURRICULUM COMMITTEE</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN THE FIELD.
********************************************
Document 2548
<Organization>THIS</Organization> ONE-SIDED PRAXIS-WORSHIP.
     
A <Organization>NORWEGIAN STATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> STUDENT REBUTS 3 CLAIMS MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> PREVIOUS
WRITERS (<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> SECTION <Organization>ON LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Location>NORWAY</Location>, 2IBID1 46 (8) 1979;
2SEE1 81/60)&apos; (1) THAT LECTURERS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> TOO LITTLE PRACTICAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPERIENCE
(&amp;H HAVE EXTENSIVE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPERIENCE, WHILE THE OTHERS MAINTAIN CONTACT WITH
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PRACTICE); (2) THAT THE COURSE CONTAINS TOO LITTLE PRACTICAL
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> (THE NEW 3-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> THEORETICAL <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> IS A STEP FORWARD. INTERNAL
AND EXTERNAL PRACTICAL WORK, THOUGH STILL <Organization>NECESSARY</Organization>, ARE OF LIMITED VALUE IN A
CONSTANTLY <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEM. THE SCHOOL&apos;S <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> TASK IS TO
EDUCATE <Organization>INDEPENDENT</Organization>, CRITICAL <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WHO <Organization>CAN</Organization> EVALUATE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE IN A
SOCIOLOGICAL PERSPECTIVE AND BE OPEN TO DEVELOPMENT AND CHANGE); AND (3) THAT
INSTRUCTION IS TOO THEORETICAL (<Organization>ON</Organization> THE CONTRARY, THERE IS A TENDENCY TO
OVER-VALUE DILIGENCE AND HARD WORK, VIEWING LIBRARIANSHIP AS A SERVICE
INDUSTRY RATHER THAN A SCHOLARLY DISCIPLINE). A MORE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> /SOCIOLOGICAL-
AND PROJECT-ORIENTED <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> IS NEEDED, CALLING FOR A <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> TYPE OF
COMMITMENT <Organization>FROM</Organization> BOTH STUDENTS AND LECTURERS.
********************************************
Document 2549
BREADTH, SPECIALISATION AND IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
     
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A MEETING OF THE COMMITTEE SET UP TO REVISE THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOL <Organization>ACT</Organization>. BOTH THE COURSES <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> TODAY, THE ONE FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND THE ONE
FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, <Organization>HAVE</Organization> ELEMENTS WHICH SHOULD BE RETAINED IN <Organization>ANY</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
<Organization>COMMON FOUNDATION</Organization> COURSE. <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A COURSE SHOULD <Organization>HAVE</Organization> THE FOLLOWING ELEMENTS&apos;
TRANSFER OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND CULTURE, <Organization>ITS</Organization> PRECONDITIONS, FORMS AND <Organization>AIM</Organization>;
EDUCATION AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>; INTERNAL ORGANISATION AND ADMINISTRATION; AND SKILLS
AND <Organization>TECHNIQUES</Organization>. SPECIALISATION, IF <Organization>ANY</Organization>, COULD TAKE PLACE WITHIN THE INDIVIDUAL
PROJECTS OR SUBSIDIARY COURSES. INCREASE IN THE NUMBER OF IN-SERVICE COURSES
WAS CALLED FOR, FINANCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE REDUCTION IN THE CAPACITY OF THE SCHOOL. THE
MINISTRY OF <Organization>CULTURAL AFFAIRS</Organization> AGREES TO AN <Organization>ORGANISATIONAL DIVISION</Organization> <Organization>INTO</Organization> 2
SECTIONS&apos; FOUNDATION COURSE AND <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> COURSES.
********************************************
Document 2550
TEACHING <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AND PERIODICAL INDEXING <Organization>AT</Organization> LIVERPOOL.
     
DESCRIBES THE METHODS USED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SCHOOL OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
STUDIES <Organization>AT</Organization> LIVERPOOL POLYTECHNIC TO TEACH <Organization>MODERN</Organization> INDEXING <Organization>TECHNIQUES</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS
CHAIN INDEXING, PRECIS, AND THE APPLICATIONS OF THE COMPUTER. GIVES THE SCALE
OF MARKING USED, AND <Organization>INCLUDES</Organization> EXTRACTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> 2 OF THE PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN <Organization>BY</Organization>
STUDENTS&apos; AN INDEX TO VOLUMES 1-8 OF A <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> JOURNAL 2THE
BLACKCOUNTRYMAN; 1AND THE INDEXING OF THE 2NORTH-WESTERN NEWSLETTER, 1A
PERIODICAL PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>NORTH</Organization> <Organization>WESTERN</Organization> BRANCH OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
AND THE <Organization>NORTH WEST DIVISION</Organization> OF THE ASSOCIATION OF ASSISTANT <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
1950 AND 1975.
********************************************
Document 2551
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION OF MUSIC-A QUESTION OF PRIORITIES.
     
DISCUSSES THE TEACHING OF <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP IN THE <Organization>DANISH LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>.
MENTIONS A <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PROTEST LETTER AGAINST THE PROPOSED ABOLITION OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization>
TEACHING. ALTHOUGH ABOLITION IS NOT SUGGESTED IN <Location>DENMARK</Location>, MUCH IN THE LETTER
IS APPLICABLE TO <Organization>DANISH</Organization> CONDITIONS. IT THUS POINTS <Organization>OUT</Organization> THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> NON-COMMERCIAL OBJECTIVES <Organization>CAN</Organization> COUNTERACT THE PREDOMINANCE OF <Organization>LARGE</Organization>
<Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> RECORD COMPANIES. IT ARGUES THAT NOW THAT <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> DEPARTMENTS IN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE BEING REDUCED, <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> SHOULD RECEIVE MORE INSTRUCTION IN
<Organization>MUSIC</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP SO THAT <Organization>THEY</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> MAKE <Organization>BETTER</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE LIMITED RESOURCES.
NOW WHEN THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IS TO BE REVISED, THE OPPORTUNITY SHOULD BE GRASPED TO
GIVE <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> A <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> PRIORITY IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2552
EDUCATION FOR RARE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP&apos; A REEXAMINATION OF TRENDS AND PROBLEMS.
     
EXAMINES THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>CURRICULAR DEVELOPMENT</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS
<Organization>FAVOURING ADVANCED EDUCATION</Organization> FOR ARCHIVAL OR RARE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP. COURSE
OFFERINGS <Organization>AT</Organization> 64 ACCREDITED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS CAPABLE OF SUPPORTING <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR
RARE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP WERE ANALYSED. <Organization>THESE DATA</Organization> ARE COMPARED WITH COMPARABLE
FIGURES FOR <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COURSE OFFERINGS, PLACEMENT <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization>, AND PREVIOUS SURVEY
DATA, GIVING A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PICTURE OF NEGLECT OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2553
THE <Organization>IMPACT</Organization> OF <Organization>LRC CONCEPT ON MEDIA EDUCATION</Organization>.
     
<Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>LEARNING RESOURCES CENTRE</Organization> (<Organization>LRC</Organization>) CONCEPT AND THE
<Organization>INTEGRATED LIBRARY MEDIA EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMME IN THE <Location>USA</Location>; EXAMINES STUDIES
<Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEDIA EDUCATION; PROPOSES A <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> FOR A <Organization>FULLY</Organization>
<Organization>INTEGRATED MEDIA EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMME IN <Location>US</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS; AND DISCUSSES THE
IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> CHANGE.
********************************************
Document 2554
REPORT TO BLR&amp;<Organization>DD</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF FORM DESIGNS FOR CATALOGUE INPUT&apos; A PROJECT
INVOLVING THE HP2645A DISPLAY STATION.
     
DESCRIBES AN INVESTIGATION OF THE <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> OF A HEWLETT PACKARD HP2645A
<Organization>TERMINAL</Organization> IN TEACHING <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>TERMINAL</Organization>&apos;S
EDITING FACILITIES, AND AN INVESTIGATION OF THE VALUE AND USEFULNESS OF
<Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> FORM OVERLAY DESIGNS FOR THE INPUT OF <Organization>MARC CATALOGUING DATA</Organization>. <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization>
FORM DESIGNS ARE COMPARED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE DIFFICULTIES <Organization>EXPERIENCED</Organization> AND
THE ERRORS MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>TEST GROUP</Organization> CONSISTING MAINLY OF STUDENTS OF
LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
Document 2555
INSTRUCTION <Organization>TAPES</Organization> FOR THE HP2645A.
     
THE AIMS OF THE PROJECT TEAM WERE TO INVESTIGATE THE FACILITIES OF THE HP2645A
<Organization>TERMINAL</Organization>, AND TO DEMONSTRATE <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> AS A TEACHING TOOL, PARTICULARLY IN
RELATION TO THE TEACHING OF <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>. TWO TRIAL <Organization>TAPES</Organization> WERE PRODUCED TO RUN
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>TERMINAL</Organization>. ONE WAS A PROGRAMMED <Organization>TEXT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> CHAPTER 21 OF AACR2 (CHOICE OF
MAIN ENTRY), AND THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> WAS AN INTRODUCTION TO MARC <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>. THE REPORT
DESCRIBES THE <Organization>TAPES</Organization> AND THE REACTIONS TO THEM OF A GROUP OF LIBRARIANSHIP
STUDENTS.
********************************************
Document 2556
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>TECHNIQUES</Organization> IN THE TEACHING OF <Organization>ONLINE</Organization> SEARCHING. AN INSTITUTE FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATORS (<Location>SEATTLE</Location>, <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>, MARCH 20-24, 1978). EXHIBITS AND SUMMARIES OF
PRESENTATIONS.
     
<Organization>USING DATA</Organization> BASES OF THE <Organization>DIALOG</Organization> SYSTEM <Organization>NEW</Organization> TEACHING <Organization>TECHNIQUES</Organization> AND <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>
ARE PRESENTED TO AN AUDIENCE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EDUCATORS. INCLUDED ARE SEARCH
DEMONSTRATIONS, TEACHING APPROACHES, SAMPLE EXERCISES AND <Organization>INSTRUCTIONAL</Organization>
PROJECTS, MULTI-DATE BASE SEARCHING METHODS, UTILISATION OF SEARCH AIDS AND
OFF-LINE RESOURCES, THE CONDUCT OF PRESEARCH INTERVIEWS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SEARCH
TACTICS, AND EDUCATIONAL PROGRAMME PLANING. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2557
WITH <Organization>BOOK</Organization> ANALYSES AGAINST MORGAN KANE.
     
THE FINAL SESSION (NOV 79) OF A COMPULSORY COURSE FOR <Organization>NORWEGIAN</Organization> PART-TIME
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> DEALT WITH <Organization>BOOK</Organization> KNOWLEDGE, EVALUATION AND <Organization>SELECTION</Organization>. <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> NOVELS, IT ALSO INCLUDED <Organization>HIGH</Organization> QUALITY AND POPULAR <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>,
INTRODUCING SYSTEMATIC <Organization>BOOK</Organization> ANALYSIS AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> TERMINOLOGY. ASSIGNING
NOVELS TO GENRES WITH THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF SUPPLYING ALTERNATIVES TO SUBSTANDARD
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> (<Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS MORGAN KANE) WAS SEEN AS BEING PARTICULARLY USEFUL. THE
<Organization>ART</Organization> OF SKIMMING <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> A <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AND GRASPING <Organization>ITS</Organization> ESSENTIALS WAS PRACTISED.
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> REVEALED THAT EVALUATIONS OF THE <Organization>SAME</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> DIFFER
WIDELY. AIDS TO <Organization>BOOK</Organization> <Organization>SELECTION</Organization> (ESPECIALLY <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> TO <Organization>RURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WITH
NO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> BOOKSHOP) WERE DISCUSSED. 2 EVENING SESSIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> POETRY WERE <Organization>HELD</Organization>.
STUDENTS RETURNED TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH A NEW INTEREST IN FICTION AND <Organization>GOOD</Organization>
INTENTIONS OF LEADING <Organization>READERS</Organization>, PARTICULARLY TEENAGERS, <Organization>TOWARDS</Organization> BETTER-QUALITY
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2558
<Organization>PARAPROFESSIONAL WORKERS</Organization> IN FOUR FIELDS&apos; A COMPARATIVE <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.
     
<Organization>COMPARES</Organization> THE EDUCATION AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TECHNICIANS WITH
THAT OF PARAPROFESSIONALS IN <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> WORK, MEDICINE, AND ARCHITECTURE.
DISCUSSES THE EMERGENCE OF THE CONCEPT OF PARAPROFESSIONALISM; ROLES OF
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> AND <Organization>PARAPROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS; <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> POLICY AND FUNDING;
ROLE AND TASKS OF PARAPROFESSIONALS; <Organization>MANPOWER</Organization> NEEDS; AND AVAILABILITY AND
LEVEL OF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES. CONCLUDES THAT THE PROPORTION OF PARAPROFESSIONALS
IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> 4 FIELDS IS LIKELY TO INCREASE; REDISTRIBUTION OF TASKS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
PROFESSIONALS AND PARAPROFESSIONALS WILL BE FELT THE MOST SEVERELY IN
LIBRARIANSHIP; AND <Organization>IMPACT</Organization> OF TECHNOLOGY WILL BE SIGNIFICANT IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> 4 FIELDS.
********************************************
Document 2559
<Organization>MISSOURI UNION</Organization> LIST OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUALS ON LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.
     
ANNOTATED BIBLIOGRAPHY OF <Organization>NON-BOOK</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE
REPRESENTING THE HOLDINGS OF 40 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>MISSOURI</Organization>.
REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2560
TEACHING AND <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. A <Organization>REVIEW</Organization> OF <Organization>RELEVANT</Organization>
AIDS PRODUCED IN <Location>GREAT BRITAIN</Location> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SUITABILITY FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
COUNTRIES, PARTICULARLY IN <Organization>EAST</Organization> <Location>AFRICA</Location>.
     
THE QUESTION OF INVESTIGATING THE NATURE AND AVAILABILITY OF <Location>UK</Location>-PRODUCED
TEACHING/<Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENCE AND EVALUATING <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SUITABILITY FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES,
ESPECIALLY <Organization>EAST</Organization> <Location>AFRICA</Location>, HAS BEEN UNDER DISCUSSION SINCE 1978. <Organization>THIS</Organization> REPORT
SURVEYS THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> KINDS OF TEACHING/<Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> AND
DISCUSSES <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SUITABILITY IN THE CLASSROOM AND FOR THE INDIVIDUAL STUDENT.
********************************************
Document 2561
<Organization>USE</Organization> OF MINIS, MICROS AND <Organization>TERMINALS</Organization> IN THE EDUCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS.
     
DISCUSSES THE <Organization>USE</Organization> MADE OF MINIS AND MICROCOMPUTERS WITHIN THE 16 <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOLS TO SUPPLEMENT <Organization>EXISTING COMPUTER</Organization> RESOURCES AND ENABLE MANY STUDENTS TO
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> HANDS <Organization>ON</Organization> ACCESS TO COMPUTER SYSTEMS IN A <Organization>WIDE</Organization> RANGE OF COURSES. ALSO
DISCUSSES THE <Organization>USE</Organization> MADE OF <Organization>TERMINALS</Organization>, <Organization>INTELLIGENT</Organization> AND NON-INTELLIGENT, IN THE
TEACHING OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2562
<Organization>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A PRIMER FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
MANAGERS.
     
LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE EFFECTS OF CHANGES IN COMMUNICATIONS TECHNOLOGY <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
<Organization>CHAPTERS</Organization> INCLUDE&apos; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE TRANSFER OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> F.W. LANCASTER
AND DONALD W. KING; BASICS OF <Organization>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> BRIGITTE L. KENNEY; CABLE
TV AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> LYNNE E. BRADLEY; COMMUNICATIONS SATELLITES <Organization>BY</Organization> RITA G.
LERNER; VIDEOTEXT&apos; IMPLICATIONS AND APPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> KATHLEEN
CRINER; FACSIMILE AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> JOAN MAIER MCKEAN; THE <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> <Organization>IMPACT</Organization> OF
<Organization>OPTICAL DISC TECHNOLOGY</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> CHARLES M. GOLDSTEIN; THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN
THE <Organization>AGE</Organization> OF <Organization>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> F.W. LANCASTER; ROADBLOCKS TO <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> IDEAL
<Organization>INFORMATION TRANSFER SYSTEMS</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> DONALD W. KING; AND A <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
INTRODUCTION TO <Organization>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> DAVID DORMAN. THE FOREWORD IS <Organization>BY</Organization> EFREM
SIGEL.
********************************************
Document 2563
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> IN <Location>BRITAIN</Location>&apos; <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization> AND PROSPECTS.
     
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>REVIEW</Organization> OF WRITINGS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>BRITAIN</Location>, WITH
<Organization>SOME</Organization> COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization>, <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A SURVEY OF
BRITISH <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS</Organization>. APPENDED ARE A REPRINTED
QUESTIONNAIRE, AND A TABLE OF THE EARLIEST <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> UK <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SYSTEMS.
********************************************
Document 2564
<Location>FRANCE</Location> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S VIEW.
     
COMPARED WITH THE <Location>USA</Location>, <Location>UK</Location> AND THE SCANDINAVIAN STATES <Location>FRANCE</Location> HAS AWAKENED <Organization>FROM</Organization>
<Organization>ITS</Organization> DREAM LATE TO TRY TO DEVELOP AN UP-TO-DATE LIBRARIANSHIP. IN RECENT YEARS
DEVELOPMENT HAS BEEN SIGNIFICANT. <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS EVIDENCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE 5-<Organization>STORY CENTRE</Organization>
GEORGES POMPIDOU INAUGURATED IN 1976. IT IS A COMPLEX OF MUSEUM, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
BOOKSHOP, RECORD SHOP, CINEMAS, THEATRE, <Organization>CONCERT</Organization> HALL, I.E. A KIND OF <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
CENTRE. AFTER AN ACCOUNT OF THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE, DESCRIBES THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PARIS MEDICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization>, WHICH HAS 2 PARTS-AN <Organization>OLDER</Organization> AND AN
UP-TO-DATE HOLDING. OBSERVING CRITICALLY, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Location>PARIS</Location> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
UNIVERSITY FALLS BEHIND THE MORE MECHANISED <Location>US</Location> ONES <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF
<Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> UNIVERSITIES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> STILL A <Organization>GREAT</Organization> DEAL OF WORK TO <Organization>DO</Organization> TO REACH
<Organization>THIS</Organization> &apos;MODEST&apos; LEVEL.
********************************************
Document 2565
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES CELEBRATING <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> HERITAGE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> IN <Location>FRANCE</Location>.
     
SURVEY OF THE NUMEROUS DIVERSE ACTIVITIES ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO
MARK THE OCCASION IN 1980. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF EXHIBITIONS, <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
ACTIVITIES, PUBLICATIONS, INVENTORIES AND RESTORATION PROJECTS, AND NOTABLE
ACQUISITIONS, WITH <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROVINCIAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH THE
PRESS TENDS TO IGNORE IN FAVOUR OF <Location>PARIS</Location> EVENTS.
********************************************
Document 2566
THE FIRST IN <Location>RUSSIA</Location>.
     
10<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>CENTURY</Organization> CHRONICLES TELL <Organization>HOW</Organization> MANY RUSSIAN PRINCES ENJOYED BOOK-COLLECTING
AND FOUNDED SCHOOLS. AN 11<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>CENTURY CHRONICLE</Organization> DESCRIBES THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> RUSSIAN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S CREATION, THE YAROSLAV <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, CONTAINING ABOUT 500 VOLUMES. OUR
ANCESTORS READ DEVOTIONAL BOOKS, LIVES OF THE SAINTS, ENCYCLOPAEDIC WORKS, AND
GEOGRAPHY. THE KIEVO-PECHERSKII MONASTERY IN <Location>KIEV</Location> HAD A <Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF
RUSSIAN AND GREEK BOOKS. A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF RYAZAN <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE NIKOLA
CHURCH IN ZARAISK EVIDENCES THE <Organization>WIDE</Organization> DISSEMINATION OF CULTURE. HALF OF <Organization>ALL</Organization>
SURVIVING 11<Organization>TH</Organization> TO 14<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>CENTURY</Organization> RUSSIAN BOOKS COME <Organization>FROM</Organization> NOVGOROD. THE SOFIISKOI
CATHEDRAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN NOVGOROD ATTRACTED MONKS <Organization>FROM</Organization> DISTANT RUSSIAN MONASTERIES
TO TRANSCRIBE THE BOOKS.
********************************************
Document 2567
CHINESE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> DURING AND AFTER THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> REVOLUTION.
     
<Organization>PAPER BASED PRIMARILY ON DATA</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A VISIT IN 1978 TO THE PEOPLE&apos;S
REPUBLIC OF <Location>CHINA</Location>. PROVIDES A BRIEF ACCOUNT OF THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF CHINESE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN CONTEMPORARY <Location>CHINA</Location>, AND ATTEMPTS TO DESCRIBE <Organization>HOW</Organization> <Organization>THEY</Organization> ARE MEETING
THE CHALLENGES OF A CULTURE MOVING AWAY <Organization>FROM</Organization> ANTI-INTELLECTUALISM TO
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> RESEARCHES, AND WHAT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SALIENT PROBLEMS ARE.
THE WORK IS IN 3 MAIN SECTIONS&apos; BEFORE THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> REVOLUTION, 1949-1966; THE
<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> REVOLUTION, 1966-1976; AND AFTER THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> REVOLUTION, 1976-.
********************************************
Document 2568
WHEN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN AGAIN SPOKE HIS MIND.
     
COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ANNUAL REPORT OF THE <Organization>DANISH RESEARCH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
(DANMARKS FORSKNINGSBIBLIOTEKSFORENINGS) GIVEN <Organization>BY</Organization> PALLE BIRKELUND, THE
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN. <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE NOT GIVEN THE <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> IN THE ECONOMIC CRISIS WHICH <Organization>THEY</Organization> RECEIVE IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>. HE EXPRESSED
FEARS THAT THE PROPOSED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>, FAR <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>CREATING</Organization> UNITY WITHIN THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, <Organization>WOULD</Organization> EMPHASISE THE DIVISION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> UNDER
THE <Organization>CULTURAL MINISTRY</Organization> AND THOSE UNDER THE EDUCATION MINISTRY. HE HOPED THAT
THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> MINISTER <Organization>WOULD</Organization> NOT BE UNDULY INFLUENCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION WHEN FORMULATING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
INSTEAD OF ATTACKING THEM FOR LACK OF OPENNESS TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> THE MINISTER
SHOULD SEE THAT ECONOMIC BARRIERS TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ACTIVITIES ARE REMOVED.
********************************************
Document 2569
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND BOTANICAL GARDENS.
     
SUGGESTS THAT BOTANICAL GARDENS SHOULD BE DIVIDED <Organization>INTO</Organization> 3 PARTS&apos; THE LIVING
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, THE DRIED <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> DESCRIBES THE
STERLING MORTON LIBRARY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE MORTON ARBORETUM, <Location>CHICAGO</Location> AND DEPLORES THE
BREAKING UP AND SELLING OFF OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> BOTANICAL GARDENS IN <Location>EUROPE</Location> AND <Location>NEW
YORK</Location>. ALSO STRESSES THAT A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS MORE THAN A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF BOOKS-IT IS A
<Organization>SELECTION</Organization> FOR A PURPOSE, CHOSEN WITH CARE AND SHOULD NOT BE <Organization>COMPLETELY</Organization>
<Organization>REPLACED BY ELECTRONIC MEDIA</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2570
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 4<Organization>TH</Organization> WORLD CONFERENCE OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, <Location>BELGRADE</Location>, 2-5
SEPTEMBER 80.
     
THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF THE <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> WAS TO <Organization>REVIEW</Organization> CHANGES IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP SINCE
THE <Location>AMSTERDAM</Location> <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> IN 1969, AND TO ANALYSE THE VARIEGATED PROBLEMS OF
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SYSTEMS.
********************************************
Document 2571
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP IN BIHAR. A CHALLENGE TO THE PROFESSION.
     
DESCRIBES THE ROLE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>MEDICAL EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND PRESENTS
A VIEW OF THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN BIHAR AND THE WORKING
CONDITIONS OF THE PROFESSIONALS ENGAGED THERE. STRESSES THE NEED FOR
REORGANISATION OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH <Organization>IMPROVED TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization>. SUGGESTS
THAT <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD <Organization>USE</Organization> THE FACILITIES <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE WORLD HEALTH
ORGANISATION, THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>DELHI</Location> AND THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
OF MEDICINE IN <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>.
********************************************
Document 2572
A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR OF <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>GERMANY</Location> DURING SEPTEMBER 1979. PART 1.
     
THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> PART OF A 2-PART ARTICLE REPORTING THE AUTHOR&apos;S VISIT TO <Organization>WEST</Organization> <Organization>GERMAN</Organization>
<Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (PART 2 IS TO BE PUBLISHED IN THE NEXT ISSUE). CONCENTRATES <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE KUNSTBIBLIOTHEK AND THE MUSEUMSBIBLIOTHEK DER STAATLICHEN MUSEEN
PREUSSISCHER KULTURBESITZ IN <Location>BERLIN</Location>, THE BIBLIOTHEK DES GERMANISCHEN
NATIONALMUSEUM, <Location>NUREMBERG</Location>, AND THE KUNST- UND MUSEUMSBIBLIOTHEK DER STADT
KOLN, <Location>COLOGNE</Location>. DESCRIBES THE SCOPE AND ORGANISATION OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
DISCUSSES <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> TOPICS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS THE EXCHANGE OF PUBLICATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> MUSEUMS
AND INTERLIBRARY COOPERATION.
********************************************
Document 2573
THEATRE LIBRARIANSHIP. <Organization>OCCASIONAL</Organization> PUBLICATION SERIES NUMBER TEN.
     
DEVELOPED TO SHED LIGHT <Organization>ON</Organization> UK THEATRE LIBRARIANSHIP, <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> DEFINES
THEATRE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ILLUSTRATES THE KIND OF WORK CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> IN THEATRE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND COLLECTIONS, <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> FUNCTIONAL PROBLEM AREAS, AND ADVOCATES
<Organization>BETTER</Organization> ORGANISATION, FINANCING, AND STAFFING FOR <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>UNIQUE</Organization> INSTITUTIONS.
REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 2574
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE HOUSE OF COMMONS.
     
A BRIEF ACCOUNT OF THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization>, DEVELOPMENT, CONTENTS, AND SERVICES OF THE <Location>UK</Location>
HOUSE OF COMMONS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND DISCUSSION OF THE DISTINCTIVE QUALITIES OF
LIBRARIANSHIP FOR LEGISLATURES.
********************************************
Document 2575
THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1975 TO 1981.
     
A SURVEY OF THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE&apos;S MAIN ACTIVITIES SINCE REORGANISATION
IN 1975 SHOWING <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization> TO DATE IN CARRYING <Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> FUNCTIONS. COVERS
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> REORGANISATION TO MEET <Organization>NEW</Organization> RESPONSIBILITIES; BUDGETING AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization>;
REALLOCATION AND RESTORATION OF BUILDINGS TO HOUSE <Organization>INCREASED HOLDINGS</Organization>, WITH
DETAILS OF PROVINCIAL VENTURES; ENRICHMENT OF COLLECTIONS, WITH DETAILS OF
RECENT DONATIONS AND PURCHASES; CONSERVATION ACTIVITIES AND PROJECTS; INDEXING
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK IN RELATION TO CATALOGUES; <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PUBLICITY AND
EXHIBITIONS, WITH DETAILS OF PUBLICATIONS AND TEMPORARY AND <Organization>PERMANENT</Organization>
DISPLAYS; <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WORK IN <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization>; AND COOPERATION WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
FINALLY DISCUSSES ADMINISTRATIVE AND FINANCIAL OBSTACLES INHIBITING A <Organization>FULLER</Organization>
REALISATION OF THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE&apos;S ROLE.
********************************************
Document 2576
A GLANCE ACROSS THE RHINE&apos; THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
THE 76 <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, COMPARABLE WITH THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CENTRES, ARE ADMINISTERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE MINISTRY OF CULTURE AND
<Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>. EACH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONTAINS A GARAGE FOR THE <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
STORES, OFFICES AND MULTI-PURPOSE ROOMS FOR COMMITTEE MEETINGS, CONFERENCES
AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SESSIONS. <Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> STOCKS AVERAGING 300,000 VOLUMES LEAD
TO SPACE SHORTAGES. <Organization>STAFF</Organization> INCLUDE BOTH <Organization>STATE</Organization> EMPLOYEES AND VOLUNTEERS. HELP
FOR CULTURALLY UNDERPRIVILEGED AREAS IS <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization>&apos; <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> LOAN TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; DEPOSIT LOAN IN FACTORIES, SCHOOLS, YOUTH CLUBS,
HOLIDAY RESORTS AND <Organization>OLD</Organization> PEOPLE&apos;S HOMES; ORGANISATION OF BOOK-ORIENTED
ACTIVITIES. THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; WORK REFLECTS THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> TENDENCY
TOWARD DECENTRALISATION.
********************************************
Document 2577
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS THE DEPENDENT VARIABLE&apos; HISTORICALLY ORIENTED THEORIES
AND HYPOTHESES OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.
     
IDENTIFIES THOSE WRITINGS IN THE AREA OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> ATTEMPTED
TO <Organization>STATE</Organization> THEORETICALLY ORIENTED GENERALISATIONS ABOUT THE DEVELOPMENT OF
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; ASSESSES THE EXTENT TO WHICH <Organization>THESE</Organization> THEORIES CONFORM TO THE
TYPES OF THEORIES USED IN THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>; AND DETERMINES THE EXTENT TO
WHICH <Organization>THESE</Organization> THEORIES OR GENERALISATIONS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN SUPPORTED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>EMPIRICAL</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> GEOGRAPHICAL FOCUS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Location>US</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
ATTENTION IS ALSO PAID TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>WESTERN
EUROPE</Location>.
********************************************
Document 2578
THE PEOPLE WANT <Organization>PAP</Organization>, OR IDEAS FOR AN ALTERNATIVE FORM OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK.
     
A YOUNG LIBRARIAN CHALLENGES HIS COLLEAGUES TO QUESTION THE ATTITUDE THAT <Organization>THEY</Organization>
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>TOWARDS</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK UNTIL NOW. <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> IN A
BLIND ALLEY. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> FORGOTTEN THAT BOOKS ARE NOT SIMPLY THE SOURCES
OF CERTAIN IDEAS&apos; <Organization>THEY</Organization> ARE ALSO GOODS <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> TO THE LAWS OF MARKETING, HENCE
