Document 5501
LESSING&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> POST IN WOLFENBUTTEL. PART I.

GOTTHOLD EPHRAIM LESSING WAS LIBRARIAN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE COURT OF <Location>BRUNSWICK</Location> AND LUNEBERG
IN THE 1770S. SOME OF HIS MOST IMPORTANT WRITINGS WERE PRODUCED DURING THIS
PERIOD BUT IT SHOULD NOT BE THOUGHT THAT THE POST WAS A SINECURE HELD TO
ENABLE HIM TO WRITE. THERE IS PROOF IN HIS OWN WORKS THAT HE TOOK
LIBRARIANSHIP SERIOUSLY. THE OPINIONS OF VARIOUS CONTEMPORARY AND MODERN
WRITERS <Organization>ON</Organization> LESSING&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK ARE ANALYSED. MANY OF HIS CONTEMPORARIES
THOUGHT HIM DISORGANISED BUT HIS CATALOGUE OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STOCKS, AMOUNTING TO
ABOUT 100,000 VOLUMES, REMAINED UNFINISHED BECAUSE OF STAFF SHORTAGES AND
ULTIMATELY BECAUSE OF HIS OWN DEATH. SOME PEOPLE REGARD HIM AS THE THEORETICAL
FOUNDER OF MODERN LENDING LIBRARIES.
********************************************
Document 5502
IN MEMORIAM. PAUL POINDRON (1912-1980).

HOMAGE DELIVERED <Organization>AT</Organization> A MEETING OF THE <Organization>FRENCH LIBRARIANS ASSOCIATION</Organization> BY A
<Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> FRIEND AND COLLEAGUE OF POINDRON, WHO FOR 45 YEARS ACTIVELY ADVANCED
THE INTERESTS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN <Location>FRANCE</Location> AND CREATED IMPORTANT CONTACTS
<Organization>THROUGH</Organization> HIS WORK <Organization>ON INTERNATIONAL</Organization> COMMITTEES. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF HIS CAREER
IN THE DIRECTORATE OF LIBRARIES AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> READING, IN RELATION TO HIS
PROMOTION OF REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INTERESTS. THE AUTHOR DESCRIBES HIS OWN <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
UNDER POINDRON, AND EMPHASISES HIS <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> QUALITIES.
********************************************
Document 5503
<Organization>GERMAN LIBRARY INSTITUTE</Organization>. PROJECTS FOR 1982.

17 PROJECTS ARE LISTED WHICH WERE BEGUN IN 1981 AND WILL BE CONTINUED IN 1982.
<Organization>NEW</Organization> PROJECTS FOR THE CURRENT YEAR ARE BRIEFLY OUTLINED AND INCLUDE
<Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> LOANS OF SHEET MUSIC, STANDARD LIST OF KEYWORDS FOR SUBJECT
CATALOGUES, STUDY <Organization>COURSES</Organization> FOR SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, STANDARD FUNCTIONAL
DESCRIPTION FOR MIDDLE-TIER LIBRARIES, A DOCUMENTARY <Organization>FILM</Organization> ENTITLED &apos;<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES TO THE SICK&apos;, AN EXHIBITION ABOUT <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> LIBRARIES AND AN
INVESTIGATION OF PRECIS (PRESERVED CONTEXT INDEXING SYSTEM).
********************************************
Document 5504
ANTI-INTELLECTUALISM IN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> LIBRARIES.

THE PLACE OF THE INTELLECTUAL IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION IS EXAMINED IN THE
LIGHT OF ANTI-INTELLECTUALIST PREJUDICE WHICH EXISTS WITHIN THE PROFESSION IN
THE <Location>USA</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5505
SOME CONSIDERATIONS ABOUT THE EPISTEMOLOGICAL SITUATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.

A POSTGRADUATE PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT UFMG LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>, EXAMINING THE
VALIDITY OF THE SCIENTIFIC STATUS CLAIMED FOR LIBRARIANSHIP. THE DISTINCTION
BETWEEN <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY IS CLARIFIED, AND RECENT THEORETICAL STUDIES <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> ADDUCED AS EVIDENCE THAT ALTHOUGH IN THEORY LIBRARIANSHIP IS
SCIENTIFIC IN CHARACTER, IN PRACTICE IT IS RATHER A TECHNOLOGY. IN CONCLUSION
THE NON-SCIENTIFIC CHARACTERISTICS OF LIBRARIANSHIP ARE ANALYSED AND A
PROGRAMME PRESENTED FOR ACHIEVING A PROPER SCIENTIFIC BASIS.
********************************************
Document 5506
THE 1980&apos;S&apos; SOME THOUGHTS <Organization>ON</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS IN <Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>.

TEXT OF THE CHAIRMAN&apos;S ADDRESS TO THE ANNUAL <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> MEETING OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION, NORTHERN <Location>IRELAND</Location> BRANCH, JAN 81. DISCUSSES THE CHANGES SOON TO
TAKE PLACE IN THE EDUCATION AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, AND HIGHLIGHTS THE
IMPORTANCE, TO THOSE ALREADY QUALIFIED, OF THE <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> REFINEMENT AND
DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> SKILLS. SURVEYS BRIEFLY THE FACILITIES FOR
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> AVAILABLE TO IRISH <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, AND SUGGESTS SOME <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
POSSIBILITIES, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>&apos; SABBATICAL LEAVE; SECONDMENT TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS; AND
CLOSER COOPERATION BETWEEN PRACTISING LIBRARIES AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS.
********************************************
Document 5507
REPORT OF THE FOURTH CONGRESS OF COORDINATORS OF POSTGRADUATE <Organization>COURSES</Organization> IN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.

THE CONGRESS, HELD IN NOV 80, WAS ATTENDED BY REPRESENTATIVES OF <Location>BRAZIL</Location>&apos;S 5
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS. PAPERS WERE PRESENTED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>; SPECIALIST
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization>; SELECTION OF DISSERTATION TOPICS; AND MAXIMISATION OF STUDENT
LEARNING OPPORTUNITIES. THE TEXTS ARE GIVEN IN FULL, WITH SUMMARY OF THE MAIN
DISCUSSION POINTS. <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> IS MADE TO THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> SCHEDULED ACTIVITIES&apos;
PRESENTATIONS OF COURSE PLANS, AND DISCUSSIONS WITH GOVERNMENT FINANCE
AGENCIES. THE REPORT CONCLUDES WITH COMMENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
EDUCATION <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> IN <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5508
AGRICULTURAL LIBRARIANSHIP AND DOCUMENTATION AS A PROFESSION.

TRANSLATION OF A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A CONGRESS OF THE IAALD IN <Location>MANILA</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1980,
GIVING A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> VIEW OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES IN THE AGRICULTURAL
FIELD IN RELATION TO LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> FIELDS. A
PRELIMINARY DEFINITION SETS OUT THE NATURE OF THE WORK OF THE AGRICULTURAL
LIBRARIAN, AND THEN THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS OF THE FIELD ARE DISCUSSED IN
DETAIL&apos; <Organization>ITS</Organization> INTERDISCIPLINARY NATURE, THE WIDE RANGE OF TYPES OF
DOCUMENTATION, <Organization>ITS INTERNATIONAL</Organization> CHARACTER, AND THE NEED TO DISSEMINATE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO A <Organization>DIVERSE COMMUNITY</Organization> REPRESENTING A WIDE VARIETY OF <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
BACKGROUNDS. THE ORGANISATION AND OPERATION OF <Organization>EXISTING SERVICES</Organization> ARE EXAMINED
WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RESOURCES AND COOPERATIVE ACTIVITIES, WHERE THE
EXTENT TO WHICH NETWORK OPPORTUNITIES ARE USED DEPENDS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SCALE AND FOCUS
OF SERVICES OFFERED, AND THIS IN TURN INFLUENCES <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> DUTIES. THE
EDUCATION AND SKILLS ESSENTIAL FOR THE P ROFESSIONAL ARE ANALYSED IN RELATION
TO THE CHANGES IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> CAUSED BY SOCIAL
AND <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS, WHICH HAVE CREATED A NEED FOR ALTERATIONS IN
<Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> CURRICULA AND THE ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> OF <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization>
EDUCATION FOR PRACTISING <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. FINALLY POTENTIAL DEVELOPMENTS TO MEET
THE DEMANDS OF THE FUTURE ARE CONSIDERED.
********************************************
Document 5509
LIBRARIANSHIP, PROFESSIONALISM &amp; SOCIAL CHANGE.T

HE LIKELY EFFECTS OF THE EMERGENCE OF A <Organization>POST-INDUSTRIAL SOCIETY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FUTURE
OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION ARE DISCUSSED IN THE LIGHT OF RECENT LITERATURE.
********************************************
Document 5510
LIBRARIES AND CENSORSHIP.

TRANSLATION OF A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A 1979 BRAZILIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
CONFERENCE DESCRIBING THE PRESENT SITUATION IN THE <Location>USA</Location>, WHERE ALTHOUGH <Organization>STATE</Organization>
CENSORSHIP OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS IS MINIMAL, THE SUBJECT IS 1 OF GREAT
IMPORTANCE TO PRACTISING <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS. THE ACTIVITIES OF
THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN ESTABLISHING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND READER RIGHTS TO
FREEDOM <Organization>FROM</Organization> INTERVENTION ARE DESCRIBED WITH <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE 1948
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL OF RIGHTS AND THE MCCARTHY PERIOD. IN CONCLUSION, <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> IS
MADE TO THE SITUATION IN <Location>BRAZIL</Location>, WHERE THE OFFICIAL CENSORSHIP HAS CHANGED,
AND BRAZILIAN <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WARNED TO GUARD AGAINST ANY ENCROACHMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
FREEDOM.
********************************************
Document 5511
THE NECESSITY FOR A <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ETHIC.

CONSIDERS THE RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE LIBRARIAN AS CUSTODIAN OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
REFERS TO THE <Location>US</Location> AND CANADIAN CODES OF PRACTICE, AND REVIEWS THE SITUATION IN
<Location>FRANCE</Location>, IN RELATION TO THE NECESSITY FOR ESTABLISHING AN INTERNATIONAL ETHIC.
A <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> CHARTER SHOULD COVER THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> TOPICS&apos; FREE CIRCULATION OF
KNOWLEDGE AND CENSORSHIP; THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S RESPONSIBILITIES, HIS RIGHT TO MAKE
MISTAKES, AND THE NOTION OF SERVICE; THE ETHICAL AND HUMAN IMPLICATIONS OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TECHNIQUES; AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> OF THE FUTURE. <Organization>EACH</Organization> POINT
IS BRIEFLY DISCUSSED, AND THE DIGNITY OF LIBRARIANSHIP AS A PROFESSION
EMPHASISED.
********************************************
Document 5512
HILBERT TRANSFORMATIONS FOR COMMUNICATIONS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THEORY. JANUARY,
1976-DECEMBER, 1981 (CITATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> FOR
THE PHYSICS AND ENGINEERING <Organization>COMMUNITIES DATA</Organization> BASE).

THIS BIBLIOGRAPHY CITES REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DERIVATION AND APPLICATIONS OF HILBERT
TRANSFORMATIONS IN COMMUNICATIONS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THEORY. A <Organization>FEW</Organization> REPORTS REFER
TO APPLICATIONS TO MEDICAL DIAGNOSTICS AND INDUSTRIAL ULTRASONIC DETECTION FOR
MATERIAL TESTING.
********************************************
Document 5513
THE WRITTEN WORD AND THE DOCUMENT&apos; CONTRADICTORY AND COMPLEMENTARY DIALECTICS.

TRANSLATION <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE ORIGINAL <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>. USING A METHODOLOGICAL FRAMEWORK DERIVED
<Organization>FROM</Organization> RECENT <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN BIBLIOLOGY AND DOCUMENTOLOGY, THE DIALECTICS OF
THE WRITTEN WORD AND THE DOCUMENT ARE ANALYSED SEQUENTIALLY, BY COMPARING AND
CONTRASTING THE PROPERTIES OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> IN RELATION TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ESSENTIAL
CHARACTERISTICS; <Organization>HOW</Organization> THEY FUNCTION WITHIN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESPECTIVE COMMUNICATION
CIRCUITS; MARXIST SOCIOLOGICAL THEORY; AND THE HISTORICAL PERSPECTIVE. <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THIS STRUCTURAL ANALYSIS OF THE 2 ENTITIES A SCIENTIFIC SYNTHESIS IS EFFECTED
DELIMITING THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN BIBLIOLOGY AND DOCUMENTOLOGY, AND THE
APPLICATIONS OF THIS THEORY IN THE TEACHING FIELD EXAMINED. THE ANALYTICAL
MODEL EMPLOYED, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> METHOD OF CONSTRUCTION, IS ADVANCED AS A <Organization>WORKING</Organization>
HYPOTHESIS FOR <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> CRITICISM, <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, AND MODIFICATION.
********************************************
Document 5514
THE COOKED AND THE <Organization>RAW</Organization>.

THE NOTION OF DATA AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> BEING DIFFERENT IN KIND IS BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
THESIS THAT THERE EXISTS <Organization>RAW</Organization> FACTS WHICH CONSTITUTE THE DATA THAT FORM THE
BASIS FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND ULTIMATELY, KNOWLEDGE. PRESENTS A NUMBER OF
ARGUMENTS TO SHOW THE FLAWS IN THIS, FOUNDATIONALIST, THEORY. PRESENTS
COMMENTS BY J. FARRADANE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE MAIN PAPER.
********************************************
Document 5515
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FEATURE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FUTURE OF ASSOCIATIONS).F

OR ABSTRACTS OF ARTICLES IN THIS <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FEATURE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FUTURE OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos;
ASSOCIATIONS, 2SEE1 THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> SERIAL NUMBERS&apos;-.
********************************************
Document 5516
ALA PERSPECTIVES FOR 1981-1982.

DISCUSSES WAYS IN WHICH THE <Organization>ALA COULD EXPAND ITS SERVICES</Organization> TO ENABLE MORE OF
<Organization>ITS</Organization> MEMBERS TO PARTICIPATE IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> ACTIVITIES. SUGGESTIONS INCLUDE&apos; ORGANISING
POSTER SESSIONS AND SLIDE PRESENTATIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> MEETINGS AND CONFERENCES; ENLARGING
THE MEMBERSHIP OF COMMITTEES; THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>
CENTRE AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRE; THE EVALUATION OF <Organization>ALL SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>;
AND THE DRAWING UP OF EMPLOYMENT GUIDELINES. ALSO NOTES THE WORK BEING DONE BY
THE ALA AS PART OF THE INTERNATIONAL YEAR OF THE DISABLED, AND THE EFFORTS IT
IS MAKING TO INCREASE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AWARENESS OF THE SERVICES OFFERED BY LIBRARIES.
********************************************
Document 5517
ALA IN <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>&apos; COUNCILOR&apos;S REPORT.

REPORT OF THE COUNCIL SESSION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ALA ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>,
1981, PRESENTING A <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> VIEW OF COUNCIL&apos;S &apos;OPERATING AGREEMENT BETWEEN ALA
AND DIVISIONS&apos;, CURRENTLY UNDER REVISION. <Organization>NEW</Organization> BY-LAWS WHICH SET STUDENT DUES
IN DIVISIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> $5.00 AND AUTHORISE DIVISIONS TO SET UP <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> CONFERENCES
GENERATED STRONG SUPPORT. THIS LATTER DECISION REFLECTS THE IMPOSSIBILITY OF
JOINING DIVISIONS AND ROUND TABLES OF PERIPHERAL INTEREST, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
QUESTIONABLE WHETHER THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> OR REGIONAL CONFERENCES WILL HURT <Organization>STATE</Organization>
CONFERENCES IN TERMS OF ATTENDANCE AND EXHIBITORS.
********************************************
Document 5518
E PLURIBUS UNUM-OR NOT?.

CONTRIBUTION TO A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FEATURE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FUTURE OF ASSOCIATIONS. IN THE LAST
YEAR THERE HAS BEEN MUCH CONCERN OVER &apos;TROUBLE&apos; <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Location>ASSOCIATION HQ</Location>. ALA DIVISIONS SEEK GREATER PARTICIPATION IN THE CONDUCT OF
<Organization>THEIR OWN FINANCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> AFFAIRS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE RIGHT TO DETERMINE
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN DUES STRUCTURES AND POLICIES, THE RIGHT TO LARGER ALLOCATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization>
ALA&apos;S <Organization>GENERAL FUND</Organization>, AND THE RIGHT TO MORE PARTICIPATION IN THE SELECTION OF
THE PERSON HIRED TO REPRESENT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INTERESTS <Organization>AT</Organization> ALA HQ. A PROPOSED &apos;OPERATING
AGREEMENT FOR ALA AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> DIVISIONS&apos; ADDRESSES MANY OF THESE CONCERNS, AND IS
THE PRODUCT OF DISCUSSIONS BETWEEN ALA HQ STAFF AND DIVISIONAL OFFICERS.
********************************************
Document 5519
ALA&apos; CLA TIES THAT BIND, BUT DON&apos;T CHAFE.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION ANNUAL CONFERENCE, JUNE 81. EXAMINES THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE
<Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, AND PLACES
IT IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> HISTORICAL PERSPECTIVE. NOTES THE UNPARALLELED GROWTH OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
AND CANADIAN LIBRARIES IN THE 1960S, AND IDENTIFIES THE CHALLENGES WHICH THEY
FACE IN THE 1980S. LIBRARIES IN BOTH COUNTRIES ARE SEEN AS HAVING TO DEAL WITH
THE PROBLEMS CAUSED BY INCREASED COSTS FOR LABOUR AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIALS,
COUPLED WITH AN <Organization>ALL</Organization> OVER DECLINE IN FUNDING, AND COMPETITION <Organization>FROM</Organization> NEW
<Organization>INFORMATION AGENCIES</Organization>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> SUPERMARKETS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> OUTLETS FOR COMMERCIAL
READING, AND <Organization>FROM</Organization> VIEWING AND LISTENING MATERIALS. DISCUSSES THE LINK BETWEEN
<Location>US</Location> AND CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>, AND INDICATES THE POSSIBLE NEED FOR A
CHANGE IN THIS RELATIONSHIP.
********************************************
Document 5520
THE ALA/ACRL RELATIONSHIP.

CONTRIBUTION TO A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FEATURE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FUTURE OF ASSOCIATIONS. DISCUSSES THE
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND THE ASSOCIATION OF
COLLEGE AND <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> LIBRARIES (<Organization>LATER</Organization>, ASSOCIATION OF COLLEGE AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
LIBRARIES). ACRL CAME INTO EXISTENCE AS A RESPONSE TO THE SEPARATE <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> OF
<Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. THE ALA/ACRL RELATIONSHIP HAS BEEN ROCKY OVER THE
YEARS-SOME SEE IT AS AN <Organization>EQUAL PARTNERSHIP</Organization>, OTHERS AS A PARENT/ADOLESCENT CHILD
RELATIONSHIP. A 1981 SUMMIT MEETING IN <Location>CHICAGO</Location> SUGGESTED <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> FUNDAMENTAL
CHANGES IN THE ALA <Organization>AT</Organization> THE HIGHEST LEVEL. THESE SUGGESTIONS ARE INVESTIGATED IN
SOME DETAIL.
********************************************
Document 5521
SUBJECT LIBRARIES IN THE <Location>GERMAN DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC</Location>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AS
EXEMPLIFIED BY <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> LIBRARIES.

THE ASSOCIATIONS&apos; SECTIONS ARE COMPOSED OF SPECIALISED SUBJECT AND <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> LIBRARIES WITH RELEVANT STOCKS IN THE SUBJECT AREA CONCERNED. THEY <Organization>AIM</Organization>
TO DEVELOP COOPERATION, THE OPTIMAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF LITERATURE, EDUCATION AND EXCHANGE
OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> EXPERIENCES. THE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> SECTION IS THE LARGEST, WITH 318
MEMBERS. <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> LIBRARIES STOCK <Organization>MAINLY</Organization> MODERN MATERIAL; <Organization>THEIR</Organization> STAFF MEMBERS
ARE <Organization>FEW</Organization>, <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OPENING HOURS ARE RESTRICTED AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS ARE
OFTEN INACCESSIBLE TO THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>. THEY ARE CLOSELY CONNECTED WITH A
SCIENTIFIC DISCIPLINE AND PROVIDE SPECIFIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES WHICH PLAY
SUBORDINATE ROLES IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> LIBRARIES. THE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SECTION IS
CURRENTLY CONCERNED WITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK IN FACTORY COMBINES,
PROBLEMS OF PATENT LITERATURE AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK IN <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COLLEGES WITHIN
INDUSTRIAL COMPLEXES.
********************************************
Document 5522
CLA/CEMA COOPERATION&apos; MACRO/MICRO PERSPECTIVES AND POSSIBILITIES.

CONTRIBUTION TO A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FEATURE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FUTURE OF ASSOCIATIONS. <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS WITH BROAD INTERESTS ARE LOSING MEMBERSHIP AS SPECIALIST
ASSOCIATIONS GROW, AND IF THE ENTIRETY IS TO HOLD TOGETHER, THERE MUST BE A
STRONG <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FLOW BETWEEN THE CONSTITUENT PARTS. THE COLORADO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION AND COLORADO <Organization>EDUCATIONAL MEDIA ASSOCIATION</Organization> HAVE HAD PAST
DISAGREEMENTS, BUT SHARE MANY COMMON INTERESTS. SUGGESTS 13 AREAS IN WHICH
THEY COULD COOPERATE AND TABULATES DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SIMILARITIES BETWEEN <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
PRESENT ORGANISATIONAL STRUCTURES.
********************************************
Document 5523
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 32ND MEETING OF THE MEMBERS OF THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos; UNION <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>REGENSBURG UNIVERSITY</Organization>, 11 JUNE 81.

THE CHAIRMAN&apos;S ANNUAL REPORT DESCRIBED THE <Organization>EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE</Organization>&apos;S WORK IN
ORGANISING CONFERENCES, PUBLISHING THIS PERIODICAL AND PRODUCING <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization>
AND QUESTIONNAIRES. THERE IS AS YET NO <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> RULING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE LEGAL POSITION
OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN UNIVERSITIES BUT PROGRESS HAS BEEN MADE <Organization>ON</Organization> CHANGING THE
UNIVERSITY LAW IN LOWER SAXONY AND <Organization>ON</Organization> THE POSITION OF SOME <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN HIGH
SERVICE GRADES. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS ALSO INCLUDED <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; THE UNION&apos;S <Organization>STATE</Organization> SECTIONS;
DER DEUTSCHER BIBLIOTHEKSVERBAND (<Organization>GERMAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>); THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONFERENCE; <Organization>IFLA</Organization>; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONFERENCES ABROAD; DISCUSSIONS BETWEEN
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND PUBLISHERS; ADVANCED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SEMINARS; STUDY GROUPS <Organization>ON</Organization>
STAFFING; UNION COMMITTEES; PUBLICATIONS; FINANCE; ELECTION OF <Organization>NEW COMMITTEE</Organization>
MEMBERS; LEGAL MATTERS; SALARIES; AND STAFF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5524
ANNUAL REPORT OF THE ASSOCIATION OF DIPLOMA <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIES
1980-1981.

THE YEAR&apos;S MOST IMPORTANT EVENT WAS THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos; CONFERENCE IN WUPPERTAL,
MAY 80, <Organization>ON</Organization> INTER-LIBRARY COOPERATION, WORK PLACES FOR USERS AND STAFF AND NEW
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TECHNIQUES. THERE IS AS YET NO IMPROVEMENT IN THE SOCIAL POSITION OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, WAGE NEGOTIATIONS HAVING COME TO A TEMPORARY HALT. ANALYSIS OF
QUESTIONNAIRES <Organization>ON</Organization> STAFFING IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIES HAS BEEN COMPLETED. THE
<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONFERENCE WILL CONSIDER THE QUESTION OF COOPERATION BETWEEN
THE DEUTSCHE BIBLIOTHEKSINSTITUT (<Organization>GERMAN LIBRARY INSTITUTE</Organization>) AND THE VARIOUS
LIBRARIANSHIP ORGANISATIONS. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> MET WITH REPRESENTATIVES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
BOOKTRADE TO DISCUSS CHANGES IN COPYRIGHT LAW, THE WORK OF THE DEUTSCHE
BIBLIOTHEK (<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>), ODIN AND THE PUBLICATION OF AGREEMENTS
BETWEEN <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND BOOKSELLERS. MINUTES OF THE MEMBERS&apos; MEETING IN
<Organization>REGENSBURG</Organization>, JUNE 81, ARE INCLUDED.
********************************************
Document 5525
<Organization>WEST VIRGINIA LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> <Organization>EXECUTIVE BOARD</Organization> MEETING.

THE MEETING WAS HELD <Organization>ON</Organization> 12 JUNE 81 <Organization>AT</Organization> CHARLESTON. A REPORT WAS MADE <Organization>ON</Organization>
RECOMMENDATIONS FOR REVISION OF THE <Organization>WEST VIRGINIA LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> BY-LAWS,
AND DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE TREASURER&apos;S REPORT, OF MEMBERSHIP AND COMMITTEES,
AND OF ACTIVITIES WITHIN THE SPHERES OF COLLEGE AND UNIVERSITY, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, SCHOOL
AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITHIN THE ASSOCIATION.
********************************************
Document 5526
<Organization>NEW</Organization> TRENDS IN EDUCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND DOCUMENTALISTS IN THE <Location>FEDERAL
REPUBLIC OF GERMANY</Location>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. HIGHLIGHTS THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> LANDSCAPE IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>.
OUTLINES THE STRUCTURE OF EDUCATION AND THE VARIOUS <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
CAREER &apos;TRACKS&apos; IN RELATIONSHIP TO THE SPECIFIC TASKS IN LIBRARIANSHIP AND
WHICH IN THE PAST RESULTED IN DIFFERENT CURRICULA. DESCRIBES COMBINED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
<Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND DOCUMENTALISTS, <Organization>THEIR</Organization> BACKGROUND, SEQUENCE OF
STUDY, AND CURRICULUM CONTENT, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE PRACTICAL DEMANDS OF THE
PROFESSIONS AND IN COMPARISON WITH EFFORTS FOR SEPARATED <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
IN DOCUMENTATION CENTRES AND LIBRARIES.
********************************************
Document 5527
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Location>INDIA</Location>.

PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ALL-INDIA SEMINAR, UNIVERSITY OF <Location>DELHI</Location>, DEPARTMENT OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>, 3-8 OCT 77.
********************************************
Document 5528
DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN JORDAN.

(MA THESIS). THE <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> MOVEMENT IN JORDAN WAS STUDIED AND
EVALUATED. EXAMINED THE FACTORS AFFECTING THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>
IN JORDAN, WHAT TYPES AND SIZE OF PERSONNEL NEEDED BY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SYSTEM AND <Organization>HOW</Organization> BEST THE <Organization>EXISTING LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> SYSTEM CAN
RESPOND TO EXPRESSED <Organization>NEEDS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5529
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Location>CANADA</Location>.

OUTLINES THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Location>CANADA</Location>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE LATE 1920S. <Location>CANADA</Location> HAS TENDED TO FOLLOW THE <Location>US</Location> PATTERN AND <Organization>ALL</Organization>
CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS STILL SUBMIT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> TO THE <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION FOR ACCREDITATION. HOWEVER ANYONE CAN CALL HIMSELF A &apos;<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
LIBRARIAN&apos; AND LIBRARIES DO NOT HAVE TO HIRE GRADUATES <Organization>FROM</Organization> ACCREDITED
SCHOOLS. MOST <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> RUN FOR 2 YEARS FOR A MASTER&apos;S DEGREE, THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> YEAR
FULL TIME AND THE 2ND PART TIME. SCHOOLS HAVE RECENTLY ORIENTED <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
<Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> AWAY <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN ROUTINE TECHNIQUES AND TOWARDS EDUCATION FOR
PLANNING, ADMINISTRATION, THE SETTING OF STANDARDS, ORGANISING POLITICAL
ACTIVITY FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SUPPORT, DEPLOYMENT OF HUMAN AND MATERIAL RESOURCES,
FUND-RAISING AND <Organization>NEW</Organization> METHODS OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> AND SUBJECT ANALYSIS.
********************************************
Document 5530
THE <Organization>SWEDISH SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND THE EDUCATION OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIES.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
(ABBREVIATED VERSION OF AN ARTICLE PUBLISHED IN 2IATUL PROCEEDINGS1, 1981).
GIVES AN ACCOUNT OF EDUCATION FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>SWEDISH SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (SSLIS) AND PRESENTS BOTH THE CURRENT AND THE REVISED
CURRICULA OF THE SCHOOL. IN THE CONTEXT OF THE REVISED CURRICULUM, DISCUSSES
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> VERSUS SPECIALISED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, PROGRAMME FLEXIBILITY AND THE MARGINS
AVAILABLE FOR THE EDUCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIES. 2SEE ALSO1
82/5537.
********************************************
Document 5531
REDISTRIBUTION ALONE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>&apos;S RESOURCES DOES NOT MAKE A SUMMER.

COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A REPORT OF THE <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>DANISH LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> ISSUED
BY THE GOVERNMENT&apos;S DEPARTMENT OF ADMINISTRATION. THE REPORT EXAMINES
PROPOSALS FOR CHANGES IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> ACT. THE PROPOSALS CONCERN A
COMMON <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, THE NEED FOR POST-GRADUATE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND
THE ORGANISATION AND CONTENT OF <Organization>COURSES</Organization>. FUTURE DEMAND AND SUPPLY OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE ESTIMATED. IT IS PROPOSED TO ESTABLISH A SECTION FOR THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization>
EDUCATION AND ANOTHER FOR THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization>. AN EDUCATION COUNCIL, APPOINTED
BY THE MINISTRY OF CULTURE, WITH REPRESENTATIVES FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> INTERESTED
ORGANISATIONS IS SUGGESTED. <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IS GIVEN <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> PRIORITY, ESPECIALLY THAT
LEADING TO DEVELOPMENT FOR THE FUNDAMENTAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SUBJECTS. THE REPORT
RECOGNISES THE DEVELOPMENT WITHIN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND DOCUMENTATION, BUT EXPECTS
THIS TO TAKE PLACE <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> CHANGE IN THE PRIORITIES OF THE SCHOOL&apos;S
EXPENDITURE <Organization>ON</Organization> PRESENT TASKS AND SEES ALLOCATION OF ADDITIONAL RESOURCES AS
POLITICALLY UNREALISTIC.
********************************************
Document 5532
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>AT AHMADU BELLO UNIVERSITY</Organization>, ZARIA.

REVIEW OF CURRENT DEVELOPMENTS IN EDUCATION FOR LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>AT</Organization> AHMADU BELLO
UNIVERSITY, ZARIA, WITH COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE LIKELY FUTURE OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN
<Location>NIGERIA</Location>. THE FUTURE IS SEEN AS VERY BRIGHT, AS THE NUMBER OF <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
ESTABLISHMENT GROWS. <Organization>AT</Organization> PRESENT <Location>NIGERIA</Location> HAS 4 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, BUT THIS NUMBER
COULD GROW TO 12 BY THE YEAR 2000 TO MEET MORE ADEQUATELY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MANPOWER
<Organization>NEEDS</Organization> OF THE COUNTRY.
********************************************
Document 5533
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE 80S&apos; THOUGHTS OF A SERVICE LIBRARIAN.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. <Organization>NEW</Organization> ASPECTS OF LIBRARIANSHIP-CHANGES IN CATALOGUING RULES, IN <Organization>USE</Organization> OF NEW
FORMS OF THE CATALOGUE, THE PROLIFERATION OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> SOURCES, <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
SEARCHING IN <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA</Organization> BASES AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> INNOVATIONS-WILL MAKE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
<Organization>UNIVERSITY OR COLLEGE</Organization> LIBRARIES BY PATRONS MORE DIFFICULT IN THE FUTURE. THE
CRUCIAL PROBLEM FOR SERVICE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IS KEEPING UP WITH THESE ASPECTS
THEMSELVES IN ORDER TO INSTRUCT, INFORM AND ASSIST THE USER. SHARING OF
KNOWLEDGE IS SUGGESTED AS A MEANS FOR INDIVIDUAL <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> TO KEEP UP WITH
<Organization>NEW</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS; SHARING <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> PUBLICATIONS, CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS,
<Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> AND IN-HOUSE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SESSIONS.
********************************************
Document 5534
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>FRENCH LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1976 TO
1980.

A REPORT BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> DIPLOMA DISSERTATION IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> PRESENTED
IN 1980-81, EVALUATING ACTIVITIES INSTITUTED BY THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> GOVERNMENT BODY
RESPONSIBLE FOR <Organization>LIBRARY AFFAIRS</Organization>. THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> IS
DEFINED AND THE RELEVANT LEGISLATION SUMMARISED. A FULL ACCOUNT OF THE
ORGANISATION AND IMPLEMENTATION OF THE PROGRAMME IS GIVEN, COVERING INITIAL
PLANNING; <Organization>COURSES</Organization> OFFERED IN <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> METHODS, MANAGEMENT, <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
SKILLS, <Organization>NEW</Organization> TECHNIQUES, PERSONNEL ALLOCATION, RECRUITMENT, AND DIPLOMA
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization>; AND THE MANAGEMENT OF THE PROGRAMME, WITH DETAILS OF THE
INSTITUTIONS INVOLVED, FINANCIAL RESOURCES AND EXPENDITURE, AND THE
PARTICIPANTS. THE RESULTS OF THE SURVEY PRESENT AN EXHAUSTIVE PICTURE OF <Organization>ALL</Organization>
ASPECTS OF THE PROGRAMME.
********************************************
Document 5535
THE NEW EDUCATION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE COLLEGE OF LIBRARIANSHIP.

DESCRIBES THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> COURSE IN LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>AT</Organization> THE COLLEGE OF LIBRARIANSHIP
WHICH BEGAN IN AUTUMN 81. CITES THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PLAN&apos;S SECTION <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; AIMS, CONTENT
AND ORGANISATION, WHICH STIPULATES THAT THE COURSE IS TO LAST 4 SEMESTERS
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> PRACTICAL AND FIELD WORK, WITH TEACHING TAKING PLACE IN THE LAST 2
SEMESTERS. A <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> PLAN INDICATES THE <Organization>COURSES</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> POINT VALUE. THE
DETAILED COURSE PLANS HAVE STILL TO BE WORKED OUT. IN THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> YEAR, THE
STUDENT STUDIES&apos; SOCIETY AND LIBRARIES, KNOWLEDGE OF LITERATURE, HANDLING AND
DISTRIBUTION OF MEDIA. IN THE 2ND YEAR THE STUDENT HAS A CHOICE BETWEEN&apos;
CULTURE-INFORMATION (KI) AND INFORMATION-DOCUMENTATION (ID). KI INCLUDES
<Organization>COURSES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTOMATION AND SPECIALIST LITERATURE; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION
AND ACTIVITIES; ADMINISTRATION. ID INCLUDES <Organization>COURSES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; LANGUAGE AND THOUGHT
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTOMATION AND DOCUMENTATION; ADMINISTRATION; KNOWLEDGE OF
STOCK. FOR BOTH OPTIONS THERE IS A CHOICE OF STUDI <Organization>ES</Organization> IN DEPTH WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
PROJECTS. PLANNING GROUPS ARE NOW <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> BOTH FOLLOW-ON <Organization>COURSES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, AND BRIDGING <Organization>COURSES</Organization> LEADING TO
QUALIFICATION IN <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5536
THE USER IN LIBRARIANSHIP CURRICULA.

EXTRACT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A POSTGRADUATE DISSERTATION PRESENTED <Organization>AT UFMG LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
<Location>BRAZIL</Location>. WITHIN THE DISCIPLINE OF LIBRARIANSHIP, USER STUDIES ARE AN IMPORTANT
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TOPIC, BUT THERE IS LITTLE SYSTEMATIC STUDY OF USERS IN LIBRARIANSHIP
CURRICULA. TO ESTABLISH <Organization>HOW</Organization> THIS IMPORTANT SUBJECT AREA SHOULD BE TREATED IN
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>, AN ANALYSIS WAS MADE OF THE LITERATURE DEALING WITH
USERS, TO ESTABLISH A THEORETICAL BASIS FOR TEACHING PURPOSES. RESULTS SHOWED
THAT THE PRIMARY FOCUS WAS <Organization>ON</Organization> USER BEHAVIOUR IN RELATION TO SOCIAL AND
CULTURAL FACTORS; <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> AND MOTIVATIONS; AND INTERACTION AND COMMUNICATION IN
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SITUATION. ACCORDINGLY, AN INTERDISCIPLINARY APPROACH, DRAWING <Organization>ON</Organization>,
FOR EXAMPLE, PSYCHOLOGY, ANTHROPOLOGY AND SOCIOLOGY, SHOULD BE ADOPTED.
********************************************
Document 5537
THE <Organization>SWEDISH SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND THE EDUCATION OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIES.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. GIVES AN ACCOUNT OF THE BACKGROUND OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (SSLIS), BORAS. PRESENTS THE CURRENT AND REVISED CURRICULA
<Organization>AT</Organization> THE SCHOOL. IN THE CONTEXT OF THE REVISED CURRICULUM, DISCUSSES <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
VERSUS SPECIALISED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, PROGRAMME FLEXIBILITY AND THE MARGINS AVAILABLE
FOR THE EDUCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIES.
********************************************
Document 5538
<Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.

ATTEMPTS A SYSTEMATIC EVALUATION OF THE PERENNIAL DEBATE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE RATIONALE AND
PRACTICE OF EDUCATION FOR <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization> BY REVIEWING CURRENT ATTITUDES,
PERCEIVED <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> AND THE EXTENT TO WHICH <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> ARE MET BY THE TEACHING
AVAILABLE. CONCLUDES THAT UNSYSTEMATIC APPROACHES TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MANAGEMENT
EDUCATION AND DEVELOPMENT MAY BE ALIENATING SOME POTENTIAL MANAGERS.
********************************************
Document 5539
EDUCATION FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INTERMEDIARIES. AN EXAMPLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE SCHOOL OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> STUDIES, <Organization>SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>N.Y.</Location>

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> A <Organization>SWEDISH AMERICAN FOUNDATION</Organization> SCHOLARSHIP, THE AUTHOR SPENT A
YEAR <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> STUDIES, <Organization>SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>NEW YORK</Location>
<Organization>STATE</Organization>. PRESENTS BRIEFLY <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> IMPRESSIONS OF <Organization>COURSES ON MANAGEMENT</Organization>,
AUTOMATION, <Organization>INFORMATION RETRIEVAL SYSTEMS</Organization>, AND INTERPERSONAL
COMMUNICATIONS/<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TRANSFER. SUGGESTS A NEED FOR MORE EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>COURSES</Organization> IN <Organization>MARKETING INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> AND IN DEFINING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROBLEMS
AND SEARCH QUESTIONS. CONCLUDES THAT SUCH ESTABLISHMENTS SHOULD FOLLOW CLOSELY
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE PROFESSION AND ADAPT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization> ACCORDINGLY.
********************************************
Document 5540
RECENT DEVELOPMENTS IN <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.

OWING TO GOVERNMENT ECONOMY MEASURES THE DOCUMENTALISTS&apos; <Organization>TRAINING SCHOOL</Organization> MUST
CLOSE BY 1893 AND THE PLANNED COURSE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND DOCUMENTATION IN
DARMSTADT MAY NOT AFTER <Organization>ALL</Organization> BEGIN IN 1982, WHICH POSES A REAL THREAT TO <Organization>ALL</Organization>
<Organization>BASIC</Organization> AND ADVANCED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization>. THERE IS STILL DISPUTE OVER THE VALUE OF
INTEGRATED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND DOCUMENTALISTS AND AS TO
WHETHER DOCUMENTALISTS SHOULD HAVE DEGREE STATUS. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS ARE
THE VITAL LINK BETWEEN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PRODUCED BY AN EVER WIDENING
RANGE OF <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> PRODUCTS. A UNIFIED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SYSTEM WITH GOOD PROMOTION
PROSPECTS MUST BE ESTABLISHED WITH DEGREE QUALIFICATIONS FOR THE HIGHEST STAFF
GRADES. THE TRANSITION PERIOD RESULTING AFTER THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A NEW
SYSTEM WILL DEMAND <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AFTER A <Organization>BASIC</Organization> QUALIFICATION HAS BEEN
OBTAINED.
********************************************
Document 5541
TOOLS FOR <Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> CONTROL&apos; A TEACHING EXPERIENCE.

A DESCRIPTION OF THE COURSE OFFERED BY THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCIENCE DEPARTMENT</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF PARANA, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>, SINCE 1976. A BRIEF INTRODUCTION TRACES
THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> CONTROL, DEMONSTRATING <Organization>ITS</Organization>
IMPORTANCE IN LIBRARIANSHIP. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>HOW</Organization> THE SUBJECT IS
INTEGRATED INTO THE WIDER CURRICULUM; THE STRUCTURE AND ORGANISATION OF THE
COURSE; THE ACTUAL CONTENT OF THE 8 COMPONENT UNITS; AND THE TEACHING METHODS
AND MATERIALS USED. FINALLY <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> IS MADE TO SURVEY WORK CONDUCTED TO
MONITOR THE EFFECTS OF INTRODUCING THE SUBJECT, AND <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> EVIDENCE CITED TO
SUPPORT THE CONCLUSION THAT <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE PROFITING <Organization>FROM</Organization> THIS INITIATIVE.
********************************************
Document 5542
EDUCATION FOR <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization>&apos; FIVE CASE STUDIES.

(<Organization>PHD DISSERTATION-PITTSBURGH UNIVERSITY</Organization>). EXAMINES, DESCRIBES AND COMPARES THE
EXPECTATIONS OF PRACTITIONERS AND EMPLOYERS IN THE AREA OF <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization>
AND THE EXTENT OF <Organization>TECHNICAL SERVICES</Organization> AND THE EXTENT TO WHICH 5 UNIDENTIFIED
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> TEACH WHAT EMPLOYERS EXPECT OF BEGINNING
PROFESSIONALS.
********************************************
Document 5543
THE TEACHING OF CATALOGUING AND CLASSIFICATION&apos; A <Organization>FEW</Organization> RANDOM THOUGHTS.

CATALOGUING AND CLASSIFICATION ARE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION, AND THE
KIND AND QUALITY OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> PROVIDED BY LIBRARIES DEPENDS GREATLY
UPON THE QUALITY OF EDUCATION AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
QUESTIONS WHO SHOULD EDUCATE THE CATALOGUERS, SUGGESTING THAT TEACHERS OF
CATALOGUING SHOULD HAVE PRACTICAL EXPERIENCE OF FULL-TIME CATALOGUING.
PRACTICAL EXPERIENCE IS THE BEST WAY TO LEARN CATALOGUING.
********************************************
Document 5544
TEACHING ONLINE SEARCHING IN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS.

REPORT OF A VISIT TO 5 SCHOOLS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location>,
IN MAR 81, TO OBSERVE THE TEACHING OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RETRIEVAL. DISCUSSES
CURRICULUM STRUCTURE, TEACHING METHODS, ASSESSMENT AND SIMULATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5545
EDUCATION FOR WORK IN <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> LIBRARIES.

THEMATIC <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO THE VIEWS OF PRACTISING <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
DIRECTORS, AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOL TEACHERS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> FOR THOSE PLANNING
TO WORK IN UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY LIBRARIES. FOR ABSTRACTS OF THE
CONTRIBUTIONS, 2SEE1 THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> SERIAL NUMBERS&apos;-.
********************************************
Document 5546
IDEAL STAFF FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> LIBRARIES.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE SITUATION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>HELSINKI</Location> (<Location>FINLAND</Location>) UNIVERSITY OF
TECHNOLOGY LIBRARIES, OFFERS A <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> VIEW <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND QUALIFICATIONS OF
STAFF IN SUCH LIBRARIES. EMPHASISES THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN
ENGINEERING, PHYSICS, AND CHEMISTRY; THE NEED FOR KNOWLEDGE OF LANGUAGES; AND
THE NEED FOR EDUCATION IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>. SUGGESTS THE OPTION
OF AN EARLIER RETIREMENT AGE FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STAFF SO THAT <Organization>NEW</Organization> STAFF MEMBERS ARE
AS YOUNG, SERVICE-MINDED, AND NON-BUREAUCRATIC AS POSSIBLE.
********************************************
Document 5547
REPORT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A COURSE FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> TEACHERS&apos; <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COLLEGES.

REPORT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A COURSE FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> TEACHERS&apos; <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COLLEGES, HELD IN
AUG 80 <Organization>AT</Organization> STABEKK. THE MAIN THEMES DISCUSSED WERE DOCUMENT RETRIEVAL, USER
EDUCATION, TEXT <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MEANS OF INSTRUCTION, AND PUBLISHING.
********************************************
Document 5548
EDUCATION FOR WORK IN <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIES IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> FOR THE EDUCATION OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>
SEEM LIKELY TO BE MET BY THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE DEPARTMENT OF LIBRARIANSHIP,
<Organization>VICTORIA UNIVERSITY</Organization> OF <Location>WELLINGTON</Location>, AND THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STUDIES,
<Location>WELLINGTON</Location> TEACHERS&apos; COLLEGE. THERE IS AN 18-WEEK SANDWICH COURSE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
COLLEGE, LEADING TO THE N.Z. <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STUDIES CERTIFICATE, FOR UNTRAINED
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STAFF. THE COUNTRY&apos;S MAIN LACK WOULD SEEM TO BE A PROPERLY
ORGANISED AND <Organization>COORDINATED</Organization> <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMME FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5549
EDUCATION FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP IN THE <Location>UNITED STATES</Location>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE ON EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
WORK. <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>US</Location> PERSPECTIVE, DISCUSSES THE CURRENT <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROFESSION; OUTLINES THE NATURE OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROBLEM;
ADDRESSES THE <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP; DEFINES THIS SUBJECT; DISCUSSES
THE DILEMMA OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> (REFLECTING THE CONFLICT OVER A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S
ROLES); AND COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FUTURE.
********************************************
Document 5550
THE TEACHING PAMPHLETS PRODUCED BY THE STAFF OF THE INSTITUTE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND SCIENTIFIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>HUMBOLDT UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>BERLIN</Location>.

THE PAMPHLET SERIES DEVELOPED SINCE 1970, ORIGINALLY FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> IN <Organization>CORRESPONDENCE</Organization>
<Organization>COURSES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>BASIC</Organization> AND POST-GRADUATE LIBRARIANSHIP, BUT IS NOW USED ALSO IN
CLASSES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>. THE <Organization>HUMBOLDT UNIVERSITY</Organization> COMBINES A <Organization>BASIC</Organization>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR BOTH <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND DOCUMENTALISTS WITH ADDITIONAL SPECIALIST
OPTIONS; THE STRUCTURE OF THE <Organization>BASIC LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> AND <Organization>CORRESPONDENCE</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization>
IS IDENTICAL. THE PAMPHLETS PROVIDE AN INTRODUCTION FOR THE STUDENT TO WORK
WITH READERS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STOCKS, CATALOGUING, BIBLIOGRAPHY,
DOCUMENTATION AND STORAGE AND POLITICAL STUDIES. THE SERIES WILL EXPAND TO
INCLUDE MORE DETAILED MONOGRAPHS <Organization>ON</Organization> VARIOUS ASPECTS OF LIBRARIANSHIP, AS HAS
ALREADY HAPPENED WITH A SIMILAR SERIES PRODUCED IN THE <Location>USSR</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5551
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF EGYPTIAN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECIALISTS&apos; A MULTIFACETED SYSTEM APPROACH.

DISCUSSES THE DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF A 2-YEAR, NON-DEGREE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SYSTEM
TO TRAIN EGYPTIAN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECIALISTS IN THE <Location>USA</Location>. THE MAJOR OBJECTIVES OF
THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SYSTEM WERE TO TRAIN A <Organization>CORE GROUP</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECIALISTS IN
THE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> SKILLS REQUIRED FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES IN <Location>EGYPT</Location>. BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ANALYSIS OF THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> REQUIREMENTS, AN
INTEGRATED, MULTIFACETED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SYSTEM WAS DEVELOPED UTILISING <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> STRATEGIES.
********************************************
Document 5552
LIBRARIES AND NEWSROOMS IN <Location>LANCASTER</Location>, PRIOR TO ADOPTION OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
LIBRARIES ACT IN 1892 AND A BRIEF SURVEY OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1893-1974.

(DIPLOMA IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STUDIES THESIS.) A BRIEF HISTORY OF THE <Organization>EARLY DEVELOPMENT</Organization>
OF LIBRARIES OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> KINDS IN <Location>LANCASTER</Location>, <Location>UK</Location>, AGAINST THE BACKGROUND OF <Organization>WORKING</Organization>
CLASS POVERTY AND RISING MIDDLE CLASS AFFLUENCE.
********************************************
Document 5553
VITAL <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> OF LIBRARIES.

FOR YEARS NOW LIBRARIES AND <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN <Location>BULGARIA</Location> HAVE BEEN <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> THE
EXAMPLE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SOVIET COUNTERPARTS IN THE ORGANISATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>. TARGETS FOR <Location>BULGARIA</Location>&apos;S ECONOMIC GROWTH, <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization>
ADVANCEMENT AND THE POPULATION&apos;S <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> LIVING STANDARD IN THE 1980S MAKE THE
SIGNIFICANCE OF SOVIET LITERATURE AND PERIODICALS STILL MORE OBVIOUS.
CONCENTRATING UPON CONCRETE TASKS AND PROBLEMS IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> AREA, <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> MUST
SUPPLY <Organization>THEIR</Organization> READERS AND OTHERS <Organization>WORKING</Organization> IN <Organization>LOCAL INDUSTRIES</Organization>, <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
INSTITUTES, SCHOOLS AND COLLEGES WITH RELEVANT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. SOVIET SOURCES,
SUCH AS <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> PERIODICALS HAVE BEEN MOST USEFUL IN THE PAST AND WILL
CONTINUE TO BE IN THE FUTURE. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> CAN RELY UPON ASSISTANCE GIVEN BY THE
STAFF <Organization>AT</Organization> THE HOUSE OF SOVIET <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND CULTURE IN <Location>SOFIA</Location>. PARTNERSHIPS WITH
SOVIET LIBRARIES HAVE ALSO PROVEN VALUABLE. SOME VENTURES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PLEVEN
REGION (NORTHERN <Location>BULGARIA</Location>) ARE GIVEN AS EXAMPLES OF SUCCESSFUL PROMOTION OF
SOVI ET LITERATURE AND EXPERIENCE IN LIBRARIANSHIP AMONG THE BULGARIAN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5554
NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> A VISIT TO JAPAN.

AN ACCOUNT OF 4 LIBRARIES VISITED DURING A <Organization>FEW</Organization> DAYS&apos; STAY IN <Location>TOKYO</Location> <Location>IN</Location> FEB 81.
DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF BUILDINGS, LAYOUT, HOLDINGS, SERVICES, USERS AND
PERSONNEL, FOR THE DIET <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Location>TOKYO</Location> METROPOLITAN <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE
KITASATO MEMORIAL MEDICAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>FRANCO-JAPANESE INSTITUTE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
THE PRINCIPAL FRENCH-LANGUAGE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>JAPAN</Location>. IN CONCLUSION, THE PROBLEMS
FACED BY JAPANESE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE BRIEFLY DISCUSSED.
********************************************
Document 5555
BRAZILIAN LIBRARIES AS SEEN BY <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND USERS.

ANSWERS OBTAINED TO A QUESTIONNAIRE CIRCULATED TO PROMINENT BRAZILIAN
INTELLECTUALS AND <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AS A PRELIMINARY TO A SURVEY OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> BRAZILIAN
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND USERS. 4 USERS, COMPRISING A PROFESSOR, 2 WRITERS, AND A
<Organization>TEACHER</Organization>, <Organization>EACH</Organization> DISCUSS THE SIGNIFICANCE OF LIBRARIES IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF
BRAZILIAN CULTURE AND THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF INTELLECTUALS; 11 <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
UNIVERSITIES, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES, <Organization>RESEARCH INSTITUTES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
SCHOOLS, DISCUSS THE FACTORS IMPEDING THE DEVELOPMENT OF LIBRARIES AND
PREVENTING <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> ACCESS.
********************************************
Document 5556
THE COMMERCIAL CIRCULATING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE 1970S.

THE HOPES PLACED IN THE &apos;TUPPENNY&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE 1930S WERE SEEN TO BE
SHORT-LIVED BY THE 1950S. CIRCULATING LIBRARIES ARE DEFINED AS THOSE <Organization>FROM</Organization>
WHICH <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> WERE BORROWED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> SUBSCRIPTION OR SMALL FEES PAID TO THE
<Organization>BUSINESS</Organization> CONCERNS <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> THEM. THEY WERE PRIMARILY FOR RECREATIONAL
READING, AND AGENTS INCLUDED HARROD&apos;S, <Organization>BOOTS</Organization> AND <Organization>SMALLER</Organization> SHOPS. STOCK WAS
BOUGHT OR OBTAINED <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> SUPPLIERS SUCH AS ALLIED LIBRARIES IN <Location>MANCHESTER</Location>,
WHO DECLINED IN THAT PART OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>BUSINESS</Organization>, AND CLOSED IT IN 1975, AND SOUTH
<Organization>COUNTY</Organization> LIBRARIES WHO SUPPLIED TO 6,000-7,000 AGENTS AFTER THE WAR, AND TO LESS
THAN 150 IN 1978. SOME AGENTS WERE RELUCTANT TO CLOSE, BECAUSE OF CUSTOMER
RELATIONS, WHILE YOUNGER SHOP OWNERS WERE OFTEN UNINTERESTED.
********************************************
Document 5557
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> ACTIVITIES OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> SUBJECT COLLECTION LIBRARIES AND
<Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> SUBJECT LIBRARIES.

IN 1973 THE DEUTSCHE FORSCHUNGSGEMEINSCHAFT (<Organization>GERMAN RESEARCH ASSOCIATION</Organization>) MADE
RECOMMENDATIONS ABOUT THE ACTIVITIES OF THESE LIBRARIES WITHIN THE CONTEXT OF
SUPER-REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION. ALTHOUGH STANDARDS GENERALLY HAVE RISEN
SINCE THEN, FINANCIAL DIFFICULTIES ARE CAUSING PROBLEMS. UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES
HAVE TO CONCENTRATE <Organization>ON</Organization> ACQUIRING EXAMINATION SYLLABUS LITERATURE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
EXPENSE OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> MATERIAL. THESE LIBRARIES SHOULD BE <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> <Organization>TOPICAL</Organization> AND
<Organization>COMPREHENSIVE INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SPECIALISED SUBJECTS AND A
CLEARING HOUSE IS NEEDED TO SORT OUT THE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> JUNGLE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SOURCES. CURRENT AND POSSIBLE FUTURE DEVELOPMENTS ARE DISCUSSED FOR&apos;
PERIODICAL INDEXING; SUBJECT CATALOGUES OF PERIODICALS; SUBJECT CATALOGUES OF
LIBRARIES; CURRENT SUBJECT BIBLIOGRAPHIES; AND ACQUISITIONS LISTS.
********************************************
Document 5558
THE PEACE PALACE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE PEACE PALACE IN <Location>THE HAGUE</Location>, <Location>NETHERLANDS</Location> AROSE OUT OF THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> HAGUE PEACE
CONFERENCE IN 1899. CONSTRUCTION OF THE PALACE, WHICH WAS FINANCED BY ANDREW
CARNEGIE, WAS BEGUN IN 1907 AND THE BUILDING WAS OPENED IN 1913. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
OF THE PEACE PALACE SERVES THE PERMANENT COURT OF JUSTICE, THE <Organization>UNITED NATIONS</Organization>
INTERNATIONAL COURT OF JUSTICE AND <Location>THE HAGUE</Location> ACADEMY OF INTERNATIONAL LAW, <Organization>ALL</Organization>
OF WHICH ORGANISATIONS ARE SITUATED IN THE PEACE PALACE. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ALSO
PROVIDES A SERVICE TO EXTERNAL USERS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> FOREIGN EMBASSY STAFF,
SPECIALISTS IN INTERNATIONAL LAW AND INDUSTRIAL LAWYERS EMPLOYED BY
MULTINATIONAL CONCERNS. THE COLLECTION CONTAINS APPROXIMATELY 580,000 VOLUMES
AND ACCESSIONS AMOUNT TO SOME 2,500 <Organization>NEW</Organization> TITLES <Organization>EACH</Organization> YEAR.
********************************************
Document 5559
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE FINNISH PARLIAMENT.

THE FINNISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF PARLIAMENT WAS FOUNDED IN 1872. <Organization>AT</Organization> PRESENT IT COMPRISES
APPROXIMATELY 430,000 VOLUMES, A STAFF OF 34 PEOPLE AND SINCE 1978 IT HAS BEEN
LOCATED IN <Organization>NEW</Organization> PREMISES OF ABOUT 5000 SQ.M. IN AN ANNEX TO THE PARLIAMENT
BUILDING. UNLIKE SIMILAR LIBRARIES IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COUNTRIES, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE
FINNISH PARLIAMENT HAS BEEN PUBLICLY AVAILABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> AS <Organization>EARLY</Organization> AS 1913. <Organization>FROM</Organization>
1919-22 IT FUNCTIONED AS THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, TOTALLY SEPARATE <Organization>FROM</Organization>
PARLIAMENT EVEN IN <Organization>ITS ADMINISTRATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5560
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PARLIAMENT 1851-1980.

THE &apos;RIKSDAG&apos; (THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PARLIAMENT) STARTED <Organization>ITS</Organization> WORK IN
1851, <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> A SERVICE TO A <Organization>POPULAR</Organization> ASSEMBLY WITH REPRESENTATIVES OF THE
CLERGY, NOBLE FAMILIES, THE BURGHERS AND PEASANTRY. A DETAILED HISTORICAL
REVIEW OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS FOLLOWED BY SECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> PRESENT DAY ORGANISATION,
INTERNATIONAL CONNECTIONS, AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> FUNCTIONS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> PUBLICATION OF
PRINTED CATALOGUES AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> LINKS WITH LAGRI, AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SYSTEM FOR
LEGISLATION AND LEGAL USAGE.
********************************************
Document 5561
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE ARMED FORCES IN <Location>NORWAY</Location>.

74 LIBRARIES SERVE THE NORWEGIAN ARMED FORCES. <Organization>WELFARE SERVICES</Organization> ARE AN
INTEGRAL PART OF THE <Organization>GENERAL CARE</Organization> AND ADMINISTRATION OF <Organization>DEFENCE</Organization> PERSONNEL AND
THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IS A SECTION OF THE <Organization>DEFENCE WELFARE SERVICE</Organization>. THE LARGER
LIBRARIES STOCK AROUND 5,000 VOLUMES, WHILE THE <Organization>SMALLER</Organization> ONES HAVE 900-1,000.
IN RECENT YEARS <Organization>ALL</Organization> 74 LIBRARIES HAVE RECEIVED THE SAME <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>, IN ORDER TO
PROVIDE THE SAME SELECTION TO <Organization>EACH</Organization> UNIT AND SOME LIBRARIES HAVE BEGUN TO
PROVIDE MUSIC COLLECTIONS.
********************************************
Document 5562
EVANGELICAL PARISH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES PAST AND PRESENT.

PROTESTANT PARISH LIBRARIES IN <Location>GERMANY</Location> BEGAN IN THE 19TH CENTURY, PARTLY
<Organization>THROUGH</Organization> MISSIONARY IMPULSES AND PARTLY <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK WAS INTERRUPTED IN THE 1930S AND BEGAN AGAIN IN 1945, WHEN
WALTER SCHWARZ AND EVA LINDBER REFOUNDED THE DEUTSCHE VERBAND EVANGELISCHER
BUCHEREIEN (<Organization>GERMAN ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF EVANGELICAL LIBRARIES), WHICH HAS OVERALL
CONTROL OF THE PARISH LIBRARIES, <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> ADVICE, ORGANISING CONFERENCES AND
COMPILING <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization>. A <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> WAS FOUNDED WHICH HAD TO CLOSE IN THE
1970S <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> LACK OF FUNDS. THE PARISH LIBRARIES ARE STAFFED <Organization>MAINLY</Organization> BY
VOLUNTEERS, FOR WHOM SHORT <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization> ARE PROVIDED, WITH <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
STAFF IN TOP POSTS. A QUARTERLY PERIODICAL IS PUBLISHED CONTAINING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
NEWS AND 1,800 REVIEWS ANNUALLY OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> PUBLICATIONS, FOR ONE OF WHICH AN
ANNUAL BOOK PRIZE IS AWARDED.
********************************************
Document 5563
CATHOLIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK IN <Location>GERMANY</Location>.

THE ROMAN CATHOLIC <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES DEVELOPED IN THE 19TH CENTURY WITH THE
ADVENT OF <Organization>POPULAR EDUCATION</Organization>. THE LIBRARIES ARE TO BE FOUND TODAY IN HOSPITALS,
AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND IN THE PARISHES; <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>AIM</Organization> IS TO PROVIDE EDUCATION,
SOCIAL COMMUNICATION AND HELP FOR THE UNDERPRIVILEGED. THE LARGEST HAVE STOCKS
OF UP TO 30,000 ITEMS BUT AVERAGE TOTALS ARE BETWEEN 1,500-5,000 ITEMS OF
LENDING AND <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> MATERIAL FOR CHILDREN AND ADULTS. STAFF ARE <Organization>MAINLY</Organization>
VOLUNTEERS, ALTHOUGH FULL-TIME PROFESSIONALS ARE EMPLOYED IN THE <Organization>DIOCESAN</Organization>
CENTRES, RESPONSIBLE FOR PLANNING AND FINANCE, STAFF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND
REPRESENTATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INTERESTS WITHIN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> DIOCESE. OVERALL CONTROL IS
MAINTAINED BY <Organization>ST</Organization>. MICHAEL&apos;S LEAGUE IN BAVARIA AND BY THE <Organization>BORROMEUS ASSOCIATION</Organization>
IN THE REST OF <Location>GERMANY</Location>, WHO PROVIDE A NUMBER OF <Organization>CENTRALISED SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5564
<Organization>STATE</Organization> SUPPORT FOR ECCLESIASTICAL <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN BAVARIA.

DURING THE LAST 30 YEARS IT HAS BEEN AFFIRMED THAT FINANCIAL SUPPORT OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
LIBRARIES RUN BY THE CHURCHES IS NEEDED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> AND <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LEVEL BECAUSE
THEY ARE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES. CHURCH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACHIEVEMENTS <Organization>AT</Organization> THIS TIME
INCLUDE STOCK INCREASES, THE DEVELOPMENT OF STAFF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND SOCIAL SERVICE
WITHIN LIBRARIANSHIP. IT IS DISPUTED AS TO WHETHER THEY ARE RELIGIOUS RATHER
THAN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES AND WHETHER <Organization>CENTRALISED SERVICES</Organization> FOR THEM ARE TOO
COSTLY. THE <Organization>SMALLER</Organization> BRANCHES COULD BE REGARDED AS A HINDRANCE TO THE <Organization>MOBILE</Organization>
LIBRARIES AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF VOLUNTARY STAFF COULD BE AN EXCUSE NOT TO EMPLOY
FULL-TIME ADMINISTRATORS. A PLURALITY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTHORITIES CAN BE REGARDED
AS ECONOMIC. FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IS PROVIDED BY THE
<Organization>STATE</Organization>, ESPECIALLY IN PLACES WHERE THE CHURCH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MAY BE THE ONLY <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5565
EVANGELICAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK IN BAVARIA.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> CONFERENCE <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>REGENSBURG</Organization>, 9-13 JUNE 81. PROTESTANT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN BAVARIA ARE RUN BY
THE BAVARIAN BRANCH OF THE <Organization>GERMAN ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF EVANGELICAL LIBRARIES WHICH
PARTICIPATES IN THE <Organization>STATE LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PROGRAMME IN RETURN FOR SOME
FINANCIAL SUPPORT. THE LIBRARIES, OPEN TO <Organization>ALL</Organization>, HAVE STOCKS COMPARABLE WITH
SMALL BRANCH LIBRARIES; THEY ARE PARTICULARLY VALUABLE IN UNDERPRIVILEGED
<Organization>RURAL</Organization> AREAS WHERE THEY ACT AS CENTRES FOR COMMUNICATION AND CULTURE. STAFF ARE
<Organization>MAINLY VOLUNTARY WORKERS</Organization> FOR WHOM PART-TIME <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization> ARE ARRANGED. THE
ASSOCIATION PUBLISHES A QUARTERLY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SHEET FOR BAVARIA AND A
QUARTERLY PERIODICAL COVERING THE WHOLE OF <Location>GERMANY</Location>. THE BAVARIAN BRANCH
MAINTAINS A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF 29,000 VOLUMES TO SUPPLEMENT SMALL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
STOCKS, ORGANISING BLOCK LOANS TO THEM AND TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> INTERESTED BODIES SUCH AS
YOUTH CLUBS AND ORGANISERS OF RETIREMENT <Organization>COURSES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5566
<Organization>ST</Organization>. MICHAEL&apos;S LEAGUE&apos; AN EXAMPLE OF ROYAL BAVARIAN INDEPENDENCE.

THE <Organization>ST</Organization>. MICHAEL&apos;S LEAGUE WAS FOUNDED IN 1901 AS AN <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> ORGANISATION
FOR PUBLISHING NEWSPAPERS AND PERIODICALS AND CONTROLLING THE ROMAN CATHOLIC
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN BAVARIA. <Organization>EACH</Organization> PARISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS SUBORDINATE TO <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>DIOCESAN CENTRE</Organization> AND THE <Organization>STATE LIBRARY CENTRE</Organization> PROVIDES A NUMBER OF <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization>
SERVICES AND OVERALL ADMINISTRATION. THE LEAGUE PUBLISHES A REVIEWING JOURNAL
JOINTLY WITH THE <Organization>BORROMEUS ASSOCIATION</Organization>, A QUARTERLY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SHEET <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES IN BAVARIA, BOOK LISTS AND A HANDBOOK FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE
STAFF, <Organization>MAINLY</Organization> VOLUNTEERS, FOR WHOM SHORT <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>COURSES</Organization> ARE PROVIDED. CLOSE
COOPERATION IS MAINTAINED WITH <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> GOVERNMENT. SINCE 1968 THE LEAGUE HAS
<Organization>COMPILED ANNUAL STATISTICS BY ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> PROCESSING; THE PROGRAMME IS
ALSO USED EVERY 3 YEARS FOR THE COMPILATION OF <Organization>STATISTICS ON ALL CHURCH</Organization>
LIBRARIES IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5567
<Organization>ST</Organization>. MICHAEL&apos;S LEAGUE, <Organization>STATE GROUP</Organization> FOR BAVARIA&apos; THE CONTRIBUTION OF THE ROMAN
CATHOLIC <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES TO LITERATURE PROVISION IN LOWER BAVARIA AND THE
UPPER RHINELAND PALATINATE.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> CONFERENCE <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>REGENSBURG</Organization>, 9-13 JUNE 81. THE ROMAN CATHOLIC <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN THIS AREA ARE
ADMINISTERED BY <Organization>ST</Organization>. MICHAEL&apos;S LEAGUE. THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, FOUNDED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
BEGINNING OF THIS CENTURY, DEVELOPED INTO <Organization>ITS</Organization> PRESENT FORM AFTER 1945. IN
1979, IN THE WHOLE OF BAVARIA, THE LEAGUE CONTROLLED 1,273 LIBRARIES STOCKING
OVER 3 <Organization>MILLION MEDIA</Organization>; LOANS TOTALLED OVER 6 <Organization>MILLION</Organization>, WITH OVER 6,000 STAFF,
<Organization>MAINLY</Organization> VOLUNTEERS. THE PARISH LIBRARIES ARE CONTROLLED BY <Organization>DIOCESAN</Organization> CENTRES
WHICH EMPLOY <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>, FULLTIME STAFF, PROVIDE ADVICE FOR <Organization>SMALLER</Organization>
LIBRARIES AND ARRANGE STAFF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>. THE <Organization>DIOCESAN</Organization> CENTRES ARE IN
TURN SUBORDINATE TO THE <Organization>STATE ADMINISTRATIVE CENTRE</Organization> IN <Location>MUNICH</Location>, WHICH IS
RESPONSIBLE FOR ORGANISING <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> PURCHASING AND INTERLOANS AND PUBLISHING A
NNUAL REPORTS, <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization> AND QUARTERLY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SHEETS. A <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
JOURNAL IS PUBLISHED JOINTLY WITH THE <Organization>BORROMEUS ASSOCIATION</Organization>, RESPONSIBLE FOR
ROMAN CATHOLIC <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES OUTSIDE BAVARIA.
********************************************
Document 5568
JOINT-USE LIBRARIES IN THE <Organization>AUSTRALIAN COMMUNITY</Organization>.

PROCEEDINGS OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>WORKSHOP</Organization>, <Location>MELBOURNE</Location>, 13-15 AUG 80. DEFINES A
JOINT-USE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS ONE WHERE 2 OR MORE DISTINCT GROUPS OF USERS ARE GIVEN
<Organization>EQUAL</Organization> PRIORITY IN THE SAME PREMISES, THE GOVERNANCE OF WHICH IS COOPERATIVELY
ARRANGED BETWEEN 2 OR MORE SEPARATE AUTHORITIES. EMPHASIS OF THE CONFERENCE
WAS PLACED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INTEGRATION OF SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES WITH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
LIBRARIES TO GIVE A <Organization>COORDINATED SERVICE</Organization>. THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> PAPERS WERE DELIVERED&apos;
JOINT-USE LIBRARIES IN PRIMARY AND SECONDARY SCHOOLS, BY J.D. DWER; JOINT-USE
LIBRARIES IN COLLEGES, BY A.J. BROWN; JOINT <Organization>USE</Organization> LIBRARIES IN COMMUNITY
CENTRES, BY G. FRASER.
********************************************
Document 5569
INTER-LIBRARY COMPARISONS: A REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> PROGRESS WITH <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES.

<Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> COMPARISONS AS A MANAGEMENT TOOL ARE DESCRIBED. A <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> OUTLINE
OF INTERFIRM COMPARISONS AS A TOOL IN MANAGEMENT IS FOLLOWED BY A DESCRIPTION
OF THE WORK CARRIED OUT BY THE CENTRE FOR INTERFIRM COMPARISON, FUNDED BY
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY R&amp;D</Organization>, INTO <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> COMPARISONS. THE FINAL PART DESCRIBES
THE SCOPE AND CONTENT OF THE MAIN COMPARISON SO FAR UNDERTAKEN FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
LIBRARIES.
********************************************
Document 5570
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN BAVARIA 1979-80.

THE TOTAL NUMBER OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN BAVARIA, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THOSE RUN BY THE
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES AND THOSE RUN BY THE CHURCHES, IS 2,343. 94.8% OF TOWNS AND
VILLAGES LARGE ENOUGH TO HAVE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN BRANCH LIBRARIES DO HAVE THEM. 46% OF
LIBRARIES STOCK UNDER 3,000 ITEMS, ONLY 4% STOCK OVER 30,000. IN 1980 22.5
<Organization>MILLION</Organization> LOANS WERE MADE TO OVER 1 <Organization>MILLION</Organization> READERS AND TOTAL EXPENDITURE
AMOUNTED TO 97.1 <Organization>MILLION</Organization> DM. IMPLEMENTATION OF THE <Organization>STATE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PROGRAMME
HAS SHOWN POSITIVE RESULTS. <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDINGS HAVE BEEN PROVIDED, OLD ONES
EXTENDED AND IMPROVED. THERE ARE MORE QUALIFIED STAFF EMPLOYED AND BETTER
STAFF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> THAN BEFORE. <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA</Organization>, PUBLICITY WORK AND
THE REGIONAL INTER-LOAN SYSTEM HAVE BECOME MORE PROMINENT. MORE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
WORKS ARE STILL NEEDED AND MORE LITERATURE FOR FOREIGN CHILDREN.
********************************************
Document 5571
<Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.

FOR ARTICLES IN THIS <Organization>ISSUE</Organization>, SEE THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> SERIAL NUMBERS.
********************************************
Document 5572
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
<Location>SWEDEN</Location>&apos;S <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK IS WELL DEVELOPED AND REACHES LARGE GROUPS OF
THE POPULATION <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> OUTREACH ACTIVITIES. RECENT STUDIES SHOW THAT
<Organization>ALMOST &amp;H</Organization> THE ADULT POPULATION AND 80-90% OF THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PEOPLE
HAVE VISITED A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE LAST YEAR. MODERN DEVELOPMENTS HAVE ACCELERATED
DURING THE 1970S LARGELY BECAUSE OF THE FUSION OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES. <Location>SWEDEN</Location>
HAS NO LIBRARIES ACT, BUT THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PARLIAMENT DECIDED TO INTRODUCE A SYSTEM
OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> GRANTS TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES AND REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES. <Organization>STATE</Organization>
GRANTS AMOUNT TO 2.5% OF THE TOTAL OPERATING COSTS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES, BUT
THEY HAVE PLAYED A LARGE ROLE IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF LIBRARIES THANKS TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
STRATEGIC DEPLOYMENT.
********************************************
Document 5573
BIBLIOTEKSTJANST-A PRESENTATION.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
BIBLIOTEKSTJANST IS THE <Organization>SWEDISH LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, WHOSE MAIN TASK IS TO HELP
STREAMLINE THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEM. IT HAS BEEN SHOWN THAT <Organization>ALMOST</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES
OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK CAN BE CONDUCTED MORE EFFICIENTLY AND RATIONALLY WITH THE <Organization>AID</Organization>
OF <Organization>CENTRALLY PRODUCED SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>AIDS</Organization>. BIBLIOTEKSTJANST, AS THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
SERVICE ORGAN, HAS THUS ACQUIRED A VERY WIDE FIELD OF OPERATION.
********************************************
Document 5574
PROJECT PROGRESS&apos; A STUDY OF THE CANADIAN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES.

THE FINAL REPORT OF A STUDY SPONSORED BY THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN
ORDER TO PROVIDE PRACTICAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS A BASE FOR PLANNING AND DECISIONS.
THIS INCLUDES BOTH SPECIFIC MATTERS OF <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION, COST-BENEFIT
ANALYSIS, PERSONNEL AND DEMOGRAPHY AND MORE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> QUESTIONS OF SOCIAL,
POLITICAL AND <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization> CHANGE.
********************************************
Document 5575
CHILDREN, LIBRARIES AND COMICS IN <Location>MEXICO</Location>.

DESCRIBES A VISIT TO MEXICO AND THE <Location>US</Location> FINANCED BENJAMIN FRANKLIN LIBRARY IN
GUADELAJARA BRIEFLY. THE CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ATTACHED TO THE &apos;CENTRO SOCIAL
MORELOS&apos; IN <Location>AGUASCALIENTES</Location> SUFFERS <Organization>FROM</Organization> LACK OF SPACE AND MATERIAL, AND THE
UNQUALIFIED LIBRARIAN&apos;S MAIN DUTY IS TO KEEP ORDER. <Organization>FEW</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES LEND
<Organization>BOOKS</Organization>. THE STREAM OF PULP MAGAZINES AND COMICS FOR ADULTS AND CHILDREN IS NOW
BEING COUNTERED BY THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>, WHO PUBLISHES MATERIAL IN SIMILAR STYLE, BUT
BETTER CONTENT. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>SAN</Location> CRISTOBAL RECEIVES MONEY FOR STAFF SALARIES
BUT NONE FOR <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>. LIKE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> LIBRARIES, BIBLIOTECA DE <Location>MEXICO</Location> IS USED <Organization>MAINLY</Organization>
BY STUDENTS. THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> CAME <Organization>ON</Organization> A MORE ORGANISED FOOTING IN
1978, AND AS NO SCHOOL LIBRARIES EXIST, CREATION OF CHILDREN&apos;S SECTIONS IS
RECEIVING PRIORITY. THERE IS GREAT DEMAND FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> TRAINED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 6
UNIVERSITIES BUT MANY ARE ATTRACTED INTO PRIVATE FIRMS. CONTINUITY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
PLANNING IS HAMPERED BY THE CHANGES OF  <Organization>CENTRAL ADMINISTRATION</Organization> EVERY 6 YEARS.
********************************************
Document 5576
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>COLOMBIA</Location>.

IN <Location>COLOMBIA</Location>, <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> HAVE BEEN IN OPERATION SOME 40 YEARS;
RESPONSIBILITY TODAY LIES WITH THE INSTITUTO COLOMBIANO DE CULTURA, THE
<Organization>COLOMBIAN INSTITUTE</Organization> OF CULTURE, (COLCULTURA) WHICH HAS RECENTLY CREATED A
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK AS PART OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SYSTEM. DETAILS ARE
GIVEN OF <Organization>HOW PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> OPERATE WITHIN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
FRAMEWORK, AND SERVE <Organization>IMMEDIATE</Organization> USER <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> LEVEL. CURRENT ACTIVITIES
AND <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> ARE OUTLINED, AND 2 <Organization>NEW</Organization> INITIATIVES, THE HOUSE OF CULTURE, AND
THE INTEGRATED CULTURAL CENTRES, DESIGNED TO PROVIDE MORE <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization>
SERVICES THAN CONVENTIONAL <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES, DESCRIBED. FINALLY THE STRUCTURE
OF THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK IS DELINEATED.
********************************************
Document 5577
BIBLIOTHEQUES CENTRALES DE PRET. 1979 <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization>.

REPORT OF THE OFFICIAL 1979 SURVEY, COVERING 73 BIBLIOTHEQUES CENTRALES DE
PRET SERVING <Organization>RURAL</Organization> POPULATIONS IN <Location>FRANCE</Location>. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF RESOURCES IN
TERMS OF FINANCE, HOLDINGS, PERSONNEL, BUILDINGS, AND VEHICLES, TOGETHER WITH
<Organization>STATISTICS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> LOANED TO VILLAGE AND SCHOOL DEPOTS. PUBLICATIONS ISSUED
AND PROMOTION OF CULTURAL ACTIVITIES, SUCH AS EXHIBITIONS AND CONFERENCES, ARE
DISCUSSED, AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> REVIEWED. <Organization>ALL DATA</Organization> IS TABULATED IN FULL IN
APPENDICES.
********************************************
Document 5578
THE EXPANSION OF THE <Organization>RURAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN BAVARIA WITHIN THE FRAMEWORK OF
THE <Organization>GENERAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF BAVARIAN LIBRARIES.

LECTURE GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 29TH CONFERENCE OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CENTRES IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>,
BURGHAUSEN, SEPT 81. <Organization>BASIC</Organization> PROVISION OF STOCKS AND STAFF IS STILL NOT AS GOOD
IN <Organization>RURAL</Organization> AS IN URBAN AREAS; <Organization>FURTHER FINANCIAL</Organization> PROVISION <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> IS
NECESSARY IF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> ARE TO BE IMPROVED. PLANS FOR IMPROVING BAVARIAN
LIBRARIES ARE LINKED CLOSELY WITH <Organization>NATIONAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> SCHEMES. EVERY VILLAGE
WITH OVER 3,000 INHABITANTS HAS A BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>SMALLER</Organization> VILLAGES ARE
SERVED BY <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> LIBRARIES, MORE OF WHICH ARE STILL NEEDED. CLOSURE OF MANY
SMALL BRANCH LIBRARIES HAS RESULTED IN A CONCENTRATION OF SERVICES AND IN
INCREASED STOCKS AND READERSHIP. COOPERATION BETWEEN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND SCHOOL
LIBRARIES AND BETWEEN LOCAL AUTHORITY AND CHURCH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IS VERY
IMPORTANT.
********************************************
Document 5579
VESTMANNAEYJAR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; FRAGMENTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE HISTORY OF AN ICELANDIC
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE VESTMANNAEYJAR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS HAD TO STRUGGLE AGAINST POVERTY, LACK OF
UNDERSTANDING, AND ULTIMATELY TO STRUGGLE FOR SURVIVAL. A LONG-STANDING
STRUGGLE FOR PROPER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PREMISES HAS TAKEN PLACE; THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, HAVING <Organization>FEW</Organization>
MEANS, WAS MOVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1 TEMPORARY PLACE TO ANOTHER UNTIL IT COULD BE MOVED
INTO A <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDING IN 1970. IN FEB 73 A VOLCANIC ERUPTION HIT THE HEIMAEY AND
DESTROYED THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BUT THE <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> WERE RESCUED. IT IS THOUGHT THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
IS THE ONLY 1 IN THE WORLD TO BE RESCUED <Organization>FROM</Organization> VOLCANIC ERUPTION.
********************************************
Document 5580
<Organization>BOOKS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE WORKPLACE: ARE WORKPLACE LIBRARIES NEEDED?.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
QUESTIONS THE NEED FOR WORKPLACE LIBRARIES IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location> VIS-A-VIS PROVISION OF
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND BRANCH LIBRARIES. IN FACT, <Organization>ALMOST</Organization> 2/3 OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> POPULATION DO
NOT REGULARLY <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> LIBRARY-THEY HAVE NOT DISCOVERED THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS AN INTELLECTUAL RESOURCE, OR AS A SOURCE OF PLEASURE AND EMOTIONAL
EXPERIENCE. SUGGESTS THE BENEFITS WHICH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> CAN AFFORD THE POPULATION,
AND SEES THE PAUCITY OF USAGE AS A WARNING SIGNAL TO SCHOOL STAFF, <Organization>POPULAR</Organization>
EDUCATIONISTS AND TRADE UNIONS.
********************************************
Document 5581
SKAMOKOWA STORY&apos; <Organization>RURAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN <Location>WASHINGTON</Location> <Organization>STATE</Organization>.

SKAMOKAWA, A VILLAGE OF 250 POPULATION, IN <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>&apos;S 2ND SMALLEST <Organization>COUNTY</Organization>,
WAHKIAKUM, HAS, IN THE LAST <Organization>FEW</Organization> YEARS, GAINED A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE NUCLEUS OF THE
COLLECTION CAME <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>LOCAL SCHOOL</Organization>, BUT THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NOW BOASTS A BOOK
COLLECTION, PAPERBACKS, <Organization>INTERLIBRARY LOAN SERVICES</Organization>, A <Organization>FILM BORROWING SERVICE</Organization>,
AND A <Organization>REFERENCE SERVICE</Organization>. VOLUNTEERS PROVIDE REMEDIAL READING, TUTORING, AND
INSTRUCTION IN <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> DONATED FUNDS, AND
FUND-RAISING IS AN EVER PRESENT CHORE. VOLUNTEER HELP IS ERRATIC AND LACK OF
TIME HAS PREVENTED THE LIBRARIAN <Organization>FROM</Organization> CATALOGUING THE COLLECTION. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SUCCEEDS, ULTIMATELY, <Organization>THROUGH COMMUNITY</Organization> DETERMINATION, AND, OPERATING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
PREMISE THAT SOMETHING IS BETTER THAN NOTHING, CARES FOR THE INDIVIDUAL BY
<Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> WHAT IS REALLY WANTED BY THE POPULATION IT SERVES.
********************************************
Document 5582
LIBRARIES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE MOVE? SCOTTISH <Organization>RURAL</Organization> MOBILES.

<Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS AND PRACTICES DIFFER WIDELY IN <Organization>RURAL</Organization>
SCOTLAND WITH NO 1 AUTHORITY ADHERING RIGIDLY TO ANY STANDARD. WHERE AND WHEN
A <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> STOPS ARE IMPORTANT FACTORS IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>. AS MOST VISITS ARE <Organization>ON</Organization>
WEEKDAYS BETWEEN 9.00 AM AND 5.00 PM, MORE WOMEN THAN MEN <Organization>USE</Organization> THE SERVICE.
MOST USERS LIVE WITHIN 1/4 OF A MILE OF A STOPPING POINT. THE SERVICE IS
GREATLY VALUED BY USERS VALUED BY USERS ALTHOUGH IT IS GENERALLY INFERIOR TO A
STATIC BRANCH. NEVERTHELESS, URGENT STUDY IS REQUIRED TO IDENTIFY <Organization>RURAL</Organization>
DWELLERS&apos; <Organization>NEEDS</Organization> SO THAT THE <Organization>APPROPRIATE SERVICE</Organization> CAN BE PROVIDED.
********************************************
Document 5583
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF SUBJECT SPECIALISTS IN SUHL DISTRICT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE DISTRICT <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS NEW TO EAST <Location>GERMANY</Location>. THE LARGE, HIGH-QUALITY
STOCK IS HELPFUL FOR THE REGIONAL STOCK-BUILDING PROGRAMME; MOST DOMESTIC
PUBLICATIONS ARE ACQUIRED TOGETHER WITH FOREIGN WORKS NEEDED FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
<Organization>EACH DEPARTMENT</Organization> IS CONTROLLED BY A SUBJECT SPECIALIST RESPONSIBLE FOR STOCKS,
CATALOGUING, ADVISORY AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK, ORGANISATION, STAFF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND
COORDINATION WITH INDUSTRY AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> INTERESTED BODIES. IN SUHL THERE ARE
SUBJECT SPECIALISTS FOR <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY, SOCIAL <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>, CHILDREN&apos;S
<Organization>BOOKS</Organization>, EARTH SCIENCES AND MUSIC. SUCH <Organization>DEMANDING POSTS REQUIRE UNIVERSITY</Organization>
GRADUATES WITH DETAILED <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> KNOWLEDGE AND AN ADDITIONAL
QUALIFICATION IN LIBRARIANSHIP. IT MIGHT ALSO BE POSSIBLE TO OBTAIN SUBJECT
SPECIALISTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE RANKS OF GRADUATE TEACHERS.
********************************************
Document 5584
THE WORK OF A <Organization>COUNTY DEPARTMENT</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
DESCRIBES THE WORK OF <Location>SWEDEN</Location>&apos;S JAMTLAND <Organization>COUNTY</Organization>, WHICH COMPRISES 2
PROVINCES-JAMTLAND AND HARJEDALEN. THE <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> IS ABOUT THE SIZE OF <Location>DENMARK</Location>,
BUT WITH ONLY 135,000 INHABITANTS, 40% OF WHOM LIVE IN THE MUNICIPALITY OF
OSTERSUND. DISTANCES BETWEEN TOWNS ARE VAST. THE OSTERSUND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BECAME THE
OFFICIAL <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN 1947. <Organization>COUNTY DEPARTMENT</Organization> WORK VARIES <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> TO
<Organization>COUNTY</Organization>, AND COMPARISONS SHOW THAT <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> DEPARTMENTS WORK MORE
FLEXIBLY THAN, SAY, <Location>FINLAND</Location>&apos;S PROVINCIAL LIBRARIES.
********************************************
Document 5585
<Organization>BOOKS</Organization> BY BOAT TO THE ARCHIPELAGO POPULATION.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>. OFF THE
COAST OF <Location>SWEDEN</Location>&apos;S BOHUS <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> LIE OVER 3,000 ISLANDS, MANY INHIBITED BUT
LACKING PERMANENT COMMUNICATION WITH THE MAINLAND. <Organization>EACH</Organization> APRIL AND SEPTEMBER A
&apos;BOOK BOAT&apos; SETS OUT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>GOTHENBURG</Location> <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR A 2-WEEK TRIP
ALONG THE 120-MILE COASTLINE. IN 1981 IT LENT OVER 18,000 VOLUMES <Organization>FROM</Organization> 49
LENDING POINTS. DESCRIBES THE BOAT&apos;S ORGANISATION, STAFFING, FUNCTIONS AND
OPERATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5586
A HISTORY OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES IN BOLTON <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE BEGINNINGS TO 1974.

(PH.D THESIS). AN OUTLINE OF THE <Organization>MUNICIPAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF BOLTON, LANCASHIRE,
IS FOLLOWED BY AN ACCOUNT OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES KNOWN TO HAVE EXISTED IN THE
TOWN BEFORE THE FIRST <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIBRARIES ACT OF 1850 IN 1852. A DETAILED
EVALUATIVE HISTORY OF THE <Organization>RATE-SUPPORTED PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IS GIVEN, <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THE WORK OF THE FIRST <Organization>LIBRARY COMMITTEE</Organization> IN 1852-53 TO THE RETIREMENT OF THE
CHIEF LIBRARIAN IN 1974.
********************************************
Document 5587
A HISTORY OF <Location>SWANSEA</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, 1870-1974.

(<Organization>FLA</Organization> THESIS). CONCENTRATES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE YEARS 1870-1920, WITH <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> LIBRARIES OPEN TO
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5588
<Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> LIBRARIES. 1979 <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization>.
