Document 5001
THE CHRISTIAN LIBRARIAN AND CENSORSHIP: ANOTHER VIEW.

A REPLY TO &apos;LIBERTY, <Organization>DEMOCRACY</Organization> AND CENSORSHIP&apos; THE RESPONSIBILITY OF THE
CHRISTIAN LIBRARIAN&apos;, CHRISTIAN LIBRARIAN (5) 1981, 29-38 (SEE PREVIOUS
ABSTRACT). RAISES THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> POINTS&apos; THE <Organization>SECURE</Organization> BELIEVER CAN MAKE A
DISCRIMINATING JUDGEMENT IN SELECTING <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, UTILIZING <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE MEANS <Organization>AT</Organization>
HIS DISPOSAL, EVEN IF IT MEANS <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THINGS HE STRONGLY DISAGREES WITH;
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> MUST BE ALERT TO THE POWER OF EVIL, BUT TO CONCEAL IT IS NOT TO
DESTROY IT; THE LIBRARIAN SPENDS <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> MONEY, GENERATED FROM PEOPLE OF MANY
FAITHS, WITH <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> AND MORAL BACKGROUNDS; <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> NEED TO BE,
AND TO BE SEEN AS, <Organization>OPEN</Organization> PERSONS WHO ARE CONSISTENTLY GRAPPLING WITH THE ISSUES
OF REAL LIFE AS THEY ARE REFLECTED BROADLY IN THE <Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization> WORLD; AND
FINALLY, <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> SHOULD BEA LIFE-ENHANCING AND A LIFE-AFFIRMING INFLUENCE
AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CAN BE A GENUINE MARKETPLACE OF IDEAS WHERE &apos;GOOD&apos; <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> MAY
COMPETE WITH THE <Organization>BAD</Organization> SIMPLY <Organization>BECAUSE</Organization> THEY ARE <Organization>THERE</Organization> TOGETHER.
********************************************
Document 5002
A CONVERSATION WITH JUDITH F. KRUG.

IN AN INTERVIEW JUDITH F. KRUG, DIRECTOR OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S
OFFICE FOR <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> FREEDOM (<Organization>OIF</Organization>), DISCUSSES THE RISE IN CENSORSHIP OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> SINCE THE ELECTION OF RONALD REAGAN TO THE <Location>US</Location> PRESIDENCY
WHICH MUST BE RESISTED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. DESCRIBES THE WORK OF THE <Organization>OIF</Organization> AND
CONCLUDES WITH RESUME OF KRUG&apos;S CAREER.
********************************************
Document 5003
A <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MAN.

EXAMINES THE NOTION OF &apos;<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MAN&apos; <Organization>BY</Organization> ANALOGY WITH &apos;ECONOMIC MAN&apos; AND
SEEKS TO DISCOVER HOW THE CONCEPT HAS BEEN USED IMPLICITLY IN <Organization>USER</Organization> STUDIES AND
BIBLIOMETRICS. THE CONCLUSION IS REACHED THAT A PRIMITIVE CONCEPTION OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MAN IS TO BE FOUND IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> STUDIES AND THE REASONS FOR <Organization>THIS</Organization> ARE
EXAMINED. MORE SOPHISTICATED VERSIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MAN ARE SEEN TO BE
EMERGING FROM <Organization>SOME</Organization> RECENT WORK.
********************************************
Document 5004
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> BANKS, DATA BANKS, AND DATA <Organization>BASES</Organization>&apos; AN ATTEMPT <Organization>AT</Organization> CLARIFICATION OF
TERMS.

A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A 1980 CANADIAN CONFERENCE WHICH DERIVES A STRUCTURAL
TYPOLOGY FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> BANKS FROM THE PRELIMINARY CONSTRUCTION OF TYPOLOGIES
OF DOCUMENTARY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND DOCUMENTARY ELEMENTS. THE 1ST TYPOLOGY DEVELOPS
THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND DOCUMENTARY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>; THE 2ND
LEADS TO REDEFINITION OF THE CONCEPTS OF RECORDS, DOCUMENTS, AND
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> ENTRIES. THE CREATION OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION BANK</Organization> TYPOLOGY LEADS
TO EXPLANATION OF THE DATA BASE CONCEPT, AND IN CONCLUSION A DEFINITION OF
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> IS ADVANCED. THE ARGUMENT IS ILLUSTRATED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
CANADIAN EXAMPLES.
********************************************
Document 5005
THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE ASSOCIATION.

REMARKS <Organization>BY</Organization> THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> TO A
MEMBERSHIP MEETING 28 JUNE 81 <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>.
CONSIDERS THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE ASSOCIATION, <Organization>EMPHASISING ITS FINANCIAL</Organization>
SITUATION, INVOLVEMENT WITH THE <Organization>MASS MEDIA</Organization> AND <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> FREEDOM, AND THE
PROGRESS OF THE DIVISIONS.
********************************************
Document 5006
THE <Organization>GERMAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>.

THE ASSOCIATION HAS 650 MEMBERS <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
<Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> EXCEPT THAT OF BAVARIA, <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, CHURCH
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>ALL</Organization> SIZES OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE
SECTIONS FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> TYPE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND GROUPS WITHIN <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization>. THE
ASSOCIATION&apos;S WORK INCLUDES&apos; <Organization>ESTABLISHING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> TARGETS, ESPECIALLY
WITHIN THE CONTEXT OF THE 1973 DEVELOPMENT PLAN; PROMOTING <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
UNDERSTANDING OF THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; REPRESENTING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INTERESTS
TO THE NATION, <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> AND POLITICAL AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> GROUPS; COOPERATING
WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> INTERESTED BODIES CONCERNED WITH THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PROGRAMME; REPRESENTING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INTERESTS CONCERNING
THE FREEDOM OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> DISSEMINATION, COPYRIGHT <Organization>LAW</Organization> AND DATA PROTECTION;
AND ADVISING <Organization>ON</Organization> STAFFING, <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY.
********************************************
Document 5007
THE 10TH ANNIVERSARY OF <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH</Organization>
CENTRE FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>).

TEXT OF AN INTERVIEW WITH DICK REUMER, DIRECTOR OF THE NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK
EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM, <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 10TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF THE CENTRE.
REUMER BELIEVES THAT THE MOST <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> PROBLEMS FACING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>THE
NETHERLANDS</Location> IN 1982 ARE THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>DECISION</Organization> TO REDUCE SUBSIDIES TO
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> 15% AND THE PROPOSED LEGISLATION RELATING TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
SERVICES, WHICH WILL REPLACE THE PRESENT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACT. FOR THE NBLC THE
<Organization>NEW</Organization> LEGISLATION WILL MEAN THE DECENTRALISATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> THROUGHOUT
THE REGIONS AND CLOSER COOPERATION AMONGST <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE SAME AREA. TO
CELEBRATE THE 10TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE NBLC A JUBILEE CONGRESS IS TO BE <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
WHICH THE CENTRE&apos;S SERVICES WILL COME UNDER CLOSE EXAMINATION AND WILL BE MORE
ACTIVELY PROMOTED TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5008
PERCEPTIONS <Organization>BY</Organization> EDUCATORS AND ADMINISTRATORS OF THE RANKING OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>
PROGRAMS.

A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WAS UNDERTAKEN TO DETERMINE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PERCEPTION OF HIGHEST-QUALITY
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>. THE <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> SOUGHT TO DETERMINE PERCEPTION
RANKINGS OF EXCELLENCE IN 4 CATEGORIES&apos; QUALITY OF MASTER&apos;S PROGRAMME, QUALITY
OF DOCTORAL PROGRAMME FOR THE PREPARATION OF EDUCATORS, QUALITY OF DOCTORAL
PROGRAMME FOR THE PREPARATION OF ADMINISTRATORS, AND CONTRIBUTION TO THE
PROFESSION <Organization>BY</Organization> THE FACULTY AS A <Organization>WHOLE</Organization>. RESULTS ARE COMPARED WITH THOSE OF
EARLIER, SMALLER SAMPLE STUDIES, AND SUGGESTIONS FOR <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TO
EXAMINE THE <Organization>COMMON</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS OF <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> GENERALLY PERCEIVED AS BEING OF
<Organization>HIGH</Organization> QUALITY ARE ADVANCED. SUGGESTS THAT AN EXAMINATION OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> QUALITIES IN
HIGHLY PERCEIVED <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> CAN LEAD TO A MEANINGFUL UPGRADING OF PRESENT
EVALUATIVE STANDARDS.
********************************************
Document 5009
A CONVERSATION WITH NORMAN HORROCKS.

AN INTERVIEW WITH NORMAN HORROCKS, DIRECTOR, SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>,
<Organization>DALHOUSIE UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Organization>HALIFAX</Organization>, NOVA SCOTIA. DISCUSSES <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> AND
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location> AND CANADA, CONCENTRATING <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>DALHOUSIE</Organization>, AND
CERTIFICATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. OFFERS ADVICE TO AMBITIOUS <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WANTING TO
PROGRESS.
********************************************
Document 5010
EDUCATION IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONSERVATION.

DISCUSSES <Organization>PRESERVATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN TERMS OF REPAIRING DAMAGE
ALREADY DONE AND PREVENTING DAMAGE THROUGH <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> OF STORAGE CONDITIONS.
DESCRIBES <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Location>US</Location> COURSES IN <Organization>PRESERVATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5011
THE NEED FOR IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> VOCATIONAL
EDUCATION: REPORT OF A QUESTIONNAIRE <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>HBO GROUP COMMITTEE</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>DUTCH ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.

SINCE THE FORMATION IN 1976 OF THE GROUP FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> VOCATIONAL
EDUCATION WITHIN THE NEDERLANDSE VERENIGING VAN BIBLIOTHECARISSEN,
DOCUMENTALISTEN EN LITERATUURONDERZOEKERS (<Organization>DUTCH ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>,
DOCUMENTALISTS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS), GROUP MEMBERS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> SEVERAL
OCCASIONS PROPOSED THAT A SCHEME OF IN-SERVICE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> BE STARTED. IN 1979 THE <Organization>GROUP COMMITTEE</Organization> AGREED TO <Organization>THESE</Organization> PROPOSALS
AND IN OCT 80 A QUESTIONNAIRE WAS CIRCULATED TO MEMBERS TO ASCERTAIN WHAT FORM
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SHOULD TAKE. OF THE 79 RESPONDENTS MORE THAN &amp;H EXPRESSED A WISH
FOR COURSES IN <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA</Organization>, MANAGEMENT TECHNIQUES AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>, AND OVER 75% WERE WILLING TO PURSUE <Organization>SUCH</Organization> COURSES IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SPARE
TIME. THE RESULTS OF THE QUESTIONNAIRE <Organization>HAVE</Organization> NOW BEEN PRESENTED TO THE
ASSOCIATI <Organization>ON</Organization> OF <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>
FOR CONSIDERATION.
********************************************
Document 5012
THE <Organization>BA</Organization> (HONS) DEGREE COURSE IN EDUCATION AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STUDIES <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LOUGHBOROUGH</Organization>
UNIVERSITY.

THE VALUE OF <Organization>DUAL EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> QUALIFICATIONS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK
WITH CHILDREN AND YOUNG PEOPLE IS STRESSED, THROUGH THE EXAMPLE OF THE SCHOOL
LIBRARIAN AND THE ENGLISH TEACHER. AN ACCOUNT IS GIVEN OF THE <Organization>LOUGHBOROUGH</Organization>
UNIVERSITY 4 <Organization>YEAR</Organization> HONOURS DEGREE COURSE IN EDUCATION AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STUDIES.
TEACHING OF THE 2 <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> SUBJECT AREAS PROCEEDS CONCURRENTLY, WITH AN
ASSOCIATED <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> SUBJECT BEING STUDIED IN THE 1ST 2 YEARS. THE <Organization>CONTENTS</Organization> OF
THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> COMPONENTS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> SUBJECT AREAS ARE DESCRIBED IN DETAIL.
<Organization>EMPLOYMENT</Organization> PROSPECTS OF GRADUATES FROM THE COURSE ARE DISCUSSED.
********************************************
Document 5013
ASSISTANT <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES-ASSISTANTS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. A
COMPARISON.

<Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE MANY PROBLEMS CONNECTED WITH THE CAREER STRUCTURES OF ASSISTANT
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND ASSISTANTS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>WEST
GERMANY</Location>. THE PROBLEMS ARISE WITH CAREERS <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>; <Organization>THIS</Organization> DIFFERS FROM 1 FEDERAL
<Organization>STATE</Organization> TO THE NEXT, ENTRANCE REQUIREMENTS ARE NOT STANDARDISED NOR ARE THE
SYLLABUSES OR FINAL EXAMINATIONS. THE TYPE OF <Organization>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTE</Organization> <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> VARIES FROM <Organization>STATE</Organization> TO <Organization>STATE</Organization> AND MAY BE A <Organization>LIBRARY COLLEGE</Organization>, A
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OR A POLYTECHNIC. <Organization>THERE</Organization> IS NO CLEARLY DEFINED CAREER
STRUCTURE FOR ASSISTANT <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> OR ASSISTANTS WHICH CAUSES DIFFICULTIES
WITHIN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHEN ALLOCATING <Organization>DUTIES</Organization> AND DIFFICULTIES IN SALARY GRADES. IT
IS NECESSARY TO <Organization>AIM</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>JOINT</Organization> CAREERS <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SCHEME FOR BOTH ASSISTANT
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS BUT BEFORE <Organization>THIS</Organization> CAN BE ACHIEVED THE ABOVE
MENTIONED PROBLEMS MUST BE SETTLED.
********************************************
Document 5014
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS IN <Location>MAURITIUS</Location>.

THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>MAURITIUS</Location> WITH THE FINANCIAL HELP OF THE INTERNATIONAL
<Organization>DEVELOPMENT RESEARCH CENTRE</Organization> OF <Location>CANADA</Location> (IDRC) EMBARKED <Organization>ON</Organization> A 15 MONTH
EXPERIMENTAL COURSE IN 1978 FOR THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS WHO WERE
ALREADY <Organization>WORKING</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF THE EXPERIMENT WAS TO EVOLVE A
COURSE OF APPROXIMATELY 1 <Organization>YEAR</Organization> TAKING 3 AFTERNOONS WEEKLY, GEARED TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
CONDITIONS AND <Organization>USING</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> RESOURCES. THE EXPERIMENT WAS A SUCCESS AND THE
COURSE, AFTER MINOR ALTERATIONS, WAS CONTINUED IN 1981.
********************************************
Document 5015
BUT...IT COULD BE <Organization>BETTER</Organization>!&apos;: TOWARDS A THIRD EDITION OF THE HANDBOOK OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>.I

N REPLY TO CRITICISM OF THE 2ND EDITION OF 2BIBLIOTHEEK EN DOCUMENTATIE&apos;
HANDBOEK TEN DIENSTE VAN DE OPLEIDINGEN1 (2<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>&apos; A
HANDBOOK FOR STUDENTS1) <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN DEC 79, THE <Organization>EDITORIAL BOARD</Organization> POINT <Organization>OUT</Organization> THE
DIFFICULTY OF PRODUCING A TEXTBOOK TO SUIT THE MANY DIFFERING COURSES IN
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>. HOWEVER, IN THE 3<Organization>RD</Organization> EDITION OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization>,
WHICH IS DUE FOR PUBLICATION IN SPRING 83, SEVERAL CHAPTERS WILL BE DEVOTED TO
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE PHILOSOPHY OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>.
IN ADDITION, THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> EDITION WILL CONTAIN MORE FACTS AND EXAMPLES TO
ILLUSTRATE THE THEORETICAL ASPECTS, AND WILL BE MORE <Organization>READABLE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5016
THE P.A. <Organization>TIELE SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND THE HANDBOOK OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>.

DURING FEB 81 <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF THE P.A. <Organization>TIELE SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN <Location>THE HAGUE</Location>,
<Location>NETHERLANDS</Location> DISCUSSED THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF 2BIBLIOTHEEK EN DOCUMENTATIE&apos; HANDBOEK TEN
DIENSTE VAN DE OPLEIDINGEN1 (2<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>&apos; A HANDBOOK FOR
STUDENTS1) 2ND EDITION, 1979 AS A TEACHING INSTRUMENT. THE HANDBOOK IS USED <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE SCHOOL AS A <Organization>BASIC</Organization> INTRODUCTION FOR STUDENTS TO A NUMBER OF COURSE
SUBJECTS. HOWEVER, INADEQUATE COVERAGE OF A NUMBER OF TOPICS AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
SPECIALISED TERMINOLOGY MAKE THE WORK UNSUITABLE FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> AS A STUDENT
TEXTBOOK. IN ADDITION, THE TEXT OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization>, WHICH WAS WRITTEN <Organization>BY</Organization> SEVERAL
AUTHORS, SUFFERS FROM A LACK OF BALANCE AND IS <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> MARRED <Organization>BY</Organization> AN INADEQUATE
INDEX.
********************************************
Document 5017
<Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization> OR TEXTBOOK?.

IN AN ATTEMPT TO OBTAIN THE VIEWS OF LECTURERS AND STUDENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 2ND EDITION
OF 2BIBLIOTHEEK EN DOKUMENTATIE&apos; HANDBOEK TEN DIENSTE VAN DE OPLEIDINGEN1
(2<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>&apos; A HANDBOOK FOR STUDENTS1) <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN 1979,
THE <Organization>EDITORIAL BOARD</Organization> OF 2<Organization>OPEN</Organization>1 CIRCULATED A QUESTIONNAIRE TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>. THE RESULTS SHOWED THAT MOST LECTURERS AND
STUDENTS MADE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization>, <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> A FEW HAD NOT USED IT <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization>, <Organization>BECAUSE</Organization>,
THEY FELT, CERTAIN TOPICS WERE INSUFFICIENTLY COVERED, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>. THE RESULTS <Organization>ALSO</Organization>
SHOWED THAT THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> WAS USED MORE AS A TEXTBOOK TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
ADDITIONAL TO THAT OBTAINED IN LECTURES, RATHER THAN AS A <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>BOOK</Organization>.
HOWEVER, <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>WHOLE</Organization> MOST RESPONDENTS FELT THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> TO BE A USEFUL
INTRODUCTION TO <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5018
THE <Location>LEEDS</Location> EVALUATION OF THE BISHOPSBURY CASE <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.

PART 1 <Organization>BY</Organization> KEN JONES REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> AN EVALUATION <Organization>BY LEEDS POLYTECHNIC SCHOOL</Organization> OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization> SIMULATION TEACHING PACKAGE. THE
BISHOPSBURY SIMULATION WHICH WAS DEVELOPED <Organization>BY</Organization> LEONARD GUY AND STUART MILLS <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>EALING COLLEGE</Organization> OF <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>. PART 2 <Organization>BY</Organization> NORAGH JONES DESCRIBES
<Organization>SUBSEQUENT</Organization> EXPERIENCE OF INTEGRATING BISHOPSBURY <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE <Organization>LEEDS BA</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> COURSE AND WIDENING <Organization>ITS</Organization> SCOPE. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> DISCUSSES POSSIBLE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
<Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> AND POTENTIAL OF THE SIMULATION FOR TEACHING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES
AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> <Organization>AS WELL AS MANAGEMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5019
WISER FROM EXPERIENCE: A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF PRACTICAL WORK AS AN ELEMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION.

<Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> COURSES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> FOR A <Organization>LONG</Organization> TIME INCLUDED PERIODS OF PRACTICAL WORK
TO ENABLE STUDENTS TO APPLY <Organization>THEIR</Organization> THEORETICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> TO PRACTICAL SITUATIONS
IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>SUCH</Organization> PERIODS MAY TAKE THE FORM OF &apos;SELF-ORIENTATION&apos; PERIODS,
<Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> THE STUDENT WITH ALL-ROUND EXPERIENCE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TECHNIQUES OR
&apos;EXPERIENCE&apos; PERIODS, DURING WHICH THE STUDENT MAY CARRY OUT DETAILED <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF
A PARTICULAR TOPIC. IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> MOST <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> COURSES ARE <Organization>TOO</Organization>
SHORT TO ALLOW STUDENTS TO GAIN MORE THAN A BRIEF VIEW OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ROUTINES IN
PRACTICE. IN ADDITION, STUDENTS OFTEN FAIL TO DERIVE THE MAXIMUM BENEFIT FROM
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>BECAUSE</Organization> OF INADEQUATE PREPARATION <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> AND THE HEAVY WORKLOAD OF COURSE TUTORS. <Organization>THERE</Organization> SHOULD BE REGULAR
CONSULTATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> STUDENT, COURSE-TUTOR AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO ENSURE THAT
<Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> ARE BEING COVERED.
********************************************
Document 5020
STATISTICS FOR AUSTRIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 1980.

A TABULATION OF STATISTICS FOR THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> ENDING 31 DEC 80 INCLUDES TOTAL <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
AND PERIODICAL STOCKS, STAFFING, ACCESSIONS, READERSHIP AND ISSUES FOR 68
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, DIVIDED <Organization>INTO</Organization> 7 CATEGORIES&apos; <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>, UNIVERSITY, <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>,
<Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization>, <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DEPARTMENTS, <Organization>MUSEUMS</Organization> AND TEACHER <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COLLEGES.
********************************************
Document 5021
CHRONICLE OF TODAY&apos;S SOKOLOV DISTRICT.

SERIES OF SHORT REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> ASPECTS OF LIFE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>WESTERN</Organization> DISTRICT OF
BOHEMIA. DEALS WITH THE IMPORTANCE OF THE UNIFIED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> IN THE
CULTURAL-EDUCATIONAL LIFE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> DISTRICT; <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> THE ACTIVITIES OF THE
DISTRICT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, ESPECIALLY <Organization>THEIR</Organization> METHODOLOGICAL ASPECTS; SERVICES TO YOUNG
READERS; AND COMPETITIONS ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>ALL</Organization> IN <Organization>ALL</Organization>, THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> CONTRIBUTED REMARKABLY TOWARDS <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization>
DISTRICT. THE DISTRICT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS THE WINNER OF THE TITLE &apos;MODEL <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;.
********************************************
Document 5022
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE REPUBLIC OF <Location>MALI</Location>.

BEFORE POLITICAL INDEPENDENCE, EDUCATION AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE DOMINATED <Organization>BY</Organization> 2
COLONIAL POWERS, THE ARABS IN THE 11TH <Organization>CENTURY</Organization> AND THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> IN THE 19TH.
SINCE INDEPENDENCE IN 1960 EDUCATION AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> DEVELOPED TO TRY AND
OVERCOME ILLITERACY. THE FORMER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>FRENCH INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR BLACK
<Location>AFRICA</Location> BECAME THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> REPUBLIC OF <Location>MALI</Location>, RESPONSIBLE
FOR <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF MATERIAL AND ADMINISTRATION OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> POLICY FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN ESTABLISHED IN <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> AND IN INSTITUTIONS FOR
<Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. <Organization>BOOK</Organization> PRODUCTION IN THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
LANGUAGES IS BEING <Organization>EXPANDED</Organization>. <Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE <Organization>AT</Organization> PRESENT A TOTAL OF 46 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH STOCKS OF <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 600-1,000 ITEMS FOR ADULTS AND CHILDREN.
<Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> CENTRES OF <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> EMBASSIES, <Organization>SOME</Organization>
<Organization>PRIVATE</Organization> ROMAN CATHOLIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF INTERNATIONAL
ORGANISATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5023
GEOGRAPHICAL DISTRIBUTION OF <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RESOURCES.

EXTRACT FROM RECENT TRENDS IN <Organization>RESOURCE ACQUISITION</Organization> IN <Organization>AUSTRALIAN</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> AND
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> G.G. ALLEN AND J.R. BROCKMAN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
47TH <Organization>IFLA</Organization> CONFERENCE, <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>, AUG 81. TABULATES AND DISCUSSES THE
DISTRIBUTION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RESOURCES <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> AS A PERCENTAGE OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
RESOURCES, DISTRIBUTION OF POPULATION, AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>/INHABITANT (<Organization>ALL</Organization>
1933-79). RESOURCES ARE FAR FROM EVENLY DISTRIBUTED AMONG THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> POPULATION
CENTRES; <Location>CANBERRA</Location> IS PARTICULARLY WELL SERVED; AND VICTORIA (2ND MOST POPULOUS
<Organization>STATE</Organization> AND CENTRE OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>&apos;S ESTABLISHMENT AND BUSINESS ACTIVITY) IS
SURPRISINGLY BADLY SERVED.
********************************************
Document 5024
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Location>HAMBURG</Location> CHAMBER OF COMMERCE.

<Organization>THERE</Organization> HAS BEEN A COMMERCIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>HAMBURG</Location> SINCE 1735. STOCKS INCLUDE
ABOUT 140,000 <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND OVER 500 <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> AND <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> LANGUAGE PERIODICALS;
ABOUT 3,000 ITEMS ARE ADDED ANNUALLY. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> MUCH MATERIAL WAS DESTROYED IN
WORLD WAR II THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS STILL VALUABLE TO BUSINESS PEOPLE, STUDENTS AND
<Organization>RESEARCH WORKERS</Organization>. SUBJECTS COVERED INCLUDE ECONOMICS, <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>,
COMMERCIAL LAW, POLITICS AND PSYCHOLOGY. THE PROXIMITY OF THE UNIVERSITY
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OBVIATES THE NEED FOR COMPREHENSIVE SUBJECT COVERAGE, WHICH IS AN
ADVANTAGE OWING TO THE INCREASED NUMBER OF <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization>, THE <Organization>CURRENT FINANCIAL</Organization>
CRISIS AND THE GROWTH OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> SUBJECTS LIKE ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION.
<Organization>TRADITIONAL</Organization> <Organization>MANUAL</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> METHODS ARE STILL FOUND TO BE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> HERE,
<Organization>ALTHOUGH ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> MAY BE IMPLEMENTED LATER.
********************************************
Document 5025
THE LIMITS OF THE COMPREHENSIBLE&apos; REFLECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 81ST ANNUAL MEETING OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>,
<Location>MONTREAL</Location>, 2 JUNE 81. THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE HEALTH <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FIELD IS
EXPLORED WITH <Organization>EMPHASIS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> HOW CHANGES IN PERSPECTIVE AND APPROACH MAY BE
INSTITUTED. <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ATTENTION IS PAID TO THE ATTITUDES AND <Organization>SKILLS</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN AS RELATED TO INSTITUTIONS AND ORGANISATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5026
ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>STUDY GROUP</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> 1980.

THE GROUP, FOUNDED IN 1966, HAS 140 MEMBERS INVOLVED IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>
IN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE PHARMACEUTICAL INDUSTRY AND HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
<Location>GERMANY</Location>, <Location>AUSTRIA</Location> AND SWITZERLAND. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PAST WORK HAS COVERED KEYWORD
CATALOGUES, ADVANCED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
<Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA</Organization> IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. TOPICS DISCUSSED HERE INCLUDED THE
<Organization>PUBLISHING</Organization> OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS IN <Organization>BASIC</Organization> SCIENTIFIC ENGLISH, CHANGES IN THE
DIMDI <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> FEES <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>GERMAN HOSPITAL INSTITUTE</Organization>, THE
<Organization>PROJECT</Organization> <Organization>ON IMPROVING HANOVER HOSPITAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ACCESS FOR <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization>
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CENTRES TO EXTERNAL DATA <Organization>BASES</Organization>, THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
<Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CENTRES AND ABSTRACTING JOURNALS, THE WORK OF THE
<Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF MEDICINE IN <Location>COLOGNE</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5027
ACCORDING TO THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PLAN (<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> WORK OF THE RNSKHBINFORM OF THE
KIRGIZ SSR).

THE PROVISION OF <Organization>AGRICULTURAL INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> IN KIRGIZIA HAS GREATLY
IMPROVED WITH THE FOUNDATION, IN 1975, OF THE RESPUBLIKANSKAYA NAUCHNAYA
SELSKOKHOZYAISTVENNAYA BIBLIOTEKA (<Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE REPUBLIC), <Organization>ITS</Organization>
DESIGNATION AS THE CENTRE OF <Organization>AGRICULTURAL INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>, AND THE
ESTABLISHMENT OF THE <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> OF <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>THESE</Organization>
FACTORS PROVIDED A FRAMEWORK FOR THE PROVISION OF CENTRALLY PLANNED, ORGANISED
AND COORDINATED <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> COMPRISING&apos; <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES, PROVISION OF <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization>
SPECIALISTS, ANSWERING OF <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> ENQUIRIES, COMPILATION OF <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> AND
RETROSPECTIVE SUBJECT BIBLIOGRAPHIES, AND THE PROMOTION OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>. THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S STOCK <Organization>BY</Organization> SPECIALISTS IN REMOTE
<Organization>RURAL</Organization> AREAS IS MADE POSSIBLE THROUGH AN <Organization>INTERLIBRARY LENDING SERVICE</Organization> RUN <Organization>BY</Organization>
THE <Organization>NET</Organization> WORK.
********************************************
Document 5028
<Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>GERMAN DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC</Location>.

PAPER PRESENTED TO THE <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SECTION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization> CONFERENCE, <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>,
AUG 81. THE BACKGROUND AND RANGE OF <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> ARE
OUTLINED, AND A BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE HOLDINGS OF <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> GIVEN.
<Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization> PRODUCED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE NOTED, AND AN
ACCOUNT OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> UNITING <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN <Location>EAST
GERMANY</Location> IS PROVIDED.
********************************************
Document 5029
STAGNATION IN THE KIBBUTZ <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

2 CHARACTERISTICS OF KIBBUTZ <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE GIVING CAUSE FOR CONCERN;
DECENTRALISATION; AND THE <Organization>AVERAGE</Organization> <Organization>AGE</Organization> OF KIBBUTZ <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. DECENTRALISATION
HAS HISTORIC AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> CAUSES. FORMERLY, MOST <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WERE VOLUNTEERS AND
<Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> GROUPS IN THE KIBBUTZ POPULATION HAD <Organization>SEPARATE</Organization> AREAS OF RESIDENCE AND
ACTIVITY. <Organization>MODERN KIBBUTZ SOCIETY</Organization> AND <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> CHANGED, BUT MANY <Organization>SMALL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> REMAINED IN EXISTENCE. DECENTRALISATION HAS MANY DRAWBACKS&apos;
INEFFICIENCY, AREAS OF INTEREST NOT COVERED <Organization>BY</Organization> ANY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, INCONVENIENCE OF
MANY READERS AND LACK OF A STRONG <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> THAT COULD BECOME A FOCAL POINT IN
THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE OF THE KIBBUTZ. THE 24 <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> SERVING IN THE KIBBUTZIM
SURVEYED AVERAGED 53.3 YEARS, ONLY 5 OF THEM BEING YOUNGER THAN 50. <Organization>THIS</Organization>
SITUATION RULES <Organization>OUT</Organization> MUCH IN THE <Organization>WAY</Organization> OF DEVELOPMENT AND INNOVATION. CALLS FOR A
SERIOUS <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF KIBBUTZ <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5030
SHOULD HOPE BE ABANDONED <Organization>BECAUSE</Organization> OF THE CRISIS?.

THE <Organization>IMPLICATIONS</Organization> OF THE WORD &apos;<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>&apos; MUST BE CONSIDERED CAREFULLY IN
CONNECTION WITH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. PARTICULAR PROBLEMS ARE CAUSED IN SELECTING FICTION
AND LEISURE MATERIAL. READERS DISLIKE EXCESSIVE AMOUNTS OF TRIVIAL MATERIAL AS
MUCH AS THE ELITIST APPROACH BUT THE ILLITERACY OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> SECTIONS OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
IS PREFERABLE TO THE TOTAL ABSTINENCE OF THE NON-READER. THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MUST BRING A <Organization>NEW</Organization> QUALITY TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICE</Organization>, EXERCISING A CORRECTIVE
FUNCTION IN RESPECT OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> MARKET TRENDS. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> MUST MOUNT AN OFFENSIVE
ACTION IN PURSUIT OF THE SENSIBLE, <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND HUMANE ASPECTS OF <Organization>THEIR SERVICE</Organization>.
IT IS DANGEROUS TO ATTACH <Organization>TOO</Organization> MUCH IMPORTANCE TO STATISTICS. <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SHOULD
BE PROVIDED THAT CROSSES <Organization>ALL</Organization> ARBITRARY BORDERS AND STIMULATES THE MIND.
********************************************
Document 5031
THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> TASKS FOR <Organization>CZECHOSLOVAK</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AFTER THE <Organization>XVITH COMMUNIST PARTY</Organization>
<Organization>CONGRESS</Organization>.

<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ACTING AS AN <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> ASSISTANT OF PARTY ORGANS AND
ORGANISATIONS, PLAY AN <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> ROLE IN GAINING SUPPORT FOR THE <Organization>COMMUNIST</Organization>
PARTY POLICIES, <Organization>ITS</Organization> PROGRAMME FOR WORLD PEACE AND THE BUILDING OF A DEVELOPED
<Organization>SOCIALIST SOCIETY</Organization>. TOGETHER WITH THE <Organization>CZECHOSLOVAK</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> THEY ARE TO PLAY AN EVEN MORE PROMINENT ROLE IN MAKING
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FOR INDUSTRY, AGRICULTURE AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> IN THE SPHERE OF CULTURE AND THE ARTS WITHIN A PARTICULAR
REGION IS BEING PREPARED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SETTING UP OF <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES.
BIBLIOGRAPHY WILL PLAY A <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> ROLE IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> PROCESS OF COMMUNICATION OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. STATISTICS, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND THE <Organization>FURTHER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF
THEORETICAL <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARE TO BECOME EVEN MORE
<Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> COMPONENTS IN THE TIME TO COME.
********************************************
Document 5032
<Organization>SOME</Organization> COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>.

SINCE WORLD WAR II <Organization>THERE</Organization> HAS BEEN AN UNPRECEDENTED GROWTH IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>
IN THE PROVISION OF <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING MEDICAL CARE</Organization>, <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> WELFARE
AND EDUCATION. <Organization>THIS</Organization> GROWTH HAS NOT BEEN ACHIEVED IN AN ORDERLY MANNER BUT HAS
COME ABOUT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SUDDEN EXPANSION OF <Organization>SEPARATE</Organization> SECTORS. IN THE LAST 10 YEARS
<Organization>CONTROL</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization> HAS BECOME A SUBJECT FOR MUCH DISCUSSION IN THE
<Organization>DUTCH</Organization> PARLIAMENT WITH THE RESULT THAT THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> HAS MADE PROVISION FOR
MEMBERS OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> TO <Organization>HAVE</Organization> A <Organization>GREATER</Organization> SAY IN THE RUNNING OF <Organization>THESE SERVICES</Organization>.
IN <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> FACTORS WHICH WILL <Organization>SERIOUSLY AFFECT PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> INCLUDE
THE SLOWDOWN IN ECONOMIC GROWTH, INCREASED UNEMPLOYMENT AND THE REDUCED
BIRTH-RATE. TO MEET <Organization>THESE</Organization> CHALLENGES A REFORM OF <Organization>LOCAL GOVERNMENT SERVICES</Organization> IS
NECESSARY.
********************************************
Document 5033
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>INDIA</Location>.

LECTURE GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ZENTRALINSTITUT FUR BIBLIOTHEKSWESEN (<Organization>CENTRAL INSTITUTE</Organization>
OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>) FEB 81. THE INDIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> DEVELOPED AFTER THE
FOUNDING OF THE REPUBLIC IN 1950. THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ACT IS A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
FRAMEWORK <Organization>LAW</Organization>. <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> HAS A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>MADRAS</Location>, <Location>BOMBAY</Location> AND DELHI. BELOW <Organization>THESE</Organization> ARE THE DISTRICT
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>EACH</Organization> RESPONSIBLE FOR <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 40 AND 80 BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. MOBILE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SERVE AREAS WHERE POPULATION IS PARTICULARLY SCATTERED. <Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE
<Organization>ALSO UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COLLEGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>PRIVATE</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PROBLEMS INCLUDE A <Organization>LARGE</Organization> POPULATION, A WIDE RANGE OF <Organization>ETHNIC</Organization>
GROUPS, RELIGIONS AND LANGUAGES, ILLITERACY, INADEQUATE SCHOOLING AND A
SHORTAGE OF MONEY.
********************************************
Document 5034
THE CAMPAIGN FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> WALES, 1929-1950.

THE PERIOD 1890-1930 WITNESSED A DECLINE IN THE NUMBER OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> WALES BUT <Organization>BY</Organization> 1930 SEVERAL PROMINENT CITIZENS BEGAN TO SEE THEM AS
USEFUL ADJUNCTS TO THE CAMPAIGN TO IMPROVE <Organization>AUSTRALIAN EDUCATION</Organization>. THE <Organization>CARNEGIE</Organization>
CORPORATION OF <Organization>NEW YORK PROVIDED FINANCIAL</Organization> SUPPORT AND THE <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MOVEMENT WAS SET UP IN <Location>SYDNEY</Location>. <Organization>MASS</Organization> DEMAND FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS NOT REALLY
A MOTIVE FORCE IN THE REVIVAL. WORLD WAR 2 EMPHASISED THE NEED TO PRESERVE
<Organization>DEMOCRACY THROUGH EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>ALSO</Organization> ESTABLISHED THE IDEA THAT CULTURE WAS NOT
THE PRESERVE OF THE <Organization>INTELLECTUAL</Organization> ELITE ALONE. POST-WAR RECONSTRUCTION BROUGHT
WITH IT A TIDE OF LARGELY BRITISH IMMIGRANTS WHO HAD <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> EXPECTATIONS OF
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. THE IMPETUS PROVIDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE WAR WAS SHORT LIVED,
HOWEVER, AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE FORCED TO STAND ALONE. <Organization>THIS</Organization> TIME THEY WERE
ABLE TO SURVIVE THROUGH THE PROFESSIONALISM OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5035
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE BILATERAL SEMINAR <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE <Location>GERMAN DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC</Location> AND
<Location>FINLAND</Location>&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK IN <Organization>RURAL</Organization> AREAS.

THE SEMINAR TOOK PLACE DURING THE 47TH ANNUAL <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> MEETING OF <Organization>IFLA</Organization>, AUG 81.
THE 2 COUNTRIES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> AN AGREEMENT <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION. SUBJECTS DISCUSSED
INCLUDED&apos; <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> AND FINLAND; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK IN <Organization>RURAL</Organization>
AREAS; THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS OF BOTH COUNTRIES IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
<Organization>RURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND QUALIFICATIONS AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF PART-TIME <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN <Organization>RURAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>EMPHASIS</Organization> WAS PLACED UPON THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LOCAL COMMUNITY</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS IN ADMINISTRATION, DIVISION OF WORK <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization>, <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> AND BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITHIN A <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> AND THE ROLE AND EFFECTIVITY OF
MOBILE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> DISCUSSED WERE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STANDARDS, SATURDAY OPENING
HOURS AND REGULAR <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF CHILDREN IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5036
N.K. KRUPSKAYA AND <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PROBLEMS IN THE <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO
<Organization>RURAL</Organization> POPULATIONS.

RAISING THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LEVEL OF LIFE IN THE COUNTRYSIDE IS STILL A <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> TASK OF
<Organization>SOVIET</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN THE 1980S. RECENT <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> PRODUCED GREAT
QUANTITATIVE IMPROVEMENTS IN <Organization>RURAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, BUT QUALITATIVELY MUCH
STILL NEEDS TO BE DONE. N.K. KRUPSKAYA WAS CLOSELY INVOLVED WITH <Organization>THIS</Organization> VERY
PROBLEM IN THE 1930S AND HER RECOMMENDATIONS ARE STILL <Organization>VALID</Organization> TODAY. IF WHAT
SHE WROTE THEN CAN BE PUT <Organization>INTO</Organization> PRACTICE NOW, THE <Organization>GAP</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE LEVELS OF
SERVICE IN TOWN AND COUNTRY CAN BE RAPIDLY NARROWED.
********************************************
Document 5037
INTAMEL CONFERENCE IN <Location>BUDAPEST</Location>, 1981.

26 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND 12 COUNTRIES WERE REPRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE INTERNATIONAL
ASSOCIATION OF METROPOLITAN <Location>CITY</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CONFERENCE. <Organization>NEW</Organization> PROJECTS FOR THE
COMING <Organization>YEAR</Organization> WILL INCLUDE COMPUTERISATION AND MAINTENANCE OF <Organization>BASIC SERVICES</Organization> IN
A TIME OF WORLD RECESSION. 2 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> CONFERENCE TOPICS WERE&apos; ADVANTAGES OF
CENTRALISING THE STOCKS OF <Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, OR BREAKING THEM DOWN <Organization>INTO</Organization> SUBJECT
SPECIALISATIONS. DISCUSSION WAS BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A PAPER PRODUCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE HUNGARIAN
<Organization>LIBRARY INSTITUTE</Organization>; AND SCIENTIFIC <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization> ORIGINATING FROM
<Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> LIBRARIES-THIS VARIES <Organization>WIDELY</Organization> ACCORDING TO THE FACILITIES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>,
BUT <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> PRODUCE A GREAT DEAL OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. A VARIETY
OF VISITS DURING THE CONFERENCE GAVE THE IMPRESSION THAT HUNGARIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
WERE MUCH INFLUENCED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>WESTERN</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> AND THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE HEAVILY
USED.
********************************************
Document 5038
DEDICATED AND UNCONVENTIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORKS&apos; IMPRESSIONS FROM <Location>BIRMINGHAM</Location>.

<Location>BIRMINGHAM</Location> HAS 1 OF THE <Organization>LARGEST</Organization> AND <Organization>BEST</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Location>EUROPE</Location>, WITH A
TOTAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUDGET OF OVER 7 MILLION POUNDS AND OVER 2 MILLION STOCK ITEMS
FOR 1 MILLION INHABITANTS. STRIKING FEATURES OF THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INCLUDE A
QUICK <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AND TRADE SECTION OF OVER 7,000 WORKS AND 7 <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
DEPARTMENTS. THE 45 BRANCHES DIVIDE <Organization>INTO</Organization> 4 <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> GROUPS IN ORDER TO
MAINTAIN CLOSE CONTACT WITH THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUT YET RETAIN A MEASURE OF
INDEPENDENCE. MANY COPE WITH <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> PROBLEMS, ESPECIALLY IN THE INNER <Location>CITY</Location>
AREA. AN <Organization>ETHNIC MINORITIES LIBRARIAN COORDINATES ALL SERVICES</Organization> TO FOREIGN
READERS. <Organization>STUDY</Organization> GROUPS ORGANISE PROJECTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> MATERIAL, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization>, RADIO <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. IN CONTRAST WITH MANY
<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, SERVICES FOR CHILDREN ARE GIVEN PARTICULAR PROMINENCE; IN
ADDITION TO SECTIONS IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> 2 <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5039
WE&apos;LL MEET IN SINDELFINGEN.

SINDELFINGEN, THE VENUE OF THE 1982 CONFERENCE OF THE ASSOCIATION OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAS A POPULATION OF 56,000. IN RECENT YEARS A
<Organization>LARGE</Organization> INCREASE IN <Organization>INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> HAS RESULTED IN A NEED FOR THE <Organization>RAPID</Organization>
AND IMPROVED PROVISION OF <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> FACILITIES. THE
1ST <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OPENED HERE IN 1909; THE PRESENT BUILDING WAS OPENED IN
1970, PARTLY FINANCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>DAIMLER</Organization> <Organization>BENZ</Organization> COMPANY. IN 1980 <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
STATISTICS REVEALED THAT SINDELFINGEN HAS THE HIGHEST PURCHASING BUDGET AMONG
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF COMPARABLE SIZE&apos; 5.70 DM PER INHABITANT, WITH A STOCK SIZE OF 2.6
MEDIA UNITS PER INHABITANT. THE MULTI-PURPOSE BUILDING <Organization>ALSO</Organization> HOUSES <Organization>ART</Organization>
EXHIBITIONS, A COMMUNAL CINEMA AND FACILITIES FOR THEATRICAL PERFORMANCES AND
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> MEETINGS.
********************************************
Document 5040
<Organization>HAMBURG PUBLIC LIBRARIES-DRAFT DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PLAN.

THE 10 <Organization>YEAR</Organization> PLAN, <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN OCT 81, <Organization>CONCENTRATES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SECTOR AND
LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION IN THE <Location>CITY</Location> <Location>IN</Location> THE LIGHT OF THE EVER-INCREASING
OUTPUT OF <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND <Organization>NON-BOOK</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AND OF <Location>HAMBURG</Location>&apos;S GROWING IMMIGRANT
POPULATION. <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION <Organization>HAVE</Organization> NOT KEPT PACE WITH DEMAND,
PARTICULARLY FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> CATEGORIES (E.G. HANDICAPPED PEOPLE). WAYS OF
COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEMS AND THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
SCHOOL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> NEEDS REAPPRAISAL. THE ROLE OF THE BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
IN MEETING THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> NEEDS OF THE <Organization>LOCAL COMMUNITY</Organization> MUST BE EXAMINED AND
<Organization>BETTER</Organization> ACCOMMODATION IS NEEDED IF THE SERVICE IS TO EXPAND. THE INTRODUCTION
OF COMPUTER TECHNIQUES SHOULD RELEASE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> TO EXPAND THE SCOPE OF THE
SERVICE.
********************************************
Document 5041
<Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITHIN THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

CONSIDERS THE ROLE THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> TO PLAY <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> LEVELS, AS
THE SCHOOL <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS UNDERGOING A RESTRUCTURING PROCESS. GIVES STATISTICS
SHOWING THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> GRADE COMPLETED FOR AGES <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 24 AND 60.
********************************************
Document 5042
<Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STATISTICS. FALL 1978 AND FALL 1979. REPORT NUMBER 12-80.

INCLUDED IN THE <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> TABLES ARE DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization>, <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, AND
OPERATING EXPENDITURES FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> INSTITUTION. DEVELOPMENTAL AREAS COVERED ARE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LOANS, TRANSACTIONS, HOURS OF SERVICE, AND MEAN SALARY OF FULL-TIME
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. ADDITIONAL <Organization>SUMMARY TABLES INCLUDE AVAILABLE TREND DATA</Organization> FOR FALL
77 THROUGH FALL 79. ENROLLMENTS FOR <Organization>EACH COLLEGE</Organization> AND UNIVERSITY ARE PROVIDED
FOR THE YEARS SURVEYED, IN ORDER THAT THE <Organization>STATISTICAL DATA</Organization> MAY BE REVIEWED IN
RELATION TO <Organization>USER</Organization> DEMAND FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FROM NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5043
AN OUTLINE OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE SENCKENBERG <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>FRANKFURT</Location>-AM-MAIN.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS PART OF A FOUNDATION ESTABLISHED IN 1763 <Organization>BY</Organization> DR. JOHANN
CHRISTIAN SENCKENBERG. IN THE 19TH <Organization>CENTURY</Organization>, SEVERAL <Organization>LEARNED</Organization> SOCIETIES
AMALGAMATED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH IT; THE STOCKS, COMPRISING WORKS IN NATURAL
<Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> AND MEDICINE, WERE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> DOCTORS AND MEMBERS OF
THE <Organization>NEWLY FORMED ASSOCIATION</Organization>. IN 1907 THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS OPENED TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>;
<Organization>NEW</Organization> PREMISES WERE USED AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> EMPLOYED. AFTER A PERIOD OF
FINANCIAL DIFFICULTY DURING WORLD WAR I, THE <Organization>JOHANN-WOLFGANG-GOETHE UNIVERSITY</Organization>
TOOK OVER FINANCIAL <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. IN 1947 A <Organization>NEW</Organization> AGREEMENT WAS MADE,
GIVING THE UNIVERSITY MORE POWERS IN <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization> AND IN 1966 THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS MOVED <Organization>INTO</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> PREMISES WITH THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5044
THE UNIVERSITY OF PETROLEUM AND MINERALS: A MODEL FOR AN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE UNIVERSITY OF PETROLEUM AND MINERALS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Location>DHAHRAN</Location>, <Location>SAUDI ARABIA</Location>, IS
ORGANISED <Organization>USING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> CLASSIFICATION AND AACR. 75% OF THE
160,000 VOLUMES COVER <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>. <Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> OVER 300,000 NONPRINT ITEMS AND
3,800 PERIODICALS. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OFFERS ACCESS TO EXTERNAL RESOURCES,
PHOTOCOPYING, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORIENTATION <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization>.
DOBIS/LIBIS, AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>, <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> INTERACTIVE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, IS BEING IMPLEMENTED
FOR THE <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization> OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FUNCTIONS.
********************************************
Document 5045
RELEVANCE OF <Organization>UAP</Organization> IN A UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IN <Location>MEXICO</Location>.

AN OUTLINE IS GIVEN OF THE BACKGROUND OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IN A UNIVERSITY
WITH 1 OF THE <Organization>LARGEST</Organization> STUDENT ENROLMENTS IN THE WORLD (OVER 300,000 STUDENTS).
<Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> COVERS 164 DEPARTMENTAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH <Organization>PROVIDE SERVICE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LEVELS. IT HAS A DIRECTORATE-GENERAL OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH
PROVIDES <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COORDINATION FOR THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AND A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SUPPORTING</Organization> THE DEPARTMENTAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. AN ACCOUNT IS GIVEN OF THE <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>
THAT <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN DEVELOPED IN SUPPORT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INFRASTRUCTURE AND THE
<Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> AVAILABILITY OF <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization> (<Organization>UAP</Organization>), IN PARTICULAR THE LIBRUNAM
<Organization>AUTOMATED</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> WORKSHOPS AND <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> EDUCATION AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5046
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HIGHLIGHTS OF 1981.

A BRIEF <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF THE BARR SMITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, UNIVERSITY OF <Location>ADELAIDE</Location>, <Organization>SOUTH</Organization>
<Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>, FOR 1981. <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> STATISTICS FOR USERS, ACCESSIONS AND LOANS AND
MENTIONS THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ON-LINE SERVICES</Organization>, GIFTS AND BEQUESTS, EXPANSION OF SPACE,
THE <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> BIBLION AND EXPENDITURE.
********************************************
Document 5047
REPORT OF THE <Organization>SELECT COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF THE BARR SMITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

A CONDENSED VERSION OF THE 2REPORT OF THE <Organization>SELECT COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT OF THE BARR SMITH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>1, UNIVERSITY OF <Location>ADELAIDE</Location>. THE
COMMITTEE&apos;S TERMS OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> WERE TO DETERMINE THE FORM IN WHICH THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SHOULD DEVELOP AND TO CONSIDER THE METHODS, SCALE OF ACQUISITION AND STORAGE
OF <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> TO BE EMPLOYED. THE REPORT PLANS THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR
15 YEARS TAKING <Organization>INTO</Organization> ACCOUNT BOTH THE URGENCY OF THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PROBLEMS AND
PREVAILING FUNDING LEVELS.
********************************************
Document 5048
THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF FORESTRY AND TIMBER INDUSTRY IN
SOPRON.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF FORESTRY AND TIMBER INDUSTRY DATES BACK TO
THE 18TH <Organization>CENTURY</Organization>. A SCHOOL OF MINING WAS FOUNDED <Organization>BY</Organization> KING KARL III IN 1735.
<Organization>THIS SCHOOL</Organization> DEVELOPED AND FROM 1770 <Organization>ALSO</Organization> TAUGHT FORESTRY <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>. IN 1808 IT
BECAME AN INSTITUTE OF FORESTRY, AND <Organization>THIS</Organization> REFLECTED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>CONTENTS</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WHICH <Organization>EXPANDED</Organization> TO COVER <Organization>NEW</Organization> SUBJECT AREAS. THE INSTITUTE BECAME THE
<Organization>ACADEMY</Organization> OF MINING AND FORESTRY IN 1846 AND ONLY <Organization>ACQUIRED UNIVERSITY</Organization> STATUS IN
1934. THE <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> HAD BEEN HAMPERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE 1ST WORLD WAR,
INADEQUATE BUILDINGS AND LACK OF <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. WITH THE FOUNDING OF THE UNIVERSITY A
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> PLANNED. THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDING WAS OPENED IN 1977. IT
IS THE ONLY ONE OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> KIND IN <Location>HUNGARY</Location>, DEVOTED ENTIRELY TO SPECIALIST
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> CONCERNING FORESTRY AND THE TIMBER INDUSTRY. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS
EQUIPPED WITH THE LATEST <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> FACILITIES AND PROVIDES AN EXCELLENT
SERVICE TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> USERS.
********************************************
Document 5049
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>HAMBURG</Location>-<Location>HARBURG</Location>.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, NOT YET COMPLETED, IS CONCEIVED AS A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH ONLY 1
<Organization>SEPARATE</Organization> DEPARTMENTAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, COVERING A TOTAL AREA OF 3,800 SQ.M. STOCKS
WILL ULTIMATELY INCLUDE 500,000 <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND 4,000 PERIODICALS, ADDING 20,000
ITEMS ANNUALLY. <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> WILL BE STORED IN SUBJECT <Organization>READING</Organization> ROOMS AND CLOSED
ACCESS STACKS. PURCHASING WILL BE CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE LIBRARIAN IN COOPERATION
WITH UNIVERSITY <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. MOST <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> MATERIAL WILL BE BOUGHT, WITH
RETROSPECTIVE COVERAGE FOR 1970-80; SELECTIVE PURCHASES OF <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> LANGUAGE
MATERIAL WILL BE MADE. <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> WILL BE USED FOR&apos; <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>
<Organization>SEARCHING</Organization>; <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, IN COOPERATION WITH <Organization>HAMBURG UNIVERSITY</Organization>; ISSUES;
INTERLOANS WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AND <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>; AND LISTS OF
ACQUISITIONS.
********************************************
Document 5050
HISTORY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>GRAZ TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> 1875-1975.

PART 1 OF AN ARTICLE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE HISTORY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> GRAZ <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
UNIVERSITY. THE FOUNDATIONS FOR A <Organization>TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> WERE LAID IN 1811 WHEN
ARCHDUKE JOHANN REALISED HIS PLANS FOR A SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTION AND DONATED
HIS <Organization>PRIVATE</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>, TO THE PROVINCE OF STEIERMARK, BUT IT
DID NOT BECOME A <Organization>STATE</Organization> INSTITUTION UNTIL 1874 AND A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WITH <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>OWN</Organization>
BUILDING, BUDGET AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, WAS NOT ESTABLISHED UNTIL 1889. THE RELATIONSHIP
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS ALWAYS FRAUGHT WITH
DIFFICULTIES AND <Organization>FULL</Organization> INDEPENDENCE FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS NOT ACHIEVED UNTIL
1960. BRIEF BIOGRAPHIES OF THE 8 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DIRECTORS TO DATE AND A REVIEW OF
STAFFING AND BUDGETS UP TO 1975 ARE INCLUDED.
********************************************
Document 5051
A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE HEALTH <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; <Organization>ITS</Organization> ROLES IN EDUCATION FOR THE HEALTH
<Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>.

DISCUSSES THE OBJECTIVES OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> CURRENTLY BEING CONDUCTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> COLLEGES OF THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> HEALTH <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S ROLES IN EDUCATION FOR THE HEALTH PROFESSIONS AS <Organization>THESE</Organization> MAY BE
AFFECTED <Organization>BY</Organization> CHANGES IN HEALTH <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> HANDLING AND MANAGEMENT. AIMS TO
DEVELOP GUIDING PRINCIPLES FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ACADEMIC HEALTH CENTRE</Organization>
ADMINISTRATORS, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ADMINISTRATORS, FEDERAL AGENCY <Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization>, AND OTHERS
INVOLVED IN <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND POLICY <Organization>DECISION</Organization> MAKING FOR HEALTH <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5052
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK <Organization>AT</Organization> FACTORIES IN <Location>SLOVAKIA</Location>.

<Organization>TRADES</Organization> UNIONS <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR FACTORY <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, ABOUT 10% OF WHICH ARE RUN
<Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>FULL</Organization> OR PART-TIME <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND THE REMAINDER <Organization>BY</Organization> VOLUNTEERS. <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
ARE <Organization>SEPARATE</Organization> FROM THE <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH CONCENTRATE <Organization>ON</Organization>
SCIENTIFIC, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC MATERIAL. <Organization>TRADES UNION</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> BEGAN <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE 19TH <Organization>CENTURY</Organization> AND IN 1948 A UNIFIED PLAN FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ORGANISATION</Organization>
AND MODERNISATION WAS BROUGHT IN. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK IS COORDINATED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>TRADES UNION</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>BRATISLAVA</Location> AND CLOSE COOPERATION WITH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IS MAINTAINED. MORE UNIFIED STANDARDS AND PROCEDURES ARE <Organization>REQUIRED</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
TECHNIQUES. THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> IMPORTANCE MUST BE
PUBLICISED AND MORE MONEY PROVIDED. STOCKS MUST BE MODERNISED AND MORE
SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> MATERIAL INCLUDED, ESPECIALLY IN PLACES WHERE <Organization>THERE</Organization>
IS NO <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5053
PROPOSED STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PROFESSIONAL HEALTH SCIENCES LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN
HOSPITALS OF <Location>NEW YORK</Location> <Organization>STATE</Organization>.

DISCUSSES IN DETAIL PROPOSED STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> HEALTH <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, DRAWN UP <Organization>BY</Organization> THE COMMITTEE FOR THE PROMOTION OF HOSPITAL
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>WESTERN</Organization> <Organization>NEW YORK LIBRARY RESOURCES COUNCIL</Organization>, IN ORDER TO
CLARIFY AND STRENGTHEN <Organization>EXISTING HOSPITAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STANDARDS. <Organization>THESE</Organization> STANDARDS
PLACE EQUAL AND <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> <Organization>EMPHASIS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; ADMINISTRATION; QUALIFICATIONS OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>; <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>; REQUIREMENT FOR A
<Organization>LIBRARY ADVISORY COMMITTEE</Organization>; <Organization>REQUIRED LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>; <Organization>REQUIRED</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
RESOURCES; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SPACE REQUIREMENTS; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUDGET; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> AND
CONSORTIUM MEMBERSHIP; <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> POLICY; AND CONTINUED
EVALUATION OF THE NEEDS OF THE HOSPITAL FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. OUTLINES THE
QUALIFICATIONS OF A HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONSULTANT.
********************************************
Document 5054
DELIVERY OF HEALTH-RELATED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO <Organization>RURAL</Organization> PRACTITIONERS.

BASED IN A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 80TH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION, <Location>WASHINGTON, DC</Location>, 18 JUNE 80. A PROGRAMME TO DEVELOP <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
RESOURCES WAS INSTITUTED IN 8 HOSPITALS AND 1 <Organization>AMBULATORY CARE</Organization> FACILITY IN THE
<Organization>RURAL</Organization> LOW COUNTRY OF <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> CAROLINA FROM JULY 78-JULY 79. THE PROGRAMME&apos;S GOAL
WAS TO INCREASE AVAILABILITY AND AWARENESS OF INFORMATIONAL RESOURCES AND
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> VALUE IN THE <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> AND IN-SERVICE EDUCATION OF HEALTH <Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization>.
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROGRAMME&apos;S INCEPTION, COMPONENTS, EVALUATION, SUCCESS AND
<Organization>IMPLICATIONS</Organization> FOR SIMILAR <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5055
RIDING THE <Organization>RURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CIRCUIT.

THE CIRCUIT RIDER LIBRARIAN CONCEPT IS DISCUSSED. THE IMPLEMENTATIONS AND
GROWTH OF THE CIRCUIT LIBRARIAN PROGRAMME SERVING <Organization>RURAL</Organization> HOSPITALS IN <Location>NEW YORK</Location>
AND PENNSYLVANIA ARE REPORTED. THE CIRCUIT RIDER LIBRARIAN&apos;S SCHEDULE AND
FUNCTIONS ARE DISCUSSED, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> TIME SPENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROAD AND <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. FINANCING, BUDGETING,
AND <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> CONTACT ARE STRESSED. DETAILED <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> STATISTICS ARE PROVIDED
TO ILLUSTRATE THE GROWTH OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>; STATISTICS ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> ANALYSED <Organization>BY</Organization>
REQUESTER CATEGORY. <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DIRECTIONS, POTENTIAL, AND RECOMMENDATIONS ARE
GIVEN FOR THE CREATION OF CIRCUIT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5056
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION FOR PEOPLE WITH SIGHT PROBLEMS IN THE <Location>GERMAN DEMOCRATIC
REPUBLIC</Location>, WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR THE BLIND IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, FOUNDED IN 1894, HAS TAKEN OVER <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>SELECTION</Organization>, PRODUCTION,
PRESENTATION AND SALES OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> FOR THE BLIND AND PARTIALLY SIGHTED IN
<Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>. LOAN STOCKS INCLUDE ABOUT 7,000 <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND 6,000 SCORES IN
BRAILLE AND OVER 3,000 TALKING <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>. MORE THAN 1,000 TITLES ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FOR
SALE. GENERALLY USERS PREFER NON-FICTION IN BRAILLE AND FICTION <Organization>ON</Organization> TAPE OR
CASSETTE. MANY OF THE 2,000 REGULAR USERS BECOME BLIND WHEN ELDERLY, SO THEY
PREFER TALKING <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> TO BRAILLE. MONTHLY LISTS OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> ADDITIONS TO STOCK ARE
<Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization>. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> NEW CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> IS SENT TO PARENTS AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>PRINT</Organization> <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>OLD</Organization> PEOPLE&apos;S HOMES. CLOSE
COOPERATION IS MAINTAINED WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ORGANISATIONS IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD, ESPECIALLY
WITH <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization> FOR THE BLIND AND MUCH ASSISTANCE IS PROVIDED FOR SERVICES IN
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES.
********************************************
Document 5057
<Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR MENTALLY RETARDED PEOPLE.

PAPER FIRST <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN 2SCANDINAVIAN PUBL. LIBR. Q1., 14 (2) 1981 FOR AN
ABSTRACT OF WHICH 2SEE1 82/1572.
********************************************
Document 5058
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND THE MENTALLY RETARDED.

PAPER 1ST <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN 2SCANDINAVIAN PUBL. LIBR. Q1., 14 (2) 1981 FOR AN
ABSTRACT OF WHICH 2SEE1 82/1573.
********************************************
Document 5059
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, RADIO AND TELEVISION IN WORK WITH YOUNG PEOPLE.

<Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE 3 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> WAYS IN WHICH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE MEDIA CAN COOPERATE. RADIO
AND TELEVISION CAN BROADCAST <Organization>RELEVANT</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS DISCUSSIONS,
INTERVIEWS WITH AUTHORS AND STORY READINGS. <Organization>LIBRARIANS CAN USE TELEVISION</Organization> AND
RADIO TO FOCUS THE ATTENTION OF YOUNG PEOPLE <Organization>ON</Organization> PARTICULAR ISSUES,
RECOMMENDING <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> AND LINKING <Organization>BOOK</Organization> DISPLAYS TO THEM. ALTERNATIVELY,
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> CAN BE ACTUALLY INVOLVED IN THE PRODUCTION OF <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> AND CAN
<Organization>USE</Organization> THEM TO PUBLICISE POPULAR <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND AUTHORS. A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization>, UNDERTAKEN IN
ROSTOV, SHOWED HOW <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> FORM OF COOPERATION COULD BE, BUT IT IS
OFTEN <Organization>DIFFICULT</Organization> TO ACHIEVE.
********************************************
Document 5060
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK FOR CHILDREN AND YOUNG PEOPLE IN THE <Location>GAMBIA</Location>.

LECTURE GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization>/<Organization>UNESCO</Organization> SEMINAR IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>, AUG 81. IN THE <Location>GAMBIA</Location>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK WITH CHILDREN IS GIVEN PRIORITY OVER THAT WITH ADULTS TO
ENCOURAGE THE SPREAD OF LITERACY. THE SERVICE MUST <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> MATERIAL TO HELP
WITH FORMAL SCHOOLING, ENCOURAGE CREATIVE AND EMOTIONAL DEVELOPMENT AND ASSIST
CHILDREN IN FINDING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. CHILDREN&apos;S DEPARTMENTS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
CATER FOR THE 11-19 <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OLDS; AN ATTRACTIVE APPEARANCE IS MAINTAINED AND
<Organization>EXTRA</Organization> ACTIVITIES LIKE STORY HOURS AND FILM SHOWS ARE PROVIDED. THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> OVER CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>PROVIDING SCHOOL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STOCKS AND ADVICE AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. ASSISTANCE IS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> PROVIDED
<Organization>BY</Organization> THE BRITISH COUNCIL. MORE <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> ARE <Organization>REQUIRED</Organization>; <Organization>THERE</Organization> ARE FEW <Organization>MODERN</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLISHING SERVICES</Organization> IN THE <Location>GAMBIA</Location>. MORE MONEY IS NEEDED, ESPECIALLY FOR
<Organization>PRIMARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND MORE COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND TEACHERS.
********************************************
Document 5061
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE PROMOTION OF <Organization>READING</Organization> HABITS IN CHILDREN.

DISCUSSES THE POTENTIAL CONTRIBUTION OF CHILDREN TO THE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT
OF A NATION, AND APPLAUDS THE <Organization>UNITED NATIONS</Organization> FOR DECLARING 1979 THE
INTERNATIONAL <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OF THE CHILD. EXAMINES <Location>NIGERIA</Location>&apos;S <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> POLICY <Organization>ON</Organization>
EDUCATION AS IT EFFECTS THE PROVISION <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>READING</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR
CHILDREN. PUTS FORWARD <Organization>SOME</Organization> RECOMMENDATIONS FOR THE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> PROVISION OF
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO MEET THE NEEDS OF <Organization>NIGERIAN</Organization>
CHILDREN.
********************************************
Document 5062
THE CHANGING ROLE OF THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE EDUCATION PROCESS.

TRACES THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization> OF <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> ADJACENT TO <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
INSTITUTIONS FROM THE ANCIENT WORLD TO THE 20TH <Organization>CENTURY</Organization>. UNTIL THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>MIDDLE</Organization> AGES <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization> WERE PART OF CENTRES OF <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> AND PROVIDED THE
MEANS OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization> FOR STUDENTS. DURING THE PERIOD WHICH STRESSED PROVISION OF A
<Organization>BASIC EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>THERE</Organization> WAS A RECESSION IN THE STATUS AND ROLE PLAYED <Organization>BY</Organization>
SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, A SITUATION CAUSED <Organization>BY</Organization> CHANGES IN <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> THEORY, <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
CHANGES AND POLITICAL AND ECONOMIC UPHEAVALS. FOCUSES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INFLUENCE OF 4
<Organization>MODERN</Organization> THEORIES OF EDUCATION UPON THE ROLE OF THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. CONCLUDES
WITH A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> COUNTRIES, ENDING WITH THE
SITUATION IN <Location>ISRAEL</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5063
LABORING IN THE VINEYARDS WILL NOT SUFFICE TO SAVE THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> VINTAGE.

<Organization>AUSTRALIAN SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> HAVING MADE <Organization>SOME</Organization> SIGNIFICANT ADVANCES IN THE
1970S APPEARS TO BE IN NEED OF AN INFLUX OF VITALITY IN THE 1980S. <Organization>OLD</Organization> AND NEW
PROBLEMS ARE INVESTIGATED, THE NEED FOR SOUND <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> IS ASSERTED, THE
QUESTIONS OF ROLE AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> IDENTITY ARE ADDRESSED AND A PLACE FOR
SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN THE LARGER <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ENVIRONMENT IS ADVOCATED. THE
PROBLEMS OF <Organization>EDUCATING SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE HIGHLIGHTED WITH <Organization>SUPPORTING</Organization>
EVIDENCE FROM A RECENT <Organization>STUDY</Organization>. CONCLUDING STATEMENTS CALL FOR A CHANGE AND
DEVELOPMENT THROUGH IMPROVED STAFFING LEVELS OF QUALIFIED PRACTITIONERS,
COUPLED WITH SOUND MANAGERIAL <Organization>PLANNING</Organization>, MONITORING, <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> AND EVALUATIVE
PROCEDURES.
********************************************
Document 5064
<Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA</Organization> PROGRAMS AND THE GIFTED AND TALENTED.

DISCUSSES THE <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> ROLE OF THE <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA</Organization> PROGRAMME IN THE
EDUCATION OF GIFTED AND TALENTED LEARNERS, AND HIGHLIGHTS THE NEED TO IMPROVE
WAYS IN WHICH THE GIFTED LEARNER CAN FIND AND <Organization>USE</Organization> A VARIETY OF MATERIAL.
DESCRIBES <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> FOR GIFTED LEARNERS WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN DEVELOPED IN
THE <Location>USA</Location> <Organization>BY</Organization>&apos; FREDERICK COUNTY PUBLIC <Organization>SCHOOLS</Organization>, MARYLAND; <Organization>TAFT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
LAKEWOOD, <Organization>OHIO</Organization>; AND RICHLAND SCHOOL DISTRICT, <Location>COLUMBIA</Location>, <Location>S.C.</Location>
********************************************
Document 5065
THE UNDERGRADUATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>: LAMONT AND THE <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> EXPERIENCE.

<Organization>THIS</Organization> REVIEW OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> UNDERGRADUATE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization>
CONTEXT FROM WHICH THEY AROSE, AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> STATUS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE 70S POINTS
<Organization>OUT</Organization> THAT A <Organization>LONG</Organization> TRADITION OF LACK OF CONCERN FOR UNDERGRADUATE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization>
NEEDS WAS BROKEN DRAMATICALLY IN 1949 <Organization>BY</Organization> THE CONSTRUCTION OF LAMONT LIBRARY,
THE <Organization>HARVARD</Organization> UNDERGRADUATE FACILITY. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> DESIGNED TO SOLVE PROBLEMS <Organization>UNIQUE</Organization>
TO HARVARD, LAMONT WAS AN EXEMPLARY CONSTRUCTION THAT SOON CAPTURED THE
IMAGINATION OF THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORLD. IT BECAME THE MODEL FOR A RASH OF
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization> SATISFYING &apos;<Organization>UNIQUE</Organization>&apos; UNDERGRADUATE NEEDS. <Organization>THESE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> PROLIFERATED DURING THE 50S AND 60S, A PERIOD OF ACCELERATED GROWTH
IN ACADEME. <Organization>BY</Organization> THE 70S, HOWEVER, THE <Organization>GENERAL FINANCIAL</Organization> RETRENCHMENT OF
<Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES HAD VIRTUALLY HALTED <Organization>NEW</Organization> CONSTRUCTION.
<Organization>FURTHER</Organization>, THE THESIS THAT PRESUMED THE NEEDS OF UNDERGRADUATES TO BE SOMEHOW
&apos;<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization>&apos;, AS WELL AS THE ADVISABI LITY OF FACILITIES EFFECTIVELY
SEGREGATING THEM FROM THE REST OF THE <Organization>ACADEMIC COMMUNITY</Organization>, CAME UNDER ATTACK IN
THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. FEW UNDERGRADUATE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE BUILT DURING
<Organization>THIS</Organization> PERIOD AND SEVERAL WERE CLOSED OR CONVERTED TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> USES. REPORT NOT
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FROM NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5066
MULTICULTURALISM AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization>
MULTICULTURALISM AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HELD AT MONASH UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>VICTORIA</Location>, <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>
FROM 7-11 NOVEMBER 1980.

THE CONFERENCE WAS ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> A COMMITTEE APPOINTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Location>VICTORIA</Location> BRANCH
OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> AND THE <Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> MULTICULTURAL
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES (VICTORIA)</Organization>. PAPERS, RELATING TO THE PROVISION OF
MULTICULTURAL <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ARE SUMMARISED.
********************************************
Document 5067
THE EMERGENCE OF JEWISH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN NINETEENTH <Organization>CENTURY</Organization> <Location>PALESTINE</Location>.

EXAMINES THE DEVELOPMENT, IN 19TH <Organization>CENTURY</Organization> <Location>PALESTINE</Location>, OF <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> TYPES OF
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; THOSE WHICH STROVE TO GATHER AND ASSEMBLE THE SPIRITUAL
HERITAGE OF THE JEWISH PEOPLE; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CREATED FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> IMMIGRANTS OF THE
1ST ALIYAH; AND THOSE ESTABLISHED TO MEET THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> NEEDS OF PUPILS AND
TEACHERS. DISCUSSES THE GROWTH OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> SOCIO-HISTORICAL
CONTEXT, TRACES <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> ROOTS IN <Location>EUROPE</Location>, AND ANALYSES THE FACTORS
WHICH STIMULATED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ESTABLISHMENT, AS WELL AS THOSE WHICH HAD A RETARDING
<Organization>EFFECT ON THEIR DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5068
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK WITH FOREIGN WORKERS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES IN <Location>HAMBURG</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

IN <Location>HAMBURG</Location> LIVE ABOUT 145,000 FOREIGNERS, MAINLY FROM <Location>TURKEY</Location>, <Location>YUGOSLAVIA</Location>,
<Location>PORTUGAL</Location>, <Location>ITALY</Location>, <Location>GREECE</Location> AND SPAIN. ONE LIBRARIAN IS RESPONSIBLE FOR THE 25,000
<Organization>BOOKS</Organization>, TAPES, NEWSPAPERS AND PERIODICALS IN 6 <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> LANGUAGES PROVIDED <Organization>ON</Organization>
AN ANNUAL BUDGET OF 200,000 DM IN THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND IN BRANCHES SERVING
AREAS WITH A <Organization>LARGE</Organization> IMMIGRANT POPULATION. THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> STOCK <Organization>EMPHASIS</Organization> SO FAR HAS
BEEN <Organization>ON</Organization> FICTION FOR ADULTS AND CHILDREN; NON-FICTION STOCKS IN FOREIGN
LANGUAGES WILL NOW BE <Organization>EXPANDED</Organization> SINCE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN THEM IS NOT ALWAYS
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> TEXTS. IT IS OFTEN <Organization>DIFFICULT</Organization> TO OBTAIN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ABOUT
<Organization>FOREIGN BOOK MARKETS</Organization> AND GERMANS KNOW LITTLE ABOUT THE WORKS THEMSELVES SINCE
FEW TRANSLATIONS ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>. IT IS <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> TO RECOGNISE THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
IDENTITY OF <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> RESIDENTS AND TO HELP THEM INTEGRATE SUCCESSFULLY <Organization>INTO</Organization>
<Organization>WEST GERMAN SOCIETY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5069
GUIDANCE OF <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> AS A WORTHWHILE ACTIVITY.

IN A TIME WHEN <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> TO WORK WITH <Organization>LARGE</Organization> NUMBERS OF READERS WITH
DEMANDS OF EVER-INCREASING COMPLEXITY, IT IS <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> TO ORGANISE PRECISELY
THE WORK OF <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> GUIDANCE. THE PROCESS <Organization>BY</Organization> WHICH A <Organization>READER</Organization> SELECTS
A <Organization>BOOK</Organization> CAN BE BROKEN DOWN <Organization>INTO</Organization> <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> STAGES AND DECISIONS, AND THE LIBRARIAN
CAN EXERT A POSITIVE INFLUENCE THROUGHOUT THE PROCESS. IF THE AIMS AND STAGES
OF THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S GUIDANCE ARE PLANNED SCHEMATICALLY BEFOREHAND, IT IS
POSSIBLE TO RECORD <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>READER</Organization>&apos;S PROGRESS AND REACTIONS IN A CONCISE CODED
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> WHICH IS SUITABLE FOR MOST <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SITUATIONS.
********************************************
Document 5070
LITERACY <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN <Location>JAMAICA</Location>.
