<Organization>Document</Organization>    1
THE <Organization>INDIAN COUNCIL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>:
A PROPOSAL FOR CONSIDERATION.

CRITICALLY EXAMINES THE <Organization>INDIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCENE. THE MANAGEMENT, OPERATION, AND
SERVICES OF MOST <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS INEFFICIENT AND INEFFECTIVE, RESULTING IN GRAVE
MISALLOCATION AND UNDERUTILISATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RESOURCES. LITTLE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
HAS BEEN CARRIED OUT. UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> COURSES ARE NOT MUCH HELP FOR
MANAGING AND OPERATING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> EFFICIENTLY. THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> SERIOUS LIMITATIONS. TO <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> THE SITUATION, PROPOSES THE ESTABLISHMENT
OF AN <Organization>INDIAN COUNCIL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. THE COUNCIL <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE <Organization>SET</Organization> UP <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>HAVE</Organization> WELL-DEFINED
ROLES AND FUNCTIONS <Organization>COVERING</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>INDIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    2
THE LINGERING FRAGRANCE: PROCEEDINGS OF THE XXIV <Organization>ALL</Organization> INDIA <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONFERENCE,
<Location>BANGALORE</Location>.

PAPERS AND PROCEEDINGS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE CONFERENCE, WITH A SUMMARY <Organization>BY</Organization> N.D. BAGARI, AND
TRANSCRIPTS OF THE INAUGURAL SPEECH, INTRODUCTORY PAPERS, AND MAIN
PRESENTATIONS. THE CONFERENCE WAS HELD <Organization>FROM</Organization> 29 JAN TO 1 FEB 78.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    3
XXV <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Location>INDIA</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONFERENCE <Location>TRIVANDRUM</Location> 14-18 MAY 1979.

PAPERS AND PROCEEDINGS OF THE CONFERENCE PAPERS RELATE TO THE <Organization>INDIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SITUATION IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN SOME OF THE STATES, AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MOVEMENT IN KERALA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    4
<Organization>MALAWI LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> SECOND ANNUAL <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> MEETING, <Organization>CHANCELLOR COLLEGE</Organization>,
SATURDAY, 26 APRIL 1980, SUMMARY OF PROCEEDINGS.

LISTS THOSE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>, AND <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> <Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE PROCEEDINGS OF THE MEETING,
WHOSE <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> <Organization>TOPICS</Organization> INCLUDED MEMBERSHIP, PUBLICATIONS, COURSES, AND
<Organization>RELATIONS</Organization> WITH INTERNATIONAL ORGANISATIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    5
A PERSONAL VIEW OF THE <Organization>ZAMBIA LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>.

PERSONAL VIEW OF THE SERVICE, BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> OBSERVATIONS MADE DURING WORK UNDER THE
<Organization>VOLUNTARY SERVICES</Organization> OVERSEAS SCHEME. IN KASAMA, THE <Organization>PROVINCIAL CENTRE</Organization> OF THE
NORTHERN PROVINCE, 3 <Organization>MAJOR PROBLEMS FACED LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>-POOR TRANSPORT; THE
LEGACY LEFT <Organization>BY</Organization> AN ACTING LIBRARIAN WHO HAD <Organization>OPERATED</Organization> HIS OWN KIND OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE WHICH WAS EXTREMELY CONFUSED ; AND THE LACK OF PROVISION FOR THE
PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF NEWLY QUALIFIED <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. IMPROVEMENTS NEED TO BE MADE TO
THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IN TERMS OF AUTHORITY, DEVELOPMENT, TRANSPORT, <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>,
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> STATUS AND PROMOTIONAL ACTIVITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    6
<Organization>CLA</Organization> 80: TURNING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE POWER.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF PROCEEDINGS OF THE 35TH ANNUAL CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
CONFERENCE, <Location>VANCOUVER</Location>, 11-17 JUNE 80, WHICH TOOK AS <Organization>ITS</Organization> THEME THE CHALLENGE OF
POWER. <Organization>AMONGST</Organization> THE <Organization>TOPICS</Organization> DISCUSSED WERE THE LIBRARIANS&apos; ASSERTION OF POWER,
AND THE POWER OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. ALSO COVERED ARE THE FINANCES OF THE <Organization>CLA</Organization>, SOCIAL
EVENTS DURING THE CONFERENCE, FUNDS AND SUPPORT FOR GAYS, AND THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> AHEAD
FOR <Organization>CLA</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    7
UNCERTAIN BEGINNINGS.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> MIDWINTER MEETING, <Location>WASHINGTON</Location> <Location>DC</Location>,
31 JAN-5 FEB 81. THE 4,307 DELEGATES EXPRESSED GRAVE DOUBTS <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
OF FEDERAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION AND TOOK THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> TENTATIVE STEPS IN A PROCESS
THAT <Organization>COULD</Organization> ULTIMATELY CHANGE THE ALA FROM A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> CONGRESS OF LIBRARIANS TO
A <Organization>LOOSE NATIONAL FEDERATION</Organization> OF LIBRARIAN ORGANISATIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    8
MIDWINTER IN REAGAN&apos;S <Location>WASHINGTON</Location>: AN ALA CONFERENCE <Organization>REPORT</Organization>.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> MIDWINTER MEETING, <Location>WASHINGTON, DC</Location>,
31 JAN-5 FEB 81. HIGHLIGHTS THE DECISION TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
DIVISIONAL MEETINGS; THE PASSING OF AN AMENDMENT TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL OF
RIGHTS; THE ACTIVITIES OF THE CANDIDATES FOR THE 1982 ALA PRESIDENCY, NORMAN
HORROCKS AND CAROL NEMEYER; THE MEETING OF ATTENDEES WITH CONGRESSIONAL
REPRESENTATIVES; AND TOURS TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF CONGRESS AND GALLAUDET COLLEGE
<Organization>LEARNING CENTER</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>    9
THE WHITE HOUSE CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES, 1979. SUMMARY,
MARCH 1980.

FOR AN ABSTRACT OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>REPORT</Organization> SEE 81/795. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   10
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>: <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> ARE JUST THE BEGINNING. THE MICHIGAN WHITE HOUSE CONFERENCE
<Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES. A <Organization>REPORT</Organization>.

DETAILS THE PROCEEDINGS OF THE MICHIGAN PRE-WHITE HOUSE CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES 26-28 MAR 79. DEMONSTRATIONS, DISPLAYS,
DISCUSSIONS, ELECTIONS, AND PARTICIPANTS ARE DESCRIBED, AND THE 68 RESOLUTIONS
ARISING <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE DISCUSSIONS ARE LISTED ACCORDING TO THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> <Organization>TOPICS</Organization>: (1)
FINANCE, (2) BARRIERS TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>, (3) OUTREACH, (4) <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>RELATIONS</Organization>, (5)
NETWORKING, AND (6) THE IMPACT OF TECHNOLOGY <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS. <Organization>REPORT</Organization>
NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   11
WHO&apos;S WHO IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 1980.

LISTS MORE THAN 1,000 PEOPLE ACTIVELY ENGAGED IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>,
GIVING <Organization>FULL</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> DETAILS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   12
TOWARDS A REDEFINITION OF BIBLIOGRAPHY.

TRACES THE HISTORY OF THE USAGE OF THE TERM BIBLIOGRAPHY, AND ARGUES FOR A
<Organization>WIDER</Organization> DEFINITION BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ANGLO-AMERICAN CONCEPT OF &apos;<Organization>REFERENCE SERVICE</Organization>&apos; TO
ACCOMMODATE THE DIVERSITY OF DOCUMENTS AND MODES OF ACCESS NOW <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   13
<Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> ESTABLISHMENTS AND <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> SERVICES IN <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 69TH CONFERENCE OF THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>GERMAN</Organization>
LIBRARIANS, <Location>BERLIN</Location>, 79. CONTRIBUTIONS ARE GROUPED AS FOLLOWS: <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
ESTABLISHMENTS, WITH GUNTER BEYERSDORFF <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>DEUTSCHES</Organization> BIBLIOTHEKSINSTITUT;
DIETER OERTEL <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DEUTSCHE FORSCHUNGSGEMEINSCHAFT; ANDREA POLDEN <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; GERHARD SCHLITT <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND DOCUMENTATION; EKKEHART
VESPER <Organization>ON</Organization> THE STAATSBIBLIOTHEK PREUSSISCHER KULTURBESITZ. <Organization>CENTRAL SERVICES</Organization>,
WITH TILO BRANDIS <Organization>ON</Organization> MANUSCRIPTS; JOHANNA EGGERT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>DEUTSCHES INSTITUT</Organization> FUR
NORMUNG; PETER LIEBENOW <Organization>ON</Organization> STATISTICS; KARL-WILHELM NEUBAUER <Organization>ON</Organization> PERIODICALS
DATA BANKS. <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, WITH ANNELIESE BUDACH <Organization>ON</Organization> RULES FOR ALPHABETICAL
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>; <Organization>HEINZ</Organization> <Organization>HABERMANN ON COOPERATIVE</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>; <Organization>HEINZ</Organization>-E. JONAS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
ODIN SYSTEM; KLAUS LAACH <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> <Organization>MONOGRAPHS</Organization>; KLAUS-DIETER LEHMANN <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN HESSE; GISELA SULE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN <Organization>NORTH</Organization> RHINE-WESTPHALIA;
MANFRED VORHOLZER <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN BAVARIA. EDUCATION, WITH KENNETH GARSIDE
<Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN THE <Location>UK</Location>; AND DETLEF SKALSKI, HERBERT BUCK, ANNI ANDREWS AND
DIETRICH FLEISCHER <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> ASPECTS OF COMBINED <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANS AND
DOCUMENTALISTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   14
<Organization>IFLA</Organization> CHALLENGES TO ACTION IN THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OF THE DISABLED.

THE 46TH <Organization>IFLA</Organization> CONFERENCE (<Location>MANILA</Location>, AUG 80), THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> HELD IN A <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
COUNTRY, AROUSED UNUSUAL INTEREST AMONG FILIPINO LIBRARIANS AND MEDIA. <Organization>IFLA</Organization>&apos;S
OBJECTIVES OF <Organization>EXTENDING INTERNATIONAL</Organization> UNDERSTANDING, COOPERATION, DEBATE,
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> FIELDS OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, CURRENTLY THROUGH <Organization>ITS</Organization>
PROGRAMMES <Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> AND UNIVERSAL AVAILABILITY OF
PUBLICATIONS WAS EMPHASISED. ACCESS TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS ESSENTIAL FOR A
COUNTRY&apos;S SOCIAL AND ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT, FINAL RESPONSIBILITY FOR <Organization>THIS</Organization>
RESTING WITH THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>. WHILE THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OF THE CHILD MUST BE FOLLOWED UP
<Organization>ESPECIALLY</Organization> IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES, THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OF THE DISABLED IS A REMINDER
THAT <Organization>HANDICAPPED</Organization> PEOPLE IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> COUNTRIES LACK EQUAL OPPORTUNITIES WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
READING GROUPS. <Organization>WORLDWIDE</Organization> ECONOMIC DIFFICULTIES MUST NOT INHIBIT THE <Organization>SEARCH</Organization>
FOR <Organization>NEW</Organization> IDEAS. CHALLENGES <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORGANISATIONS TO FOCUS ATTENTION IN 1981
PARTICULARLY <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NEED OF BLIND AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>HANDICAPPED</Organization> READERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   15
A CLEARING HOUSE FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LITERATURE-PAST EXPERIENCE AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
POSSIBILITIES.

<Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROBLEMS FACING EDITORS OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> JOURNALS IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> AND DEVELOPED COUNTRIES SUGGESTS BROAD
SOLUTIONS THAT MIGHT HELP TO TRANSFER AND MAKE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> THE SURPLUS OF
PRODUCTS IN 1 GEOGRAPHIC AREA TO ANOTHER IN WHICH <Organization>SUCH</Organization> PRODUCTS ARE IN SHORT
SUPPLY. AREAS ADDRESSED <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization> (1) <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> BACKGROUND, (2) <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>
ORGANISATIONS, (3) THE PAUCITY OF AUTHORS, (4) <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> RESPONSIBILTIES,
(5) EDITORS&apos; REQUIREMENTS, (6) UNWANTED ARTICLES, (7) THE <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> WORLD&apos;S
PROBLEMS, AND (8) THE NEED FOR A <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization> CLEARINGHOUSE. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   16
THE PLACING OF THE PERIODICAL KNIZNICE A VEDECKE INFORMACIE WITHIN THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>
OF PERIODICAL PUBLICATIONS.

<Organization>ON</Organization> THE BASIS OF <Organization>COMPARATIVE</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> OF PERIODICALS WITH RELATED THEMATICS AND
OF A SOCIOLOGICAL INVESTIGATION OF THE READERS OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> PERIODICAL, <Organization>ITS</Organization> OVERALL
POSITION WITHIN THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF <Organization>MASS COMMUNICATION MEDIA</Organization> IS GIVEN. IT IS HOPED
THAT READERS&apos; LETTERS WILL HELP IN THE EFFORT TO RAISE THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> LEVEL OF
<Organization>THIS</Organization> PERIODICAL.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   17
ZZZZ.

A <Organization>MONTHLY UK BUSINESS MAGAZINE</Organization> &apos;DEDICATED TO THE PURSUIT OF SIMPLICITY AND
UNDERSTANDING IN A COMPLEX COMMERCIAL WORLD OILED <Organization>BY</Organization> AN ENDLESS SUPPLY OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>&apos;. IT WILL EXAMINE <Organization>EVERY</Organization> ASPECT OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>: SOURCES,
INTERPRETATION, <Organization>USE</Organization>, COLLATION, STORAGE, AND RETRIEVAL. IT IS PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>PRINTEL LTD</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>EDITORIAL OFFICE</Organization> IS <Organization>AT</Organization> 55 FLEET STREET, <Location>LONDON</Location>, EC4Y 1LQ.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   18
THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT.

OUTLINE OF THE NATURE, RANGE AND SIGNIFICANCE OF THE <Organization>BLR</Organization>&amp;<Organization>D DEPARTMENT</Organization>&apos;S WORK,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> RELATIONSHIP WITH ICCSTI (THE INTERDEPARTMENTAL <Organization>COORDINATING</Organization>
COMMITTEE FOR <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>), THE R&amp;<Organization>D DEPARTMENT</Organization>&apos;S
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ROLE AND <Organization>ACHIEVEMENTS</Organization>, AND THE DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   19
AAL PRESIDENT 1981.

PROFILE OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> PRESIDENT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S ASSOCIATION OF
ASSISTANT LIBRARIANS, PATRICK CONWAY, WHOSE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPERIENCE INCLUDES WORK
IN <Location>GRIMSBY</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND GATESHEAD <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. ALSO INCLUDED IS THE
PRESIDENT&apos;S <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>YEAR</Organization> MESSAGE, ENCOURAGING LIBRARIANS TO BE MORE AGGRESSIVE TO
GAIN CREDIBILITY IN <Organization>WIDER</Organization> CIRCLES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   20
HISTORY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SUPREME COUNCIL</Organization> OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> ECONOMY.

PROMINENT SCIENTIST IN THE FIELD OF POWER <Organization>ENGINEERING</Organization>, YU.N. FLAKSERMAN WORKED
IN THE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC DEPARTMENT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SUPREME COUNCIL</Organization> OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> ECONOMY
AFTER THE CIVIL WAR. BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> WITH HIM, <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> HIS WORK FOR THE
COUNCIL, WITH <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> HIS INVOLVEMENT IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE
<Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> READING ROOM OF THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   21
WE, TOO, MUST BECOME &apos;GATEKEEPERS&apos;-OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.I

F LIBRARIANSHIP IS TO BE REFORMED, IT IS NECESSARY TO CONVINCE THOSE WHO RUN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>OR HAVE AUTHORITY</Organization> OVER LIBRARIANS, THAT PEOPLE OF A <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> OR
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> BENT <Organization>HAVE</Organization> AN <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> AND RIGHTFUL PLACE IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. (THE ARTICLE
IS A RESPONSE TO JOHN SHARP&apos;S ARTICLE IN LIBR. ASS. REC. 83 (4) APR 81,
192-193. SEE) CONTENDS THAT IF LIBRARIANS, (BOTH <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>), ADOPT
THE CORRECT PHILOSOPHY THEY WILL FIND A PLACE IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
MICROELECTRONICS REVOLUTION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   22
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION IN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>: SUMMARY OF A DISSERTATION.

SUMMARY OF AN MA THESIS SUBMITTED TO THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, ARCHIVE AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>, UNIVERSITY COLLEGE, <Location>LONDON</Location>, DEC 75. 150 <Organization>MALAYSIAN</Organization>
LIBRARIANS WERE SENT QUESTIONNAIRES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE MAIN FACTORS WHICH INFLUENCED <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
CHOICE OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AS A CAREER AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OPINIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROFESSION IN
RELATION TO <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND EDUCATION. 77 RESPONDED. 58 WERE 24-37 YEARS <Organization>OLD</Organization>; 59
WERE FEMALE; 68 HAD A <Organization>UNIVERSITY EDUCATION</Organization>; 49 CHOSE <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AFTER THEY
<Organization>FINISHED AT UNIVERSITY</Organization>; MOST LANDED IN THE PROFESSION <Organization>BY</Organization> ACCIDENT; <Organization>ALL</Organization>
FAVOURED FURTHER <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> (MOST PREFERRED TO GO ABROAD TO GAIN
<Organization>WIDER</Organization> EXPERIENCE AND ADSORB <Organization>NEW</Organization> IDEAS); 23 <Organization>WOULD</Organization> ADVISE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> CHILDREN TO BE
LIBRARIANS; 29 HAD <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> QUALIFICATIONS WHEN 1<Organization>ST</Organization> APPOINTED; 47 HAD
WORKED <Organization>ONLY</Organization> IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND MOST LIKED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> BUT
EXPRESSED DISSATISFACTION WITH SALARY AND PROMOTION PROSPECTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   23
FEELING THE DRAFT: QUALITY IN OUR ETHICAL DEBATE.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DRAFT CODE OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ETHICS PRODUCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>ASSOCIATION WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> ETHICS. LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORKERS IN THE
<Location>UK</Location> ARE LATECOMERS TO THE QUESTION OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ETHICS. A <Location>US</Location> CODE WAS
DEVELOPED IN 1938, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PROFESSIONS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> HAD CODES <Organization>SINCE</Organization> THE 19TH
CENTURY. THE OVERRIDING REASON FOR <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A CODE IS THE <Organization>PROTECTION</Organization> OF THE
CLIENT, BUT IT ALSO OFFERS <Organization>PROTECTION</Organization> FOR THE PROFESSIONALS THEMSELVES, AND
<Organization>COULD</Organization> ENHANCE THE STATUS OF THE PROFESSION. <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>VERY</Organization> HEART OF THE <Location>LA</Location> CODE
IS RESPONSIVE AND RESPONSIBLE PROFESSIONALISM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   24
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ETHICS.

CRITIQUE OF THE DRAFT CODE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ETHICS PRODUCED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION. THE CODE IS BADLY WRITTEN, CONFUSED, SILLY, CONTRADICTORY AND
THREATENS TO BRING THE <Location>LA</Location> INTO DISREPUTE. NOTES <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> LITTLE ILLUMINATION;
CODES OF ETHICS <Organization>DO</Organization> NOT PER SE BRING PROFESSIONALISM; A LIBRARIAN&apos;S PRIMARY
DUTY IS OFTEN TO A CORPORATE BODY; THERE IS CONFUSION <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> POSSIBLE CONFLICTS
IN SERVICE; AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IS IMPUDENT IN SUGGESTING THAT IT WILL
IMPOSE SANCTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THOSE WHO FAIL TO KEEP ABREAST OF DEVELOPMENTS IN
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>. SUGGESTS THAT THE <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> <Organization>WOULD</Organization> <Organization>DO</Organization> WELL TO REFER TO THE
<Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> CODE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   25
THE SUBJECT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.

THE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> DEFINITIONS OF &apos;THE SUBJECT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>&apos; ARE REVIEWED AND
<Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> APPROACHES TO THE DEFINITION OF THE SUBJECT OF A <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>
DISCIPLINE ARE DISCUSSED. IT IS SUGGESTED THAT THE SUBJECT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>
<Organization>CAN</Organization> BE DESCRIBED AS &apos;THE LAWS GOVERNING THE PROCESSES ASSOCIATED WITH AND
RELATED TO THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>&apos;, AND THE SUBJECT OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AS &apos;THE
LAWS GOVERNING THE PROCESSES ASSOCIATED WITH AND RELATED TO THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>
IN <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos;. BELIEVES THAT &apos;<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>&apos; IS NOT AN
INDEPENDENT DISCIPLINE AND ARGUES THAT THERE IS <Organization>ONLY</Organization> ONE DISCIPLINE CALLED
&apos;<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>&apos; AND THAT THE THEORETICAL PRINCIPLES OF SOVIET <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>
APPLY TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   26
FACTS AND FACTUAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE IN INFORMATICS.

INVESTIGATES <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> INTERPRETATIONS OF THE CONCEPT &apos;FACT&apos;. DEFINES FACT IN
ACCORDANCE WITH THE MARXIST THEORY AS AN ELEMENT OF OBJECTIVE REALITY. FACT IN
INFORMATICS IS A PIECE OF KNOWLEDGE WHOSE OBJECTIVE VERITY HAS BEEN
SUFFICIENTLY PROVED. FACTUAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS A PIECE OF KNOWLEDGE, INVESTIGATED
IN THEORY AND PROVED IN PRACTICE, <Organization>CAN</Organization>NOT BE CHALLENGED; IT <Organization>CAN</Organization>, HOWEVER, <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
<Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> INTERPRETATIONS. THE INFLUENCE OF FACTS AND FACTUAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
DEVELOPMENT OF INFORMATICS AS A <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> BRANCH <Organization>BY</Organization> MEANS OF THE FORMULATION
OF HYPOTHESES, THEORIES AND <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> THEORIES IS DISCUSSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   27
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO CHILDREN-A <Organization>JOB</Organization> OR A PROFESSION?.

EMPHASISES THE IMPORTANCE OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AS A PROFESSION. THE
CHILDREN&apos;S LIBRARIAN MUST BE ABLE TO COMMUNICATE WITH CHILDREN; TO INVOLVE
HIM/HERSELF CONTINUALLY WITH CHILDREN, <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AND IDEAS; TO PLAN FOR
THE DEVELOPMENT OF SERVICES; AND TO BE AWARE OF HIS/HER RESPONSIBILITIES TO
TOMORROW&apos;S ADULTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   28
THE CANDIDATES RESPOND.

PRESENTS RESPONSES TO 5 QUESTIONS <Organization>BY</Organization> THE NOMINEES FOR ALA PRESIDENT, CAROL A.
NEMEYER AND NORMAN HORROCKS. QUESTIONS RELATE TO: PROBLEMS WITH THE ALA; THE
<Organization>MAJOR</Organization> BARRIERS TO CITIZEN ACCESS TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; ATTITUDES TO
THE GROWING AUTONOMY OF ALA&apos;S DIVISIONS; ALA&apos;S ROLE IN CONTRIBUTING TO THE
DEVELOPMENT OF A &apos;<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICY&apos;; AND VIEWS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROLE OF THE
<Organization>ALA COMMITTEE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> ACCREDITATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   29
MARIANNE SCOTT: &apos;THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> VOICE IS THE <Organization>SUM</Organization> OF <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> VOICES&apos;.A

N INTERVIEW WITH MARIANNE SCOTT, WHO BECAME PRESIDENT OF THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION (<Organization>CLA</Organization>) IN JUNE 81. DISCUSSES HER VIEWS OF THE <Organization>CLA</Organization>, <Organization>ITS</Organization> GOALS, AND
THE ROLE OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> PRESIDENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   30
ANNUAL <Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>JORDAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>-1980 (IN ARABIC).

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>JLA</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE BOARD</Organization> DURING <Organization>ITS</Organization> 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>YEAR</Organization>
OF ADMINISTRATION. THE <Organization>ACHIEVEMENTS</Organization> OF 1980 EXCEEDED THOSE OF PREVIOUS YEARS
IN THE AREAS OF NUMBER OF MEETINGS HELD, <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES CONDUCTED, TRAINEES
PARTICIPATING IN THE COURSES, AND PUBLICATIONS ISSUED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   31
CHAIRMAN&apos;S <Organization>REPORT</Organization>, 1978/80.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>MALAWI LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S BOARDS AND ACTIVITIES <Organization>FROM</Organization> APR 78
TO MAR 80, WITH DETAILS OF <Organization>EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE</Organization> MEMBERSHIP, MEETINGS HELD,
MEMBERSHIP, FUND RAISING VENTURES, NATIS FOR <Location>MALAWI</Location>, PUBLICATIONS, COURSES,
EXTERNAL <Organization>RELATIONS</Organization>, AND <Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Location>TOURS</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   32
WHITHER SAILIS? THOUGHTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATION</Organization>.

THE FOUNDING OF THE <Organization>SOUTH AFRICAN INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (SAILIS) AS A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ORGANISATION HAS BEEN FAVOURABLY
RECEIVED NATIONALLY AND INTERNATIONALLY. <Organization>ITS</Organization> STRUCTURE WILL BE DEVELOPED IN
THE COMING YEARS TO FOLLOW EFFECTIVELY THE 2 BASIC PRINCIPLES LAID DOWN DURING
<Organization>ITS</Organization> PLANNING: THAT THE ENTIRE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROFESSION BE CATERED
FOR <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ORGANISATION, AND THAT PROVISION BE MADE FOR
<Organization>FULL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF INTERESTS AND REALISATION OF ASPIRATIONS OF <Organization>EVERY GROUP</Organization> IN
THE PROFESSION. HOPES THAT SAILIS WILL SERIOUSLY CONSIDER A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> AND CALLS FOR A PENETRATING <Organization>ENQUIRY</Organization> INTO THE NATURE
AND SCOPE OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FUNCTIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   33
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> LIBRARIANS FOR THE 80S.

TEXT OF A PAPER GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ANNUAL <Organization>JOINT</Organization> CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION OF <Location>IRELAND</Location>, AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, N. IRELAND BRANCH, HELD
IN BLARNEY, <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Location>CORK</Location> <Location>IN</Location> MAY 80. EXAMINES SOME LIKELY AREAS OF CONCERN OF
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANS IN THE 1980S, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>: THE NEED FOR
MORE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN THE MANAGEMENT OF THE <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization>; THE INCREASING
IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SKILLS, PARTICULARLY THOSE ASSOCIATED WITH
<Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RETRIEVAL; AND THE INCREASING IMPORTANCE OF
<Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization> AND THE ASSOCIATED ARTS OF BOOK SELECTION. ARGUES THAT
THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> <Location>UK</Location> ONE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> <Organization>POST</Organization> <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> COURSE FOR LIBRARIANS IS NOT LONG
ENOUGH, AND STRESSES THE NEED FOR <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> WITHIN THE PROFESSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   34
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IN THEORY AND PRACTICE.

IN THE <Location>USA</Location>, <Location>UK</Location> AND COMMUNIST COUNTRIES, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> IS NOW FULLY
<Organization>ESTABLISHED</Organization> AS A <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> DISCIPLINE AND INCLUDED <Organization>AMONGST UNIVERSITY</Organization>
FACULTIES. <Organization>SINCE</Organization> THE 19TH CENTURY, HOWEVER, OPINION IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location> HAS BEEN
DIVIDED AS TO <Organization>WHETHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> HAS <Organization>ITS</Organization> OWN THEORETIC BASIS OR <Organization>WHETHER</Organization>
IT CONSISTS OF PURELY PRACTICAL KNOWLEDGE. EXAMINATION OF THE RESPECTIVE
ARGUMENTS SUGGESTS THAT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE REGARDED AS AN APPLIED <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
CLOSELY LINKED WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> DISCIPLINES, E.G. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>,
<Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>, CYBERNETICS AND LINGUISTICS. <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> ASPECTS OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> EMPHASISED HITHERTO SHOULD PLAY <Organization>ONLY</Organization> A SUBORDINATE ROLE; THE
MAIN EMPHASIS MUST BE <Organization>ON</Organization> SCIENTIFICALLY BASED, ECONOMIC <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>
LINKED WITH <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. <Location>COLOGNE</Location> IS THE <Organization>ONLY GERMAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> POSSESSING A
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> FACULTY; MORE <Organization>SUCH</Organization> FACULTIES ARE NEEDED TO PRODUCE LIBRARIANS
OF THE REQUIRED CALIBRE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   35
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Location>ISRAEL</Location>.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE HISTORY OF <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Location>ISRAEL</Location>, AS OBSERVED AND RECORDED
<Organization>BY</Organization> ONE WHO HAS BEEN ACTIVE IN PART OF <Organization>ITS DEVELOPMENT</Organization>, AND NOTES THE INFLUENCE
OF <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TRADITIONS. CONCLUDES THAT IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>, AS IN MANY
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> RESPECTS, <Location>ISRAEL</Location> IS A LABORATORY WHERE THE INTERPLAY OF <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> (AND
OFTEN CONTRADICTORY) SOCIAL FORCES AND DIVERSE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> TRADITIONS <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE
OBSERVED AND, TO SOME EXTENT, TESTED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   36
IMPLICATIONS OF THE WHITE HOUSE CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES
FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> PRESENTED TO THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS OF THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS <Organization>BY</Organization> THE TASK FORCE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE IMPLICATIONS OF THE WHITE HOUSE
CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES (WHCLIS) FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>,
1980. IDENTIFIES WHCLIS RESOLUTIONS HAVING IMPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>;
EXPANDS UPON <Organization>THEIR</Organization> THEMES; MAKES RECOMMENDATIONS TO THE ASSOCIATION CONCERNING
<Organization>ITS</Organization> RESPONSE TO THE RESOLUTIONS; AND ASSUMES THAT <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTION
WILL INTERPRET THE IMPLICATIONS OF THE RESOLUTIONS ACCORDING TO <Organization>ITS</Organization>
UNDERSTANDING OF THEM AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> READINESS FOR CHANGE OR EXPANSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   37
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF INTERMEDIATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN EASTERN <Location>AFRICA</Location>.

SURVEYS <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> THE FACILITIES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF INTERMEDIATE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> CENTRES IN EASTERN <Location>AFRICA</Location>: <Organization>EAST AFRICAN SCHOOL</Organization>
OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, <Location>UGANDA</Location>; <Location>KENYA</Location> POLYTECHNIC; <Organization>TANZANIA LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>; SCHOOL
OF EXTRA MURAL <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>, UNIVERSITY OF <Location>KHARTOUM</Location>, <Location>SUDAN</Location>; DEPARTMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>, <Organization>ADDIS ABABA UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>ETHIOPIA</Location>; <Organization>MINDOLA EUCUMENICAL FOUNDATION</Organization>,
KITWE, <Location>ZAMBIA</Location>; UNIVERSITY COLLEGE, <Location>BOTSWANA</Location>; AND SCHOOL OF ADMINISTRATION,
UNIVERSITY OF <Location>MAURITIUS</Location>. INCLUDES THE SYLLABUSES FOR COURSES RUN <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>THESE</Organization>
CENTRES. <Organization>INDICATES</Organization> SOME OF THE PROBLEMS OF INSUFFICIENT <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, BUILDINGS, AND
TEACHING <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FACED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>THESE</Organization> CENTRES, AND SUGGESTS SOME WAYS OF MAKING
<Organization>EXISTING</Organization> TEACHING PROGRAMMES MORE <Organization>USEFUL</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   38
THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> <Organization>AT DALHOUSIE UNIVERSITY</Organization>.

THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, <Organization>DALHOUSIE UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Organization>HALIFAX</Organization>, NOVA SCOTIA, WAS
<Organization>ESTABLISHED</Organization> IN 1969, IN RESPONSE TO THE NEED FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> WITHIN
<Location>CANADA</Location>&apos;S ATLANTIC PROVINCES. A PRAGMATIC <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> APPROACH ENCOURAGES
STUDENTS TO WORK WITH <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AS <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> OBJECTS, WITH COURSES IN PRINTING
HISTORY, BOOKBINDING AND PRESERVATION. THE SCHOOL&apos;S EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PHYSICAL
BOOK IS SEEN AS AN EXAMPLE <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS SHOULD FOLLOW.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   39
FUNDING FOR <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO INDIVIDUALS IN THE FIELD OF
LIBRARIANSHIPS.

<Organization>THIS</Organization> DIRECTORY OF SOURCES OF FINANCIAL AID FOR LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>
MEMBERS INTERESTED IN <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> LISTS <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization>, <Organization>STATE SCHOOL AGENCIES</Organization>, <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> AGENCIES, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS IN THE <Location>US</Location> AND CANADA, AND FEDERAL AGENCIES. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROVIDED
INCLUDES THE ADDRESS, A CONTACT PERSON, FUNDS <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PURPOSE,
ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS, <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PLANS FOR FUNDING, AND DIRECTIONS FOR
<Organization>APPLICATION</Organization>. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   40
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> PERIMETERS FOR EAST AND <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>AFRICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PERSONNEL.

DISCUSSES THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>, AND <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE FACILITIES
FOR THE <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PERSONNEL WHICH EXIST IN <Organization>EAST</Organization> <Location>AFRICA</Location>
TODAY. GIVES BRIEF DETAILS OF THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> PROGRAMMES IMPLEMENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE EAST
<Organization>AFRICAN SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, <Location>UGANDA</Location>: <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES IN
DOCUMENTATION; <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> COURSE IN DOCUMENTATION TECHNIQUES; IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
COURSES FOR SCHOOL LIBRARIANS; AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS COURSE. MAKES
SUGGESTIONS FOR IMPROVING THE <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> PROVIDED
IN <Location>UGANDA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   41
<Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> CHANGE IN THE 80S-TIME FOR SIGNIFICANT DEVELOPMENTS.

A BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY-FUNDED CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PROJECT, BEGUN IN 1978, IS NOW
IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> FINAL STAGES. IT HAS ASSUMED THAT NOW IS A GOOD <Organization>TIME</Organization> TO CONSIDER
CHANGE, THAT SIGNIFICANT CHANGE IS NEEDED IN THE STRUCTURE AND CONTENT OF
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>UK</Location>, AND THAT ULTIMATELY IT IS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOL STAFFS WHO WILL DECIDE WHAT CHANGES TO MAKE, AND WHEN. DISCUSSES SOME
OF THE QUESTIONS CONSIDERED OF INTEREST IN THE <Organization>CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT</Organization>
PROJECT&apos;S FINDINGS, AND WHICH WILL INDICATE THE SCOPE OF A <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> GROUP MEETING TO BE HELD IN SEPT 81 TO DISCUSS THE PROJECT
AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> IMPLICATIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   42
MARKET RECEPTIVITY FOR AN EXTENDED M.L.S.

AS PART OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF AN EXTENDED MASTER&apos;S DEGREE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization>, THE <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization>
DISTRIBUTED A QUESTIONNAIRE TO A <Organization>REPRESENTATIVE</Organization> CROSS-SECTION OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>,
<Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>, SCHOOL, AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIANS, SOLICITING <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESPONSES TO THE
RELATIVE MERITS OF (1) A 1-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> VERSUS EXTENDED MASTER&apos;S <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND (2) A 1-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> MASTER&apos;S IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> WITH AND WITHOUT A 2ND
MASTER&apos;S IN ANOTHER SUBJECT. THE RESPONSES INDICATED THAT RESPONDENTS WERE
SPEAKING IN TERMS OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND EXPERIENCE, RATHER THAN IN TERMS
OF <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS AND NEEDS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE SURVEY RESULTS ARE THUS
BEST DESCRIBED AS <Organization>USEFUL</Organization> BUT INCONCLUSIVE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   43
THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF THE ARCHIVE PROFESSION IN <Location>QUEBEC</Location>: <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, EDUCATION AND
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.

THE ARCHIVE PROFESSION IN <Location>QUEBEC</Location> CURRENTLY FACES A <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF CRISIS BECAUSE OF
LACK OF FINANCE, PERSONNEL, AND PROVISION FOR <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. TO DEMONSTRATE BOTH
THE NECESSITY FOR AND THE FEASIBILITY OF ESTABLISHING A COURSE IN ARCHIVE
<Organization>STUDIES</Organization>, PARALLELS ARE DRAWN WITH <Organization>DOCUMENT MANAGEMENT</Organization> IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, SHOWING THE
SIMILARITIES OF THE TASKS INVOLVED AND THE INTERDEPENDENCE OF THE 2 FIELDS OF
OPERATION. A <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> WHICH <Organization>WOULD</Organization> SERVE FOR BOTH IS OUTLINED. THE
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS ARE URGED TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> SUPPORT FOR ARCHIVE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>,
AND RECOMMENDATIONS MADE TO <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> TO ENSURE A SECURE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> FOR <Organization>PRIVATE</Organization>
AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> ARCHIVES IN THE PROVINCE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   44
THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF PROBLEMS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION IN THE COURSE OF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
PERSONNEL IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS IN THE <Location>USSR</Location> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> SOCIALIST
COUNTRIES.

<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN INSTITUTIONS OF <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> IN SOCIALIST COUNTRIES
REGULARLY <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION. THE TOPIC IS <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> INTO
COURSE SYLLABUSES AND TEXTBOOKS, AND IS DISCUSSED IN DETAIL IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> COURSES AS
&apos;ORGANIZATION AND MANAGEMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>&apos; TAUGHT <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS IN THE <Location>USSR</Location>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> COURSE INCLUDES THEMES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MANAGEMENT, PLANNING OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> WITHIN THE
<Location>USSR</Location>, <Organization>ALL</Organization> STRESSING THE IMPORTANCE OF LEGISLATION. A <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> COURSE <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION ADDRESSES THE PRINCIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LAWS OF SOCIALIST AND
NON-SOCIALIST COUNTRIES; MOREOVER, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION IS INTERWOVEN
THROUGHOUT THE STUDENT <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OF <Organization>STUDY</Organization>. SIMILAR
PROGRAMMES EXIST IN INSTITUTIONS IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>, <Location>POLAND</Location>, <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>,
<Location>BULGARIA</Location>, <Location>HUNGARY</Location> AND <Organization>OT</Organization> HER SOCIALIST COUNTRIES. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
<Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   45
MARKETING AND MARKETING <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>: WHAT THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MANAGER SHOULD LEARN.

DISCUSSES THE NEED FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> MANAGERS TO BE TRAINED
IN MARKETING AND MARKET <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TECHNIQUES. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> SOME OF THE CONCEPTUAL
BARRIERS AND IDEOLOGICAL STIMULANTS TO MARKETING EDUCATION AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, AND
CONSIDERS THE QUESTION OF WHO SHOULD <Organization>DO</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. <Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization>
CONTEMPORARY <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PROGRAMMES WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> INCLUDED, OR FOCUSED <Organization>ON</Organization>, MARKETING
FOR THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>, AND PROPOSES A PROSPECTUS FOR A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MANAGEMENT COURSE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   46
GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>.

<Organization>THESE</Organization> GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT</Organization> FOR DOCUMENTALISTS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SPECIALISTS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS, AND LIBRARIANS STRESS THE NEED FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization>
PARTIES TO THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROCESS, IN WHATEVER CAPACITY OR COUNTRY, TO
RECEIVE A COMMON <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> THAT WILL ENABLE THEM TO UNDERSTAND ONE ANOTHER AND
TO COLLABORATE <Organization>ON</Organization> EQUAL TERMS TO THE PROGRESS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TRANSFER. <Organization>REPORT</Organization>
NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   47
<Organization>LEARNING</Organization> HOW TO HELP THE <Organization>CITIZEN</Organization>.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE THINKING BEHIND AND EXPERIENCE OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> SHORT COURSE <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FOR THE COMMUNITY, ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE CENTRE FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>, <Organization>CITY UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>LONDON</Location> FOR STUDENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> MSC AND DIPLOMA COURSES AND
OTHERS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>ADVICE</Organization> CENTRES. THE COURSE
HAS THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> LIBRARIANS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OFFICERS AND OTHERS TO HELP
SOLVE SOCIAL AND PERSONAL PROBLEMS IN HOUSING, EMPLOYMENT, SOCIAL WELFARE AND
THE <Organization>WHOLE</Organization> RANGE OF LEGAL PROBLEMS. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE COVERAGE OF THE COURSE,
STUDENT REACTION TO IT (TO DATE, 29 <Organization>HAVE</Organization> ATTENDED), AND THE PHILOSOPHY BEHIND
THE COURSE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   48
A <Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF TWO MONTHS&apos; <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>OTAGO</Organization>
UNIVERSITY, DUNEDIN, <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>, FEBRUARY 10-MARCH 31, 1979.

THE VISIT WAS <Organization>UNDERTAKEN</Organization> TO FURTHER THE AUTHOR&apos;S KNOWLEDGE IN THE FIELD OF
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>, THROUGH AN ATTACHMENT TO THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>/DENTAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
OF THE <Organization>OTAGO UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>OBSERVATION</Organization> AND PRACTICE OF THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF
OPERATION IN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AN ADVANCED <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   49
A SURVEY OF <Organization>RURAL LIBRARIANS ON CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>.

PRESENTS THE METHODS AND RESULTS OF A SURVEY OF <Location>US</Location> <Organization>RURAL</Organization> LIBRARIANS TO <Organization>SAMPLE</Organization>
<Organization>THEIR OPINIONS ON CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>. ANALYSES THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OBTAINED <Organization>ON</Organization>:
THE <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> COURSES TAKEN <Organization>BY</Organization> PARTICIPANTS&apos; <Organization>THEIR</Organization> VIEWS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
VALUE OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> COURSES; AND SOME REASONS WHICH WERE GIVEN FOR NOT <Organization>TAKING</Organization>
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> COURSES. DRAWS A NUMBER OF CONCLUSIONS <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE LIKES
AND DISLIKES OF <Organization>RURAL</Organization> LIBRARIANS, AND WHAT THEY PERCEIVE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> NEEDS TO BE IN
<Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   50
GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>FORMULATING POLICY ON EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, AND DEVELOPMENT OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PERSONNEL.

<Organization>THESE</Organization> GUIDELINES <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>ADVICE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> ISSUES AND FACTORS TO BE
CONSIDERED IN <Organization>FORMULATING</Organization> AN <Organization>INFORMATION MANPOWER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> POLICY,
<Organization>ESPECIALLY AS CONCERNS EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PERSONNEL. THE
CHANGING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ENVIRONMENT AND SOCIAL NEEDS WILL DICTATE MODIFICATIONS
OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> GUIDELINES AND THE FORMULATION OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> ONES. DISCUSSES THE IMPACT OF
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> REVOLUTION, THE CONCERN OF INTERNATIONAL ORGANISATIONS, AND
THE NEED FOR POLICY GUIDELINES. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   51
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>HANDICAPPED</Organization> INDIVIDUALS.

PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS CONFERENCE,
<Location>AUSTIN</Location>, <Organization>TEXAS</Organization>, FEB 80. <Organization>US FEDERAL</Organization> LEGISLATION NOW <Organization>REQUIRES</Organization> THAT <Organization>HANDICAPPED</Organization>
INDIVIDUALS BE GIVEN AN OPPORTUNITY FOR <Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>. DISCUSSES THE
IMPACT OF <Organization>SUCH LEGISLATION ON LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN TERMS OF NEEDED
MODIFICATION IN <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> CONTENT, MEDIA FORMATS, AND ACCESS TO PROGRAMMES
AND SERVICES. <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> OPPORTUNITY RESULTS IN OCCUPATIONAL OPPORTUNITY AND
<Organization>REQUIRES</Organization> BASIC <Organization>JOB</Organization> REDEFINITION, AS IN THE <Organization>NEW AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
STATEMENT <Organization>ON</Organization> EMPLOYMENT OPPORTUNITIES FOR THE <Organization>HANDICAPPED</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
EMPHASIS IS PLACED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE NEED TO MODIFY STEREOTYPED ATTITUDES OF FACULTY,
STUDENTS, AND PROFESSIONALS PEERS CONCERNING HANDICAPPED PERSONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   52
<Location>PARIS</Location> &apos;80: AAL <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR TO FRANCE, OCTOBER 80.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE 1980 <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR OF <Location>PARIS</Location> <Organization>BY</Organization> MEMBERS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S
ASSOCIATION OF ASSISTANT LIBRARIANS. INCLUDED IN THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> WERE VISITS TO
THE BIBLIOTHEQUE PUBLIQUE D&apos;<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>POMPIDOU CENTRE</Organization>, THE SERVICE
TECHNIQUE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>, AND TO THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> CERGY-PONTOISE, OUTSIDE
<Location>PARIS</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   53
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR OF SWEDISH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> LIBRARIANS <Organization>FROM</Organization> EASTERN, <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> AND
SOUTHERN <Location>AFRICA</Location>, 30TH AUGUST-20TH SEPTEMBER 1980.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> A GROUP OF LIBRARIANS <Organization>FROM</Organization> SCECSAL (<Organization>STANDING</Organization>
CONFERENCE OF THE EASTERN, <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> AND SOUTHERN <Organization>AFRICAN</Organization> LIBRARIANS) TO SWEDISH
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AUG-SEPT 80. <Organization>ITS</Organization> PURPOSE WAS TO ENABLE VISITING LIBRARIANS TO VIEW
THE LATEST DEVELOPMENTS IN <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>, TO DISCUSS <Organization>AFRICAN</Organization>
PROBLEMS WITH SWEDISH LIBRARIANS, AND TO ESTABLISH THE BEGINNINGS OF A
<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> EXCHANGE <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> SWEDISH AND SCECSAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   54
THE 1980 DIRECTORY OF <Organization>LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Location>NEW YORK</Location> <Organization>STATE</Organization> WITH LISTINGS <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
AS OF DECEMBER 1979.

THE 1980 EDITION OF A DIRECTORY TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEMS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> MEMBER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN <Location>NEW YORK</Location> <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>COMPILED</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SUPPLIED <Organization>BY</Organization> DIRECTORS OF THE
SYSTEMS AND <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>DEPARTMENTS OR AGENCIES</Organization> ADMINISTERING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROGRAMMES.
<Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   55
A BIBLIOGRAPHY OF WEST VIRGINIA <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HISTORY.

BIBLIOGRAPHY OF <Organization>BOOKS</Organization>, PERIODICALS AND THESES, INTENDED TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> BASIC
COVERAGE OF THE PUBLISHED <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> DEALING WITH WEST VIRGINIA <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
HISTORY. IN SOME CASES IT WAS FOUND TO BE DIFFICULT TO LOCATE CITATIONS, AND
<Organization>EVEN</Organization> MORE DIFFICULT TO EXAMINE <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>. MANY WORKS IDENTIFIED NEITHER
PUBLISHER NOR PRINTER, NOR DID THEY IDENTIFY A CORPORATE BODY. ENTRIES ARE
ARRANGED ALPHABETICALLY <Organization>BY</Organization> TYPE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND NAME OF <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OR
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> REGION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   56
MIDF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

FORMED IN MAR 60, THE <Organization>MALAYSIAN INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> FINANCE BERHAD (MIDF)
HAS BECOME THE COUNTRY&apos;S <Organization>LEADING DEVELOPMENT</Organization> FINANCING INSTITUTION WITH 2
SUBSIDIARY AND 2 ASSOCIATE COMPANIES AND 7 BRANCHES. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS
<Organization>ESTABLISHED</Organization> IN 1962 AND GREW RAPIDLY AS MIDF EXPANDED. IN 1972, THE <Organization>MALAYSIAN</Organization>
<Organization>INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> FINANCE <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> CONSULTANTS (MIDFIC, ONE OF THE
SUBSIDIARIES) <Organization>SET</Organization> UP A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE 2 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE MERGED IN 1973. THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAD 6,000 <Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND PAMPHLETS, 485 PERIODICAL TITLES, 60 MAPS, 1,250
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AND <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> COMPANY AND <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> INSTITUTION ANNUAL REPORTS,
250 REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> INDUSTRY, AND 550 TRADE CATALOGUES. THE EMPHASIS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RUNS <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>AWARENESS</Organization>, <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>, <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>SEARCH</Organization>,
SIMPLE TRANSLATION, AND <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LOAN SERVICES</Organization> AND IS INVOLVED IN THE
<Organization>SMALL-SCALE INDUSTRIES INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   57
IALL <Location>MANILA</Location> ROUNDTABLE AND <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> MEETING: A FURTHER <Organization>REPORT</Organization>.

<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF LAW <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ROUNDTABLE AND
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> MEETING <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 46TH <Organization>IFLA</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> CONFERENCE, <Location>MANILA</Location>, <Location>PHILIPPINES</Location>,
18-23 AUG 80, WHOSE THEME WAS &apos;THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SYSTEMS: GLOBAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> EXCHANGE FOR <Organization>GREATER INTERNATIONAL</Organization> UNDERSTANDING&apos;.
<Organization>SESSIONS INCLUDED TOURS</Organization> OF ONGSIAKO LAW OFFICES AND THE <Organization>SUPREME</Organization> COURT, AND A
VISIT TO THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> ASSEMBLY (BATASANG PAMBANSA), AND <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> PAPERS WHICH
ARE SUMMARISED <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   58
THE WOMEN&apos;S HISTORY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>: NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> A DECADE.

DISCUSSES THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF THE WOMEN&apos;S HISTORY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WOMEN&apos;S HISTORY
<Organization>RESEARCH CENTER</Organization>, INC., <Location>BERKELEY</Location>, CALIFORNIA, WHICH DOCUMENTED <Organization>PAST</Organization> AND
CONTEMPORARY HISTORY OF WOMEN. DUE TO LACK OF FUNDS, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CLOSED IN
1974, BUT MUCH OF THE STOCK IS <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MICROFILM</Organization> AND NORTHWESTERN
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   59
THE <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCENE IN <Location>EGYPT</Location>.

<Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>EGYPT</Location>, AS PART OF A BROADER <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CONTEXT, <Organization>DO</Organization> NOT
PLAY A VITAL ROLE IN THE PRESERVATION, SURVEY, AND DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>ART</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN THE COUNTRY. <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES LACK THE RECOGNITION AND
FINANCIAL SUPPORT NECESSARY TO ALLOW THEM TO BECOME ACTIVE, UP-TO-DATE <Organization>ART</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CLEARINGHOUSES. DISCUSSES 2 <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>ART</Organization> DOCUMENTATION CENTRES IN
<Location>CAIRO</Location>: THE <Organization>EGYPTIAN MUSEUM</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE CRESSWELL <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE <Organization>AMERICAN UNIVERSITY</Organization>. IDENTIFIES COMMON PROBLEMS AMONG <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
SUGGESTS STEPS WHICH <Organization>COULD</Organization> LEAD TO <Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> CONDITIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   60
THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.

DISCUSSES THE ROLE OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE INTERNATIONAL CONTEXT, WITH
<Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO UNESCO RECOMMENDATIONS. TRADITIONAL AND <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> FUNCTIONS ARE
DESCRIBED, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO CANADA: ACQUISITION, CONSERVATION, MAINTAINING A
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY, AND MAKING <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>. THE ADDITIONAL ESSENTIAL
FUNCTIONS ARE THEN DETAILED: THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION, AND PROMOTION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   61
THE EVOLUTION OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>NIGERIA</Location>: ANTECEDENTS, ESTABLISHMENT,
AND RECENT DEVELOPMENTS.

A HISTORY OF THE SETTING-UP OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Location>NIGERIA</Location>. INCLUDES
SECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>: FACTORS IN THE RISE OF <Organization>MODERN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>NIGERIA</Location>; THE CONCEPT
OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> BEFORE 1940; <Organization>STANDING COMMITTEE</Organization> TO
ADVISE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROVISION OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; THE 1953 <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> SEMINAR <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>AFRICA</Location>; THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ADVISORY</Organization>
COMMITTEE; THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>FORD FOUNDATION</Organization>; <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION; AND
<Organization>MAJOR</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS <Organization>SINCE</Organization> 1970. CONCLUDES WITH A SUMMARY OF <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>AIMS</Organization> AND
PROBLEMS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   62
THE <Organization>BOTSWANA NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>-ORGANISATION TASKS AND CONTRIBUTION TO
<Organization>NATIONAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.

DISCUSSES THE MULTI-FUNCTIONAL ROLE OF THE <Organization>BOTSWANA NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>
(<Organization>BNLS</Organization>) WHICH, AS WELL AS ACTING AS A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, IS ALSO RESPONSIBLE
FOR: THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>; THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>; THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
AND <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>; <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT; AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
PROVIDES <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>BNLS</Organization>: ORGANISATIONAL
STRUCTURE; STAFFING; BUDGET; BOOKSTOCK; AND USERS. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE CONTRIBUTION
OF THE <Organization>BNLS</Organization> TO THE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT OF <Location>BOTSWANA</Location> IN THE AREAS OF:
AGRICULTURE AND <Organization>RURAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENT; WATER AND MINERAL RESOURCES; EDUCATION AND
MANPOWER. HIGHLIGHTS THE PART TO BE PLAYED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN THE
ESTABLISHMENT OF A <Organization>DEMOCRATIC SOCIETY</Organization> IN <Location>BOTSWANA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   63
THE HISTORY AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> OF <Location>MALAWI</Location> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
1968-1980.

(<Organization>MLS</Organization> DISSERTATION.) THE <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> OF <Location>MALAWI</Location> WAS <Organization>ESTABLISHED</Organization> IN
1967, WITH <Organization>FREE SERVICES</Organization> PROVIDED THROUGH THE HEADQUARTERS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Location>LILONGWE</Location>, <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> AND BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CENTRES TO PRIMARY AND
SECONDARY SCHOOLS, THE <Organization>POSTAL LOAN SERVICE</Organization> TO OUTLYING REGIONS, AND TO THOSE
WHOSE NEEDS ARE NOT SATISFIED THROUGH THE <Organization>LIBRARY CENTRE</Organization> COLLECTIONS.
DISCUSSES PROBLEMS, COLLECTIONS, STOCK AND USAGE, AND THE LIKELY <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF THE
SERVICE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   64
THE <Organization>MUSIC DIVISION</Organization>.

THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>CANADA MUSIC DIVISION</Organization>&apos;S PRINCIPAL <Organization>AIM</Organization> IS TO BUILD THE
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF MUSICAL CANADIANA. <Organization>ITS</Organization> RESPONSIBILITIES IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREAS
ARE THE WORLD&apos;S BASIC PRINTED <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MUSIC</Organization>, <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> MOST LIKELY TO
BE BORROWED <Organization>BY</Organization> SMALLER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND THE ESSENTIAL BACKGROUND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> FOR
CANADIAN <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>. IT ALSO RECEIVES GIFTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>FOREIGN</Organization> GOVERNMENTS AND
ACQUIRES RARE <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> CANADIAN INTEREST IN DANGER OF BEING SCATTERED OR
SOLD ABROAD. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>BRIEFLY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> SCOPE; <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> HIGHLIGHTS;
SERVICES TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; EXHIBITIONS; PUBLICATIONS; AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
PROSPECTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   65
THE OBJECTIVES OF THE LAW COURTS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Location>SYDNEY</Location>.

THE LAW COURTS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS A <Organization>JOINT</Organization> COMMONWEALTH/<Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ESTABLISHED</Organization> TO
OBTAIN, EXPLOIT AND <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> LEGAL <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>SUPREME</Organization>
COURT OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> WALES, FEDERAL COURT AND COMMONWEALTH COMMISSIONS AND
TRIBUNALS. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SERVICE OBJECTIVES (TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
AND <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> TO THE JUDICIARY AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COURT PERSONNEL); INTERNAL OBJECTIVES
(TO BACK-UP IN-SERVICE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>); AND <Organization>RELATIONS</Organization> WITH PARENT BODIES-THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>NSW</Organization>; <Organization>NSW DEPARTMENT</Organization> OF THE ATTORNEY <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND OF JUSTICE, AND THE
<Organization>AUSTRALIAN DEPARTMENT</Organization> OF THE ATTORNEY <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   66
<Organization>MEASURING LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>-TO CUT COSTS?.

<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE PROCESS OF <Organization>MEASURING</Organization> THE QUALITY OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>,
PARTICULARLY IN THE LIGHT OF THE BRITISH <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>&apos;S INTENTION TO INTRODUCE A
PROCESS WHEREBY <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> MUST DISCLOSE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> COSTS AND
PERFORMANCE TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, WITH THE RESULT THAT EXPENDITURE <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
AUTHORITIES IS REDUCED TO THE <Organization>LOWEST SPENDING AUTHORITY</Organization>&apos;S LEVEL, AND NOT TO
THE LEVEL OF THE AUTHORITY PROVIDING THE <Organization>HIGHEST QUALITY SERVICES</Organization>. MEASURES
SHOULD REFLECT THE DESIRED OUTCOME OF THE SERVICES OFFERED, AND LIBRARIAN&apos;S
ATTEMPTS TO AUDIT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK WILL <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT THEY ARE
TRYING TO <Organization>DO</Organization> FOR SOCIETY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   67
<Organization>DO LIBRARIANS CARE</Organization> FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PAST</Organization>?.

A SURVEY OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> 166 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTHORITIES IN THE <Location>UK</Location> WAS CARRIED OUT TO
DETERMINE <Organization>WHETHER LIBRARIANS TAKE AS MUCH CARE</Organization> IN PRESERVING THE
CORRESPONDENCE, MEMORANDA, PLANS, MINUTES AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> RECORDS OF THE <Organization>PAST</Organization>, AS
THEY <Organization>DO</Organization> IN PRESERVING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> SORTS OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ORGANISATIONS. IN
MANY CASES THERE WAS EVIDENCE OF A LACK OF CLEARLY THOUGHT-OUT POLICIES.
<Organization>REVIEWS</Organization> THE RESULTS OF THE SURVEY. IN ORDER TO OBTAIN THE NECESSARY <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization>
PERSPECTIVE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PROBLEMS THE NEED FOR A <Organization>USABLE FUND</Organization> OF SOURCE <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization>
IS INESCAPABLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   68
STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>: REACTIONS TO A <Organization>REPORT</Organization> (3).

PARTS 1 AND 2 OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> ARTICLE APPEARED IN BIBLIOTHEEK EN SAMENLEVING 9 (2) FEB
81, 46-51 AND 9 (3) MAR 81, 80-85 RESPECTIVELY. THE RECOMMENDED STANDARDS FOR
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, WHICH WERE PUBLISHED <Organization>RECENTLY</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>), HAS AROUSED MUCH OPPOSITION <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES. THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization>
WAS SUBMITTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE NBLC TO THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>, WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR <Organization>ONLY</Organization> 20%
OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FINANCE. THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES, WHICH ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE REMAINING 80%, WILL BE REQUIRED TO RAISE <Organization>LARGE</Organization> SUMS OF MONEY <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
TAXATION TO MEET THE RECOMMENDED STANDARDS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   69
RECOMMENDED STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>: A MORE DETAILED EXPLANATION.

IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> THE RECOMMENDED STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
<Organization>RECENTLY</Organization> BEEN PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE KOMMISSIE KOORDINATIE NORMERING. THE COMMITTEE
WAS FORMED IN 1977 TO CONSOLIDATE AND EXPAND THE STANDARDS PROPOSED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
MEETING OF THE NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>) IN MAR OF THAT <Organization>YEAR</Organization>. THE COMITTEE HAS BEEN
CRITICISED FOR THE OMISSION OF A THEORETICAL BASIS TO THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization>. HOWEVER, AS
<Organization>THESE</Organization> ARE THE FIRST STANDARDS TO BE PUBLISHED, THE COMMITTEE HOPES THAT THEY
WILL FORM THE THEORETICAL BASIS IN <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> DISCUSSIONS. IT ALSO INTENDS TO
INCORPORATE THE CRITICISM LEVELLED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>REPORT</Organization> IN A <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> REVISION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   70
INSTITUTION BUILDING FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN <Location>TAIWAN</Location>.

<Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> <Location>TAIWAN</Location>&apos;S ECONOMY IS BOOMING, THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN NEGLECTED
FOR DECADES AND <Organization>THIS</Organization> NEGLECT <Organization>COULD</Organization> HARM THE ECONOMIC GROWTH. SUGGESTS THAT THE
MINISTRY OF EDUCATION <Organization>SET</Organization> UP AN OFFICE OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO BRING <Organization>ABOUT</Organization>
REFORMS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   71
<Location>DURHAM</Location> MOBILEMEET.

A BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> MOBILEMEET TO BE HELD IN THE NORTH-EAST OF
ENGLAND, 6 SEPT 80, <Location>ST. MARY&apos;S</Location> COLLEGE, <Location>DURHAM</Location>. 79 PEOPLE WITH 12 VEHICLES
ATTENDED TO HEAR SPEECHES <Organization>BY</Organization> ANNE BETTISON, JUDITH BOWEN, STAN DEEM AND DAVID
GREAVES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   72
THE <Organization>AIMS</Organization> OF <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.

DURING THE LAST 13 YEARS OF THE 20 YEARS&apos; EXISTENCE OF <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>
IN <Organization>FINLAND THIS SERVICE</Organization> HAS BECOME OF <Organization>CONSIDERABLE</Organization> IMPORTANCE. THERE IS A
<Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STANDARD AND THE <Organization>FINNISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> HAS <Organization>SET</Organization> UP A
<Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY WORKING GROUP</Organization>. <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF DRIVERS HAS BEEN NEGLECTED <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization>
THEY DEAL WITH THE BULK OF THE <Organization>LOANS</Organization>. THE MOBILES, UNTIL THE INTRODUCTION OF
THE STANDARD, WERE UNCOMFORTABLE AND WASTEFUL IN ENERGY, AND HAD A SHORT LIFE.
<Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>YEAR</Organization> 4.5 <Organization>MILLION</Organization> F MARKS WILL BE SPENT <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> MOBILES <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> 12 <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
AUTHORITIES. 40 AUTHORITIES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> APPLIED FOR A <Organization>GRANT</Organization>. THE <Organization>FOLLOWING</Organization> ASPECTS OF
A <Organization>MOBILE SERVICE</Organization> NEED <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>: <Organization>IMPROVED SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RATIONALISATION,
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF DRIVERS, COOPERATIVE PURCHASE OF MOBILES <Organization>BY</Organization> 2 OR MORE AUTHORITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   73
SETTING UP OF A <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> SECTION: NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>WORKING</Organization> PROCESSES IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>.

THE 3<Organization>RD</Organization> PART OF THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> DEALING WITH THE SETTING UP OF A <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> SECTION IN A
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS ENTITLED &apos;INTER-DISCIPLINARY TEAM&apos;. PARTS 1, 2 AND 4
APPEARED IN CTENAR 32 (11) (12) AND 33 (3) . THE TASKS CONCERNING A <Organization>MUSIC</Organization>
SECTION <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE DIVIDED INTO 4 AREAS: <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPHERE,
MUSICOLOGICAL SPHERE, PEDAGOGICAL SPHERE AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC SPHERE. A
SPECIALIST WORKS IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF THEM AND THEY <Organization>ALL</Organization> COOPERATE WITH <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization>.
DECISIONS CONCERNING THE FINAL SYNTHESIS ARE MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE MANAGER-LIBRARIAN.
THE COMPETENCE OF THE ADVISERS-SPECIALISTS AND THE LIMITS TO WHICH THE
LIBRARIAN SHOULD LET THEM INTERFERE WITH HIS <Organization>JOB</Organization> ARE DISCUSSED IN <Organization>GREATER</Organization>
DETAIL.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   74
<Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; <Organization>REGIONAL SERVICE</Organization>-PROBLEMS AND <Organization>LINES</Organization> OF DEVELOPMENT.

THE <Organization>NORWEGIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS CURRENTLY IN A PHASE OF STAGNATION, PARTLY DUE
TO ECONOMIC FACTORS, BUT ALSO BECAUSE OF UNCERTAINTIES IN <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> AREAS.
<Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> CONTINUES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INTRODUCTION OF COMPUTERISATION, AND A
RATIONALISATION <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization>, NOW OVER 10 YEARS <Organization>OLD</Organization>, IS ATTEMPTING TO APPORTION
FUNCTIONS AND FINANCIAL RESPONSIBILITY <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
AUTHORITIES. <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> TRIPLE TASK OF <Organization>ADVISORY SERVICE</Organization>,
<Organization>INTER-LIBRARY</Organization> LENDING, AND <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, ARE PARTICULARLY
VULNERABLE. <Organization>THESE SERVICES</Organization>, WHICH BENEFIT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
AND INDIVIDUAL READERS, <Organization>COULD</Organization> BE ADVERSELY AFFECTED <Organization>BY</Organization> SOME RATIONALISATION
PROPOSALS. THE FIRST 2 <Organization>COULD</Organization> BE MAINTAINED AND <Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> IF <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
WERE MADE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS ATTACHED TO <Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>MOBILE</Organization>
SERVICES ARE POORLY DEVELOPED IN <Location>NORWAY</Location>, PARTLY BECAUSE NOT <Organization>ALL</Organization> AREAS ARE
GEOGRAPHICALLY SUITABLE. A RESTRUCTURING OF TH E COUNTRY&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS
URGENTLY NEEDED, AND <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> LIBRARIANS MUST EVALUATE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN POSITION AND
SERVICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   75
BRIDGES TO THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>: <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN <Location>MADISON</Location> <Organization>COUNTY</Organization>, IOWA.

<Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN 1 <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> IN <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> IOWA EXAMINES THE
WORKINGS OF THE EARLHAM, TRURO, AND WINTERSET <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND EXPLORES THE
ELEMENTS IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESPECTIVE <Organization>COMMUNITIES</Organization> WHICH <Organization>AFFECT CURRENT LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>
AND WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> POTENTIAL IMPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PLANNING. IN ADDITION
TO DETAILED PROFILES OF THE 3 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, INCLUDES ANALYSES OF THE <Organization>COMMUNITIES</Organization>
OF <Location>MADISON</Location> <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   76
A BROAD BACK AND A TERRIER&apos;S HEAD: AN INTERVIEW WITH THE HEAD OF A <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
<Organization>VOLUNTARY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

IN THE OUTSKIRTS OF MONNICKENDAM IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RUN
ENTIRELY <Organization>BY</Organization> UNPAID VOLUNTEERS WAS FOUNDED IN 1973. THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> WAS STARTED
WITH THE PURCHASE OF A BANKRUPT STOCK OF <Organization>BOOKS AT MINIMAL COST</Organization> AND IS
PRESENTLY HOUSED IN A FORMER SCHOOL. IT NOW TOTALS 14,500 VOLUMES AND <Organization>LOANS</Organization>
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> RISEN <Organization>FROM</Organization> 10,163 IN 1973 TO 60,368 IN 1980. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS SEPARATE
ADULT AND CHILDREN&apos;S SECTIONS AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MAKE REGULAR VISITS TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> SCHOOLS.
IT HAS CLOSE LINKS WITH THE TOWN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH WHICH IT IS <Organization>PLANNED</Organization> TO MERGE
FORMALLY IN THE NEAR <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>. MRS VAN DRIEL, HEAD OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, RECOGNISES
THE <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> CONTRIBUTION OF HER <Organization>VOLUNTARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS, ADDING THAT THE
ESSENTIAL QUALIFICATION OF A VOLUNTEER IS &apos;A BROAD BACK AND THE HEAD OF A
TERRIER&apos;.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   77
<Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S &apos;<Organization>BOOKS</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> &apos;<Organization>BUS</Organization>&apos;.D

ESCRIBES A PROJECT <Organization>BY</Organization> BRADFORD <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (<Location>UK</Location>) TO BUILD UP CLOSER CONTACTS WITH
THE <Organization>LOCAL COMMUNITY</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> CONVERTING A DOUBLE-DECKER <Organization>BUS</Organization> INTO A <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
THE <Organization>BUS</Organization> <Organization>CONTAINS</Organization> A CITIZENS&apos; <Organization>ADVICE BUREAU</Organization> AND <Organization>AIMS</Organization> TO <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> ADULT LITERACY
IN THE AREA. <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization>: 1 LIBRARIAN; 1 <Organization>ADVICE</Organization> WORKER; 1 LITERACY WORKER;
AND 2 DRIVERS/ASSISTANTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   78
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Organization>HIGHER PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>: AN <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> APPROACH.

IN 1972 A SURVEY OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN COLLEGES OF <Organization>HIGHER PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> IN
<Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> REVEALED A LOW STANDARD OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION. AS A RESULT THE
<Organization>STATE LIBRARY ADVISORY COUNCIL</Organization> HAS PUBLISHED A NUMBER OF PROPOSALS FOR THE
IMPROVEMENT OF SERVICES. <Organization>MODERN</Organization> TRENDS IN <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS INCREASED
STUDENT NUMBERS AND <Organization>NEW</Organization> METHODS IN TEACHING, <Organization>HAVE</Organization> HAD A PROFOUND EFFECT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
COLLEGES OF <Organization>HIGHER PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> COLLEGES MUST
NOW BECOME <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES, EASILY ACCESSIBLE TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> STUDENTS AND EQUIPPED
WITH <Organization>ADEQUATE</Organization> CATALOGUES. COLLEGE LIBRARIANS WILL NEED TO PAY INCREASING
ATTENTION TO THE ACQUISITION OF REPORTS, CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS AND
<Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AND SHOULD <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> COURSES OF FORMAL INSTRUCTION FOR
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND STUDENTS IN THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   79
THE 1979 DIRECTORY OF COLLEGE AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>NEW YORK</Location> <Organization>STATE</Organization> WITH
<Organization>STATISTICAL DATA</Organization> FOR FY 1978. TWELFTH EDITION.

<Organization>THIS</Organization> EDITION OF A DIRECTORY TO 265 COLLEGE AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>NEW
YORK</Location> <Organization>STATE</Organization>, <Organization>COMPILED FROM DATA</Organization> FURNISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>STATE EDUCATION</Organization> DEPARTMENT,
INCLUDES ADDRESS AND TELEPHONE NUMBER, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DIRECTOR, INSTITUTION
PRESIDENT, NUMBER OF VOLUMES, NUMBER OF PERIODICAL TITLES RECEIVED, ANNUAL
EXPENDITURES FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, ANNUAL <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> OPERATING EXPENDITURES,
NUMBERS OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> AND NONPROFESSIONAL <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, <Organization>REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization>
LIBRARIAN, <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LOAN</Organization> LIBRARIAN, TYPE OF INSTITUTION, 3R&apos;S IDENTIFIER,
AND PUBLICATIONS ISSUED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>REPORT</Organization> NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>   80
<Location>BERNE</Location> <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>: EXTRACTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE ANNUAL <Organization>REPORT</Organization> 1980.
