<Organization>Document</Organization>  501
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES FOR THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>: PROCEEDINGS OF THE 8TH
CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>PAPUA NEW GUINEA LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>.

THE CONFERENCE WAS HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE COLLEGE</Organization> OF <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>,
WAIGANI, <Location>PORT MORESBY</Location>, 18-19 OCT 79. PAPERS ARE IN 5 SECTIONS: STRATEGIES IN
THE PLANNING OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES; STATE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR THE
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> IN <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>; LITERACY AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; REACHING OUT: ACCESS TO
<Organization>LIBRARY-BASED INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> IN THE RURAL AREAS OF <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>; AND
AGENCIES INVOLVED IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK. TRANSCRIPTIONS OF QUESTION AND ANSWER
SESSIONS ARE ALSO INCLUDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  502
SURVEY OF CZECH AND <Organization>SLOVAK</Organization> PERIODICALS AND BULLETINS <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP AND
INFORMATICS.

MORE THAN 20 PERIODICALS, NEWSLETTERS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PAPERS DEALING WITH THE THEORY
AND PRACTICE OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE ARE LISTED. THE <Organization>SLOVAK</Organization>
CITATEL&apos; AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> CZECH COUNTERPART CTENAR NOW CATER FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>.
ALTHOUGH <Organization>ORIGINALLY</Organization> DESIGNED WITH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN MIND. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PERIODICALS
ARE MORE <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization>, DEALING WITH THE PROBLEMS OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND
ECONOMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES IN INDUSTRY; IN UNIVERSITY, COLLEGE
AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>NATIONAL HEALTH SERVICE</Organization>
ESTABLISHMENTS. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EDITORIAL <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MAKE EVERY EFFORT TO IMPART <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> READERS, <Organization>NOT</Organization> ONLY <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ROUTINES AND TECHNIQUES, <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO <Organization>SOME</Organization>
INSIGHT INTO THE READERS PSYCHOLOGY, THE SITUATION IN A SIMILAR FIELD ABROAD,
THE LATEST PUBLICATIONS, <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> EVENTS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> INTEREST AND THE LIKE. A
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> NEWSLETTER TAKES UP <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS , <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
FURNISHING AND <Organization>EQUIPMENT</Organization>, <Organization>BOOK</Organization> COLLECTIONS AND <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>. ALTHOUGH <Organization>SLOVAK</Organization>
TRADE UNIONS <Organization>AS WELL AS MUSEUM</Organization> AND <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> STILL LACK
PERIODICALS OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN, THE CHOICE IS WIDE AND NO LIBRARIAN AND/OR
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTIST NEED BE BEHIND THE TIMES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  503
<Organization>INDIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO A SECTION DEVOTED TO INDIA. THE 10 MOST RELIABLE <Organization>INDIAN</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE JOURNALS PUBLISHED IN <Organization>ENGLISH</Organization> WERE SELECTED AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> CONTENTS
<Organization>FROM</Organization> 1974-76 ANALYSED AND APPRAISED. 499 ARTICLES MET THE <Organization>SELECTION</Organization> CRITERIA:
92% WERE CONSIDERED TO BE DESCRIPTIVE ONLY, AND THE REMAINDER WERE JUDGED TO
BE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARTICLES. 90 ARTICLES WERE CONCERNED WITH <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE, 82
WITH THE ORGANISATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIALS, AND 45 WITH <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. THE VOLUME OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN <Organization>ENGLISH</Organization> AND PUBLISHED IN
<Location>INDIA</Location> RANKS ONLY AFTER THAT PUBLISHED IN THE <Location>USA</Location> AND UK.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  504
ZZZZ.

1ST ISSUE OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>JOURNAL</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>, BUILDINGS AND TECHNOLOGY IN
ARCHIVE, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK. THE ANNUAL SUBSCRIPTION (FOR 4 ISSUES)
IS DM70, AND CORRESPONDENCE SHOULD BE ADDRESSED TO THE EDITOR, PETER
SCHWEIGER, UNIVERSITATSBIBLIOTHEK, DER TECHNISCHEN UNIVERSITAT, POSTFACH 20 24
20, 8000 MUNCHEN 2.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  505
YEARS OF CITATEL&apos;.<Organization>ON</Organization>

THE EVE OF THE 30TH ANNIVERSARY, THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> POINTS OF THE PERIODICAL&apos;S HISTORY
ARE OUTLINED. IT WAS FOUNDED WITH THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> PURPOSE OF ASSISTING <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. WITH <Organization>TIME</Organization>, <Organization>ITS</Organization> IMPACT HAS SPREAD TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
IN <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> IN <Location>SLOVAKIA</Location>. LIBRARIANS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN INFORMED OF NEW, INVENTIVE
IDEAS, BOTH <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>HOME</Organization> AND ABROAD. THEORY AND PRACTICE OF LIBRARIANSHIP IN THE
<Location>SOVIET UNION</Location> HAS ALWAYS ATTRACTED <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ATTENTION. ALTHOUGH THE EDUCATIONAL
<Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF CITATEL&apos; HAS BEEN EMPHASISED AS THE MOST <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> ONE, THERE HAS
ALWAYS BEEN ENOUGH SPACE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> PAGES TO ADVISE LIBRARIANS OF <Organization>IMPROVEMENT</Organization> IN
<Organization>WORKING</Organization> CONDITIONS, AND TO CAMPAIGN FOR THE ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
TODAY, CITATEL&apos; IS WELL ESTABLISHED <Organization>NOT</Organization> ONLY IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT ALSO
HAS A <Organization>GOOD</Organization> REPUTATION ABROAD, AND INTEREST IN IT IS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INCREASE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  506
<Organization>RESEARCH DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIANS: ONE UNIVERSITY&apos;S APPROACH.

EXPANDS UPON A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> JENKINS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>STAFF DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OFFICERS OF
<Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC LIBRARIES DISCUSSION GROUP</Organization>, <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
MIDWINTER MEETING, <Location>CHICAGO</Location>, JAN 80. IN THE <Organization>LIGHT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INCREASING</Organization> EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization>
PUBLISHED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIANS, <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> EFFORTS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE MORRIS
INVOLVEMENT IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> AREA. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>FACULTY DEVELOPMENT</Organization>
ACTIVITIES, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> INTEREST GROUP DESIGNED TO ENABLE
LIBRARIANS TO DISCUSS AND EVALUATE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IDEAS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  507
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN LIBRARIES-SOME STEPS FOR ACTION.

THE DEVELOPMENT PROCESS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>/<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE IN <Location>INDIA</Location>
IS NOW IN THE FINAL PHASE-SELF-SUFFICIENCY. IDENTIFIES THE AREAS COVERED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>THIS</Organization> DISCIPLINE; BRIEFLY TRACES THE GROWTH OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE PRE-RANGANATHAN
AND RANGANATHAN ERAS; AND HIGHLIGHTS THE PROFESSION&apos;S <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> POSITION,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> DEVALUATION THROUGH LOW PAY AND STATUS. LOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE FACULTIES AND IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. PLEADS FOR SUBJECT
SPECIALISATION AMONG <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>; SUGGESTS WORKSHOPS TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> WORK LOAD
AND STANDARDS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND CALLS FOR THE FORMATION OF AN INSTITUTE OF
<Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> STUDIES IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE TO START AND COORDINATE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  508
INAUGURAL LECTURES AND MASTER&apos;S AND DOCTORAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> SOUTH AFRICAN
<Organization>UNIVERSITIES</Organization>.

LISTS, FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE, TITLES OF INAUGURAL LECTURES;
MASTER&apos;S THESES AND DOCTORAL DISSERTATIONS ACCEPTED IN 1968-80; AND <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS FOR MASTER&apos;S AND DOCTORAL DEGREES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  509
MY RAMBLING RECOLLECTIONS AND REMARKS AS A LIBRARIAN.

AUTOBIOGRAPHICAL NOTES AND OBSERVATIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>BY</Organization> THE DIRECTOR OF
THE PHARR MEMORIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>TEXAS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  510
THE <Organization>PERMANENT</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>&apos; PROTECTING THE ESTHETIC AND INTELLECTUAL VALUE OF
<Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>.

SURVEYS THE DISPARATE ROLES PLAYED IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>ARCHIVAL</Organization> WORLD <Organization>BY</Organization>
LIBRARIANS, CURATORS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECIALISTS, ARCHIVISTS AND RECORD MANAGERS,
AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> PROBLEMS THAT <Organization>THIS</Organization> ABUNDANCE OF ROLES CREATES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  511
FOR <Organization>GOOD</Organization> OR EVIL, LIBRARIANSHIP IS STERILE.

LIBRARIANS FAIL TO ATTRACT THE RIGHT PEOPLE TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RANKS; THEY ARE NEITHER
INVENTIVE NOR <Organization>INNOVATIVE</Organization>, THERE IS TOO LITTLE IN LIBRARIANSHIP TO JUSTIFY EVEN
A FIRST DEGREE; ONLY LIBRARIANS THEMSELVES WOULD CONSIDER <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OCCUPATION TO
BE A PROFESSION; AND FELLOWSHIP SHOULD BE RESERVED FOR AWARD <Organization>ON</Organization> AN HONORARY
BASIS (AND THEN ONLY RARELY). LIBRARIANSHIP SHOULD RECOGNISE <Organization>ITS</Organization> MODEST PLACE
IN SOCIETY, RECRUIT THOSE WITH A <Organization>NATURAL</Organization> FLAIR FOR ORGANISATION, AND ORGANISE
ITSELF ALONG BUSINESSLIKE LINES TO PROVIDE A SERVICE THE NATURE OF WHICH DOES
<Organization>NOT</Organization> NEED EXPLICATING EXCEPT TO THOSE MORE INTERESTED IN ABSTRACT PHILOSOPHY
THAN PRACTICAL UTILITY. LIBRARIANSHIP IS MUCH MORE INTERESTED IN RHETORIC THAN
LOGIC.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  512
THE FOUNDATIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE. PART 3. QUANTITATIVE ASPECTS&apos;
OBJECTIVE MAPS AND SUBJECTIVE LANDSCAPES.

THE METRICAL CHARACTERISTICS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPACE ARE COMPARED WITH THOSE OF
<Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> SPACE. AN ABSTRACT MODEL IS USED TO SHOW THAT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPACE IS
LIKE THAT OF LANDSCAPES AND SKYSCRAPERS. AS INDIVIDUALS WE LEARN VERY EARLY TO
CORRECT THE DISTORTIONS THAT SUBJECTIVE APPEARANCES IMPOSE <Organization>ON</Organization> US <Organization>BUT</Organization> TRACES OF
<Organization>THIS</Organization> PROCESS ARE SHOWN <Organization>BY</Organization> COSMOLOGICAL HISTORY. <Organization>THESE</Organization> ARGUMENTS ARE SUPPORTED
<Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> EVIDENCE INDICATING THAT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> QUANTITIES SHOULD BE MEASURED
LOGARITHMICALLY. FOR PARTS 1 AND 2 SEE 81/1828 AND 81/1829. FOR PART 4 SEE THE
FOLLOWING <Organization>SERIAL</Organization> NUMBER:.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  513
THE FOUNDATIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE. PART IV. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE&apos; THE
CHANGING PARADIGM.

THE ARGUMENTS OF PARTS I-III ARE APPLIED TO 2 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> ISSUES&apos; (1) SEPARATION OF
THE <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> AND MENTAL COMPONENTS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PHENOMENA, ILLUSTRATED <Organization>BY</Organization> A
<Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> OF PERIODICAL AGEING; AND (2) THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF <Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S LAW AND
RANKING TECHNIQUES AS A MEANS OF EXPLOITING <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INHERENT IN
THE <Organization>RAW DATA</Organization>. CONCLUDES WITH A BRIEF <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> OF A PROPOSED <Organization>NEW</Organization> KIND OF DATA
<Organization>BASE</Organization> IN WHICH OBJECTIVE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS STRUCTERED INTO OBJECTIVE KNOWLEDGE.
FOR PART 1 AND 2 SEE 81/1828 AND 81/1829. FOR PART 3 SEE THE PREVIOUS
ABSTRACT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  514
EMMORPHOSIS&apos; <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS PROCESS.

A MODEL OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS THE PROCESS OF REDUCING UNCERTAINTY (EMMORPHOSIS) IS
PROPOSED AS A MEANS OF EXPLORING AND EXPANDING THE DEFINITIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENCE <Organization>BY</Organization> PROVIDING A NON-TRADITIONAL VIEW OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> CONCEPT. OUTLINES
<Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> RAMIFICATIONS OF THE MODEL AND CALLS FOR <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> INVESTIGATIONS INTO
THE MECHANISMS AS WELL AS THE IMPLICATIONS OF THE PROCESS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  515
THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF THE LIBRARIAN IN HIS FIELD AND THE FUNCTION OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

ARGUES THAT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD EMPLOY <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> <Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization> TO EXPAND
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INVOLVEMENT IN THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>, <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT OF THE
COMMUNITY. BEFORE 1960, LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>PROVIDED ONLY LIMITED</Organization>
SERVICES TO A MINORITY OF <Organization>USERS</Organization>; WITH THE AVAILABILITY OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> AND
<Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, THE LIBRARIAN MUST MEET THE CHALLENGE OF RESPONDING TO
THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> NEEDS OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> CITIZENS, AND COMBAT THE
COMPETITION BOOKS FACE <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MEANS OF COMMUNICATION. OUTLINES RECENT
<Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE PROFESSION, AND <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> A VIEW OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE COMING DECADES AS AN AGENT IN THE PROMOTION OF <Organization>READING</Organization>, THE
DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, AND SOCIO-CULTURAL CHANGE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  516
COLLEGE LIBRARIANS IN <Location>INDIA</Location>.

CONTRIBUTION TO A SECTION DEVOTED TO INDIA. EXPOSES THE ATTITUDE TOWARDS
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>INDIA</Location> AS A WHOLE ALTHOUGH AIMED PRIMARILY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE DEPARTMENT OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>DELHI</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1947, THERE HAS BEEN NO
SPECIALISATION IN THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> CONTENT-THERE IS NO <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>COURSE</Organization> IN COLLEGE
LIBRARIANSHIP. THE COLLEGE LIBRARIAN IS STILL MADE ACCOUNTABLE FOR EVERY LOSS,
AND EQUALITY OF STATUS AND PAY WITH <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> HAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> BEEN ACHIEVED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  517
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS IN <Location>BANGLADESH</Location>.

<Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS IN <Location>BANGLADESH</Location>.
LIBRARIANS MUST SHOW GREATER UNITY AND WORK FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF A STRONG
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN ORDER TO MAKE A MAXIMUM IMPACT <Organization>ON</Organization> GOVERNMENTS AND THE
<Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>USER</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  518
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE WORK OF THE ASSOCIATION OF SWISS LIBRARIANS 1980-81.

<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS GIVEN <Organization>ON</Organization> MEMBERS&apos; MOVEMENTS AND <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ASSOCIATION&apos;S FINANCES.
THE PRESIDENT&apos;S REPORT <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE EFFECTS OF ECONOMIC PROBLEMS, THE
<Organization>INCREASING</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> PROCESSING IN UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE NEW
COPYRIGHT LAWS, THE PROPOSED LAW <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND CONTACT WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
LIBRARIANSHIP ORGANISATIONS. REPORTS ARE INCLUDED <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> ORGANISATIONS,
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> GROUPS <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; EDUCATION <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; FRENCH-SWISS <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND <Organization>FROM</Organization> COMMITTEES <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; EXAMINATIONS; <Location>BERNE</Location>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES; FRENCH-SWISS <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES; <Location>ZURICH</Location> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> COURSES;
<Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>; STATISTICS; <Organization>PUBLICITY</Organization>; DICTIONARY <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>; COPYRIGHT;
SOUND RECORDING CENTRES; <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA</Organization>; EDITING NACHR./NOUV./NOTIZ.;
MANUSCRIPT PRESERVATION; LAW <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; MAP <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AUTOMATION</Organization>; AND
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  519
THE <Organization>FINNISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN 1980.

THE <Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> PROVINCIAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> LEFT A PROPOSAL WITH THE MINISTRY OF
EDUCATION FOR THE REFORM OF THE RELEVANT SECTION OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION.
THE <Organization>BOOKMOBILE WORKING GROUP</Organization> HAD <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>BOOKMOBILE</Organization> STANDARD PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>KIRJASTOPALVELU OY</Organization>. THE <Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> BECAME A <Organization>PERMANENT GROUP</Organization> OF THE
ASSOCIATION IN 1981. A MEMORANDUM ABOUT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> CONDITIONS WAS SENT TO
THE MINISTRY OF EDUCATION. <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> GRANTS WERE GIVEN FOR THE 1ST <Organization>TIME</Organization> FOR THE
<Organization>SELECTIVE ACQUISITION</Organization> OF BOOKS WITH A NARROW <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization>. THE <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION NOW OWNS ABOUT 90% OF THE SHARES OF <Organization>KIRJASTOPALVELU OY</Organization>. THE
<Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> OF KIRJASTOLEHTI WAS 7,500. MANY <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PUBLICATIONS WERE
PUBLISHED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  520
THE PROPOSED PLAN OF THE <Organization>FINNISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> FOR 1982.

THE MOST <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> AREAS FOR ACTION <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>FINNISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> ARE&apos;
REFORM OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION; <Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> CONDITIONS; COMMUNICATION
NETWORKS; <Organization>IMPROVED SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND THE <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> SUBJECT HEADING LIST. THE
<Organization>PERMANENT</Organization> COMMITTEES OF THE ASSOCIATION WILL CARRY <Organization>ON</Organization> WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK AS WILL
THE <Organization>PERMANENT</Organization> SECTIONS OF THE ASSOCIATION. THE ASSOCIATION IS ASKING <Location>TAMPERE</Location>
UNIVERSITY TO ORGANISE A <Organization>COURSE ON NEW COMMUNICATIONS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF
THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PROPOSED COURSES ARE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION, AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF THE
<Location>MIDDLE EAST</Location>. MANY PUBLICATIONS ARE DUE IN 1982. THE ASSOCIATION IS APPLYING
FOR A <Organization>GRANT</Organization> OF 385,000 FMARKS FOR NEXT YEAR.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  521
THE NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
CENTRE) MEMBERS&apos; MEETING, 11TH DECEMBER 1980&apos; A PERSONAL IMPRESSION.

REPORT OF THE MEETING OF NBLC MEMBERS IN <Location>AMSTERDAM</Location>, 11 DEC 80. TOPICS
DISCUSSED INCLUDED CUTBACKS IN FINANCIAL <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> FOR
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>, RAISING OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEMBERSHIP
CHARGES, AND REDUCTION OF THE AGE-LIMIT FOR FREE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEMBERSHIP. ALTHOUGH
MANY OF THOSE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> WERE OPPOSED TO A REDUCTION IN <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization>
FELT THAT THE GROWTH OF RECENT YEARS, IF ALLOWED TO CONTINUE, COULD LEAD TO A
REDUCTION IN THE <Organization>QUALITY</Organization> OF SERVICES. THE QUESTION OF ALLOWING THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> A
GREATER <Organization>VOICE</Organization> IN THE RUNNING OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE POSITION OF UNPAID
<Organization>VOLUNTARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> WERE ALSO DISCUSSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  522
<Organization>INTEGRATING EDUCATION</Organization> IN LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE.

CONCERNED WITH THE MANY PRESSURES TO WHICH <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IS SUBJECT <Organization>ALL</Organization>
OVER THE WORLD, CONCENTRATES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN LIBRARIANSHIP,
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE, AND THE ACCOMMODATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EDUCATION. THE EMERGENCE AND DOMAIN OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE IS BRIEFLY
REVIEWED, AND THE NEED FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> TO TAKE INTO ACCOUNT NEW
<Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization> FRAMEWORKS AND <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL SERVICES</Organization> OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENCE IS INDICATED. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  523
THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF OKLAHOMA.

THE ONLY ALA-ACCREDITED GRADUATE PROGRAMME IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN OKLAHOMA IS
CELEBRATING <Organization>ITS</Organization> 52ND ANNIVERSARY IN 1981. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF
OKLAHOMA&apos;S SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE, <Organization>ITS</Organization> COURSES AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EVOLUTION TO MEET
TODAY&apos;S NEEDS, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> EDUCATION IN PRESERVATION TECHNIQUES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  524
AN INVESTIGATION OF <Organization>ATTITUDES ABOUT CONTINUING PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMS
IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS HELD <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>FACULTY</Organization> MEMBERS AND DEANS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS WITH
ACCREDITED MASTER&apos;S PROGRAMS.

HELD <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>FACULTY</Organization> MEMBERS AND DEANS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS ABOUT THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization>, VALUE,
ADMINISTRATION, DESIGN, AND STUDENTS OF <Organization>CONTINUING PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization>
PROGRAMMES IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, AND IDENTIFIES RELATIONSHIPS <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> BETWEEN
CERTAIN PERSONAL, <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization>, AND INSTITUTIONAL CHARACTERISTICS AND <Organization>THESE</Organization>
<Organization>ATTITUDES</Organization>. DATA WERE GATHERED <Organization>BY</Organization> SURVEYING <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>FACULTY</Organization> MEMBERS AND DEANS IN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> MASTER&apos;S PROGRAMMES ACCREDITED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  525
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE ARRANGEMENT OF &apos;<Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE&apos; IN <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> COLLEGES OF
REPUBLIC OF <Location>CHINA</Location> (SIC) (IN <Organization>CHINESE</Organization>).

MUCH OF THE <Organization>CHINESE EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, <Organization>PARTICULARLY</Organization> IN THE AREA OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCIENCE, IS TRANSFERRED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>USA</Location>, AND THERE ARE MANY DEFECTS IN THE
ARRANGEMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE CURRICULA. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> TRENDS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>PRACTICES</Organization>, AND INVESTIGATES CURRICULA FOR THE
WOULD-BE-LIBRARIAN IN <Location>CHINA</Location>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE DIFFICULTIES THE NEWLY-GRADUATED
LIBRARIAN WILL FACE <Organization>ON</Organization> BEGINNING WORK, AND <Organization>ATTEMPTS</Organization> TO DISCOVER THE DEGREE TO
WHICH <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization> ARRANGEMENT IS <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  526
EDUCATING LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS TO PROVIDE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES TO <Organization>DISABLED</Organization> INDIVIDUALS.

CONTRIBUTION TO A <Organization>THEMATIC ISSUE ON INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>DISABLED</Organization>.
SCHOOLS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>NOT</Organization> ONLY PROVIDE INITIAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>,
<Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO ARE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> CENTRES FOR <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> AND UPDATING THE EDUCATION OF
PRACTITIONERS. THEY SHOULD <Organization>THUS</Organization> PLAY A <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>ROLE</Organization> IN SPREADING THE KNOWLEDGE
AND AWARENESS ESSENTIAL FOR THE PROVISION OF <Organization>VIABLE SERVICES</Organization> TO THE <Organization>DISABLED</Organization>.
EXAMINES THE NEEDS, ISSUES, AND IMPLICATIONS OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A <Organization>ROLE</Organization> AND EXHORTS
EDUCATORS IN THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FIELD AND LEADERS IN <Organization>REHABILITATION</Organization> TO JOIN
FORCES TO DEVELOP A SUITABLE <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  527
OPPORTUNITIES FOR THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>TURNKEY EDP SYSTEMS</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF EDUCATION IN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE.

THE <Organization>INCREASING</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF DATA PROCESSING IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SCIENCE DEMANDS THAT THE SUBJECT SHOULD BE COVERED DURING THE EDUCATION
PERIOD. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>TURNKEY LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> <Organization>USING</Organization> MINICOMPUTERS.
<Organization>ALL SYSTEMS</Organization> WERE CHOSEN BECAUSE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> USEFULNESS IN EDUCATION. <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> AN
OVERVIEW OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> SOFTWARE PACKAGES FOR MINICOMPUTER
SYSTEMS, ARRANGED ACCORDING TO UNIFORM CRITERIA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  528
CATALOGING ADMINISTRATORS&apos; <Organization>VIEWS ON CATALOGING EDUCATION</Organization>.

A BASIC QUESTION IN STRUCTURING A <Organization>GRADUATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization>
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> <Organization>COURSE</Organization> IS THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>TEACHING</Organization> IN THE
<Organization>THEORETICAL</Organization> <Organization>VS</Organization>. PRACTICAL MODE OR A COMBINATION OF BOTH. REPORTS THE RESULTS
OF A SURVEY OF CATALOGUERS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OPINIONS OF&apos; (1) STRUCTURE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOL <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>; (2) RELATIONSHIP OF THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMPUTERS IN
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> TO THE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>; AND (3) ADEQUACY OF PREPARATION OF
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> GRADUATES FOR POSITIONS AS CATALOGUERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  529
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMPUTER-BASED PACKAGES IN THE <Organization>TEACHING</Organization> OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE. REPORT OF A <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> MANCHESTER POLYTECHNIC 23-26
JULY 1979.

IN JULY 79, THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FUNDED A 3-DAY <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> MANCHESTER
POLYTECHNIC <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMPUTER-BASED PACKAGES FOR <Organization>TEACHING</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE. AS WELL AS HEARING ABOUT THE PACKAGES USED, THE
<Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> ENABLED REPRESENTATIVES <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE SCHOOLS
TO HEAR ABOUT USEFUL <Organization>TEACHING</Organization> PACKAGES, TO SEE THEM BEING RUN, AND TO <Organization>USE</Organization> THEM
DURING THE NUMEROUS PRACTICAL SESSIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  530
THE <Location>COLOGNE</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCENE AND COLOGNE <Location>CITY</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE UNIVERSITY AND MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WITH ABOUT 2,000,000 VOLUMES AND 12,000
PERIODICALS IS THE LARGEST <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>COLOGNE</Location>. THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF MEDICINE
STOCKS 500,000 VOLUMES AND 6,000 PERIODICALS. THERE ARE <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
BELONGING TO FOREIGN <Organization>CULTURAL INSTITUTES</Organization>, E.G. THE BRITISH COUNCIL. MANY
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND ARCHIVES PROVIDE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> COLOGNE AND THE RHINELAND,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>ART</Organization> AND MUSEUM <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE RHINE PICTURE ARCHIVE, THE
CATHEDRAL ARCHIVE AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF INDUSTRIAL AND TRADE ASSOCIATIONS. <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
<Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE THOSE OF THE COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY, THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization>
<Organization>PHYSICAL TRAINING COLLEGE</Organization> AND <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT INSTITUTES</Organization>. <Location>COLOGNE</Location> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS PART OF A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> 2 DISTRICT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 21
BRANCHES, 6 MOBILES, 4 <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> DEPARTMENTS AND 10 SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  531
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> VISIT <Location>CHINA</Location>.

REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR, SUPPORTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE BRITISH COUNCIL, WHICH TOOK PLACE
<Organization>FROM</Organization> 1-14 JUNE 81, <Organization>AT</Organization> THE INVITATION OF THE INSTITUTE OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OF <Location>CHINA</Location> (ISTIC). THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF THE VISIT WAS TO LEARN
ABOUT THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IN <Location>CHINA</Location>, TO LOOK <Organization>AT</Organization> POSSIBLE FORMS
OF COOPERATION BETWEEN THE <Location>UK</Location> AND CHINA, AND TO LOOK <Organization>AT</Organization> POSSIBLE FORMS OF
COOPERATION BETWEEN THE <Location>UK</Location> AND CHINA, AND TO EXAMINE THE SCOPE FOR EXTENDING
THE <Organization>LENDING DIVISION</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>INTERNATIONAL PHOTOCOPY SERVICE</Organization> TO CHINA. PEKING,
<Location>SHANGHAI</Location>, WU-HAN AND CANTON WERE VISITED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  532
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES IN THE <Location>PHILIPPINES</Location>&apos; A REVIEW OF <Organization>DOCUMENTS</Organization>
RECEIVED.

EXAMINES <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES IN THE <Location>PHILIPPINES</Location> <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
EXPERIENCE GAINED <Organization>ON</Organization> A RECENT VISIT AND <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE ON SERVICES</Organization> IN THE AREA.
PROV8DES BASIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ABOUT RECENT <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization>, AND AIMS TO ENCOURAGE
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> LIBRARIANS TO UNDERTAKE A MORE COMPREHENSIVE AND DETAILED <Organization>STUDY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  533
STATISTICS FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN 1980.

3 <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE STARTED IN 1980. THERE WAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> MUCH CHANGE IN
THE STATISTICS FOR <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> PREVIOUS YEARS. THE
BOOKFUNDS <Organization>INCREASED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> ABOUT 15%. THE <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> EXPENDITURE <Organization>ON</Organization> BOOKS WAS
26,500,000 FMARKS. 1,630,543 <Organization>HOME</Organization> LOANS WERE MADE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  534
IRANIAN <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN REVOLUTION.

ACCOUNT OF THE IMPACT OF THE IRANIAN REVOLUTION <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
WITH BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PRE-REVOLUTIONARY STATUS. THE OVERALL EFFECT
OF THE REVOLUTION HAS BEEN MIXED, AND WHILST <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCE LIBRARIANS ARE
ENCOURAGED <Organization>BY</Organization> EVIDENCE OF <Organization>INCREASED</Organization> DEMOCRACY IN <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization>, THEY WERE
DISAPPOINTED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>BUDGET</Organization> CUTS AND <Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization> FREEZES. HOWEVER, <Organization>SINCE</Organization> THE
DEPARTURE OF THE MONARCHY, THEY HOPE FOR A MORE ENCOURAGING SITUATION IN THE
FUTURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  535
ROUND TABLE/SQUARE RAFT/<Organization>IFLA</Organization> IN <Location>MANILA</Location>&apos; AUGUST 18-23.

REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> PROCEEDINGS OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ROUND TABLE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 46TH <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
CONFERENCE OF <Organization>IFLA</Organization>, <Location>MANILA</Location> AUG 80, WITH DETAILS OF DISCUSSIONS, PAPERS
PRESENTED AND VISITS MADE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  536
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PERCIVAL DAVID FOUNDATION</Organization> OF <Organization>CHINESE</Organization> <Organization>ART</Organization>.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF FOUNDATION FORMS A PART OF THE GIFT MADE IN 1951 <Organization>BY</Organization> THE LATE
SIR PERCIVAL DAVID TO THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>LONDON</Location>. INCLUDES <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CHINESE</Organization>
PAINTING AND PORCELAIN, IN EUROPEAN LANGUAGES, <Organization>CHINESE</Organization> AND JAPANESE, ALSO MANY
CATALOGUES AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> HISTORIES AND GAZETEERS OF PARTS OF <Location>CHINA</Location> WHERE THERE
WERE KNOWN TO BE KILNS OPERATING AS EARLY AS 10TH CENTURY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  537
RECOLLECTED IN TRANQUILITY: <Organization>SOME</Organization> IMPRESSIONS OF THE IAML 12TH CONGRESS, IASA
11TH ANNUAL CONFERENCE, <Location>CAMBRIDGE</Location> 3-8 AUGUST 1980.

PERSONAL REFLECTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
CONFERENCE, WITH COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ISSUES UNDER <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization>, THE RELEVANCE OF THE
LECTURES, RECEPTIONS, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> EVENTS. CONCLUDES THAT THE CONFERENCE WAS A
SUCCESS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  538
THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>: PURCHASE OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDING SITE.

THE LATEST ANNUAL REPORT CONFIRMS THE PURCHASE OF A SITE OF 19,000 SQ.M. FOR
THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDING REQUIRED TO EASE THE SPACE SHORTAGE. THE DATA PROCESSING
PLANT HAS BEEN ENLARGED AND <Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> AND IS NOW LINKED WITH EURONET DIANE.
THERE WAS A RECORD <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> STOCK GROWTH OF 13.8%. <Organization>MAIN</Organization> STOCK INCREASES OCCURRED
FOR MAPS, <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> AUTHORS EXILED IN THE 1930&apos;S, DISSERTATIONS,
<Organization>MUSIC</Organization> SCORES AND <Organization>MICROFORM</Organization> PUBLICATIONS. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> RULES <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
BEEN ADAPTED TO THE <Organization>RAK</Organization> (<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> ALPHABETICAL <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> RULES) FOR <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; PRODUCTION OF THE DEUTSCHE BIBLIOGRAPHIE (<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
BIBLIOGRAPHY) HAS SHOWN WIDER COVERAGE AND <Organization>IMPROVEMENT</Organization> IN PROCEDURES. OVER
139,000 REQUESTS FOR <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> WERE MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> ABOUT 10,000 READERS. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ORGANISED <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> EXHIBITIONS AND WAS INVOLVED IN COOPERATIVE ACTIVITIES WITH
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>HOME</Organization> AND ABROAD.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  539
ANNIVERSARY OF THE <Organization>UKRAINIAN CENTRE</Organization> OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>.

REVIEWS THE HISTORY AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
OF THE <Organization>UKRAINIAN</Organization> SSR, WHICH WAS FOUNDED <Organization>ON</Organization> 6 NOV 30. INITIALLY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAD
A STOCK OF 28,000 ITEMS AND SERVED 1,000 <Organization>USERS</Organization>. <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS
30,000 <Organization>USERS</Organization> AND, IN ADDITION TO THE <Organization>USUAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, ALSO <Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> A
<Organization>TRANSLATION SERVICE</Organization>. IN 1965 THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ESTABLISHED AN ARCHIVE OF <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTS AS THE <Organization>METHODOLOGICAL CENTRE</Organization> FOR 1,340 <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Location>UKRAINE</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  540
FOCUS <Organization>ON</Organization> STATE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A REPORT TO THE NATION.

STATE OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> REVIEW OF AUSTRALIAN STATE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, DEFINING THE CONCEPT OF
A STATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, PROVIDING AN HISTORICAL BACKGROUND, AND DISCUSSING PROBLEMS
OF STATE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE NEEDS OF STATE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR THE FUTURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  541
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.

THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT&apos;S <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> HAS DEVELOPED RAPIDLY <Organization>SINCE</Organization> 1978. PROJECTS INCLUDE STATE OF
THE <Organization>ART</Organization> REVIEWS, PRELIMINARY OR ENABLING STUDIES, EVALUATION OF EXPERIMENTAL
SERVICES, AND OPERATIONAL <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS. IN ADDITION, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
PROJECTS <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN CARRIED OUT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> CENTRES SUPPORTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
DEPARTMENT. FUTURE WORK WILL PROBABLY CONCENTRATE MORE <Organization>ON</Organization> DISSEMINATION AND
PROMOTION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> RESULTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  542
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE SITUATION OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IN NORTH RHINE-WESTPHALIA.

A SHORT REPORT WAS MADE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SITUATION OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN NORTH
RHINE-WESTPHALIA (NRW) <Organization>ON</Organization> 20 AUG 80 <Organization>AT</Organization> THE EDUCATION COMMITTEE MEETING OF THE
CITIES&apos; ASSEMBLY OF NRW IN DUISBURG. A <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> OF 18 MILLION BOOKS ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>
IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN NRW FOR A POPULATION OF 17 MILLION. <Organization>THIS</Organization> DOES <Organization>NOT</Organization>
COMPARE WELL WITH FIGURES OF 5, 6 OR EVEN 8-10 BOOKS PER HEAD OF POPULATION IN
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> EUROPEAN COUNTRIES. THE TARGET FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN NRW IS 2 BOOKS
PER HEAD <Organization>BUT</Organization> EVEN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIGURE WILL BE DIFFICULT TO ACHIEVE IN THE FACE OF
RISING <Organization>BOOK</Organization> COSTS AND A <Organization>STATIC ACQUISITION</Organization> <Organization>BUDGET</Organization>. ALTHOUGH THERE ARE <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization>
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE LARGER TOWNS THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IS UNEVENLY
<Organization>DISTRIBUTED</Organization> AND HARDLY EXISTS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> COUNTRY AREAS. THE LIBRARIANS
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> PUT FORWARD SUGGESTIONS FOR A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LAW AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization> IMPROVING THE
SITUATION TO THE MINISTER OF EDUCATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  543
DANISH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 1980&apos; A PERSONAL VIEW.

IMPRESSIONS GAINED DURING THE AUTHOR&apos;S TERRAPIN RESKA AWARD TOUR OF DANISH
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORGANISATIONS, 15-26 SEPT 80. CONCENTRATES <Organization>ON</Organization>
FEATURES FOUND INTERESTING <Organization>BY</Organization> THE AUTHOR AND DIFFERENT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  544
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN FRIESLAND.

THE 1ST <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY FINANCED FROM LOCAL AUTHORITY</Organization> SOURCES IN THE PROVINCE
OF FRIESLAND IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> WAS FOUNDED <Organization>AT</Organization> LEEUWAARDEN IN 1905. IN THE
YEARS FOLLOWING, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE FOUNDED IN THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LARGE</Organization> TOWNS OF THE
PROVINCE, WHILST IN THE SMALLER COMMUNITIES <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>STAFFED</Organization> WITH UNPAID
VOLUNTEERS WERE FORMED, OFTEN WITH THE <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LOCAL CHURCH</Organization>
AUTHORITIES. FOLLOWING THE FORMATION IN 1917 OF THE VERENIGING VOOR OPENBAAR
LEESZAALWEZEN IN FRIESLAND (ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> ROOMS IN FRIESLAND)
A REGULAR DELIVERY OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> BOXES WAS ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE TOWN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR THE
<Organization>LOCAL COMMUNITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THROUGHOUT THE PROVINCE THERE ARE NOW <Organization>SOME</Organization> 180,000
REGISTERED <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization>, REPRESENTING MORE THAN 30% OF THE POPULATION,
AND LOANS <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> 8 MILLION ANNUALLY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  545
STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>&apos; REACTIONS TO A REPORT (PART) 2.

PART 1 OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> ARTICLE APPEARED IN BIBLIOTHEEK EN SAMENLEVING 9 (2) FEB 81,
46-51 (SEE 81/5155). THE GUIDELINES FOR STANDARDS OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>
PUBLISHED IN 1980 IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE COMMITTEE FOR THE COORDINATION OF
STANDARDS IN <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> CONTAIN NO <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> OF THE BACKGROUND TO
THE SUGGESTED STANDARDS. <Organization>SOME</Organization> SECTIONS OF THE REPORT CONTAIN CONSIDERABLY
GREATER DETAIL THAN OTHERS, WHICH <Organization>GIVES</Organization> THE REPORT AN UNBALANCED APPEARANCE.
IT IS ALSO NOTEWORTHY THAT NO STANDARDS FOR STAFFING ARE INCLUDED. IN
COMPARISON WITH THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization> STANDARDS OF SERVICE AND THOSE IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COUNTRIES THE
STANDARDS HERE PROPOSED ARE SOMEWHAT LOW. ONLY EXPERIENCE IN PRACTICAL <Organization>USE</Organization> CAN
SHOW WHETHER THEY ARE ADEQUATE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  546
<Organization>CALIFORNIA PUBLIC LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> DIRECTORY, 1980.

CONTAINS LISTINGS FOR <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization>&apos;S 15 <Organization>COOPERATIVE LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> AND 3
<Organization>SINGLE-JURISDICTION LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization> ORGANISED UNDER THE <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES <Organization>ACT</Organization> AS WELL AS LISTINGS FOR THE <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> CENTRES OR
NETWORKS SERVING MORE THAN 1 <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> WHICH WERE ORGANISED AS DEMONSTRATION
PROJECTS UNDER THE <Organization>FEDERAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization>
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FRON <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  547
ASSESSMENT CHECKLIST-A GUIDE TO STRENGTHEN COMMUNITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
COOPERATION.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF THE COMMUNITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location>, AND <Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization>
GUIDELINES TO HELP STRENGTHEN THE ROLES AND LINKS OF A COMMUNITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN
PROVIDING <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> A CHECKLIST TO HELP LIBRARIANS ASSESS&apos; POLICY
STATEMENTS; <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE</Organization> <Organization>ATTITUDES</Organization>; THE COMMUNITY; AND <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization>
STRUCTURES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  548
RECOMMENDATIONS FOR THE ACQUISITION AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> OF BOOKMOBILES.

(WORK PREPARED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> BOOKMOBILES OF THE <Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> (NBLC).) THE <Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> STUDIED <Organization>EXISTING</Organization>
MODELS OF <Organization>BOOKMOBILE</Organization> WHICH MIGHT BE ADAPTED TO <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> CIRCUMSTANCES. <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization>
GUIDELINES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF THE ACQUISITION AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> OF BOOKMOBILES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  549
A BRIEF HISTORY OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARIES COMMISSION</Organization>&apos; A SURVEY OF 25 YEARS.

A REVISED VERSION OF A PAPER GIVEN TO THE <Organization>MUSIC LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN <Location>BOSTON</Location>,
3 MAR 78, AND, IN A DIFFERENT FORM TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARIES COMMISSION</Organization> DURING
THE <Location>SALZBURG</Location> MEETING OF IAML, 2 JULY 78. SUMMARISES THE DEVELOPMENT AND
ACHIEVEMENTS OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARIES COMMISSION</Organization>, WHICH WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1954
AS PART OF IAML. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> BRIEFLY THE WORK OF THE COMMISSION IN PROMOTING AND
SUPPORTING THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>MUSIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND NOTES THE
CONTRIBUTION MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> 1ST PRESIDENT, <Organization>DR</Organization> ALFONS OTT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  550
SCOTLAND 1980. PART ONE.

A SHORT REPORT OF THE INTAMEL (INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF METROPOLITAN <Location>CITY</Location>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) CONGRESS HELD IN <Location>GLASGOW</Location> AND EDINBURGH IN SEPT 80, GIVING DETAILS
OF THE CONFERENCE SESSIONS AND VISITS, TO WHICH ARE APPENDED 3 DESCRIPTIVE AND
HISTORICAL ACCOUNTS COVERING&apos; <Location>GLASGOW</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 1874-1980; <Location>EDINBURGH</Location>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, 1886-1980; AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN SCOTLAND, 1853-1980.
DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF FOUNDATION AND DEVELOPMENT OF SERVICES, AND THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>
SITUATION FULLY DESCRIBED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  551
REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR OF <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>UNITED STATES</Location> AND CANADA.

THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR WAS UNDERTAKEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE REQUEST OF THE PRINCIPAL OF <Location>SHEFFIELD</Location>
<Location>CITY</Location> POLYTECHNIC. THE PURPOSE WAS TO VISIT A RANGE OF <Organization>US HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>
INSTITUTIONS, TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> THE STRUCTURE AND ORGANISATION OF LEARNING RESOURCE
PROVISION, AND TO EXAMINE AND ASCERTAIN <Organization>HOW</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> PROVISION <Organization>RELATES</Organization> TO <Organization>TEACHING</Organization>
METHODS AND <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>CURRICULUM DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  552
AUSTRALIAN <Organization>AID</Organization> TO INDONESIAN UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE AUSTRALIAN <Organization>ASIAN UNIVERSITIES CO</Organization>-OPERATIVE SCHEME WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1969
TO ASSIST IN THE <Organization>IMPROVEMENT</Organization> OF INDONESIAN <Organization>UNIVERSITIES</Organization> AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>
INSTITUTIONS IN <Location>SINGAPORE</Location> AND MALAYSIA. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> ACTIVITIES IN <Location>INDONESIA</Location>;
THE SOCIO-POLITICAL, <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>, AND LINGUISTIC HURDLES FACING STUDENTS; THE
CHALLENGES FACING THE AUSTRALIANS; PROGRESS TO DATE; AND REMAINING
DIFFICULTIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  553
POPULAR CULTURE AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A PRACTICAL PERSPECTIVE.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO POPULAR CULTURE AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>
THE HISTORY AND CONTENTS OF THE POPULAR CULTURE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT BOWLING GREEN STATE
UNIVERSITY</Organization>, OHIO; <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> CONCERN IS THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND ORGANISATION OF
POPULAR CULTURE MATERIALS FOR <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> AND DISSEMINATION TO A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
CONSTITUENCY OF POPULAR CULTURE STUDENTS AND SCHOLARS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  554
POPULAR CULTURE AND THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; THE NYE COLLECTION.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN ISSUE DEVOTED TO POPULAR CULTURE AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization>
THE GROWTH AND UNIQUE PROBLEMS OF MANAGING THE RUSSEL B. NYE POPULAR CULTURE
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> WITHIN THE <Organization>SPECIAL COLLECTIONS DEPARTMENT</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MICHIGAN STATE
UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  555
COLLEGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN ANDHRA PRADESH, WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>OSMANIA</Organization>
UNIVERSITY AREA-A SURVEY.

A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF ARTS, SCIENCE, AND COMMERCE COLLEGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN ANDHRA PRADESH,
<Location>INDIA</Location>, WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>OSMANIA UNIVERSITY</Organization> AREA, WHICH HAS 84
AFFILIATED COLLEGES. DATA WAS COLLECTED THROUGH VISITS AND A MAILED
QUESTIONNAIRE. ANALYSES THE DATA IN TERMS OF MANAGEMENT, <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, FINANCE,
BUILDING AND FURNITURE, ACQUISITION POLICY, PROCESSING, <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization>,
MAINTENANCE OF <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, REGULATIONS, AND STATISTICS. MAKES 24 SUGGESTIONS
CONCERNING STANDARDISATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  556
POLYTECHNIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN HARYANA&apos; A SURVEY.

DEFINES A POLYTECHNIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND TRACES THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
HARYANA (A STATE IN NORTH <Location>INDIA</Location>). EVALUATES <Organization>THEIR</Organization> COLLECTIONS AND SERVICES;
EXPOSES <Organization>THEIR</Organization> DRAWBACKS; AND SUGGESTS STEPS TO <Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FUNCTIONING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  557
DIRECTORY OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>INDIA</Location> AND SRI LANKA&apos; VOLUME TWO.

<Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> 213 <Organization>INDIAN</Organization> AND SRI LANKAN <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. FOR AN ABSTRACT OF VOLUME 1 SEE 81/3136.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  558
DISLIC&apos; DIRECTORY OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>.

DIRECTORY OF 314 <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location> <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AGENCIES,
CONTAINING FULL DETAILS PRINTED <Organization>FROM</Organization> A COMPUTER-BASED FILE, AND 7 INDEXES
PROVIDING ENTRY POINTS TO THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> LISTING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  559

THOUGH <Organization>SOME</Organization> FACTORY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>CLOSED</Organization> OWING TO ECONOMIC PROBLEMS, THOSE
REMAINING ARE CLEARLY THRIVING, PROVIDING VALUABLE <Organization>ASSISTANCE</Organization> IN THE CREATION
OF LEISURE ACTIVITIES. TOPICS DISCUSSED INCLUDE&apos; FAIRY TALES AND FANTASY
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF THE 1960S AND 1970S, ELEMENTS OF WHICH ARE NOW OFTEN FOUND IN
THE WORKS OF <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> DISTINGUISHED AUTHORS; SCIENCE FICTION, WHICH IS OFTEN OF
LITTLE LITERARY VALUE; THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF BLACK <Location>AFRICA</Location> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> CONFLICT WITH
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> CULTURES; TOPICALITY IN DICTIONARIES; THE INTRODUCTION OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> READERS TO
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, INVOLVING THE <Organization>IMPROVEMENT</Organization> OF CATALOGUES, <Organization>PUBLICITY</Organization> FOR NEW
ACCESSIONS, SEMINARS WITHIN THE FIRM AND CONTACT WITH YOUTH CLUBS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  560
THE WORK WITH STOCK IN A <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF AN INDUSTRIAL
CORPORATION.

THE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE EDUCATION DEPARTMENT OF THE
ALEKSANDRIYAUGOL&apos; CORPORATION WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1960. THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> TASK OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS TO HELP WORKERS INCREASE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> QUALIFICATIONS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> IDEOLOGICAL
AND POLITICAL AWARENESS. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WITH A <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF 2 SERVES 1,100 <Organization>USERS</Organization>.
THE <Organization>USER GROUP INCLUDES WORKERS</Organization> ATTENDING THE COURSES ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
EDUCATION DEPARTMENT, LECTURERS AS WELL AS THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization> DEPARTMENTS OF
THE CORPORATION WHICH DO <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE MANAGEMENT OF THE STOCK OF
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (35,000 ITEMS) IS DISCUSSED WITH EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> PLANNING AND
COORDINATION OF ACQUISITION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  561
HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STANDARDS FOR 1980 AND BEYOND (FEATURE).

SECTION DEVOTED TO THE <Organization>US JOINT COMMISSION</Organization> (<Organization>JCAH</Organization>) HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STANDARDS,
<Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PRINCIPLE THAT THE <Organization>HOSPITAL SHALL PROVIDE LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO
MEET THE INFORMATIONAL, EDUCATIONAL, AND, WHEN <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization>, THE
RESEARCH-RELATED NEEDS OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> AND HOSPITAL STAFFS. THE 1ST STANDARD
STATES THAT SERVICES SHALL BE ORGANISED TO ASSURE <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization> DIRECTION OR
SUPERVISION, STAFFING AND <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>; AND THE 2ND STANDARD STATES THAT
PROVISION OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> SHALL BE GUIDED <Organization>BY</Organization> WRITTEN POLICIES
AND PROCEDURES. A SUBJECT INDEX TO THE STANDARDS IS ALSO <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization>, AND A BRIEF
REVIEW OF ELOISE C. FOSTER&apos;S <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> OF THE STANDARDS, RECENTLY PUBLISHED
IN THE BULLETIN OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> FOLLOWS, WRITTEN <Organization>BY</Organization> LEE
BROOKE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  562
SURVEY OF <Organization>NEW ENGLAND HOSPITAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE <Organization>NEW ENGLAND LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SECTION SENT A
QUESTIONNAIRE TO 472 <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> HOSPITALS, WITH 159 USABLE RESPONSES. <Organization>ITS</Organization> ORIGINAL
PURPOSE WAS TO PROVIDE HOSPITAL LIBRARIANS WITH A PROFILE OF COLLEAGUES AND TO
ASSIST IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> PLANNING. QUESTIONS CONCERNED SIZE AND TYPE OF HOSPITAL;
NUMBER, SALARY, AND CHARACTERISTICS OF <Organization>STAFF</Organization>; AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BUDGET</Organization>, <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>,
AND SERVICES. THE RESPONSES ARE TABULATED AND DISCUSSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  563
<Organization>RIVERSIDE METHODIST HOSPITAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY RESOURCE CENTRE</Organization>.

BRIEFLY <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY RESOURCE CENTRE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>RIVERSIDE</Organization>
<Organization>METHODIST HOSPITAL</Organization>, <Location>COLUMBUS</Location>, OHIO, WITH A STEP-BY-STEP ACCOUNT OF <Organization>HOW</Organization>
JOSEPHINE YEOH, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DIRECTOR, CONVINCED THE <Organization>HOSPITAL ADMINISTRATION</Organization> OF
THE NEED FOR SIGNIFICANTLY MORE SPACE FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. A PLAN OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
IS INCLUDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  564
<Organization>DR</Organization>. DOUGLAS DUNCAN, JAN SHULMAN, THE <Organization>JCAH</Organization> AND THIRTY LIBRARIANS IN <Organization>THEIR BOARD</Organization>
ROOM.

UNEDITED <Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF A 90-MINUTE MEETING IN THE <Organization>JOINT COMMISSION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> ACCREDITATION
OF HOSPITALS (<Organization>JCAH</Organization>) BOARD ROOM, <Location>CHICAGO</Location>, ILLINOIS, 5 AUG 80, ATTENDED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>DR</Organization>.
DOUGLAS DUNCAN (<Organization>JCAH HOSPITAL</Organization> ACCREDITATION PROGRAM ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR), JAN
SHULMAN (<Organization>JCAH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> RELATIONS DIRECTOR), HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> REPRESENTATIVES,
AND 30 <Location>CHICAGO</Location>-AREA <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> SCIENCE LIBRARIANS. THE <Organization>JCAH</Organization> REPRESENTATIVES
ANSWERED QUESTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE COMMISSION&apos;S STANDARDS <Organization>ON</Organization> AND ATTITUDE TOWARDS
HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  565
IF HOSPITALS WEREN&apos;T FRIENDLY PLACES...WE&apos;D HAVE TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE NECESSITY FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> STATE HOSPITALS,
COVERING&apos; THE DIFFICULTIES OF INITIATING A SERVICE OPERATED <Organization>BY</Organization> NON-MEDICAL
<Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization>; RELATIONS WITH MANAGEMENT; WHAT KIND OF <Organization>STAFF</Organization> TO CHOOSE; THE
OPERATION OF THE SERVICE; WHAT KIND OF BOOKS TO STOCK; AND FINANCIAL
<Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  566
SERVING <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE COMMUNITY&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO THE DISADVANTAGED.

PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization>, WESTON-SUPER-MARE, NOV 79. TOPICS COVERED
INCLUDE&apos; SERVICES TO ETHNIC MINORITIES IN NOTTINGHAMSHIRE, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
LITERACY, HOSPITAL AND PRISON <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, AND SERVICES TO THE ELDERLY
AND HOUSEBOUND.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  567
BOOKS FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization>.

THE PHYSICALLY AND MENTALLY HANDICAPPED, CONTRIBUTE ROUGHLY 6% OF
<Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>&apos;S POPULATION. TO <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>END</Organization>, THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> CONFERENCE <Organization>AT</Organization> POPRAD,
(<Location>SLOVAKIA</Location>), HELD IN MAY 81 DEALT WITH THE <Organization>IMPROVEMENT</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR
HANDICAPPED PEOPLE. THE LECTURES GIVEN SHOWED A <Organization>GOOD THEORETICAL FOUNDATION</Organization>
VERY OFTEN MORE <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> THAN THE PRACTICAL <Organization>ASSISTANCE</Organization> GIVEN TO THE
HANDICAPPED AND <Organization>DISABLED</Organization>. LIBRARIANS CAN INFLUENCE THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>&apos;S
ATTITUDE TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> HANDICAPPED FELLOW-CITIZENS. THE CONFERENCE PARTICIPANTS
MADE <Organization>SOME</Organization> USEFUL SUGGESTIONS, FOR EXAMPLE, ADJUSTMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>EQUIPMENT</Organization> FOR
THE HANDICAPPED, DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>READING</Organization> AIDS FOR BEDRIDDEN PEOPLE AND THE
LIKE, AND THERE WAS ALSO AN APPEAL TO THE PRESS FOR FULL COVERAGE OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> AND
MANY <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PROBLEMS FACING THE HANDICAPPED IN <Organization>THIS</Organization>, THE INTERNATIONAL YEAR OF
THE <Organization>DISABLED</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  568
THE HANDICAPPED AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE HANDICAPPED ARE DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> FOR SPREADING KNOWLEDGE OF
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> AIDS AND THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. SOCIETY CREATES THE HANDICAP <Organization>BY</Organization>
MAKING ACTIVITIES UNAVAILABLE. IT IS THEREFORE THE RESPONSIBILITY OF SOCIETY
AND INDIVIDUALS TO SEE THAT OBSTACLES ARE REMOVED <Organization>NOT</Organization> JUST TO <Organization>BETTER</Organization> LIVING
CONDITIONS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO TO A FULL <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE FOR THE HANDICAPPED. THE DEMAND
FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> FOR THE HANDICAPPED <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS
SHOWN IN A CAMPAIGN LED <Organization>BY</Organization> KALMAR <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO BE GROWING AMONG
TEACHERS TRYING TO <Organization>INTEGRATE</Organization> THE HANDICAPPED IN SCHOOLS. <Organization>STAFF</Organization> WITHIN THE
<Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS CAN ALSO <Organization>ACT</Organization> AS LINKS BETWEEN THE HANDICAPPED AND THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MUST STIMULATE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO INITIATE
<Organization>DOMICILIARY SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> SYSTEMS FOR <Organization>LENDING</Organization> OF SPEAKING BOOKS AND
PERSONAL CONTACTS WITH <Organization>USERS</Organization>. THE <Organization>MASS MEDIA</Organization> AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> TEACHERS ARE <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
MEANS OF REACHING THE HANDICAPPED WITH <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ABOUT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVI CES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  569
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> TO <Organization>DISABLED</Organization> INDIVIDUALS.

A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ISSUE COMPRISING 7 ARTICLES, FOR <Organization>ABSTRACTS</Organization> OF WHICH SEE THE
FOLLOWING <Organization>SERIAL</Organization> NUMBERS&apos;.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  570
ARCHITECTURAL AND PROGRAM ACCESSIBILITY&apos; A REVIEW OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROGRAMS,
FACILITIES AND PUBLICATIONS FOR LIBRARIANS SERVING <Organization>DISABLED</Organization> INDIVIDUALS.

CONTRIBUTION TO A <Organization>THEMATIC ISSUE ON INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>DISABLED</Organization>.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>, ATTITUDINAL, AND <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> BARRIERS THAT <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
HISTORICALLY CONFRONTED HANDICAPPED PEOPLE; OUTLINES RELEVANT LEGISLATION; AND
LISTS <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> PUBLICATIONS AND <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> OF INTEREST TO LIBRARIANS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  571
MAKE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ACCESSIBLE TO <Organization>ALL</Organization>!.

6 YEARS AFTER THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> AGREED <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> POLICY, NO PROPOSALS FOR
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> A POLICY <Organization>ON</Organization> THE NEEDS OF THE HANDICAPPED EXIST. DESPITE OUR CONCERN FOR
FREEDOM OF EXPRESSION, MANY HANDICAPPED ARE DENIED ACCESS TO THE SPOKEN AND
PRINTED <Organization>WORD</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> AN OBLIGATION TO MAKE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> ACTIVITIES
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO <Organization>ALL</Organization>. <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization> ACCESSIBILITY MEANS THAT THE HANDICAPPED CAN
REACH THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, ENTER IT AND STAY THERE. <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> BUILDINGS AND
TRANSPORT CAN<Organization>NOT</Organization> REPLACE THE <Organization>DOMICILIARY LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. INDIRECT
ACCESSIBILITY MEANS THAT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES AND MEDIA MUST BE ADAPTED TO REACH
<Organization>NEW</Organization> GROUPS. &apos;EASY READERS&apos; ARE AN EXAMPLE OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A MEDIUM AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
PUBLICATION AND DISTRIBUTION THROUGH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE DISCUSSED. THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> STATE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR <Organization>SPEECH</Organization> AND BRAILLE PRINTING IS THE 1ST STAGE IN PROVISION FOR THE
BLIND AND PARTIALLY-SIGHTED; THE NEXT IS THE <Organization>INCREASED</Organization> DISTRIBUTION OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> GROUPS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  572
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO THE VISUALLY HANDICAPPED IN <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>.

REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> CONCERNED WITH THE VISUALLY HANDICAPPED IN
<Location>MALAYSIA</Location> TO REVIEW <Organization>PRESENT SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>SET</Organization> UP A MODEL FOR A SERVICE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Location>KUALA LUMPUR</Location>, RECOMMEND IMPROVEMENTS TO <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> SERVICES AND
ORGANISE A <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization>. ONLY 8,000 OF AN ESTIMATED 40,000 BLIND IN WEST <Location>MALAYSIA</Location>
ARE REGISTERED AS THERE IS NO OBLIGATION TO DO <Organization>SO</Organization>. THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HOPES
TO <Organization>HAVE</Organization> A SECTION FOR THE VISUALLY HANDICAPPED WHEN <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDING IS READY
IN 1983, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>PRINT</Organization> BOOKS ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> ALREADY. <Location>MALAYSIA</Location> HAS 4
SOCIETIES FOR THE BLIND. THE <Organization>MALAYAN ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN KAULA <Location>LUMPUR</Location> PRODUCES AND
LENDS BRAILLE BOOKS TO REGISTERED <Organization>USERS</Organization>. TALKING BOOKS ARE PRODUCED <Organization>BY</Organization> ST.
<Organization>NICHOLAS SCHOOL</Organization> FOR THE BLIND IN <Location>PENANG</Location>. MOST <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> IS IN <Organization>ENGLISH</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT
IS HOPED TO INCREASE THE PRODUCTION OF BOOKS IN MALAY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE EXPENSE OF
<Organization>ENGLISH</Organization>, AS THE LATTER <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> CAN BE BORROWED <Organization>FROM</Organization> ABROAD.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  573
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR TALKING BOOKS AND BRAILLE.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR TALKING BOOKS AND BRAILLE (TPB) WAS ESTABLISHED <Organization>ON</Organization> 1 JAN 80
WHEN THE STATE TOOK OVER THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES OF THE SOCIETY FOR THE BLIND.
THE 1ST <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR THE BLIND HAD BEGUN IN 1892, AND WITH THE ARRIVAL OF TAPES
THE SOCIETY BEGAN <Organization>LENDING</Organization> TALKING BOOKS IN 1955, NOW AS CASSETTES THE DOMINANT
MEDIUM. <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE START THE BOOKS WERE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE
BOOKS ARE SOLD <Organization>AT COST</Organization> PRICE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
THE PROVISION WAS THE SUBJECT OF <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> REPORTS, ABOVE <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE HANDICAP
COMMISSION&apos;S REPORT CULTURE FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization>, 1976. <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> LOANS TO INDIVIDUALS <Organization>FROM</Organization>
TPB ARE FALLING, AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>ROLE AS CENTRE</Organization> FOR LOANS OF DEPOSIT
COLLECTIONS IS GROWING. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WHICH IS LED <Organization>BY</Organization> 7 STATE APPOINTEES, HAS
UNITS FOR PRODUCTION, <Organization>LENDING</Organization>, EDUCATIONAL <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization>, DEVELOPMENT AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  574
FIFTEEN YEARS OF SERVICE TO CHILDREN AND YOUNG PEOPLE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE MARIANO PICON
SALAS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

AN ACCOUNT OF THE GROWTH OF <Location>VENEZUELA</Location>&apos;S 1ST CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, DESCRIBING
SERVICES AND ACTIVITIES, <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> PROGRAMMES, COLLABORATION WITH SCHOOLS, AND
THE EVENTS PLANNED TO CELEBRATE <Organization>ITS</Organization> ANNIVERSARY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  575
<Organization>INFORMATION EDUCATION</Organization> OF PUPILS AND THE <Organization>ROLE</Organization> OF THE TEACHER.

THE &apos;<Organization>INFORMATION EDUCATION</Organization>&apos; OF SCHOOL CHILDREN IS <Organization>NOT</Organization> JUST THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF LIBRARIANS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> IT SHOULD BE AN INTEGRAL PART OF THE <Organization>MODERN</Organization> <Organization>TEACHING</Organization>
PROCESS IN EVERY SUBJECT. SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> TRADITIONALLY OPERATED <Organization>ON</Organization> A
RUDIMENTARY LEVEL AS BOOKSTOCKS WITH <Organization>LENDING</Organization> OUTLETS-MOSTLY SUPPLYING
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> RELEVANT TO THE <Organization>TEACHING</Organization> OF THE MOTHER TONGUE. <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS NO LONGER
ADEQUATE AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MUST BE TRANSFORMED INTO UP-TO-DATE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
AND <Organization>STUDY</Organization> CENTRES. THE <Organization>SLOVAK MINISTRY</Organization> OF EDUCATION HAS ISSUED A DIRECTIVE NO
3767/1979 WHICH <Organization>ENVISAGES SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FULFILLING 3 ROLES&apos; SUPPLYING
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> TO BOTH TEACHERS AND PUPILS; CONTRIBUTING TO
THE UPBRINGING OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> SOCIALIST GENERATION THROUGH <Organization>WORKING</Organization> WITH BOOKS;
EDUCATING BOTH TEACHERS AND PUPILS TO <Organization>USE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES INDEPENDENTLY
DURING <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization>, CAREER <Organization>SELECTION</Organization> AND LEISURE. ACQUISITION MUST PLACE
GREATER EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>, TE CHNICAL AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> SUBJECT ORIENTED BOOKS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  576
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> BEHAVIOR.

THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IS DIVIDED INTO 4 SECTIONS&apos; (1) <Organization>USER</Organization> ATTRIBUTES; (2) ANALYSIS OF
<Organization>USER</Organization>&apos;S PERCEPTION OF WHICH SOURCES ARE MOST LIKELY TO PROVIDE THE DESIRED
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS WELL AS HIS/HER SEARCH STRATEGY; (3) <Organization>USER</Organization>&apos;S PREFERENCE FOR A
<Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> SOURCE VERSUS HIS/HER ACCEPTANCE OF ANY <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> AS LONG AS IT WILL
FURNISH THE DATA NEEDED; (4) IMPACT OF <Organization>MASS MEDIA</Organization>, AND TELEVISION IN
<Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization>, <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SEEKING BEHAVIOUR.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  577
<Organization>USE</Organization> STUDIES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS.

EDITED VERSION OF &apos;<Organization>USE</Organization> AND THE <Organization>USER</Organization>&apos; PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A <Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization>
COMMITTEE MEETING, 26 JUNE 79. JUDGES THE MOST <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> CONCLUSIONS
REACHED <Organization>SO</Organization> FAR THROUGH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIALS <Organization>USE</Organization> STUDIES TO BE&apos; (1) RECORDED <Organization>USE</Organization>
IN MANY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS LOW; (2) <Organization>USE</Organization> WITHIN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PARALLELS <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization>;
(3) PAST <Organization>USE</Organization> PREDICTS FUTURE <Organization>USE</Organization>; (4) RECENT MATERIALS ARE USED MORE
FREQUENTLY; AND (5) AMERICANS <Organization>USE</Organization> FEW FOREIGN-LANGUAGE MATERIALS. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>
PROBLEMS OF MEASUREMENT AND INTERPRETATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  578
AN EVALUATION OF <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> UTILIZATION METHODOLOGIES AND FINDINGS.

A RECENT EVALUATION OF <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> INDICATES THAT THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
CAN<Organization>NOT</Organization> BE COMPARED; <Organization>BUT</Organization>, THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS CAN BE COMPARED IF THE
OBJECTIVES FOR THE COLLECTIONS ARE THE <Organization>SAME</Organization>. THE REASONING BEHIND <Organization>THIS</Organization> THESIS
IS <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization> ALONG WITH AN EVALUATION OF <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> UTILISATION
METHODOLOGIES AND FINDINGS. A <Organization>SET</Organization> OF VARIABLES THAT ARE TO BE ACCOUNTED FOR IN
COMPARATIVE STUDIES IS ALSO <Organization>PROVIDED</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  579
THE RANGES OF LIFE INTERESTS AND <Organization>READING</Organization> INTERESTS AMONG <Organization>ADULT</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN COMMUNITIES OF <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> SIZES.

QUESTIONNAIRE SURVEY OF <Organization>USERS</Organization> OF 6 ILLINOIS <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SERVING
COMMUNITIES OF <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> SIZES. THE FINDINGS INDICATE THAT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TEND
TO SERVE THE MORE EDUCATED, THE YOUNG, AND WHITE <Organization>COLLAR WORKERS</Organization>, WHO WERE
INTERESTED IN A WIDE RANGE OF SUBJECTS. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE IMPLICATIONS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ACQUISITION POLICIES AND MAKES SUGGESTIONS FOR <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Organization>RELATED</Organization>
AREAS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  580
THE DEVELOPMENT AND TESTING OF A <Organization>CONCEPTUAL</Organization> MODEL OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization>
BEHAVIOR.

THE OBJECTIVE OF THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WAS TO TEST THE FOLLOWING HIERARCHICAL MODEL&apos;
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> IS A FUNCTION OF (1) <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS; (2)
AWARENESS OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>; (3) PERCEIVED ACCESSIBILITY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; (4)
PERCEIVED EASE OF <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; AND (5) <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization> NON-PUBLIC
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE MODEL WAS TESTED WITH 4 DIFFERENT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> MEASURES-A
DICHOTOMISED MEASURE OF <Organization>USE</Organization> AND NONUSE, AND, AMONG <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization>, FREQUENCY OF
<Organization>USE</Organization> AND 2-FACTOR ANALYTICALLY DERIVED INDEXES DESCRIPTIVE OF 2 DISTINCTLY
DIFFERENT TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>. TYPE 1 <Organization>USE</Organization> APPEARED TO MEASURE <Organization>USE</Organization> INTENSITY;
TYPE 2-IN-HOUSE <Organization>USE</Organization>. <Organization>INTERVIEW DATA</Organization> WERE COLLECTED <Organization>FROM</Organization> 202 RESIDENTS OF
<Location>SYRACUSE</Location>, <Location>NEW YORK</Location>. RESULTS INDICATED THAT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization> PERCEIVED THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS MORE ACCESSIBLE THAN DID NONUSERS, AND <Organization>USE</Organization> FREQUENCY WAS <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO
AWARENESS OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROGRAMMES, AS WAS INTENSITY OF <Organization>USE</Organization>, AND IN-HOUSE
<Organization>USE</Organization> WAS <Organization>RELATED</Organization>  TO <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  581
THE SUBJECT INTENSITY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>&apos; <Organization>SOME</Organization> ASPECTS OF POLYTECHNIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>.

STUDIES OF <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> IN POLYTECHNICS ARE REPORTED. ISSUES
WERE INVESTIGATED IN 3 POLYTECHNIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, REPRESENTING DIFFERENT LEVELS OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION, AND ANALYSED IN TERMS OF SIZE AND NOVELTY OF STOCK. NEWER
STOCK WAS FOUND TO BE PREFERRED ALMOST UNIVERSALLY, AND LARGER STOCKS WERE
MORE HEAVILY USED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  582
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTS</Organization> USAGE IN AN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; THE CASE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> IBADAN
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

EXAMINES USAGE OF <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTS</Organization> FOR <Organization>RESEARCH AT IBADAN UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Location>NIGERIA</Location>. THE RESULTS SHOW THAT <Organization>SUCH</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTS</Organization> CONSTITUTE A
SUBSTANTIAL PART OF THE MATERIALS USED FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND THAT STATISTICAL
PUBLICATIONS ARE THE MOST FREQUENTLY CONSULTED MATERIALS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  583
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AND LITERARY <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.

A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A 1980 <Organization>QUEBEC CORPORATION</Organization> DES BIBLIOTHECAIRES
PROFESSIONNELS CONFERENCE, DISTINGUISHING THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS OF THE
LITERARY RESEARCHER <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> NEEDS. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> IN DETAIL THE KIND OF
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> REQUIRED, AND SHOWS <Organization>HOW</Organization> THE NOTIONS OF OBSOLESCENCE AND
EXHAUSTIVITY ARE LARGELY IRRELEVANT. TO MEET <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> NEEDS, <Location>QUEBEC</Location>
SHOULD <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> A UNION <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> AND A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>; HERE THE COMPUTER IS <Organization>NOT</Organization> THE SOLUTION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  584
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND SCIENCE.

THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> CONCERN OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES SHOULD BE <Organization>SPEEDY</Organization> AND
<Organization>EFFECTIVE SERVICE</Organization> TO <Organization>USERS</Organization>. THEY MUST BE CONCERNED TO ELIMINATE ANY
UNNECESSARY DELAYS, WHICH MAY CAUSE DELAYS IN THE SCIENTIST&apos;S WORK. LIBRARIANS
SHOULD TAKE AN ACTIVE INTEREST IN THE WORK OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EDUCATION
AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> EXPERTISE SHOULD ALLOW THEM TO DO <Organization>SO</Organization>. A SURVEY IN THE <Organization>SLOVAK</Organization>
<Organization>ACADEMY</Organization> OF SCIENCE HAD SHOWN THAT MOST SOUGHT AFTER ARE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES
1-3 YEARS <Organization>OLD</Organization> IN <Organization>NATURAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> AND MEDICINE, 1-10 YEARS <Organization>OLD</Organization> IN THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>. <Organization>GOOD ACQUISITION</Organization> POLICY, <Organization>QUALITY</Organization> IN <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES CONTRIBUTE TO <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> DEVELOPMENT AND <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGICAL
REVOLUTION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization>  585
<Organization>USER</Organization> SATISFACTION IN THE <Organization>HUGH STEPHENS COLLEGE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
