<Organization>Document</Organization> 3001
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LENDING RIGHT&apos; <Organization>SITUATION</Organization> IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location> AND AUSTRALIA.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A THEMATIC ISSUE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LENDING RIGHT (PLR). <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location>
AND AUSTRALIA INTRODUCED PLR SCHEMES IN 1973 AND 1974 RESPECTIVELY. THERE WAS
NO COOPERATION AND THE SCHEMES ARE DISSIMILAR. OUTLINES THE QUALIFICATION
RULES FOR AUTHORS AND WORKS IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> SCHEME. UNLIKE <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>, <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location> DOES
<Organization>NOT</Organization> MAKE PAYMENTS TO <Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> AND THE SCHEME&apos;S INTRODUCTION INVOLVED CLOSE
COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> AUTHORS AND LIBRARIANS. IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>, PAYMENTS ARE THE
SAME AS IN 1973 DESPITE AN INCREASE IN THE CONSUMER PRICE INDEX OF NEARLY 100%
AND DESPITE MANY ATTEMPTS TO INCREASE PAYMENTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3002
VIDEODISC-THE PROGRAMMING REALITIES.
     
THE WORK OF THE <Organization>NEBRASKA VIDEODISC DESIGN</Organization>/<Organization>PRODUCTION GROUP</Organization>, WHICH HAS PRODUCED
33 DIFFERENT VIDEO <Organization>DISC</Organization> PROGRAMMES, IS REVIEWED AND THE <Organization>PREMASTERING SERVICE</Organization>
WHICH THE GROUP OFFERS, COVERING <Organization>ALL</Organization> STEPS UP TO, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>, ACTUAL
VIDEO <Organization>DISC</Organization> MASTERING IS DESCRIBED. 3 <Organization>BASIC</Organization> LEVELS OF <Organization>INTERACTIVE</Organization> CAPABILITY
FOR VIDEO <Organization>DISC</Organization> PLAYERS AND PLAYER SYSTEMS ARE IDENTIFIED AND THE <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>EACH</Organization> LEVEL FOR INTERACTIVITY IS ASSESSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3003
<Organization>DIAL-A-SLIDE SERVICE</Organization> FOR PRODUCERS.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>VISUAL</Organization> RESOURCES <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> DEVELOPED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>COMPANY</Organization> MARTAK FOR
<Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF OVER 50,000 SLIDES. A CUSTOMER&apos;S REQUIREMENTS ARE RUN
AGAINST THE <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> INDEX AND THE COMPUTER SELECTS AND DISPLAYS DETAILS
OF THE MOST <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization> SLIDE. A COPY OF THE SLIDE IS MADE AND DESPATCHED.
MOST <Organization>USERS</Organization> ARE PRODUCERS OF TAPE/SLIDE PRESENTATIONS. MARTAK IS HOPING TO
SERVICE THE <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization> OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization> COMPANIES AND IS TO MARKET A LESS <Organization>COMPLEX</Organization>
VERSION OF THE SOFTWARE, ENABLING COMPANIES TO SORT OUT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization>
THEMSELVES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3004
A STUDY OF THE RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE FEED-BACK ABILITY AND THE DENSITY AND
<Organization>RESOLUTION</Organization> OF THE MICROFILM (IN CHINESE).
     
SUCCESSFUL DUPLICATION OF MICROFILMS DEPENDS <Organization>ON</Organization>, 2INTER ALIA1, THE DENSITY AND
<Organization>RESOLUTION</Organization> OF THE MICROFILMS. COMPARES THE MICROFILMING <Organization>QUALITY</Organization> REQUIREMENTS
OF DOCUMENTS CONTAINING BOTH CHINESE CHARACTERS AND ROMAN LETTERS AND
DOCUMENTS CONTAINING ROMAN LETTERS ONLY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3005
THE <Organization>RESOLUTION POWER</Organization> OF MICROFILMS (IN CHINESE).
     
IN ORDER TO HAVE A DEEPER UNDERSTANDING OF THE <Organization>INFLUENCE</Organization> OF <Organization>RESOLUTION POWER</Organization>
<Organization>ON</Organization> MICROFILMS, <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE DETERMINING METHODS OF <Organization>RESOLUTION POWER</Organization> FOR FILM
MANUFACTURING AND <Organization>USER</Organization>&apos;S APPLICATION. THE EXPRESSION OF <Organization>RESOLUTION POWER</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization>
LINES PER MIN IS SOMETIMES CONFUSING, SO THE METHOD READABLE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE PATTERN
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>NBS</Organization> <Organization>RESOLUTION</Organization> TEST CHART 1010A REGARDLESS OF THE REDUCTION RATIO HAS
<Organization>BEEN</Organization> INTRODUCED. FURTHERMORE, <Organization>USING</Organization> THE <Organization>QUALITY</Organization> INDEX CHART, IT IS <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> TO
UNDERSTAND THE DIFFERENCE <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE <Organization>RESOLUTION POWER</Organization> REQUIRED TO MICROFILM
THE ORIGINALS CONTAINING ONLY ROMANIC LETTERS AND THOSE CONTAINING CHINESE
CHARACTERS, WHICH ARE MUCH MORE COMPLICATED IN STRUCTURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3006
WHEN MONEY IS SCARCE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE MUST GROW.
     
INTERVIEWS INGAR BECKMAN-HIRSCHFELDT, CHAIRMAN OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
LIBRARIANS&apos; UNION (SFF) IN CONNECTION WITH A CAMPAIGN ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization> DIK
(<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, CULTURE), AN <Organization>UMBRELLA ORGANIZATION</Organization> OF 8
ASSOCIATIONS, OF WHICH SFF IS A MEMBER. THE CAMPAIGN AIMS TO PUT <Organization>PRESSURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization>
POLITICIANS UP TO THE <Organization>TIME</Organization> OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AND <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ELECTIONS IN 1982 AND
DEMONSTRATE THE CONSEQUENCES OF CUTS; A DISCUSSION BOOK DESCRIBING THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>
<Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND STATING ALTERNATIVES WHICH <Organization>WOULD</Organization> GIVE
HIGHER PRIORITY TO CULTURE IS TO BE PUBLISHED. <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> OPINION IS TO BE
MOBILISED AND A <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> FOR DIK DRAWN UP. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> NO SECTION OF
THE CAMPAIGN IS AIMED SPECIFICALLY <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, DEMAND FOR A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization> TO
ENSURE REASONABLE AND UNIFORM STANDARDS WILL BE MADE. CUTS IN <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
SERVICES ARE UNACCEPTABLE TO DIK AND LIBRARIANS ARE URGED <Organization>NOT</Organization> TO COOPERATE IN
SUGGESTING CUTS IN SERVICES AND MANPOWER. SFF EXPECTS LITTLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY COMMISSION</Organization>, <Organization>ON</Organization> WHICH IT IS <Organization>NOT</Organization> REPRESENTED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3007
AN <Organization>ANALYSIS</Organization> OF THE METHODS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO CONVEY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>COMPLEX</Organization> BIOCHEMICAL
STRUCTURES, <Organization>BY</Organization> REPRESENTATIONS AND CODING SYSTEMS.
     
(MSC THESIS.) REPRESENTATIONS ARE VITAL FOR THE <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> OF PROTEIN
STRUCTURAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. <Organization>THESE</Organization> REPRESENTATIONS CAN BE CLASSIFIED ACCORDING TO
BIOCHEMICAL STRUCTURE, AND VARY IN COMPLEXITY AND METHOD OF <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization>. MANY
TYPES OF REPRESENTATION ARE NECESSARY TO FULLY <Organization>DOCUMENT</Organization> A PROTEIN STRUCTURE.
INVESTIGATES THE PRIMARY <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OF PROTEIN STRUCTURE, AND THE METHODS <Organization>USED</Organization>
<Organization>BY</Organization> BIOCHEMICAL AND <Organization>CHEMICAL</Organization> DATA <Organization>BASES</Organization> IN HANDLING PROTEIN STRUCTURES.
<Organization>EXPLORES</Organization> <Organization>ASPECTS</Organization> OF NOMENCLATURE OF PROTEINS AND CODING SYSTEMS FOR PROTEINS,
AND THE SUITABILITY OF NOERR STRUCTURES FOR STORING BIOCHEMICAL STRUCTURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3008
REGISTRATION OF <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> DRUGS, <Organization>ITS</Organization> UTILITY FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization> REGISTRATION IN FOREIGN
COUNTRIES.
     
THERAPEUTIC VALUE AND SIDE-EFFECTS OF, AND NECESSITY FOR DRUGS IN <Location>HUNGARY</Location> ARE
SUPERVISED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL INSTITUTE</Organization> OF PHARMACY, WITH CIRCULATION AUTHORISED
<Organization>BY</Organization> THE MINISTRY OF HEALTH. REGISTRATION IS CARRIED OUT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
INSTITUTE, WHICH ALSO DETERMINES THE QUALITATIVE REQUIREMENTS OF THE <Organization>PRODUCT</Organization>
AND CONFIRMS THE FACTORY&apos;S <Organization>USE</Organization> AND DOSAGE INSTRUCTIONS. DRUG <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> IS
HANDED OVER AFTER PRECLINICAL AND CLINICO-PHARMACOLOGICAL EXAMINATIONS, AND
INCLUDES ANTECEDENTS OF THE ACTIVE AGENTS AND VEHICLES, AND DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> TOXICITY,
AND CARCINOGENIC AND MUTAGENOUS PROPERTIES. REGISTRATION IS AN <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization>
<Organization>FACTOR</Organization> FOR EXPORT-MOST COUNTRIES REGISTER <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> DRUGS ONLY AFTER THEY HAVE
<Organization>BEEN</Organization> REGISTERED ALREADY IN <Location>HUNGARY</Location>. FOREIGN ACKNOWLEDGEMENT AND CIRCULATION OF
A DRUG REQUIRE <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> REGISTRATION PRESCRIPTIONS IN THE PARTNER
COUNTRIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3009
THE EVOLUTION OF AN INTERNATIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> COMMUNITY.
     
CONTENDS THAT THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> FAR-REACHING SCOPE AND VARIETY OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> AND
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITY <Organization>AT</Organization> THE INTERNATIONAL LEVEL, AS MANIFESTED IN THE WORK OF MANY
DIFFERENT KINDS OF INTERNATIONAL ORGANISATION, ARE <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> ONLY BECAUSE OF
THE EMERGENCE AFTER WORLD WAR I OF AN <Organization>INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY</Organization> WHICH DID <Organization>NOT</Organization>
PREVIOUSLY EXIST. SUGGESTS WHY, IN THE PROFESSION OF LIBRARIANSHIP, THE LEAGUE
OF <Organization>NATIONS ORGANIZATION</Organization> FOR INTELLECTUAL COOPERATION BECAME THE SYMBOL OF AND
CENTRE FOR <Organization>THIS COMMUNITY</Organization> RATHER THAN THE PALAIS MONDIAL OR MUNDANEUM, CREATED
<Organization>BY</Organization> PAUL OTLET AND HENRI LAFONTAINE IN <Location>BRUSSELS</Location> OVER 20 YEARS BEFORE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3010
THE <Organization>NATIONWIDE</Organization> PROVISION AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>: ASLIB/<Organization>IIS</Organization>/<Location>LA</Location>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> BRIEFLY THE PROCEEDINGS OF THE 1ST EVER JOINT CONFERENCE OF ASLIB,
THE INSTITUTE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS, AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, HELD IN
<Location>SHEFFIELD</Location>, 15-19 SEPT 80. THE THEME OF THE CONFERENCE WAS &apos;THE <Organization>NATIONWIDE</Organization>
PROVISION AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>&apos;. SUMMARISES THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> POINTS OF: PROFESSOR
SAUNDERS&apos; OPENING ADDRESS <Organization>ON</Organization> &apos;<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, THE UNSCARCE <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization>&apos;; AND THE
PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> KEN BAKEWELL, CHRISTINA BEALE AND ALAN WHEATLEY <Organization>ON</Organization> &apos;THE
INDEX: ACCESS OR BARRIER TO <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>&apos;. (SEE 81/2966).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3011
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ACTIVITIES IN EUROPEAN COUNTRIES. (1) IMPRESSIONS OF
<Location>HUNGARY</Location>.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> A VISIT MADE <Organization>BY</Organization> THE AUTHOR TO HUNGARY IN ORDER TO ATTEND THE 2ND
INTERNATIONAL SEMINAR <Organization>ON</Organization> &apos;APPLICATIONS OF STANDARDS IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>&apos; AND TO
VISIT SEVERAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND ATTEND LECTURES AND MEETINGS CONCERNED WITH
<Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> VISITS TO THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE PARLIAMENT
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>HUNGARIAN ACADEMY OF SCIENCES</Organization>. GIVES
IMPRESSIONS OF <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> LIFE IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization>
LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3012
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Location>RUSSIA</Location>...LIBRARYWISE.
     
FEATURE ORIGINATING IN A 1980 STUDY VISIT <Organization>BY</Organization> A DELEGATION OF ITALIAN
LIBRARIANS TO KIEV, <Location>MOSCOW</Location> AND LENINGRAD, INTRODUCED <Organization>BY</Organization> A TRANSLATION OF A
<Organization>UNESCO TEXT ON SOVIET LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. A SERIES OF 5 TRANSLATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> RECENT
SPECIALIST <Organization>SOVIET</Organization> JOURNALS <Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE LENIN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
<Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NETWORKS</Organization>, CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND THE CAREERS ADVISORY
SERVICE. ALSO INCLUDED ARE <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Location>KIEV</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR CHILDREN
AND YOUNG PEOPLE, AND CONTENTS SUMMARIES OF 13 RECENT <Organization>SOVIET</Organization> TEXTS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCIENCE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3013
IN THE SHADOW OF THE BLACK KRONE.
     
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>SWEDISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S ANNUAL MEETING IN <Location>KIRUNA</Location>, JUNE
81. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE ACCUSED OF FIXATING <Organization>ON</Organization> LOAN FIGURES AND NEGLECTING <Organization>QUALITY</Organization>.
PROTESTS AGAINST CUTS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPENDITURE AND CALLS FOR A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization> HAVE
COME <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization>, AUTHORS AND TRADE UNIONS, AS WELL AS LIBRARIANS. <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE
<Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION</Organization>&apos;S REMIT DOES <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization> PROPOSALS FOR A LAW, NOR
MAY IT RECOMMEND <Organization>ACTION</Organization> WHICH INVOLVES <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> EXPENDITURE. IT IS FOREMOST AN
EXAMINATION OF THE STATUS QUO. IT HOPES TO DRAW <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FINDINGS</Organization> OF THE DALA
<Organization>PROJECT</Organization>, A <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> CAMPAIGN STARTING IN AUTUMN 81. AN ACCOUNT OF THE
<Organization>VIDEOGRAM COMMISSION</Organization>&apos;S WORK WAS GIVEN; STRESS WAS LAID <Organization>ON</Organization> THE POSITIVE <Organization>ASPECTS</Organization>
OF VIDEO, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>GREATER</Organization> AVAILABILITY OF RARE AND UNPOPULAR FILMS AND AIDS
FOR MINORITIES. A <Organization>DISTRIBUTION</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> FOR SERIOUS VIDEO <Organization>PRODUCTION</Organization> <Organization>INVOLVING</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS CALLED FOR. A <Organization>RESOLUTION</Organization> AGAINST THE INTRODUCTION OF LENDING
FEES AND FOR A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LAW WAS REJECTED AS UNANI MITY AMONG REPRESENTATIVES
WAS LACKING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3014
ROLE OF SCIENTIFIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
     
IN THE 1980S, <Organization>BULGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MUST MEET THE <Organization>COMMUNIST PARTY</Organization> REQUIREMENTS
TO BECOME <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> CONTRIBUTORS <Organization>NOT</Organization> ONLY TO THE COUNTRY&apos;S <Organization>TECHNOLOGICAL</Organization>
PROGRESS <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO TO THE <Organization>POPULATION</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>AESTHETIC EDUCATION</Organization>. TO BECOME EQUAL
PARTNERS IN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, SCIENTIFIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE TO
REASSESS THE <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> FOR, AND THE MEANS OF IMPLEMENTING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION
AND COORDINATION IN RESPECT OF <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP <Organization>THEIR</Organization> BOOK <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization>. ACQUISITION
OF <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization> AND PERIODICALS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE CAPITALIST COUNTRIES MUST, IN
<Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization>, BE PLANNED VERY CAREFULLY CONSIDERING THE FOREIGN CURRENCY
RESOURCES. <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> HAND, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MUST CONSIDER AS THE 1ST AND FOREMOST
DUTY THE DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> REGARDING THE ACHIEVEMENTS OF THE <Location>USSR</Location>
AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> SOCIALIST COUNTRIES <Organization>FROM</Organization> WHICH <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization> ARE FREELY <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>.
INTERLIBRARY LENDING MUST BE BACKED UP AND EXPEDITED <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> <Organization>TELEX</Organization> AND
<Organization>PHOTOCOPYING SERVICES</Organization>. WELL-KEPT B IBLIOGRAPHIC RESOURCES <Organization>NOT</Organization> ONLY HAVE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> VALUE <Organization>BUT</Organization> THEY ALSO HELP IN ATTRACTING <Organization>NEW</Organization> READERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3015
THE <Organization>CHANGING</Organization> ROLE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; BACKGROUND PAPERS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE WHITE HOUSE
CONFERENCE.
     
BACKGROUND PAPERS PREPARED FOR DELEGATES TO THE WHITE HOUSE CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES (WHCLIS), <Location>WASHINGTON, DC</Location>., NOV 79. THE 6
PAPERS ARE&apos; <Organization>NEIGHBOURHOOD INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> CENTERS; SERVING CITIZENS WITH
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> NEEDS; CAREER AND EMPLOYMENT <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>; <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization>
EDUCATION SERVICES; <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND STRENGTHENING THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3016
TEXAS <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> ACT, ANNUAL PROGRAM,
FFY 1981.
     
PLANS, OBJECTIVES, AND EXPECTED RESULTS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization>
ACT <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> IN TEXAS ARE PRESENTED FOR 1981. STATEMENTS <Organization>DOCUMENT</Organization> THE NEED,
OBJECTIVES, AND PRODUCTS, LSCA PRIORITY, TIMETABLE, AND SUGGESTED METHOD FOR
EVALUATION FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF 13 PROGRAMMES UNDER THE <Organization>TITLE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS.
APPLICATION GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ESTABLISHMENT AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION
INCENTIVE GRANTS ARE PROVIDED, AS WELL AS SUGGESTIONS FOR PREPARING <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>
PLANS AND BUDGETS FOR <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> CENTRES. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3017
TEXAS <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> ACT, ANNUAL REPORT, FFY
1979 (<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> FINAL REPORTS FOR FY 1978 CARRY OVER).
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> OVERVIEW OF DEVELOPMENTS IN PROGRAMMES AND PROJECTS FUNDED UNDER THE
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> AND <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> ACT IN 1979 ALSO <Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
<Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE</Organization> EXPENSES AND PROCEDURES OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT DIVISION</Organization> OF
THE TEXAS <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN ALLOCATING <Organization>THESE</Organization> FUNDS. BRIEF SUMMARIES REPORTING
PROGRESS IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> AREA ARE FOLLOWED <Organization>BY</Organization> EVALUATION REPORTS. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3018
ZZZZ.
     
1ST ISSUE OF A JOURNAL (PUBLISHED IN ENGLISH) AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization> REPORTING <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
CARRIED OUT <Organization>USING</Organization> THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>CAPE TOWN</Location>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> A VEHICLE FOR THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> CONCERN OF UCT
LIBRARIANS. IT IS INTENDED TO PRODUCE 1 ISSUE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>YEAR</Organization>. J.W.
JAGGER LIBRARY, UNIVERSTY OF <Location>CAPE TOWN</Location>, <Organization>PRIVATE</Organization> BAG, RONDEBOSCH, 7700, CAPE
PROVINCE, <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3019
ZZZZ.
     
1ST ISSUE OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICAL</Organization> PUBLISHED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE GROUP FOR <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CENTRES IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>. THE 1ST ISSUE <Organization>CONTAINS</Organization> ARTICLES <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE GROUP FOR <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND LEGAL DATA BANKS IN <Location>THE
NETHERLANDS</Location> AND THE <Location>USA</Location> TOGETHER WITH BIBLIOGRAPHIES OF RECENT LEGAL THESES
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> UNIVERSITIES AND BOOKS AND ARTICLES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP. ALSO
INCLUDED ARE NOTICES OF THE GROUP&apos;S ACTIVITIES AND NEWS OF MEMBERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3020
ZZZZ.
     
FIRST ISSUE OF A JOURNAL FOR <Organization>LAW</Organization> LIBRARIANS AND THOSE WHO WORK WITH
<Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization> CENTERING AROUND <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> AIMS ARE TO MEET THE NEEDS
OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> LIBRARIANS WHO DEAL WITH THE INCREASING NUMBER OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
QUESTIONS <Organization>INVOLVING</Organization> THE LAW, OR WHERE THE LEGAL ASPECT IS A PART OF THE
<Organization>COMPLETE</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> ANSWER. THE JOURNAL IS TO BE PUBLISHED IN SPRING, SUMMER,
AUTUMN AND WINTER, AND AN INDEX WILL BE INCLUDED IN THE WINTER ISSUE OF <Organization>EACH</Organization>
VOLUME. SUBSCRIPTIONS ARE <Organization>ON</Organization> A CALENDAR <Organization>YEAR</Organization>, PER VOLUME BASIS, TO BE MADE IN
<Location>US</Location> OR CANADIAN FUNDS ONLY-$25.00 INDIVIDUALS, $40.00 INSTITUTIONS AND
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; ($25.00 AND $60.00 RESPECTIVELY FOR OVERSEAS ORDERS). POSTAGE AND
HANDLING, <Location>US</Location> ORDERS ADD $1.50, CANADIAN ORDERS ADD $5.00 <Location>US</Location> OR $5.50 CANADIAN
CURRENCY; FOREIGN ORDERS, ADD $10.00. (THE <Organization>SUBSCRIPTION DEPARTMENT</Organization>, THE
<Organization>HAWORTH PRESS</Organization>, 149 FIFTH AVENUE, <Location>NEW YORK</Location> <Location><Location>NY</Location></Location> 10010).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3021
<Organization>GERMAN LIBRARY INSTITUTE</Organization> <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> &apos;<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE&apos; (DOBI).
REPORT FOR 1980.
     
A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHY</Organization> IS PLANNED TO BRING TOGETHER <Organization>ALL</Organization> RECENT DEVELOPMENTS IN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE AND TO FACILITATE THE EXCHANGE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. IT WILL BE A
CLASSIFIED LIST (15 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> DIVISIONS, AND 171 SUBDIVISIONS) WITH SEVERAL
INDEXES, AND WILL SPECIALISE IN LISTING UNPUBLISHED OR OTHERWISE INACCESSIBLE
MATERIAL. THE <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> COMPILATION OF THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHY</Organization> IS EXPLAINED AND A
SAMPLE ISSUE WILL BE MADE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization> LATE IN 1981.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3022
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TO PRACTICE. MARGINAL NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> THE RESULTS OF THE LIBRARIANSHIP
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> FOR 1976-1980.
     
THE <Organization>NATIONAL COUNCIL</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> FORMERLY ELABORATED A
MIDDLE-RANGE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> FOR <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> DURING 1976-80. <Organization>THIS</Organization>
STUDY ASSESSES TO WHAT EXTENT THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> HAS <Organization>BEEN</Organization> CARRIED OUT. THE MOST
ACTIVE AREAS OF DEVELOPMENT HAVE <Organization>BEEN</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF READING <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
INVESTIGATIONS PRECEDING THE INTRODUCTION OF MECHANISED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> STORAGE
AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> SYSTEMS. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREAS OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HAVE <Organization>BEEN</Organization> IN THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT FIELD AND EXPLORATION OF WRITTEN DOCUMENTS OF THE <Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization>
CULTURE. FINALLY, THE STUDY MAKES PROPOSALS FOR TRANSLATION OR ADAPTATION TO
<Organization>HUNGARIAN</Organization> CIRCUMSTANCES OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> FUNDAMENTAL <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> BOOKS PUBLISHED ABROAD
<Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE IN ORDER TO SYNTHESISE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
<Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> FOR PRACTICE AND EDUCATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3023
THE CONTENT AND ORGANISATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> (EARLY RESULTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE FIRST 10
YEARS).
     
<Organization>SOVIET</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE SEEN A 25% INCREASE IN USAGE OVER THE LAST 10 YEARS.
<Organization>THIS</Organization> EXPANSION HAS <Organization>BEEN</Organization> ACCOMPANIED <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>SIGNIFICANT DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>INTO</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP. RESOURCES HAVE <Organization>BEEN</Organization> CONCENTRATED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE STUDY OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF
THE VERY REAL PROBLEMS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> GROWTH (THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> FUNCTION OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
WAYS OF IMPROVING BOTH <Organization>IDEOLOGICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WORK, <Organization>ORGANISING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SYSTEMS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>BASES</Organization> OF CENTRALISATION AND COOPERATION), THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
AND PLACES INVOLVED IN <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HAS INCREASED AND THE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF DIRECTING
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HAS CHANGED WITH THE STRENGTHENING OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> AND THE
COORDINATION OF <Organization>LONGTERM</Organization> PLANNING.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3024
REFLECTIONS OF A BLACK LIBRARIAN.
     
THE AUTHOR WAS RECRUITED <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE <Location>US</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROFESSION IN THE 1950S BECAUSE
OF AN EXPRESSED NEED FOR MORE BLACK <Location>MALE</Location> LIBRARIANS. HE DECIDED TO WORK IN
BLACK ACADEMIC INSTITUTIONS BECAUSE HE FELT HIS EXPERTISE WAS NEEDED THERE.
THE CIRCUMSTANCES SURROUNDING <Organization>SUCH</Organization> ESTABLISHMENTS COMPELLED HIM TO GIVE
<Organization>QUALITY LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> WITH <Organization>LIMITED FINANCIAL</Organization> RESOURCES. CLAIMS THAT BECAUSE
OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> BLACK LIBRARIANS HAVE TO BE TWICE AS <Organization>GOOD</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE UNIQUE ROLE
OF BLACK LIBRARIANS IN THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AND THE HURDLES THEY MUST
CONQUER.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3025
HE BOUGHT 100 BOTTLES OF RED WINE AND WENT <Organization>HOME</Organization> AND BURIED HIMSELF IN
DICKENS&apos;S <Organization>COLLECTED</Organization> WORKS.
     
A PORTRAIT OF KNUD LARSEN, 1895-1981. AFTER GRADUATING IN THEOLOGY <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
UNIVERSITY OF COPENHAGEN, HE OBTAINED EMPLOYMENT IN THE COMMERCIAL <Organization>HIGH</Organization>
SCHOOL&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND DEVELOPED IT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF BOOKS <Organization>ON</Organization> COMMERCE <Organization>INTO</Organization>
A <Organization>MODERN</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH 36,000 VOLUMES AND A <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF 11 IN 1962. APART
<Organization>FROM</Organization> LITERARY AND THEOLOGICAL WORKS HE WROTE HANDBOOKS FOR STUDENTS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>USE</Organization> AND, WHILE ATTACHED TO UNESCO IN <Location>PARIS</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1948-9, HIS <Organization>MAIN</Organization> WORK&apos; 2<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>THEIR</Organization> CREATION AND OPERATION. 1<Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>AGE</Organization> OF 67,
LARSEN WENT TO UGANDA TO CREATE THE <Organization>EAST AFRICAN LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>MAKERERE UNIVERSITY COLLEGE</Organization>. HIS LAST WORK FOR INTERNATIONAL LIBRARIANSHIP WAS
THE ORGANIZATION OF THE <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> COURSES IN LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>AT</Organization> THE DANISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOL IN 1966, 68, AND 70.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3026
CLARENCE E. WALTON AND THE <Organization>HARVARD UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization>.
     
THE CONTRIBUTION OF CLARENCE E. WALTON, ASSISTANT LIBRARIAN <Organization>AT</Organization> HARVARD
UNIVERSITY IN THE 30S AND 40S, TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>HARVARD UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization> AND TO THE FIELD OF <Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization> GENERALLY IS REVIEWED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3027
JUSTIN WINSOR&apos; <Organization>SCHOLAR-LIBRARIAN</Organization>.
     
TRACES THE CAREER OF JUSTIN WINSOR, WHO DIED IN 1897 WHILE SERVING HIS 9<Organization>TH</Organization>
MANY CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE PRACTICAL AND PHILOSOPHICAL <Organization>ASPECTS</Organization> OF
LIBRARIANSHIP. PART I DEALS WITH WINSOR&apos;S LIFE AND CAREER WHICH INCLUDED THE
POSITION OF SUPERINTENDENT OF <Location>BOSTON</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AN <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> ROLE IN THE
FOUNDING OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND <Organization>SCHOLAR-LIBRARIAN</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> HARVARD
UNIVERSITY. PART II LISTS SELECTED WRITINGS OF WINSOR <Organization>ON</Organization> THE TOPICS; <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, PROFESSIONALISM, ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND THE SCHOLARS CRAFT. PART
III IS A <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHY</Organization> OF WINSOR&apos;S PUBLISHED AND UNPUBLISHED WORKS AND
<Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3028
THE KATHOLIEK LITERATUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>CATHOLIC LITERATURE CENTRE</Organization>) IN A <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization>
MOVEMENT.
     
THE <Organization>CATHOLIC LITERATURE CENTRE</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> WAS CREATED IN 1971 <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
KATHOLIEK BIBLIOTHEEK EN LECTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>CATHOLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
CENTRE). THE KBLC ITSELF WAS FORMED IN 1968 <Organization>BY</Organization> THE FUSION OF SEVERAL OLDER
<Organization>ORGANISATIONS</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE BOND VAN ROOMS-KATHOLIEKE OPENBARE LEESZALEN EN
BOEKERIJEN (ASSOCIATION OF ROMAN <Organization>CATHOLIC</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> READING ROOMS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>)
AND THE KATHOLIEKE CENTRALE VERENIGING VOOR LECTUURVOORZIENING (<Organization>CATHOLIC</Organization>
<Organization>CENTRAL SOCIETY</Organization> FOR <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> PROVISION). AS AN EXTRAORDINARY MEMBER OF THE
NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>) THE CENTRE AIMS TO REPRESENT THE INTERESTS OF THE <Organization>CATHOLIC CHURCH</Organization>
IN <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY AFFAIRS</Organization> AND IS ESPECIALLY CONCERNED TO PROMOTE THE INTERESTS
OF CHRISTIAN <Organization>ORGANISATIONS</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS THE <Organization>INTERDENOMINATIONAL PEACE COUNCIL</Organization>, PAX
CHRISTI AND THE <Organization>CENTRAL COMMISSION</Organization> FOR MISSIONARY WORK <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LIB
RARIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3029
THE PRINCIPLES OF LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> PRINCIPLES OF LIBRARIANSHIP AS GUIDES FOR <Organization>ACTION</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> LIBRARIANS WHICH
SHOULD APPLY TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND SHOULD <Organization>NOT</Organization> BE CHANGED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
PASSAGE OF <Organization>TIME OR TECHNOLOGICAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> 2 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> PRINCIPLES&apos;
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE FOR <Organization>USERS</Organization>; AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE TO BE PAID FOR; AND MENTIONS
SEVERAL OTHERS. PART 2 DEALS WITH THE APPLICATION OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> PRINCIPLES; TO THE
SCIENCE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LENDING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND TO THE STAFFING
OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RECORDS. IN CONCLUSION <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE REASONS WHY
<Organization>THESE</Organization> PRINCIPLES ARE RARELY <Organization>USED</Organization> AND SUGGESTS <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> IMPROVEMENTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3030
CAN WE SERIOUSLY BELIEVE IN THE INTERDEPENDENCE OF <Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization> AND RECORDS
MANAGEMENT IN <Location>NORTH AMERICA</Location>?.
     
ARGUES THAT THE MANAGEMENT OF RECORDS AND <Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization> ARE 2 DISTINCT OCCUPATIONS,
AND <Organization>NOT</Organization> 2 SPECIALIST BRANCHES OF THE <Organization>ARCHIVE</Organization> PROFESSION. ACKNOWLEDGES THE
DESIRABILITY OF COLLABORATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE 2, AND EXAMINES THE CONTRIBUTION OF
<Organization>EACH DEPARTMENT</Organization> TO THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> CONCLUDES THAT THE ATTEMPT TO ANNEX THE
FIELD OF RECORDS MANAGEMENT TO <Organization>ARCHIVE</Organization> ADMINISTRATION IS ULTIMATELY AN ATTEMPT
TO CREATE A <Organization>MODERN</Organization> IMAGE FOR THE PROFESSION <Organization>BY</Organization> IMPORTING EUROPEAN <Organization>TERMINOLOGY</Organization>
INAPPROPRIATE TO THE <Organization>NORTH</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> ACTUALITY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3031
SHODDY AND PERNICIOUS BOOKS AND YOUTHFUL PURITY&apos; LITERARY AND MORAL
CENSORSHIP, THEN AND NOW.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 41ST CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>GRADUATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
UNIVERSITY OF <Location>CHICAGO</Location>, 16-17 MAY 80, CHILDREN&apos;S ACCESS TO SERVICES AND
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN SCHOOL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THOUGH <Organization>SOME</Organization> LIBRARIANS AND TEACHERS
BELIEVE CENSORSHIP IS A RECENT PHENOMENON, IT HAS <Organization>BEEN</Organization> A PART OF LIBRARIANS&apos;
LIVES FOR MORE THAN A CENTURY. INDEED, MANY LATE-19<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY LIBRARIANS
REGARDED THEMSELVES PRIMARILY AS CENSORS, DUTY-BOUND TO PROTECT THE YOUNG <Organization>FROM</Organization>
SHODDY AND PERNICIOUS BOOKS, ESPECIALLY FICTION. <Organization>SOME</Organization> LIBRARIANS AND TEACHERS
TODAY CARRY ON THIS CENSORIAL TRADITION <Organization>BY</Organization> CIRCULATING OR TEACHING ONLY WORKS
OF <Organization>HIGH</Organization> LITERARY MERIT OR THE PROPER MORAL CONTENT. THOSE CENSORING <Organization>ON</Organization>
LITERARY GROUNDS OFTEN <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> ONLY SUBJECTIVE CRITERIA, JUSTIFYING CENSORSHIP
<Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN PERSONAL TASTES. THOSE CENSORING <Organization>ON</Organization> MORAL GROUNDS OFTEN <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization>
NO <Organization>BETTER</Organization> CRITERIA, JUSTIFYING CENSORSHIP <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN PERSONAL MORALITY. LIBR
ARIANS AND TEACHERS HAVE NO RIGHT TO IMPOSE PERSONAL LITERARY OR MORAL
STANDARDS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>, YOUNG OR <Organization>OLD</Organization>. THEY HAVE A DUTY TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>
OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> SORTS TO ALLOW CLIENTS AND STUDENTS TO SEARCH <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> AND SEEK OUT
IDEAS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3032
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> THEORETICAL FOUNDATIONS.
     
<Organization>SOME BASIC CONCEPTS CONCERNING INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE DEFINED AND
INVESTIGATED. WITH EVERY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> A QUERY LANGUAGE IS ASSOCIATED AND
<Organization>ITS</Organization> SYNTAX AND SEMANTICS IS FORMALLY DEFINED. <Organization>SOME</Organization> ELEMENTARY PROPERTIES OF
THE QUERY LANGUAGE ARE STATED. THE PRESENTED APPROACH LEADS TO A NEW
<Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> ORGANISATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3033
MEMEX&apos; AS AN IMAGE OF POTENTIALITY IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
DEVELOPMENT.I
     
N 1945, VANNEVAR BUSH WROTE AN ARTICLE URGING SCIENTISTS TO TURN TO THE TASK
OF MAKING THE GROWING STORE OF <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> MORE ACCESSIBLE. (AS WE MAY THINK,
2ATLANTIC MONTHLY1 176 (1) 101-108). ONE DEVICE IN <Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization> WHICH HE URGED
FOR DEVELOPMENT WAS THE MEMEX-&apos;A MACHINE THAT SHOULD BE AN <Organization>EXTENSION</Organization> OF THE
PERSONAL MEMORY AND BODY OF <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> BELONGING TO AN INDIVIDUAL, AND SHOULD
WORK IN A FASHION ANALOGOUS TO THE <Organization>WORKING</Organization> OF THE <Organization>HUMAN BRAIN-BY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
RATHER THAN <Organization>BY</Organization> CATEGORICAL <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization>&apos;. ASSESSES THE <Organization>IMPACT</Organization> OF BUSH&apos;S
IDEAS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FIELD OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>, <Organization>USING</Organization> BOTH <Organization>QUANTITATIVE</Organization> AND
QUALITATIVE <Organization>ANALYSIS</Organization>. THE 1945 ARTICLE HAS <Organization>BEEN</Organization> WIDELY CITED AND HAS <Organization>BEEN</Organization> <Organization>USED</Organization>
AS A SYMBOL FOR A NUMBER OF CONCEPTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3034
<Organization>INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY</Organization> AND THE SCIENCE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
     
IN DEALING WITH THEORIES OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RATHER THAN OF <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>, ONE
NEEDS TO <Organization>USE</Organization> THE SAME LOGARITHMIC MEASURES IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> AS ARE
<Organization>USED</Organization> IN THE <Organization>ANALYSIS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INTERNAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROCESSES OF THE COMPUTER.
ONE <Organization>WOULD</Organization> THEN BE DEALING WITH <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OBJECTIVELY THROUGHOUT, RATHER THAN
A MIX OF OBJECTIVE AND SUBJECTIVE MEASURES. <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> 2PER <Organization>SE</Organization>1 IS AN EMPTY
CONCEPT. <Organization>MAN</Organization> NEEDS TO LEARN <Organization>HOW</Organization> TO RELATE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MORE DIRECTLY TO
<Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization>, AS A 1ST STEP OBSERVING THE GROWTH OF <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> STRUCTURES IN
COMPACT FIELDS OF SCIENCE. A FIRMER METAPHYSIC FOR <Organization>SUCH</Organization> STUDIES IS NEEDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3035
GOVERNMENTS COME AND GO-ALA REMAINS.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>. IT WAS FOUNDED IN 1876 AND HAS
35,000 MEMBERS IN THE <Location>USA</Location> AND CANADA. <Organization>ITS</Organization> MEMBERS ARE MAINLY INDIVIDUAL
LIBRARIANS, <Organization>BUT ALSO LIBRARY COMMITTEE</Organization> MEMBERS, AUTHORS AND <Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization> ILLUSTRATE THE WIDE COVERAGE OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> ACTIVITIES&apos; <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>
RULES, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PLANNING, EDUCATION, AUTOMATION, PR MATERIAL. IT DOES <Organization>NOT</Organization> ACT
AS A <Organization>TRADITIONAL</Organization> TRADE UNION, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE <Organization>PRESSURE ON ITS OFFICE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
PERSONNEL RESOURCES TO TAKE UP THE MATTER OF UNEQUAL PAY IS STRONG, ESPECIALLY
<Organization>FROM</Organization> YOUNGER WOMEN, AND THE OFFICE IS NOW PUBLISHING ANNUAL SURVEYS OF
SALARIES. IN LINE WITH <Organization>THIS</Organization>, THE ALA IS BOYCOTTING STATES WHO HAVE <Organization>NOT</Organization>
RATIFIED THE EQUAL RIGHTS AMENDMENT, A <Organization>DECISION</Organization> WHICH HAS CAUSED FRICTION IN
THE ASSOCIATION. <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> THE <Organization>REAGAN ADMINISTRATION</Organization> HAS MEANT CUTS FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE ALA IS CONFIDENT THAT IT CAN RIDE THE STORM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3036
YEARS OF <Organization>FID</Organization>.SPE
     
CIAL ISSUE COVERING <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> <Organization>ASPECTS</Organization> OF <Organization>FID</Organization> (INTERNATIONAL FEDERATION FOR
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>) AND CONTAINING THE FOLLOWING&apos; THE <Organization>INTERNATIONAL FEDERATION</Organization> FOR
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization> HELMUT ARNTZ; <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> AND IMMEDIATE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>FID</Organization>, <Organization>BY</Organization>
RICARDO A. GIETZ; INTERNATIONAL FEDERATION FOR <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>&apos; <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>
OPERATION, STRUCTURE AND ACTIVITIES, <Organization>BY</Organization> KENNETH R. BROWN; THE MEDIUM-TERM
<Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INTERNATIONAL FEDERATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> FOR 1981-1984, <Organization>BY</Organization>
PETER LAZAR; ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>FID COMMITTEE</Organization> FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE THEORETICAL
BASIS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> (<Organization>FID</Organization>/RI), <Organization>BY</Organization> VYACHESLAV YU. AFREMOV; 35 YEARS OF <Organization>FID</Organization>/<Organization>CR</Organization>
(<Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>), <Organization>BY</Organization> INGETRAUT DAHLBERG; <Organization>FID</Organization>/<Organization>DT</Organization> (<Organization>TERMINOLOGY</Organization> OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>)&apos; <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>STATE</Organization> AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PROSPECTS, <Organization>BY</Organization>
VALENTINA I. GORKOVA; <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL
COOPERATION, <Organization>BY</Organization> TAMAS FOLDI; AND <Organization>FID</Organization> PUBLISHING ACTIVITIES, <Organization>BY</Organization> NINA E.
CHEREDNIK.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3037
<Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MALAWI LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>.
     
A BRIEF OUTLINE OF THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>MALAWI LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, DESCRIBING
THE 1ST MEETINGS IN 1975, THE ELECTION OF A <Organization>STEERING COMMITTEE</Organization> AND THE
<Organization>INAUGURATION AT CHANCELLOR COLLEGE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> 30 APR 76 WITH RODERICK MABOMBA AS
CHAIRMAN AND DR. H. KANUZU BANDA AS PATRON. TOUCHES <Organization>ON</Organization> MORE RECENT
DEVELOPMENTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3038
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SKILLS.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> WORKBOOK DESIGNED FOR A <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SKILLS COURSE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF
MISSOURI ALSO SERVES AS A COMPONENT FOR <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
COURSES. IT IS STRUCTURED TO INTRODUCE THE STUDENT TO THE <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> AND
<Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESOURCES AND TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> ELEMENTARY
INSTRUCTION IN THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROCESS. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3039
AN INTERNATIONAL STRUCTURE FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> A <Organization>PROPOSED INTERNATIONAL</Organization> STRUCTURE FOR <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> WHICH <Organization>WOULD</Organization>
ESTABLISH A BASE FOR THE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> PLANNING AND COORDINATION OF WORLD WIDE
ACTIVITIES IN AND <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO THE EDUCATION OF LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SPECIALISTS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> STRUCTURE IS <Organization>CENTRED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>COORDINATING COUNCIL</Organization> (<Organization>CC</Organization>) AND A
<Organization>STANDING</Organization> CONFERENCE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EDUCATORS (SC). <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization>
ACTIVITIES OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> BODIES WHICH <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization>; THE ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOLS; IMPROVEMENT OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> INFRASTRUCTURES; PUBLISHING; APPRAISAL AND
CERTIFICATION OF PROGRAMMES; AND PROMOTION OF TEACHING METHODOLOGY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3040
THE CHANCES OF A <Organization>UNIVERSITY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE FRAMEWORK OF <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
IN <Location>BERLIN</Location> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> IS NOW COMPLETELY <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY
AS PART OF THE <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> SCIENCE FACULTY, THE 1ST <Organization>TIME</Organization> THAT <Organization>THIS</Organization> HAS
OCCURRED IN <Location>GERMANY</Location>. OBJECTIONS TO UNIVERSITY STATUS FOR LIBRARIANSHIP COURSES
WERE FORMERLY MADE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE GROUNDS THAT THE LIBRARIANSHIP COURSES OCCUPY ONLY 6
<Organization>SEMESTERS WHERE OTHER UNIVERSITY</Organization> COURSES REQUIRE 8 OR 9 AND THAT A UNIVERSITY
COURSE <Organization>WOULD</Organization> <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> INADEQUATE PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. IF LIBRARIANSHIP IS TO BE
REGARDED AS PART OF <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> SCIENCE <Organization>NEW</Organization> THEORETIC FIELDS MUST BE
DEVELOPED WHICH WILL AFFECT LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. LIBRARIANS MUST BE TRAINED
IN <Organization>CRITICAL MEDIA</Organization> SELECTION AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> DISSEMINATION; IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
LIBRARIANSHIP PERSONAL <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND READERS MUST BE
<Organization>IMPROVED</Organization> TO COUNTERACT THE IMPERSONAL EFFECTS OF INCREASING CENTRALISATION.
LIBRARIANS NEED A <Organization>BETTER GENERAL EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> OF CONNECTED ACADEMIC
SUBJECTS LIKE SOCIOLOGY AND PSYCHOLOGY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3041
<Organization>STATE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND <Organization>EXTENSION</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF LIBRARIANS.
     
AN ABRIDGED VERSION OF THE PROPOSALS PREPARED <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>WORKING COMMITTEE</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>HUNGARIAN COUNCIL</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> RELATING TO THE CONTENT, <Organization>ORGANISATIONAL</Organization> AND
<Organization>QUANTITATIVE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, WHICH IN THE PAST HAS <Organization>NOT</Organization> KEPT
PACE WITH THE INCREASE IN <Organization>STAFF</Organization> NUMBERS <Organization>WORKING</Organization> IN THE FIELD NOR WITH THE
DEVELOPMENT AND GROWTH OF <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization> NECESSARY FOR BOTH THE LIBRARIAN AND THE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECIALIST.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3042
COMPARATIVE STUDY OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCIENCE EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>UNITED STATES</Location> AND INDIA.
     
MAKES A <Organization>CRITICAL</Organization> STUDY OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCIENCE EDUCATION</Organization> IN <Location>INDIA</Location> AND THE <Location>USA</Location>.
REVEALS THAT THE COURSE CONTENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE IN <Location>US</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS IS
COMPARABLE TO THAT OF <Organization>INDIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS. REVIEWS AND COMPARES THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization>
COURSES THAT ARE OFFERED IN THE 2 COUNTRIES. ANALYSES THE ROLES OF THE
<Organization>AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND THE <Organization>UNIVERSITY GRANTS COMMISSION</Organization> IN <Organization>PROMOTING</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SCIENCE EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>US</Location> AND INDIA RESPECTIVELY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3043
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 3 PERSPECTIVES&apos; COGNITIVE, CYBERNETIC, AND
DEVELOPMENTAL.
     
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> HAS <Organization>BEEN</Organization> PART OF THE <Organization>US HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> SINCE 1870.
IT REMAINED POPULAR UNTIL WORLD WAR II AND THEN THERE WAS A SUDDEN DROP IN
POPULARITY. IT WAS REVIVED ONLY IN THE LATE 1950S AND EARLY 60S. ANALYSES THE
<Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> IN TERMS OF <Organization>LEARNING</Organization>, TEACHING, CURRICULUM AND
EVALUATION <Organization>FROM</Organization> COGNITIVE, CYBERNETIC AND DEVELOPMENTAL PERSPECTIVES.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> A 3 PART <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> WHICH WAS DEVELOPED AND IMPLEMENTED SUCESSFULLY
<Organization>AT COLGATE UNIVERSITY</Organization>. PROGRAMMES OF THE <Organization>PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Organization>OHIO</Organization>
STATE UNIVERSITY AND UNIVERSITY OF <Location>DENVER</Location> ARE ALSO DISCUSSED. THE EXPERIENCE
OF LIBRARIANS IS THAT IT IS EASY FOR STUDENTS TO LEARN THE BROADER CONCEPTS OF
THE USAGE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND DO <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, RATHER THAN REMEMBER MANY TITLES FOR
<Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3044
<Organization>SOME</Organization> PROBLEMS WITH PART-TIME COURSES IN LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
IN ADDITION TO FULLTIME COURSES OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE SCHOOL OF LIBRARIANSHIP IN
<Location>SOFIA</Location>, PART-TIME COURSES, I.E. IN-SERVICE COURSES, HELP TO INCREASE THE NUMBER
OF QUALIFIED LIBRARIANS. <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1960 TO 1976, 936 PART-TIME STUDENTS ENROLLED,
AND 834, I.E. 89%, <Organization>COMPLETED</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> STUDIES <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> 16 STUDENTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
CYRIL AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. 99% OF THE STUDENTS WERE WOMEN, WHO WERE
FORCED FREQUENTLY TO EXTEND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> STUDIES BEYOND 3 YEARS BECAUSE OF MATERNITY
LEAVE, ILLNESS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> REASONS. IN <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>, THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, IN
<Organization>PARTICULAR</Organization>, MUST HELP TO SELECT SUITABLE CANDIDATES AS PROSPECTIVE PART-TIME
STUDENTS. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ALSO HAVE A DUTY TO INTENSIFY <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ASSISTANCE TO ENROLLED
PART-TIME STUDENTS, <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> HELP DURING THE COURSE AS WELL AS TO ASSIST THOSE
STUDENTS WHO ARE PREPARING FOR FINAL EXAMINATIONS AND THESES. ONLY THEN CAN
PART-TIME COURSES GRADUALLY BECOME AN EQUIVALENT TO FULLTIME STUDY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3045
A STUDY OF <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> ACTIVITIES OF THREE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS.
     
REPORTS <Organization>FINDINGS ON EXISTING CONTINUING LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>EXPLORES</Organization> THE
SCOPE AND FUNCTION OF <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> PROGRAMMES OFFERED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
PERSONNEL <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS. IT ALSO <Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> ADDITIONAL
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> TO ASSIST <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS IN <Organization>PROGRAMME DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OR
MODIFICATION. A <Organization>LITERATURE SEARCH ON CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> MODELS, A DATA
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> SHEET, AND A DATA SUMMARY ARE INCLUDED. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization>
<Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3046
OPTIMIZING SELECTION OF <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> STUDENTS.
     
ATTEMPTS TO ASSESS THE EFFECTIVENESS OF ADMISSION REQUIREMENTS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS GRADE
POINT AVERAGE, <Organization>GRE</Organization> TEST SCORES, PERSONAL REFERENCES, WORK EXPERIENCE AND
PERSONAL GOALS STATEMENTS IN PREDICTING STUDENT PERFORMANCE IN SPECIFIC
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCIENCE CLASSES AND THROUGHOUT A <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> MASTER&apos;S <Organization>DEGREE</Organization>
<Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization>. SUGGESTS THAT THE FACTORS WHICH PREDICT PERFORMANCE BEST ARE
DIFFERENT FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> CLASS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> PREVIOUS GRADE POINT AVERAGE AND THE <Organization>GRE</Organization>
<Organization>QUANTITATIVE</Organization> TEST SCORE PREDICT <Organization>OVERALL</Organization> STUDENT PERFORMANCE <Organization>BETTER</Organization> THAN <Organization>ANY</Organization>
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> TEST VARIABLES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3047
MANUAL OF PROCEDURES FOR EVALUATION VISITS UNDER STANDARDS OF ACCREDITATION.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> FULLY REVISED MANUAL OF PROCEDURES FOR EVALUATION VISITS <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization>
GUIDELINES FOR SITE VISITS TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS SEEKING ACCREDITATION FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
PROGRAMMES OF STUDY. VISITS TO <Organization>SUCH</Organization> SCHOOLS <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> THE COMMITTEE <Organization>ON</Organization>
ACCREDITATION WITH DATA TO ASSIST IN REACHING A JUDGMENT WHETHER TO GRANT
ACCREDITED STATUS. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3048
SELF-STUDY&apos; A GUIDE TO THE PROCESS AND TO THE PREPARATION OF A REPORT FOR THE
     
A STANDARD REQUIREMENT OF THE ACCREDITATION PROCESS, THE SELF STUDY REPORT
PREPARED <Organization>BY</Organization> REQUESTING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, IS NECESSARY <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> FOR THE
ACCREDITATION REQUEST AND <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> SITE VISIT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE COMMITTEE <Organization>ON</Organization>
DETAILED PROCEDURES FOR ACCOMPLISHMENT OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> STUDY. REPORT <Organization>NOT</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3049
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE PROFESSIONALS.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> ISSUES RAISED IN CURRICULUM PLANNING AND DEVELOPMENT FOR A
<Organization>POSTGRADUATE</Organization> COURSE IN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE. CONSIDERS <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENCE AS
AN INTERDISCIPLINARY <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> AREA CONCERNED WITH THE <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>
OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> SUBSTANTIVE NUCLEUS, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. ACCORDINGLY, TEACHING PROGRAMMES ARE
REQUIRED TO COVER BOTH ACADEMIC INSTRUCTION AND PRACTICAL APPLICATION, WITH
THE CURRICULUM ITSELF SERVING AS A MODEL OF <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>. THE
QUESTION THEN NECESSARILY ARISES WHETHER COURSES SHOULD BE <Organization>ORIENTED</Organization> TOWARDS
INSTILLING THE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> CORPUS OF COGNITIVE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, OR IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
CAPABILITIES FOR DEALING WITH <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> NEEDS. WHEREAS ACADEMIC
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> EMPHASISES THE SEARCH FOR TRUTH, <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> REQUIRES
PREPARATION FOR <Organization>DECISION</Organization> MAKING. PROPOSES IN CONCLUSION A MODEL OF CURRICULUM
ORGANISATION ENCOMPASSING BOTH THEORY AND APPLICATION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3050
THE BLAISE/MARC FILES&apos; AN INVESTIGATION <Organization>INTO</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> AND VALUE IN TEACHING.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE BLAISE/MARC FILES IN TEACHING STUDENTS OF
LIBRARIANSHIP THE PRINCIPLES AND METHODS OF <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> AND
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>. THE FACILITIES OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> AN HP2645A TERMINAL WERE INVESTIGATED
IN 2 WAYS&apos; (1) <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>USING</Organization> THE TERMINAL TO ACCESS THE BLAISE/MARC FILES AND (2)
<Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>USING</Organization> THE TERMINAL <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> OWN AS A TEACHING TOOL. THE REPORT <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
PROBLEMS OF <Organization>USING</Organization> THE TERMINAL&apos;S RESOURCES, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>ITS</Organization> STORAGE, EDITING AND
PROGRAMMING CAPABILITIES. A NUMBER OF CONCLUSIONS ARE DRAWN <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE NEED
FOR <Organization>BETTER</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> FOR THE TERMINAL, AND FOR <Organization>USING</Organization> THE BLAISE/MARC FILES
TO PRODUCE SELF-INSTRUCTIONAL TEACHING PACKAGES FOR STUDENTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3051
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN AN ACADEMIC SETTING.
     
IN AN EFFORT TO DETERMINE THE MOST <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> MEANS OF <Organization>TRAINING LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>
STUDENTS FOR LATER PERFORMANCE AS <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> CATALOGUERS, EXAMINES THE METHODS OF
SIMULATION, DIAL-UP ACCESS TO ESTABLISHED <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>NETWORKS</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>USE</Organization>
OF A <Organization>CRT</Organization> TERMINAL DEDICATED TO ONE <Organization>SUCH</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization>. <Organization>ANALYSIS</Organization> OF THE PROBLEM
INDICATED THAT 2 MODES OF <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> ARE REQUIRED&apos; DEVELOPMENT OF THE
INTELLECTUAL CAPACITY FOR ORIGINAL <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>; AND INCULCATION OF
USER-COMPUTER <Organization>INTERACTIVE</Organization> FACILITY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3052
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> TECHNIQUES FOR <Organization>CHEMICAL</Organization> <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> <Organization>ONLINE</Organization>: CONSIDERATIONS IN <Organization>DESIGNING</Organization>
A COURSE IN <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>.
     
BACKGROUND CONSIDERATIONS IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF A <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> COURSE
IN &apos;<Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> THE <Organization>CHEMICAL</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN THE <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization>&apos; FOR THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> ARE DELINEATED. THE INTEREST OF ASSOCIATION MEMBERS IN
SUBJECT-ORIENTED COURSES IN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> IS DISCUSSED WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
MENTION OF THE <Organization>STANDING COMMITTEE</Organization> FOR <Organization>ONLINE RETRIEVAL EDUCATION</Organization> (SCORE) OF
THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF MEDICINE. DISTINCTIONS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> AND
<Organization>FACTUAL DATA</Organization> <Organization>BASES</Organization> ARE OUTLINED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3053
SOURCES FOR THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF CLIMATE.
     
WORK PRESENTED IN 1979 <Organization>AT</Organization> A COURSE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization> IN THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>MONTREAL</Location>
<Organization>HISTORY DEPARTMENT</Organization>. THE 1ST SECTION DETAILS THE <Organization>POSSIBLE DATA</Organization> SOURCES&apos;
METEOROLOGICAL READINGS; TREE DATING; <Organization>HARVEST RECORDS</Organization>; <Organization>EMPIRICAL</Organization> QUALITATIVE
CLIMATE OBSERVATIONS; AND GLACIER STUDIES. THE 2ND SECTION <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
DIFFICULTIES INVOLVED IN GATHERING ADEQUATE SCIENTIFIC <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> CASE,
AND CONCLUDES <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>EMPHASISING</Organization> THAT THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF CLIMATE IS NECESSARILY AN
INTER-DISCIPLINARY AND COMPARATIVE FIELD WHERE THE ROLE OF THE ARCHIVIST IS
FUNDAMENTAL.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3054
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS POWER: THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS A <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization>.
     
TRANSLATED <Organization>BY</Organization> TAMAS VOLGYES. IN A RAPIDLY <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> AND STEADILY <Organization>CHANGING</Organization>
WORLD, EXAMINES THE ROLE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND OF ACCUMULATED <Organization>HUMAN</Organization> <Organization>KNOWLEDGE</Organization>.
OUTLINES THE LACK OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> AREAS AND THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S ROLE IN
ELIMINATING, OR <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LEAST</Organization> ALLEVIATING <Organization>THIS</Organization> PROBLEM, WITH UP TO DATE SERVICES.
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FUNCTIONS MUST BE EXTENDED AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> DEVELOPED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3055
<Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> PERSPECTIVE OF THE WORLD&apos;S ANCIENT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
AN ACCOUNT OF THE WORLD&apos;S 2 MOST ANCIENT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> NINEVEH AND
THE ALEXANDRIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WHICH FLOURISHED OVER 4,000 YEARS AGO. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> ORIGINS AND ORIGINATORS; <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE ARRANGEMENT OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> CONTENTS;
AND ASSESSES <Organization>HOW</Organization> <Organization>MODERN</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ORGANISERS WERE IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> THINKING OF THE
PRINCIPLES OF LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3056
<Location>LEIPZIG</Location>-WELL WORTH A VISIT.
     
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A VISIT TO LEIPZIG IN CONNECTION WITH IFLA&apos;S 47<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> HELD
THERE IN AUG 81. THE PRESIDENT, ELSE GRANHEIM, STRESSED THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE
ALSO FOR THE DISABLED AND POINTED TO THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>FREE</Organization> ACCESS TO
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> A VISIT TO A BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>. IT WAS WELL
PROVIDED WITH BOOKS, JOURNALS, RECORDS AND REPRODUCTIONS AND <Organization>HAD</Organization> ARRANGEMENTS
FOR CHILDREN AND ADULTS. THERE ARE ABOUT 70 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LARGER</Organization> PLACES OF WORK
UNDER TRADE UNION LEADERSHIP AND ABOUT 280 VOLUNTARY BOOK <Organization>COLLECTIONS</Organization> IN
KINDERGARTENS, SCHOOLS, BLOCKS OF FLATS AND SMALLER WORKPLACES. A VISIT WAS
ALSO PAID TO THE ZENTRALBIBLIOTHEK DER DEUTSCHEN KLASSIK IN WEIMAR. IN <Organization>ALL</Organization>,
THE AUTHORS FOUND SYMPATHETIC, INQUIRING PEOPLE DESPITE THE OFFICIAL LACK OF
FREEDOM OF EXPRESSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3057
CAMPANIA&apos; <Organization>ASPECTS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SITUATION</Organization>.
     
A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> DESCRIPTION OF <Organization>EXISTING SERVICES</Organization> IN A SOUTHERN ITALIAN REGION
BEFORE THE EARTHQUAKE IN NOV 80, SHOWING THE <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> INADEQUACY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
PROVISION, AND ABSENCE OF <Organization>ANY</Organization> OFFICIAL RECOGNITION OF THE NEED FOR LEGISLATIVE
INITIATIVES AND A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> POLICY TO DEVELOP SERVICES AND <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANS. RELIABLE STATISTICS ARE UNAVAILABLE, <Organization>BUT</Organization> SUFFICIENT
EVIDENCE IS PRESENTED TO DEMONSTRATE THAT BOTH IN <Location>NAPLES</Location> AND THROUGHOUT THE
REGION, THE MAJORITY OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE RESTRICTED TO UNIVERSITY <Organization>USERS</Organization> OR <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
PRIVILEGED GROUPS, AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> ACCESS TO READING IS EXTREMELY LIMITED. <Organization>ANY</Organization>
ACTIVITIES TO DEVELOP <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> HAVE <Organization>BEEN</Organization> ISOLATED INITIATIVES, WITHOUT
RECOGNITION OF THE IMPORTANCE OF THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE COMMUNITY;
EXPANSION IS HAPHAZARD AND THE CONCEPTS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION AND <Organization>NETWORK</Organization>
PLANNING UTTERLY UNKNOWN. SUGGESTIONS ARE MADE FOR THE CREATION OF <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization>
CENTRES AS A 1ST STEP IN AMELIORATING THE SITUATI <Organization>ON</Organization>. A NOTE CALLS ATTENTION
TO THE INCREASED URGENCY FOR <Organization>ACTION</Organization> FOLLOWING DESTRUCTION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS
<Organization>BY</Organization> EARTHQUAKE, AND AN APPENDIX DEALS WITH THE PROBLEMS OF RESCUING <Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization>
NOW <Organization>AT</Organization> RISK BECAUSE OF EARTHQUAKE DAMAGE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3058
SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
THE 12<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> OF THE <Organization>BULGARIAN COMMUNIST PARTY</Organization> <Organization>SET</Organization> <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> TARGETS IN
RESPECT OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> ECONOMIC GROWTH, THE RESULT OF INTENSIVE APPLICATION
OF <Organization>CHEMISTRY</Organization>, AUTOMATION AND ROBOTICS. SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE
A <Organization>SIGNIFICANT</Organization> PART TO PLAY ASSISTING WITH <Organization>THEIR SERVICES</Organization> IN IMPLEMENTATION OF
THE TARGETS. THE MAJORITY OF YOUNG SCIENTISTS HAVE A <Organization>GOOD</Organization> COMMAND OF <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>LEAST</Organization>
1 WESTERN LANGUAGE AND RUSSIAN <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IS IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>. HOWEVER, THERE IS
STILL MUCH TO BE DONE TO ATTRACT SCIENTISTS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> EXPERTS WHO HAVE <Organization>BEEN</Organization>
AVOIDING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SO FAR. PERSONAL RAPPORT WITH <Organization>SUCH</Organization> PEOPLE IS DECISIVE AND
LIBRARIANS SHOULD DRAW IDEAS <Organization>FROM</Organization> INSTRUCTIVE <Organization>PUBLICATIONS</Organization> ISSUED FOR <Organization>THIS</Organization>
PURPOSE <Organization>BY</Organization> MANY <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. IN ADDITION TO BOOKS, PERIODICALS, PATENTS,
TRADE CATALOGUES AND <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES HAVE TO BE UTILISED TO THE
FULL. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> NEED EQUIPMENT TO BE ABLE TO OFFER TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> READERS
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> MICROFORM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3059
<Organization>IV INTERNATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.
     
THE WORK OF THE <Organization>CONGRESS</Organization> DUE TO BE HELD IN <Location>BELGRADE</Location> <Location>IN</Location> SEPTEMBER 1980, AND
ACCOMPANYING DOCUMENTS ARE SUMMARISED. CONCLUSIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS FOR
<Organization>FURTHER</Organization> WORK IN <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP ARE OUTLINED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3060
STUDY TOUR OF <Location>HELSINKI</Location>, 6-12 DECEMBER 80.
     
<Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE FRAMEWORK OF THE FINNISH-HUNGARIAN <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> AGREEMENT, THE DIRECTOR
OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL INFORMATION CENTRE</Organization>, <Location>HUNGARY</Location>, <Organization>HAD</Organization> THE OPPORTUNITY TO STUDY THE
WORK OF THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>HELSINKI</Location>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE STAFFING,
ORGANISATION, AND SERVICES OFFERED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3061
ARLIS/NA ANNUAL CONFERENCE 1981).S
     
PECIAL SECTION DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 9<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE
<Organization>ART LIBRARIES SOCIETY</Organization> OF <Location>NORTH AMERICA</Location>, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, 20-26 FEB 81.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3062
ARE MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> THREATENED BECAUSE OF THE RECESSION?.
     
THE 3<Organization>RD</Organization> SCANDINAVIAN MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONFERENCE WAS HELD IN <Location>STOCKHOLM</Location> AND
MAARIANHAMINA IN MAY 81. THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> WAS PLANNED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE NORDIC IAML SECTION.
50 PEOPLE ATTENDED IN MAARIANHAMINA. THE CONFERENCE DEALT WITH THE EFFECTS OF
RECESSION <Organization>ON</Organization> MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE QUALIFICATIONS OF MUSIC LIBRARIANS, AND THE
<Organization>VARIOUS INTERNATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> RULES FOR MUSIC.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3063
THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> THEATRICAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization>.
     
THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> THEATRICAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS ONE OF THE MOST POPULAR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
<Location>MOSCOW</Location> AND OFFERS A WIDE RANGE OF SERVICES TO MANY WORKERS IN THE ARTS. <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> STOCKS, BUILT UP SINCE 1922, FORM AN INTEGRAL PART OF THE
RESOURCES OF THE <Organization>SOVIET</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization>. THERE IS SCOPE, HOWEVER, FOR <Organization>GREATER</Organization>
COOPERATION WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ESPECIALLY IN THE FIELD OF EDUCATION, AND
THERE IS A NEED FOR A WHOLE <Organization>NEW</Organization> APPROACH TO THE ORGANISATION OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
BEFORE IT CAN DEVELOP TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> FULL <Organization>POTENTIAL</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3064
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DESCRIPTION&apos; THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>BRUSSELS</Location>.
     
THE 1ST <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVING THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES WAS FOUNDED IN
1952 IN LUXEMBURG FOR THE EUROPEAN COAL AND STEEL COMMUNITY, FOLLOWED IN 1958
<Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC COMMUNITY AND EURATOM. AFTER THE
REORGANISATION OF THE SEPARATE COMMUNITIES IN 1967 TO FORM THE COMMISSION OF
THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>BRUSSELS</Location> BECAME THE <Organization>MAIN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH
RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE FINANCIAL <Organization>CONTROL</Organization> AND FOR THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> ORDERING AND
<Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> MATERIAL FOR THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> BRUSSELS
CURRENTLY <Organization>CONTAINS</Organization> 232,000 BOOKS AND 7,000 PERIODICALS, COVERING A WIDE RANGE
OF SUBJECTS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization>, ECONOMICS, TRADE, AGRICULTURE AND POLITICS, IN <Organization>ALL</Organization>
LANGUAGES OF THE COMMISSION.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3065
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SERVING <Organization>STATE</Organization> GOVERNMENTS.
     
<Organization>CONTAINS</Organization> ANALYSES OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, FINANCE, <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, AND SERVICES IN
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SERVING <Organization>STATE</Organization> GOVERNMENTS AND TABULATIONS OF <Organization>AGGREGATE DATA</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> 1,134 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> RESPONDING TO THE <Organization>SURVEY</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3066
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SERVING <Organization>STATE</Organization> GOVERNMENTS&apos; <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>TABLES</Organization>.
     
<Organization>CONTAINS</Organization> TABULATIONS OF DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, FINANCE, <Organization>STAFF</Organization>, AND
SERVICES <Organization>FROM</Organization> A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF 1,134 <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SERVING <Organization>STATE</Organization> GOVERNMENTS,
PRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> INDIVIDUAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>BY</Organization> 14 TYPES OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3067
THE ROLE OF THE UNION OF YUGOSLAV <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF
LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Location>YUGOSLAVIA</Location>.
     
THE UNION OF YUGOSLAV <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1962 IN ORDER TO
ASSIST THE COOPERATION AND COORDINATION OF WORK OF THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> REPUBLICAN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE FUNCTIONS OF THE UNION ARE&apos; DEVELOPMENT OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHY</Organization>, ORGANISATION OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>, AND
COOPERATION WITH <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ABROAD AND WITH INTERNATIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>ORGANISATIONS</Organization>. THE UNION HAS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> 2 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> TASKS&apos; DEVELOPMENT OF A UNIFIED
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AND THE DEVELOPMENT AND IMPROVEMENT OF
INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION. THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF THE UNIFIED <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> IS DISCUSSED
<Organization>WITHIN</Organization> THE FRAMEWORK OF 6 <Organization>MAIN</Organization> POINTS. <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INTERNATIONAL SCENE THE UNION
ACTS AS THE COORDINATOR OF INTERNATIONAL ACTIVITIES OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> MEMBER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3068
THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; PHENOMENON OF THE SEVENTIES OR PROTOTYPE OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PLANNING.
     
IN <Organization>ITS</Organization> LEGISLATION, THE COMPOSITION AND POWERS OF <Organization>ITS BOARD</Organization>, AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
UNDERSTANDING OF THE ROLE AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE
70S AND BEYOND, THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MIGHT JUSTIFIABLY BE DEEMED A PROTOTYPE OF
<Organization>MODERN</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PLANNING; <Organization>BUT</Organization> SINCE IT BEGAN <Organization>FROM</Organization> A VANTAGE POINT <Organization>NOT</Organization>
ACCESSIBLE TO <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE DEVELOPED COUNTRIES
(AND BEYOND THE REACH OF THOSE IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES), IT MAY BE VIEWED
RATHER AS A PHENOMENON OF THE 70S.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3069
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR <Location>BANGLADESH</Location>.
     
TRACES THE ORIGIN OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>BANGLADESH</Location> AND REVEALS THAT <Organization>ITS</Organization>
GENESIS GOES BACK TO 1961 WHEN <Location>BANGLADESH</Location> WAS KNOWN AS <Organization>EAST</Organization> <Location>PAKISTAN</Location>.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE REVISED <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> FOR THE ESTABLISHMENT OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN
THE 2ND 5 <Organization>YEAR</Organization> PLAN (1980-85). CONCLUDES THAT, ACCORDING TO THE <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
PLANS AND PROGRAMMES, A FUNCTIONAL <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WILL <Organization>NOT</Organization> BE ESTABLISHED
BEFORE 1985.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3070
THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY LENDING DIVISION</Organization> IN 1980-81.
     
DURING 1980-81, THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY LENDING DIVISION</Organization> RECEIVED 2,346,000
REQUESTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>UK</Location> (DOWN <Organization>BY</Organization> 1.2%) AND 510,000 <Organization>FROM</Organization> ABROAD (DOWN <Organization>BY</Organization> 6.3%). AN
<Organization>EXPERIMENTAL</Organization> SCHEME OF LENDING BOOKS IN ORIENTAL LANGUAGES (AS A LAST RESORT)
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>REFERENCE DIVISION</Organization> WAS STARTED. THE 2CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS INDEX1
BECAME <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>. THE DIVISION RECEIVED 56,000 <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> SERIALS (3.7%
INCREASE), 105,000 MONOGRAPHS, AND 200,000 REPORTS. CONSERVATION WAS OF
INCREASING CONCERN. SURVEYS INCLUDED AN <Organization>ANALYSIS</Organization> OF SERIALS <Organization>USE</Organization>. DISCUSSIONS
TOOK PLACE WITH <Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>POSSIBLE</Organization> COOPERATION IN <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> STORAGE AND
<Organization>TRANSMISSION</Organization> OF JOURNAL ARTICLES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3071
CULTURE FOR THE CUBAN PEOPLE.
     
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> A VISIT TO CUBA TO STUDY THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> CENTRES. A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization> OF
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> CENTRES IS BEING BUILT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE MINISTRY OF CULTURE&apos;S DEPARTMENT FOR MASS
CULTURE. ACTIVITIES <Organization>SERVE</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>, RECREATIVE AND <Organization>IDEOLOGICAL</Organization> FUNCTIONS.
<Organization>EACH CENTRE</Organization> HAS A DIRECTORATE, <Organization>TECHNICAL COMMITTEE</Organization>, CONTACT GROUP AND <Organization>USER</Organization>
GROUP, AND ACTIVITIES RANGE <Organization>FROM</Organization> CREATIVE WORKSHOPS, STUDY GROUPS, LECTURES,
MUSIC FESTIVALS, EXHIBITIONS, AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE ACTIVITIES LAID <Organization>ON</Organization> IN 1 OF
<Location>HAVANA</Location>&apos;S <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> CENTRES, THE PLAZA DE <Location>LA</Location> REVOLUCION, ARE DESCRIBED IN
DETAIL. THE CENTRE&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS MAINLY <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> WORKS NEEDED FOR THE
ACTIVITIES, <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> THE CHILDREN&apos;S SECTION HAS A SOMEWHAT BROADER SELECTION.
THE INTENTION IS THAT <Organization>ALL</Organization> CUBA&apos;S DISTRICTS SHALL HAVE AS A MINIMUM A <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
CENTRE, <Organization>HISTORICAL MUSEUM</Organization>, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, CINEMA, BOOKSHOP, <Organization>ART</Organization> SHOP, CHOIR,
ORCHESTRA, THEATRE AND <Organization>ART</Organization> GALLERY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3072
CARNEGIES LIVE.
     
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> US <Organization>CARNEGIE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> OVER 120 RESPONSES TO AN INVITATION
TO LIBRARIANS TO DESCRIBE THE WAYS IN WHICH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>CARNEGIE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE
RESPONDED, OR FAILED TO RESPOND TO <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> NEEDS AND PRACTICES. A <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization>
SECTION, <Organization>FROM</Organization> GEORGE S. BOBINSKI&apos;S 2<Organization>CARNEGIE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>1 <Organization>PROVIDES</Organization> BACKGROUND
MATERIAL <Organization>ON</Organization> THE BUILDINGS AND THE <Organization>MAN</Organization> BEHIND THEM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3073
<Organization>FROM</Organization> CAXTON TO CASSETTE.
     
EXCERPTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE KEYNOTE ADDRESS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> ANNUAL
CONFERENCE, MARGATE, SEPT 81. BRIEFLY <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE CHANGES IN <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PRINTING OF CAXTON TO THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> DAY AND SUGGESTS A DEVELOPMENT IN
THE ROLE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO <Organization>INCLUDE</Organization> FUNCTIONS NOW CARRIED OUT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>POST</Organization>
OFFICE, CITIZENS&apos; ADVICE BUREAUX AND CONSUMER ADVICE CENTRES, AND ENCOURAGE
PATRONS TO BUY BOOKS. CRITICISES THE LACK OF FINANCIAL SUPPORT FOR AUTHORS AND
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> OUTPUT <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3074
RESULTS OF THE ACTIVITIES OF CZECH <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN 1980.
     
<Organization>THIS</Organization> ANNUAL TABULATED <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> GIVES DETAILS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES IN
1980 FOR THE WHOLE OF THE CZECH SOCIALIST REPUBLIC AS WELL AS <Organization>ITS</Organization> INDIVIDUAL
COUNTIES. GIVES LOAN STATISTICS FOR FICTION, NON-FICTION AND PERIODICALS FOR
BOTH ADULTS AND CHILDREN. <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> AND FACTOGRAPHIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
(CHARACTERISED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE NUMBER OF ANSWERED WRITTEN AND ORAL ENQUIRIES)
ILLUSTRATES <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ACTIVITIES. ALSO ENUMERATES <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
ACTIVITIES, INTERLIBRARY LOANS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USERS</Organization>. TOTALS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LOANS ARE
GIVEN FOR 1976-80. FOR DETAILS OF THE 1979 <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> 2SEE1 81/3080.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3075
GEORGE POMPIDOU AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> READING.
     
AN ACCOUNT <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> DIRECTOR OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1964 TO 1975, WRITTEN
SHORTLY BEFORE HIS DEATH. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>HOW</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> INTERVENTION, INSTIGATED
CHIEFLY <Organization>BY</Organization> POMPIDOU, REVERSED THE DECLINE OF INTEREST IN READING <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
IMPLEMENTATION OF A 10-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> PLAN OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EXPANSION. THE ARTICLE IS
FOLLOWED <Organization>BY</Organization> SHORT TRIBUTES <Organization>FROM</Organization> 2 OF THE AUTHOR&apos;S COLLEAGUES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3076
THE ZERO GROWTH SYNDROME AND THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; WORK FOR REFORMS.
     
CONTRIBUTION TO A PANEL DEBATE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE 80S, ORGANISED <Organization>BY</Organization>
THE DANISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> INSPECTORATE AND HELD IN OCT 81. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE FACED WITH A
<Organization>SITUATION</Organization> IN WHICH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>, ESPECIALLY THAT <Organization>INVOLVING REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization>,
GROWS, WHILE <Organization>DEMANDS</Organization> FOR CUTS OR ZERO GROWTH ARE MADE. LIBRARIANS HAVE TO GIVE
UP <Organization>SOME SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS LENGTHY <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SEARCHES, IN ORDER TO KEEP A
BALANCE IN THE <Organization>GENERAL SERVICE</Organization> LEVEL AND ARE FACED WITH AN INVIDIOUS CHOICE
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE KINDS OF MATERIAL-NEWSPAPERS, <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> BOOKS, JOURNALS-WHICH HAVE
TO BE AXED. THERE IS A NEED FOR AN <Organization>OVERALL</Organization> PLANNING BODY WHICH CAN DECIDE
PRIORITIES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> GROUNDS. ARGUES FOR STRENGTHENING OF THE <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization>
SECTIONS IN SMALLER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> APPOINTMENT OF <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> LIBRARIANS AND FOR
THE <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>DISTRIBUTION</Organization> OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHY</Organization> TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> PUBLICLY OWNED
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. CENTRALLY PRODUCED <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> AIDS HELP IN THE CHOICE OF PRIORITIES
