<Organization>Document</Organization> 3501
TECHNICAL WRITING&apos; PAST, PRESENT AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
     
NO ABSTRACT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3502
DOLLARS-AND-CENTS VALUE OF <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> PRESENTATION. A PLEA FOR THE RETENTION OF
THE WELL-PRODUCED <Organization>PRIMARY</Organization> JOURNAL.
     
ATTEMPTS TO DEMONSTRATE, WITH THE <Organization>HELP</Organization> OF A SIMPLE ECONOMIC MODEL, THAT THE
PRESENT TREND TOWARD LOW-COST AND LOW-QUALITY PUBLICATION OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> WORK
MAY BE BENEFICIAL FOR THE <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> PUBLISHER <Organization>BUT</Organization> HARMFUL TO THE COMMUNITY AS
A WHOLE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3503
EXCERPTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> MY BOUBOULINA FILE.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 41<Organization>ST</Organization> CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>GRADUATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
UNIVERSITY OF <Location>CHICAGO</Location>, 16-17 MAY 80, CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO SERVICES AND
MATERIALS IN SCHOOL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THERE ARE <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> DIFFERENCES
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> A TEXTBOOK AUTHOR&apos;S AGREEING TO ALLOW STICKERS TO BE PLACED OVER
PORTIONS OF HER BOOK FOUND OBJECTIONABLE <Organization>BY</Organization> A <Organization>SCHOOL ADMINISTRATION</Organization> AND A
SUCCESSFUL WRITER&apos;S AGREEING TO EXPURGATE PORTIONS OF HIS NOVEL TO CUT COSTS.
<Organization>EXAMINES</Organization> <Organization>THESE</Organization> DIFFERENCES <Organization>BY</Organization> TRACING THE CHAIN OF COMMAND OF CENSORSHIP WITH
WHICH AUTHORS MUST DEAL <Organization>FROM</Organization> ENCOUNTERS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> AN AUTHOR <Organization>ON</Organization> 1 SIDE AND
EDITORS, PUBLISHERS, TEACHERS, AND SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization>.
EXAMPLES <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>EACH</Organization> LINK IN THE CHAIN ARE ILLUSTRATED WITH EXCERPTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
AUTHOR&apos;S <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> FILE <Organization>ON</Organization> CENSORSHIP, CALLED &apos;BOUBOULINA&apos;.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3504
INTERNATIONALISM&apos; AND THE CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE COMMUNITY</Organization> IN THE <Location>UNITED
STATES</Location>: A SECOND LOOK.P
     
APER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 41<Organization>ST</Organization> CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>GRADUATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
UNIVERSITY OF <Location>CHICAGO</Location>, 16-17 MAY 80, CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> TO SERVICES AND
MATERIALS IN SCHOOL AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. RAISES <Organization>QUESTIONS</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE TERM
&apos;INTERNATIONALISM&apos; AS IT IS <Organization>USED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THOSE IN THE FIELD OF CHILDREN&apos;S
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location>. IT IS MOST COMMONLY APPLIED TO THOSE ACTIVITIES WHICH
CENTRE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> PHASE OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> OUTSIDE THE COUNTRY. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>
APPEARS WITH GREATER FREQUENCY IN ARTICLES <Organization>ON</Organization> CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND
SEMINAR <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>. EXAMINATION OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> TEXTBOOKS, THEMES FOR
DOCTORAL THESES PRESENTED 1930-79, AND THE STATUS OF LANGUAGE REQUIREMENTS IN
<Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS AND COLLEGES OF EDUCATION INDICATE THAT THE
INTERNATIONALISM OF THE FIELD IS INCLINED TO BE SUPERFICIAL.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3505
INTERNATIONAL CHILDREN&apos;S CENTRE.
     
DISCUSSES THE FOUNDATION OF THE INTERNATIONAL CHILDREN&apos;S CENTRE IN <Location>PARIS</Location> <Location>IN</Location>
1949 AND ENUMERATES <Organization>ITS</Organization> AIMS AND OBJECTIVES. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> PRESENT ACTIVITIES
WHICH INCLUDE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AND PUBLICATIONS, AND
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. DISCUSSES THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> BODIES WHICH <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> THE CENTRE&apos;S
ACTIVITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3506
<Organization>TRENDS</Organization> IN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> ATLAS CARTOGRAPHY.
     
NOTES THAT COMPARATIVELY <Organization>LITTLE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> HAS BEEN DONE <Organization>ON</Organization> US ATLASES, POSSIBLY
BECAUSE THEY <Organization>HAVE</Organization>, THROUGHOUT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> HISTORY, BEEN CONSIDERED TO BE INFERIOR TO
<Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> ONES, AND <Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> A PRELIMINARY SURVEY OF <Organization>TRENDS</Organization> IN <Location>US</Location> ATLAS
CARTOGRAPHY <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE EARLIEST DAYS OF THE REPUBLIC TO THE PRESENT. IDENTIFIES
A NUMBER OF DISTINCTIVE PERIODS IN THE HISTORY OF <Location>US</Location> ATLAS CARTOGRAPHY, AND
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE CHARACTERISTIC FORM OF THE ATLASES PRODUCED IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF <Organization>THESE</Organization>
PERIODS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3507
PLR: DRAFT OF THE DRAFT SCHEME.
     
ASSESSES THE PROPOSALS FOR A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> LENDING RIGHT (PLR) SCHEME ISSUED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Location>UK</Location> MINISTER FOR THE ARTS <Organization>ON</Organization> 24 JULY 81. THE PROPOSALS ARE A DRAFT OF THE DRAFT
SCHEME WHICH, AFTER CONSULTATIONS, WILL REACH PARLIAMENT IN LATE AUTUMN 81.
UNDER THE SCHEME, ELIGIBLE AUTHORS (WHO MUST BE REGISTERED) WILL RECEIVE
PAYMENT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> REGISTRAR. THE AMOUNT PAYABLE WILL BE CALCULATED <Organization>BY</Organization>
ANALYSING THE <Organization>LOANS</Organization> OF 16 <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND EXTRAPOLATING THE RESULTS TO OBTAIN
FIGURES FOR THE WHOLE COUNTRY. A RATE OF 1/2 P/LOAN IS ESTIMATED. DISCUSSES
THE RAMIFICATIONS CONCERNING PAYMENT LIMITS (UPPER AND LOWER).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3508
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, RESEARCHING AND LEARNING WITH VIDEODISC.
     
THE POTENTIAL OF THE VIDEODISC AS AN <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> TOOL IS DISCUSSED. THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization>
CONCEPT OF VIDEODISCS IS EXPLAINED, SHOWING HOW THEY ARE <Organization>USED</Organization>, AS ARE <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
PRINCIPAL FEATURES AND ADVANTAGES OVER <Organization>OTHER RECORDING SYSTEMS</Organization>, PARTICULARLY
VIDEOTAPE. THE <Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> FOR VIDEODISCS IN EDUCATION ARE CONSIDERED IN <Organization>SOME</Organization>
DETAIL, WITH PARTICULAR EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE EDUCATION OF CHILDREN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3509
THE SLIPPERY MARKET FOR VIDEODISCS.
     
THE DEVELOPMENT COSTS, SALES, PRICES AND PRINCIPLE OF OPERATION OF THE <Organization>RCA</Organization>
SELECTAVISION VIDEODISC PLAYER ARE COMPARED WITH THE PIONEER AND MAGNAVOX
MACHINES. COMPETITION <Organization>FROM</Organization> VIDEO-CASSETTE RECORDERS IS DISCUSSED AND THE
TYPICAL KIND OF CUSTOMER FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> IS CONSIDERED. THE DEVELOPMENT OF A RENTAL
MARKET FOR CASSETTES AND DISCS ARE DESCRIBED. JAPANESE DEVELOPMENT OF DISC
PLAYERS AND CASSETTE SYSTEMS IS CONSIDERED AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> VIDEO COLOUR CAMERAS ARE
DISCUSSED. WHETHER <Organization>RCA</Organization> WILL <Organization>RECOVER ITS DEVELOPMENT</Organization> COSTS FOR THE
VIDEODISC-PLAYER IS ALSO EXAMINED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3510
VIDEO DISC FOR THE <Organization>STORAGE</Organization> OF OFFICE DOCUMENTS AND ENGINEERING GRAPHICS.
     
A DESCRIPTION OF THE <Organization>OPTICAL DATA</Organization> DISC, A MEANS OF CONVERTING HUMAN-READABLE
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> TO HIGH-DENSITY <Organization>STORAGE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> PHOTO SENSITIVE MATERIALS, IS GIVEN,
WITH DETAILS OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> DIMENSIONS AND MANUFACTURERS. ATTRIBUTES OF THE OPTICAL
DATA DISC, <Organization>INCLUDING DATA</Organization> ENTRY, CODE FORMAT, REPLICATION AND PROJECTED COST
OF BLANK DISCS, ARE OUTLINED. A COMPARISON OF OPTICAL DATA DISCS AND
MICROFORMS IS <Organization>MADE</Organization>, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>STORAGE</Organization> CAPACITY, <Organization>MATERIAL COST</Organization> AND
<Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> <Organization>TIME</Organization>. THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> AVAILABILITY OF THE DISC IS ASSESSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3511
NEWSPAPERS AND HOME VIDEO <Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>&apos; THE PRESENT, THE PROMISE AND
THE PERIL.
     
THE WAYS IN WHICH NEWSPAPERS AND <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization> ARE CURRENTLY
COEXISTING AND THE WAYS IN WHICH THEY MAY AFFECT <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> IN THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> ARE
INVESTIGATED. <Organization>AT</Organization> PRESENT THERE EXISTS AN ATTITUDE WITHIN NEWSPAPERS THAT NEW
TECHNOLOGY <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO THE ADVANTAGE OF THE NEWSPAPER. <Organization>CABLE</Organization> TELETEXT,
VIEWDATA, AND VIDEODISCS ARE DISCUSSED IN RELATION TO NEWSPAPERS AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STORAGE</Organization>, AND TRANSMISSION. CONCERNING THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>, THE TYPE OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WHICH MAY BE MORE SUITED TO <Organization>ELECTRONIC</Organization> THAN <Organization>TRADITIONAL</Organization> IS
CONSIDERED. LONG TERM <Organization>EFFECTS</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> NEWSPAPERS ARE DISCUSSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3512
MICROFILM READERS. CATEGORY&apos; HARDWARE <Organization>STANDARD</Organization>. SUBCATEGORY&apos; COMPUTER OUTPUT
MICROFILM READERS.
     
THE OBJECTIVE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>STANDARD</Organization> IS TO FACILITATE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
INTERCHANGE WHEN THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IS RECORDED <Organization>ON</Organization> MICROFORMS GENERATED <Organization>BY</Organization>
COMPUTER SYSTEMS. THE <Organization>STANDARD</Organization> <Organization>DEFINES</Organization> THE MINIMUM ACCEPTABLE <Organization>IMAGE</Organization> <Organization>QUALITY</Organization>
FOR MICROFILM READING DEVICES FOR THE DISPLAY OF COMPUTER OUTPUT MICROFORMS.
IT ALSO SETS REQUIREMENTS FOR HEAT AND NOISE <Organization>FACTORS</Organization> ASSOCIATED WITH THE SAFE
<Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> READING DEVICES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3513
NEWS <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> MICROFILM.
     
AFTER A DESCRIPTION OF THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> SITUATION IN THE FIELD OF MICROFILM AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>APPLICATIONS</Organization> <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> ARE INTRODUCED IN 12 CHAPTERS&apos; CAMERAS,
READERS FOR MICROFICHE AND ROLLFILM, READER-PRINTERS, ACCESSORIES, FILMS,
CHEMICALS, LABORATORY EQUIPMENT ETC.; A USEFUL REGISTER OF FIRMS IS ADDED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3514
<Location>AMERICA</Location>&apos; CULTURE AND SOCIETY&apos; DEFINING AND DESCRIBING A VISUAL <Organization>ARCHIVE</Organization>.
     
TALK DELIVERED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>ART LIBRARIES SOCIETY</Organization> OF <Location>NORTH AMERICA</Location> 9<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNUAL
CONFERENCE, <Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location>, FEB 81, <Organization>BY</Organization> THE DIRECTOR OF THE <Location>UK</Location> MICROPUBLISHING
FIRM, <Organization>CHADWYCK-HEALY LTD</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> 5 VISUAL ARTS PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
FIRM IN RECENT YEARS, EMPHASISING THE <Location>US</Location> CONTENT, AND DISCUSSES THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THE FIRM&apos;S PUBLISHING <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> IN THE REPRODUCTION OF VISUAL
<Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3515
REALISTIC <Organization>VS</Organization>. SYSTEMATIC NOMENCLATURE.
     
THE PLACE OF SYSTEMATIC NOMENCLATURE IS APPRAISED <Organization>BY</Organization> RELATING <Organization>ITS</Organization> FUNCTIONS TO
RECENT <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3516
WILL <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> BE NEEDED?.
     
STARTING <Organization>FROM</Organization> F.W. LANCASTER&apos;S VISION OF A <Organization>PAPERLESS SOCIETY</Organization> THE AUTHOR
DISCUSSES <Organization>SOME</Organization> ASPECTS OF THE <Organization>FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF PUBLISHING AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>, AS WELL AS THE ROLES OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3517
PRESIDENTIAL ADDRESS.
     
THE <Organization>QUALITY</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN SCOTLAND WILL BE GREATLY ASSISTED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>GOOD</Organization> LEGISLATION TOGETHER WITH COMPREHENSIVE STANDARDS WHICH ARE CONSTANTLY
REVIEWED. <Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE LIMITATIONS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COOPERATION COMMITTEE OF THE
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF SCOTLAND AND RECOMMENDS THE SETTING UP OF AN ADVISORY
PANEL SIMILAR TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ADVISORY COUNCILS IN ENGLAND AND WALES WHICH
COULD <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> ENCOURAGEMENT AND ASSISTANCE TO AUTHORITIES IN FULFILLING <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
STATUTORY OBLIGATIONS. AN ADEQUATELY <Organization>STAFFED SCOTTISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>
WOULD <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> THE NECESSARY BACKUP FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN THE FIELD AND WOULD BE
ABLE TO COMMUNICATE THE OPINION OF THE PROFESSION MUCH MORE EFFECTIVELY TO THE
<Organization>SCOTTISH OFFICE</Organization> AND A <Organization>SCOTTISH LIBRARY ADVISORY COUNCIL</Organization>. STRESSES THE
INITIATIVE, COMMITMENT AND ABILITY NEEDED IN <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE POINT OF
SERVICE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3518
PEEBLES &apos;81&apos; PROCEEDINGS OF THE 67<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>SCOTTISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION 25-28 MAY 1981-THEME FOR THE TIMES&apos; A CONSIDERATION OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>MAJOR</Organization> ISSUES CONFRONTING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE 1980&apos;S.
     
PROCEEDINGS OF THE 67<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>SCOTTISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>,
PEEBLES, 25-28 MAY 81, WHICH CONSIDERED <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> ISSUES CONFRONTING <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
THE 1980S. FOR ABSTRACTS OF THE <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> PAPERS 2SEE1 THE FOLLOWING SERIAL
NUMBERS&apos;-.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3519
LENIN&apos;S <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> IN ACTION (ALL-UNION <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND PRACTICAL CONFERENCE).
     
<Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> SUMMARIES OF PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE APPLICATION OF
LENIN&apos;S IDEAS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PRACTICE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>SOCIALIST SOCIETY</Organization> ORGANISED TO
COMMEMORATE THE 110<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNIVERSARY OF LENIN&apos;S BIRTH IN MAY 80. <Organization>SOME</Organization>
CONTRIBUTIONS WERE DEVOTED TO <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> WORK <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS
THE ROLE OF BIBLIOGRAPHY IN THE PROMOTION OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND TECHNICAL
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, AND <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> IN THE <Organization>ACADEMY OF SCIENCES</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> PAPERS CONCENTRATED <Organization>ON</Organization> ACHIEVEMENTS IN <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> WORK OF THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> REPUBLICS, <Organization>THEIR SERVICES</Organization> TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF READERSHIP,
PUBLISHING ACTIVITIES, <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LOANS</Organization>, CENTRALISATION OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
NETWORKS AND <Organization>METHODOLOGICAL</Organization> GUIDANCE TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITHIN THE <Organization>NETWORK</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3520
<Organization>TURKISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization>.
     
THE <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> ROLE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> CAME TO BE GRADUALLY APPRECIATED IN
<Location>TURKEY</Location> ONLY IN THE 1940S WHEN ADNAN OTUKEN RETURNED <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>
<Organization>STUDIES</Organization> IN <Location>GERMANY</Location>. DETERMINED TO MAKE LIBRARIANSHIP A RECOGNISED PROFESSION,
HE CAMPAIGNED FOR A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (ESTABLISHED IN 1946), TAUGHT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (BASIS OF DEPARTMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE AT ANKARA UNIVERSITY</Organization>), AND
HELPED FOUND THE <Organization>TURKISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> IN 1949. <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND CHILDREN&apos;S
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>INCREASED</Organization> IN NUMBERS IN THE LAST DECADE (244 TO 700 AND 174 TO
400). <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> INCLUDE LACK OF TRAINED <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND THE 180,000 MANUSCRIPTS
AND RARE BOOKS IN <Organization>THEIR CARE</Organization>. <Organization>UNIVERSITY LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> HAS BEEN UNEVEN
AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE MOST NEGLECTED. TURDOK (<Organization>NATIONAL DOCUMENTATION CENTRE</Organization>
FOR <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY) WAS ESTABLISHED IN 1966. <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>
<Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN ESTABLISHED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3521
THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>TANZANIA</Location>.
     
FOLLOWING INDEPENDENCE IN 1961 THE GOVERNMENT OF THE FORMER BRITISH COLONY OF
<Location>TANZANIA</Location> HAS PLACED A HIGH PRIORITY <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PROVISION OF EDUCATION FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization>
LEVELS OF THE POPULATION. AS PART OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> FUNDS <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
BEEN ALLOCATED IN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BUDGET FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.
IN 1963 THE GOVERNMENT FOUNDED THE <Organization>TANGANYIKA LIBRARY SERVICES BOARD</Organization> WHICH WAS
REPLACED IN 1975 <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>TANZANIA LIBRARY SERVICES BOARD</Organization>. THE BOARD&apos;S FUNCTIONS
INCLUDE THE SUPERVISION OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
AND THE PUBLICATION OF THE <Location>TANZANIA</Location> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY. HOWEVER, BECAUSE OF
THE LACK OF <Organization>ADEQUATE FINANCIAL</Organization> RESOURCES AND OF TRAINED <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> THE BOARD
HAS BEEN UNABLE TO ACHIEVE <Organization>ITS</Organization> OBJECTIVES OF PROVIDING <Organization>AT</Organization> LEAST 1 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Organization>EACH</Organization> REGION OF THE COUNTRY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3522
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Location>SWAZILAND</Location>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>SWAZILAND</Location>. HIGHLIGHTS <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization>
IN <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN THAT COUNTRY. SUGGESTIONS FOR IMPROVEMENT OF THE
PRESENT SITUATION ARE OUTLINED ALONG WITH RECENT MOVES <Organization>BY</Organization> THE GOVERNMENT TO
<Organization>IMPROVE</Organization> THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ACTIVITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3523
SHARING <Organization>AT</Organization> CHRISTCHURCH. LAA-NZLA CONFERENCE 1981.
     
REPORT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>JOINT</Organization> CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> AND
THE <Organization>NEW ZEALAND LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, <Location>CHRISTCHURCH</Location>, JAN 81. <Organization>TOPICS</Organization> COVERED
<Organization>INCLUDED EDUCATION</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANSHIP, THE NEED FOR <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization>,
INTERNATIONAL LIBRARIANSHIP, AND THE EFFECT OF TECHNOLOGICAL CHANGES IN
SOCIETY AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> INFLUENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SHARING OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES. PAPERS AND PANEL SESSIONS ARE SUMMARISED AND CRITICISM IS LEVELLED
<Organization>AT</Organization> THE CHAIRMANSHIP AND <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>PRACTICE</Organization> OF READING PAPERS RATHER THAN
DISCUSSING MAIN POINTS THEREIN.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3524
LOTKA&apos;S LAW AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
     
THE APPLICABILITY OF LOTKA&apos;S LAW TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> WAS TESTED <Organization>BY</Organization>
COLLECTING <Organization>AUTHORSHIP DATA</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 2<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>1 (1978 CUMULATED ANNUAL
VOLUME) AND <Organization>BY</Organization> CREDITING WORKS OF MULTIPLE <Organization>AUTHORSHIP</Organization> TO ONLY THE FIRST-NAMED
AUTHOR. THE DATA WAS FOUND TO CONFORM TO AN INVERSE CUBE <Organization>LAW</Organization> MORE CLOSELY THAN
AN INVERSE SQUARE <Organization>LAW</Organization> (I.E. LOTKA&apos;S LAW).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3525
DOCUMENTS PREPARED IN CONNECTION WITH THE IFLA CONFERENCE.
     
<Organization>ALPHABETICAL</Organization> LIST OF 95 DOCUMENTS PREPARED FOR THE 46<Organization>TH</Organization> IFLA <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
CONFERENCE, <Location>MANILA</Location>, 1980. INDICATES THE LANGUAGES IN WHICH THE DOCUMENTS ARE
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> (ENGLISH, <Organization>FRENCH</Organization>, <Organization>GERMAN</Organization>, AND/OR <Organization>RUSSIAN</Organization>).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3526
A <Organization>SELECTED</Organization> LIST OF NEWSLETTERS IN THE FIELD OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.
     
FOR AN ABSTRACT 2SEE 182/1011.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3527
<Organization>CITATION</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>&apos; <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> RESULTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> A
BIBLIOMETRIC SURVEY.
     
DEALS WITH <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PAPERS <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> IN ENGLISH IN 39 <Location>USA</Location>, <Location>UK</Location> AND
INTERNATIONAL CORE JOURNALS IN THE YEARS 1950, 1960, 1965, 1970 AND 1975 AND
IS A CONTINUATION OF AN EARLIER PAPER (2SEE1 81/5043).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3528
CITATIONS OF THE SOURCE JOURNALS IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
RANKING.
     
A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> HAS BEEN CARRIED OUT TAKING THE CITATIONS APPEARING IN THE 2ANNALS OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (AFTERWARDS ANNALS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>)
1DURING 1954-1975 (VOLS. 1-22) AS A <Organization>BASE</Organization>. OF THE <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> 1545 CITATIONS WHICH
APPEARED IN THE JOURNAL 217 RELATE TO INDIAN JOURNAL ARTICLES AND 350 RELATE
TO FOREIGN JOURNAL ARTICLES. OF THE INDIAN PERIODICALS 2ANNALS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (ANNALS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>) 1WAS CITED MOST
ACCOUNTING FOR 48.4% OF THE INDIAN JOURNAL CITATIONS. OF THE FOREIGN
PERIODICALS, 2<Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> 1WAS CITED MOST ACCOUNTING FOR 12% OF THE
<Organization>TOTAL</Organization> FOREIGN JOURNAL CITATIONS. THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> ALSO REVEALS THAT 77% OF THE INDIAN
JOURNAL CITATIONS RELATE TO ONLY 5 JOURNALS, OUT OF 24 AND 68.3% OF THE
FOREIGN JOURNAL <Organization>CITATION</Organization> RELATE TO 16 JOURNALS OUT OF 85 JOURNALS CITED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3529
ZZZZ.
     
A <Organization>NEW</Organization> JOURNAL <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>HAWORTH PRESS</Organization>, INC., THE PURPOSE OF WHICH IS TO
&apos;CONSIDER THE FULL SPECTRUM OF CREATION, CONTENT, AND <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
RECORDS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE PRINCIPLES, FUNCTIONS, AND TECHNIQUES OF DESCRIPTIVE
<Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, THE <Organization>WIDE</Organization> RANGE OF METHODS OF SUBJECT ANALYSIS AND <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization>,
THE ADMINISTRATION AND MANAGEMENT OF THE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> FUNCTION, THE
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC RECORDS</Organization> IN AN INFORMATIVE <Organization>NETWORK</Organization>, AND THE POLICIES AND PLANNING
LEADING TO THE <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC RECORDS</Organization> IN <Organization>MODERN SOCIETY</Organization>&apos;. IT
IS EDITED <Organization>BY</Organization> C. DONALD COOK AND THE EDITORIAL OFFICES ARE <Organization>AT</Organization> 149 FIFTH AVENUE,
<Location>NEW YORK</Location>, <Location>N.Y.</Location> 10010, <Location>USA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3530
AS I KNEW IT: THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORLD.
     
<Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE HISTORY OF THE JOURNAL THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORLD (LATER TO BECOME NEW
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORLD) DURING THE YEARS OF THE AUTHOR&apos;S EDITORSHIP-1960-71. DISCUSSES
THE JOURNAL&apos;S MAIN FEATURES AND POLICY UNDER THE SUCCESSIVE OWNERSHIP OF:
CLIVE BINGLEY; ANDRE DEUTSCH; AND W.H. SMITH. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> BRIEFLY THE BACKGROUND
TO THE REPURCHASE OF THE JOURNAL <Organization>BY</Organization> CLIVE BINGLEY IN 1971, AND THE REASONS FOR
THE AUTHOR&apos;S SUBSEQUENT RESIGNATION AS EDITOR.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3531
ZZZZ.
     
AN <Organization>IRREGULAR FREE PUBLICATION FROM CARROLLTON PRESS</Organization>, INC. (1911 <Organization>FT</Organization>. MYER
DRIVE, <Organization>ARLINGTON</Organization>, VIRGINIA 22209) TO <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization>
<Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO THE COMPANY&apos;S <Organization>REMARC</Organization> DATABASE PROJECT. THE PROJECT CONCERNS THE
CREATION OF A DATA <Organization>BASE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> AN ESTIMATED 5.2 MILLION NON-MARC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF
<Organization>CONGRESS CATALOGUE RECORDS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3532
ZZZZ.
     
1<Organization>ST</Organization> ISSUE OF A QUARTERLY JOURNAL DEALING WITH <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKS
AND COOPERATION. PARTICULAR ATTENTION IS GIVEN TO THE APPLICATION OF
<Organization>INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RESOURCE SHARING. <Organization>PUBLISHED BY HAWORTH PRESS</Organization>
INC., 149 FIFTH AVENUE, <Location>NEW YORK</Location>, <Location><Location>NY</Location></Location>, 10010.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3533
ZZZZ.
     
1<Organization>ST</Organization> ISSUE OF A MONTHLY JOURNAL CONTAINING ARTICLES AND NEWS ITEMS DEALING WITH
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF MINI- AND MICROCOMPUTERS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>GRADUATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA, 1515 E. FIRST STREET, <Location>TUCSON</Location>, <Location>AZ</Location>, 85721, <Location>USA</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3534
ZZZZ.
     
A SUMMARY OF THE STANDARDISATION WORK IN <Location>NORWAY</Location> IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>
AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND THE CONNECTIONS TO NORDIC AND INTERNATIONAL COMMITTEES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3535
PUBLICATIONS <Organization>BY</Organization> DR. HANSJORG SUBERKRUB.
     
<Organization>COMPLETE</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY OF OVER 140 WORKS <Organization>BY</Organization> DR. HANSJORG SUBERKRUB, THE FORMER
LIBRARIAN OF BIELEFELD <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND CHAIRMAN OF THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION, ARRANGED CHRONOLOGICALLY AND COVERING MANY ASPECTS OF
LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL LEVELS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3536
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
     
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF THE DEPARTMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> OF <Organization>TAMPERE UNIVERSITY</Organization> DATES <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1976. THE AREAS FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARE&apos;
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES IN SOCIETY; PRODUCTION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>ITS</Organization> USERS; <Organization>STORAGE SYSTEMS</Organization>; AND ADMINISTRATION AND PLANNING. <Organization>THESE</Organization> TEND TO BE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORIENTED RATHER THAN <Organization>USER</Organization>/COMMUNITY ORIENTED. <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> SHOULD
IDENTIFY <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> NOT OFFER SOLUTIONS. PERHAPS IT WOULD BE MOST FRUITFUL TO
SEE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AS A PART OF SOCIOLOGY. THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> POST OF
ASSISTANT PROFESSOR IN THE DEPARTMENT <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY SHOULD ALSO <Organization>HAVE</Organization> THE
RESPONSIBILITY FOR <Organization>RESEARCH DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3537
P.N. BERKOV AND THE BEGINNINGS OF SOVIET <Organization>RUSSIAN</Organization> BOOK <Organization>STUDIES</Organization> (1923-1935).
     
<Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE <Organization>CAREER</Organization> OF PAVEL N. BERKOV, <Organization>RUSSIAN</Organization> TEACHER AND PUBLISHING
SCHOLAR; FOCUSSING <Organization>ON</Organization> HIS <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> WORK <Organization>PUBLISHED</Organization> <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 1923-1935.
DISCUSSES BERKOV&apos;S MAIN CONTRIBUTIONS AS A BIBLIOGRAPHER, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>&apos; HIS
ATTEMPT TO APPLY MARXIST-LENINIST METHODOLOGY TO BOOK <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>; AND HIS VIEWS
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE TECHNIQUES OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization>, OR HEURISTICS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3538
THANKS TO HANSJORG SUBERKRUB: THE RETIREMENT OF A GREAT LIBRARIAN.
     
AFTER THE <Organization>WAR</Organization> SUBERKRUB <Organization>STUDIED AT KIEL UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>HAMBURG LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>.
HE WORKED IN KIEL LIBRARY FROM 1954-55 AND IN THE FOLLOWING <Organization>YEAR</Organization> BECAME
<Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN OF BIELEFELD, WHERE HE REMAINED, MODERNISING AND EXPANDING
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> UNTIL HIS RETIREMENT IN OCT 81. SUBERKRUB HAS BEEN AN ACTIVE
<Organization>MEMBER</Organization> OF MANY <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization>, <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL COMMITTEES, ESPECIALLY AS
CHAIRMAN OF THE <Organization>GERMAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1965 TO 1973. HE PLAYED AN
<Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> PART IN THE CREATION OF BIBLIOTHEKSPLAN &apos;73, A SCHEME FOR <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LEVELS. SINCE 1973 HE HAS BEEN OCCUPIED WITH
LIBRARIANSHIP IN NORTH RHINE WESTPHALIA, <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND
AS CHAIRMAN OF THE <Organization>STUDY GROUP</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> LARGE <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. HE IS A PROLIFIC
AND <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> AUTHOR <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3539
THE NEED FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
THE <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS AS WELL AS THE COMPUTERISATION OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN <Organization>STUDIED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>
DEPARTMENT <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CYRIL AND METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>SOFIA</Location>. NOW, THE <Organization>TIME</Organization>
HAS COME TO ESTABLISH AN <Organization>INDEPENDENT TECHNICAL CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, SIMILAR
TO THE ONE IN <Location>PRAGUE</Location>, <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>. AMONG THE CENTRE&apos;S 1<Organization>ST</Organization> AND FOREMOST
COMMITMENTS SHOULD BE THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE CONTEMPORARY
WORLDWIDE <Organization>TRENDS</Organization> IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> UP-TO-DATE
EQUIPMENT. <Organization>THIS</Organization> BROAD <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> KNOWLEDGE SHOULD BE POOLED FOR THE NEW,
SPECIFIED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS, AND ALSO FOR THE RECONSTRUCTION, EXTENSION AND
MODERNISATION OF <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>SUCH</Organization> ACTIVITIES SHOULD LEAD TO THE
ESTABLISHMENT OF <Organization>ARCHIVES</Organization> OF TECHNICAL <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AND <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> CATALOGUES
FOR THE BENEFIT OF ARCHITECTS, DESIGNERS, <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND OTHERS. <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
LONG-TERM TARGETS INCLUDE THE DESIGN OF A NEW, PROGRESSIVE METHOD OF SERVICE
TO  READERS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> USERS AND TO ENHANCE THE <Organization>QUALITY</Organization> OF BOTH WORK AND
<Organization>PRIVATE</Organization> LIVES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3540
<Organization>UNESCO</Organization> AND <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
     
THE WORK OF <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>ARCHIVE</Organization>
SERVICES THROUGHOUT THE WORLD IS ANALYSED. THE INTERGOVERNMENTAL CONFERENCE OF
<Organization>UNESCO</Organization>-UNISIST II AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> ACTIVITIES CONCERNING THE FULFILMENT OF THE UNISIST
<Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> ARE OUTLINED AND THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF <Organization>UNESCO</Organization> IS
DISCUSSED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3541
<Organization>BETWEEN ADMINISTRATION</Organization> AND <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>: THE <Organization>IMAGE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIAN IN
CONTEMPORARY DISCUSSION.
     
LECTURE GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 10<Organization>TH</Organization> <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SEMINAR FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
HERZOG AUGUST <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN WOLFENBUTTEL, FEB 81. FOR YEARS <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
ARGUED OVER THE RELATIONSHIPS <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> PURE LIBRARIANSHIP AND ADMINISTRATION IN
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK, WHICH ARE PARTICULARLY <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> WHEN ALLOTTING TASKS TO THE
HIGHEST <Organization>STAFF</Organization> GRADES. <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> FEEL THEMSELVES TO BE INADEQUATELY
REPRESENTED WHEN <Organization>QUESTIONS ON UNIVERSITY</Organization> STAFFING ARISE AND SHOULD STRIVE FOR
<Organization>BETTER</Organization> COORDINATION. ADMINISTRATION IS NOT PART OF THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> DISCIPLINE OF
LIBRARIANSHIP AND CLOSE LINKS MUST BE ESTABLISHED <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> DISCIPLINE AND
THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LIBRARIAN. <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE</Organization> AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> DUTIES FOR THE HIGHEST
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> GRADES, ESPECIALLY FOR HEADS OF SUBJECT DEPARTMENTS, MUST BE CLEARLY
DEFINED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3542
POLITICS, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND UAP.
     
THE FIRST ISSUE OF 2SLJ&apos; <Organization>SOCIALIST</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> JOURNAL1 CLAIMS THAT THERE IS A
NEED FOR AN INTERNATIONAL FORUM <Organization>ON</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP <Organization>FROM</Organization> A <Organization>SOCIALIST</Organization> VIEWPOINT,
<Organization>BUT</Organization> FAILS TO EXPLAIN THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> TENETS OF <Organization>SOCIALIST</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP. REVIEWS <Organization>SOME</Organization>
OF THE RECENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> TOPIC, AND SUGGESTS THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MUST,
THROUGH FREE <Organization>ACCESS</Organization> AND UAP (<Organization>UNIVERSAL</Organization> AVAILABILITY OF PUBLICATIONS), ALLOW
EVERY THINKING PERSON TO BE ABLE TO FORM HIS OR HER OWN OPINION OF THE WORLD
AND THE SOCIETY ROUND THEM. WHILST 2SLJ1 LACKS INGENUITY AND IS OFTEN
INCOMPREHENSIBLE, IT ALSO FAILS TO INDICATE THAT SOCIALISM MUST REQUIRE A
SOLID PHILOSOPHICAL AND POLITICAL INFRASTRUCTURE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3543
<Organization>DO</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> FEAR PROFESSIONALISM?.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARIANS ASSOCIATION</Organization>-SPONSORED <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE <Organization>MICHIGAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, 11 OCT 80. ARGUES THAT IN THE <Location>USA</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN UNABLE TO ACHIEVE THE DISTINCTIVE STATUS OF A PROFESSION. THEY <Organization>HAVE</Organization>
NO <Organization>WAY</Organization> OF MAKING THE CLAIM STICK THAT THEY <Organization>HAVE</Organization> CRUCIAL SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE
OF VITAL IMPORTANCE TO SOCIETY. AS A RESULT THEY ARE AN <Organization>OCCUPATIONAL GROUP</Organization>
UNABLE TO INCREASE SIGNIFICANTLY THE ECONOMIC WELL BEING AND PRESTIGE OF
LIBRARIANSHIP THROUGH <Organization>TRADITIONAL</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> MEANS. BECAUSE OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS&apos; EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INSTITUTION, THERE IS A LACK OF CONCENTRATION <Organization>ON</Organization>
WHAT CONSTITUTES THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> BASIS FOR LIBRARIANSHIP; THE ASSOCIATIONS
<Organization>HAVE</Organization> CREATED A SITUATION WHERE THE LIBRARIAN HAS <Organization>OCCUPATIONAL</Organization> POWER WITHOUT
THE GROWING <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL POWER</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3544
<Organization>ON</Organization> EMPIRICAL FOUNDATIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>.
     
IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF EMPIRICAL FOUNDATIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>, PERTINENT
EMPIRICAL LAWS AND HYPOTHESES, WHICH <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN REPORTED IN <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND
TECHNICAL <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, WERE CATALOGUED, DESCRIBED, AND ANALYSED FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
DEPENDENCIES AND RELATIONSHIPS. THE MAIN OBJECTIVE OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> WAS TO IDENTIFY
A BODY OF KNOWLEDGE, DERIVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> EMPIRICAL OBSERVATIONS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
PHENOMENA AND REPRESENTATIVE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AS A DISTINCT <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>
DISCIPLINE. <Organization>THIS</Organization> BODY OF KNOWLEDGE DEALS WITH CONCEPTS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
VALUE, RELEVANCE, AGING OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, GROWTH OF KNOWLEDGE, OBSOLESCENCE,
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCATTER, PRODUCTIVITY OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SOURCES AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> FLOW.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3545
THEORETICAL <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF INFORMATICS&apos; CRITERIA OF THE <Organization>QUALITY</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SYSTEMS AND PROCESSES.
     
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF PAPERS DEVOTED ALMOST ENTIRELY TO THE PROBLEM OF <Organization>EVALUATING</Organization> THE
<Organization>QUALITY</Organization> AND EFFECTIVENESS OF <Organization>INFORMATION SYSTEMS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3546
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE VALUE MEASUREMENT OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
     
CONSIDERS A THEORETICAL MATHEMATICAL MODEL OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> VALUE DETERMINATION
AND PROPOSES A CRITERION FOR PRACTICAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> VALUE ESTIMATION. SHOWS
THAT <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AN APPROACH REPRESENTS A GENERALISATION OF THE STATISTICAL AMOUNT OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3547
QUANTITATIVE AND SEMANTIC ASPECTS OF THE CONCEPTION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
     
COMPARES THE MEANINGS OF THE SEMANTIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> QUANTITY UNIT AND SHANNON&apos;S
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> QUANTITY UNIT AND THE CONDITIONS UNDER WHICH THEY <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE <Organization>USED</Organization>.
CONCLUDES THAT THE FORMER <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE A MEANS OF CALCULATING THE DEGREE OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> ADEQUACY AND DOES NOT EXHAUST <Organization>ALL</Organization> METHODS OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
MEASUREMENT. IF ONE PASSES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE TASK OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>TRANSFER</Organization> TO THAT OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STORAGE</Organization>, THE CONCEPT OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> QUANTITY BECOMES THE CONCEPT
OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> VOLUME.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3548
AASL&apos;S FIRST <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> CONFERENCE.
     
THE FIRST <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> CONFERENCE OF THE <Organization>AMERICAN ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>
TOOK PLACE <Organization>FROM</Organization> 25-28 SEPT 80 <Organization>AT</Organization> LOUISVILLE, KENTUCKY, TAKING AS <Organization>ITS</Organization> THEME
&apos;&apos;80 AND BEYOND&apos;. REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROUTINE MATTERS OF THE CONFERENCE, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>
REGISTRATION, TICKET SALES, AND RESPONSE TO <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>, AND SUMMARISES FORUMS
WORKSHOPS AND SESSIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3549
<Organization>DO STOP THIS DIVISION</Organization>.
     
COMMENTS WITH REGRET <Organization>ON</Organization> THE FACT THAT <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, WHICH FOR 73
YEARS HAD BEEN PART OF THE <Organization>DANISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> (DANMARKS
BIBLIOTEKSFORENING), FELT IT NECESSARY IN 1978 TO FORM <Organization>THEIR OWN ASSOCIATION</Organization>
(DANMARKS FORSKNINGSBIBLIOTEKSFORENINGS) AND THUS CAUSING A SPLIT IN THE
<Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. DESPITE <Organization>DF</Organization>&apos;S CHAIRMAN&apos;S CONCILIATORY REMARKS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>DB</Organization>&apos;S 75
YEARS&apos; JUBILEE IN 1980 THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LIBRARIAN, <Organization>DF</Organization>&apos;S VICE CHAIRMAN, <Organization>MADE</Organization> <Organization>SHARP</Organization>
ATTACKS <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>DB</Organization>, THE MINISTER FOR <Organization>CULTURAL AFFAIRS</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
POLITICIANS IN HIS REPORT TO <Organization>DF</Organization>&apos;S ANNUAL MEETING 1981. HE ALSO ATTACKED THE
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL, ALTHOUGH <Organization>THIS</Organization> IS SUPPORTED <Organization>BY</Organization> BOTH THE EDUCATION AND THE
<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> MINISTRIES. THE BILL PROPOSES 1 <Organization>OVERALL ADMINISTRATION</Organization> AND A
DIRECTORATE FOR <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF THE SECTORS, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. ARGUES THAT <Organization>DF</Organization>
SHOULD <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> UNIFICATION OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>. <Organization>DB</Organization> SHOULD TAKE THE
INITIATIVE <Organization>BY</Organization> ORGANISING A MEETING OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> PARTIES TO <Organization>DISCUSS</Organization> A LINK <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization>
THE 2 ORGAN ISATIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3550
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> IN <Location>FINLAND</Location>.
     
<Location>FINLAND</Location> HAS MORE THAN 10 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS, THE MOST <Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> IS SUOMEN
KIRJASTOSEURA (THE <Organization>FINNISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>), ESTABLISHED IN 1910. IT IS
MAINLY CONCERNED WITH <Organization>FURTHER EDUCATION</Organization>, PUBLISHING, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION. SINCE 1978, THE <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>GRANT</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAS
BEEN <Organization>INCREASED</Organization> TO 68%, MAKING <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> THE <Organization>LARGEST</Organization> RECIPIENTS
OF <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>AID</Organization> IN SCANDINAVIA. THE 1978 PROPOSAL TO <Organization>TRANSFER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>SCHOOL BOARD</Organization> TO THE EDUCATION MINISTRY HAS NOT YET BEEN IMPLEMENTED.
NOR HAS <Organization>ANY</Organization> ACTION BEEN TAKEN <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>FINANCE MINISTERIAL WORKING PARTY</Organization>&apos;S
REPORT OF 1979 <Organization>ON</Organization> STAFFING AND <Organization>JOB</Organization> DISTRIBUTION IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. A 3 <Organization>YEAR</Organization>
<Organization>COURSE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS WAS BEGUN IN 1978. THE <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION HAS POINTED OUT THAT DESPITE REASONABLE <Organization>STATE</Organization> GRANTS, CERTAIN
SECTORS, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> AND <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ARE INADEQUATELY FUNDED.
<Organization>OUTLINES</Organization> THE ASSOCIATION&apos;S OBJECTIVES FOR THE 1980S.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3551
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION</Organization> CHANGES <Organization>COURSE</Organization> AGAIN.
     
CONSIDERS THE DESIRABILITY OF <Organization>CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>, AND
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> WAYS IN WHICH <Location>UK</Location> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS ARE PARTICIPATING IN
<Organization>THIS</Organization> PROCESS. DISCUSSES THE PROVISION FOR, AND POTENTIAL OF&apos; SHORT COURSES;
PART-TIME 1<Organization>ST</Organization> DEGREE AND POST-GRADUATE COURSES IN LIBRARIANSHIP; TAUGHT MA
COURSES IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>STUDIES</Organization>; AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> DEGREES. ALSO
CONSIDERS THE POSSIBILITY OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS BECOMING INVOLVED, THROUGH BEC,
WITH SUB-PROFESSIONAL <Organization>LEVEL</Organization> COURSES. ANALYSES THE RESULTS OF 2 SURVEYS
DESIGNED TO JUDGE THE EFFECTIVENESS OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> CONTRIBUTION TO
<Organization>STAFF DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN RECENT YEARS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3552
ZZZZ.
     
COMPARES THE EDUCATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location> WITH THAT IN THE NORDIC
COUNTRIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3553
THE CENTRE FOR THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND BIBLIOGRAPHERS.
     
PROVIDES A REVIEW OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE LEADING <Organization>RUSSIAN</Organization> INSTITUTION IN THE
FIELD OF <Organization>ACADEMIC LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>, THE <Organization>MOSKOVSKII GOSUDARSTVENNYI INSTITUT</Organization>
KUL&apos;TURY (<Organization>MOSCOW STATE INSTITUTE</Organization> OF CULTURE). THE INSTITUTE WAS ESTABLISHED IN
1930 AND OWES <Organization>ITS FOUNDATION</Organization> TO THE <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> INITIATIVE OF N.K. KRUPSKAYA, WHO
LAID DOWN THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> <Organization>STRUCTURE</Organization> OF THE INSTITUTE AS A <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> BODY
SPECIALISING IN THE <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND BIBLIOGRAPHERS, ESTABLISHED <Organization>ITS</Organization>
AIMS AND OBJECTIVES AND ADVISED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> ORGANISATION AND MANAGEMENT. THE
<Organization>STRUCTURE</Organization> OF THE INSTITUTE AND THE COURSES PROVIDED <Organization>HAVE</Organization> CHANGED <Organization>SEVERAL TIMES</Organization>
DURING THE 50 YEARS OF THE INSTITUTE&apos;S EXISTENCE. <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> ARE
COVERED IN DETAIL. ALSO <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> AND RESULTING PUBLISHING ACTIVITIES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3554
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ISSUE DEVOTED TO THE DIRECTORY OF THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SCHOOLS 1981).1
     
1<Organization>TH</Organization> EDITION OF THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS&apos; DIRECTORY OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS, FACULTIES, AND ASSOCIATION MEMBERS AS A <Organization>SEPARATE</Organization> PUBLICATION.
INCLUDES 2 <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> SECTIONS&apos; A <Organization>LISTING BY SCHOOL</Organization> OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> FACULTY MEMBERS AND
SUBJECTS AREAS; AND AN <Organization>ALPHABETICAL</Organization> LIST OF PERSONNEL WITH TITLE AND SCHOOL. A
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>CLASSIFICATION</Organization> SCHEME HAS BEEN <Organization>USED</Organization> IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> ISSUE TO INDICATE THE TEACHING
AREAS AND INTERESTS OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> FACULTY. 2 <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> FEATURES OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> EDITION ARE
THE NAMES OF THOSE RESPONSIBLE FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND A LIST OF
FACULTY MEMBERS QUALIFIED TO TEACH IN A FOREIGN LANGUAGE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3555
IN <Organization>DEFENCE</Organization> OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
     
REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE MEETING OF THE 2 FACULTIES <Organization>ON</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY (<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>) OF THE <Organization>LENINGRADSKII GOSUDARSTVENNYI INSTITUT</Organization> KUL&apos;TURY (<Location>LENINGRAD</Location>
<Organization>STATE INSTITUTE</Organization> OF CULTURE) WHOSE LECTURERS MET TO <Organization>DISCUSS</Organization> THE ARTICLE IN
2SOVETSKAYA BIBLIOGRAFIYA1, 4 (1980) <Organization>BY</Organization> O.P. KORSHUNOV <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> NEEDS IN
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>. KORSHUNOV&apos;S SUGGESTIONS FOR THE REORGANISATION OF
<Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> COURSES ARE EXPECTED TO <Organization>HAVE</Organization> A GREAT EFFECT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE IMPROVEMENT
OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> IN THE <Location>USSR</Location> IN <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>. PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
PARTICIPATING LECTURERS DISCUSSED THE EFFECT OF THE REORGANISATION <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
COURSES IN <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY. A CONCLUSION WAS REACHED THAT <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization>
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> WILL BENEFIT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PLANNED CHANGES AND GREATER COORDINATION OF
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY COURSES WILL <Organization>HAVE</Organization> A POSITIVE EFFECT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
EDUCATION OF <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHERS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3556
TEACHING BIBLIOMETRICS.
     
CLAIMS THAT BIBLIOMETRICS, AS A <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> SUBJECT TOPIC, IS BEING NEGLECTED <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS AND IS TREATED IN A LESS THAN SATISFACTORY MANNER <Organization>BY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
METHODS TEXTBOOKS AND THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. ARGUES THAT BIBLIOMETRICS
SHOULD BE MOVED <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE <Organization>MAINSTREAM</Organization> OF <Organization>GRADUATE LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> CURRICULA.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3557
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AS A PART OF THE SYLLABUS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS.
     
THE TERM &apos;<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>&apos; WAS 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>USED</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> PAUL OTLET OF THE INSTITUT
INTERNATIONAL DE BIBLIOGRAPHIE IN 1905. OTLET REGARDED &apos;BIBLIOGRAPHY&apos; AS TOO
RESTRICTED A TERM TO COVER HIS ACTIVITIES. WITH THE INCREASING <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
<Organization>AUTOMATED SYSTEMS</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE 1960S <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE TERM &apos;<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>&apos;
HAS BECOME MORE FREQUENTLY APPLIED TO CERTAIN TASKS IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
IT IS THEREFORE UNREALISTIC TO CONSIDER LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AS
<Organization>SEPARATE</Organization> DISCIPLINES. <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>FREDERIK MULLER SCHOOL</Organization> OF LIBRARIANSHIP IN
<Location>AMSTERDAM</Location>, <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> IS TAUGHT AS AN INTEGRAL PART OF THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> FOR
ASSISTANT <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. THE SUBJECT OCCUPIES 20% OF THE SYLLABUS AND INCLUDES
SUBJECT INDEXING, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> AND ABSTRACTING TECHNIQUES.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3558
COURSES FOR <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP OFFERED IN A.L.A. ACCREDITED PROGRAMS AND
IMPLICATIONS FOR THE EDUCATION OF <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>/TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
     
A SURVEY WAS <Organization>MADE</Organization> OF THE 68 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS WITH A.L.A. ACCREDITATION TO
ASCERTAIN THE EXTENT AND TYPES OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> COURSES IN <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP, IN
<Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND IN <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. <Organization>FROM</Organization>
THE SURVEY RESULTS IT WAS POSSIBLE TO MAKE AN ANALYSIS OF THE EXTENT TO WHICH
<Organization>THESE</Organization> COURSES WOULD SERVE THE NEEDS OF THOSE INTERESTED IN <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>/TECHNOLOGY
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE ROLE OF FIELD WORK WAS ALSO INVESTIGATED. STATISTICS ARE
PRESENTED <Organization>ON</Organization> THE NUMBER AND TYPES OF COURSES OFFERED AND THE TYPE OF FIELD
WORK <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> FOR STUDENTS CONCERNED WITH SCI-TECH LIBRARIANSHIP.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3559
THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF WESTERN
<Location>ONTARIO</Location>.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENT AND WORK OF THE SCHOOL OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY OF WESTERN <Location>ONTARIO</Location>. DISCUSSES THE SCHOOL&apos;S APPROACH
AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> GOALS, AND HIGHLIGHTS THE FACILITIES, RESOURCES AND <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization>
WHICH ARE OFFERED FOR THOSE PROFESSIONALLY INTERESTED IN CONSERVATION AND
PRESERVATION THEORY AND <Organization>PRACTICE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3560
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SPECIALISTS&apos; PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A SYMPOSIUM <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Location>PRETORIA</Location>, <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location> <Organization>ON</Organization> 6-7.
     
IN THE LAST DECADE A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>INDUSTRY</Organization> HAS EMERGED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE CONJUNCTION OF DATA
BASES, COMPUTERS, TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>. THE
GROWTH OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>INDUSTRY</Organization> IS REVIEWED SHOWING HOW THE INITIAL APPLICATION OF
COMPUTERS FOR PRODUCTION PURPOSES PRODUCED <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>FORMS</Organization> OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WHICH
ALLOWED THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>. THE <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> <Organization>TRENDS</Organization> IN THE
DATA <Organization>BASE</Organization> FIELD ARE IDENTIFIED AND THE RESULTS OF AN ECONOMIC MODELLING <Organization>STUDY</Organization>
ARE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO PROJECT <Organization>FUTURE COST</Organization> LEVELS FOR <Organization>SEARCHING DATA</Organization> BASES <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization>
GENERATES THE NEED FOR <Organization>INCREASED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> WITH DATA BASES IF <Organization>INDUSTRY</Organization> IS TO
GET MAXIMUM RETURN <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3561
A <Organization>LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>COURSE</Organization> TO TEACH <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> <Organization>LEVEL</Organization> STUDENTS TWO COMMERCIAL
<Organization>INTERACTIVE SYSTEMS</Organization>.
     
PROFICIENCY IN <Organization>SEARCHING</Organization> 2 <Organization>COMMERCIAL SYSTEMS</Organization> (DIALOG AND ORBIT) IS THE
OBJECTIVE OF THE 15 WEEK <Organization>COURSE</Organization> TAUGHT TO <Organization>GRADUATE</Organization> STUDENTS IN THE SCHOOL OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> (SLIS) <Organization>AT PITTSBURGH UNIVERSITY</Organization>. SOFTWARE WAS
DEVELOPED TO REPLICATE THE LANGUAGE, FORMATS AND <Organization>SEARCH</Organization> CAPABILITIES OF
DIALOG, ORBIT AND <Organization>BRS</Organization>. 60 STUDENTS ARE TAUGHT <Organization>EACH</Organization> TERM; THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization> IS OFFERED
3 TIMES ANNUALLY. THE STUDENTS <Organization>ATTEND</Organization> A LECTURE AND A 2 HOUR SUPERVISED
LABORATORY SESSION <Organization>EACH</Organization> WEEK. THE LECTURES ARE STRUCTURED TO GIVE THE STUDENTS
AN OVERVIEW OF <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> ASPECTS OF THE <Organization>COMPUTER-BASED</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PROFESSION.
THE LABORATORY SESSIONS ARE OF PRIME IMPORTANCE BECAUSE THROUGHOUT THE <Organization>COURSE</Organization>
EMPHASIS IS PLACED <Organization>ON</Organization> LEARNING THE SYSTEMS <Organization>BY</Organization> BEING <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization>. <Organization>EACH</Organization> STUDENT HAS
THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF A TERMINAL DURING THE LABORATORY SESSION; AND CONSEQUENTLY IS
<Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> A MINIMUM OF 30 HOURS PER TERM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3562
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> NON-PROFESSIONAL <Organization>STAFF</Organization>&apos; A QUESTIONNAIRE APPROACH.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> A QUESTIONNAIRE TECHNIQUE RECENTLY <Organization>USED BY GLASGOW UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS PART OF A SEMINAR IN <Organization>READER SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR NON-PROFESSIONAL
<Organization>STAFF</Organization>. THE QUESTIONNAIRE AND THE DISCUSSIONS PROMPTED <Organization>BY</Organization> IT ALLOWED A
CONSIDERABLE AMOUNT OF GUIDANCE <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE PERFORMANCE OF <Organization>READER SERVICES</Organization> TO BE
CONVEYED IN A SHORT <Organization>TIME</Organization>, AND IN A MANNER WHICH THE TRAINEES SEEMED TO FIND
STIMULATING. BRIEFLY ANALYSES THE <Organization>QUESTIONS</Organization> INVOLVED AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> POSSIBLE AND
ACCEPTABLE ANSWERS, AND INDICATES HOW <Organization>THIS</Organization> TECHNIQUE COULD BE ADAPTED TO SUIT
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> CIRCUMSTANCES AND REQUIREMENTS FOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3563
<Organization>IMPROVING LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>SELECTED</Organization> MINORITIES.
     
INTENDED TO IDENTIFY <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> PRACTICES THAT <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> IN
PREPARING SPANISH SURNAMED AND <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> INDIAN STUDENTS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CAREERS
AND TO DESCRIBE RECOMMENDATIONS FOR <Organization>IMPROVING LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> FOR
<Organization>THESE</Organization> MINORITIES, <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> EXAMINED 8 <Organization>SUCH</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMMES</Organization> THROUGH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FINAL
REPORTS, INTERVIEWS WITH PARTICIPATING FACULTY AND STUDENTS, AND DOCUMENTS
ASSOCIATED WITH <Organization>PROGRAMME DEVELOPMENT</Organization> AND <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> AFFAIRS. THE <Organization>SET</Organization> OF 18
RECOMMENDATIONS ARE ORGANISED UNDER 5 <Organization>TOPICS</Organization>&apos; STUDENT RECRUITMENT, STUDENT
SELECTION, <Organization>CURRICULUM DESIGN</Organization>, <Organization>SUPPORT SERVICES</Organization>, AND PLACEMENT/FOLLOW-UP
ACTIVITIES. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NTIS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3564
RESOURCES FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 98<Organization>TH</Organization> MEETING OF THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
<Location>NEW YORK</Location>, 7-8 MAY 81. PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE MEETING WERE: &apos;<Organization>HIGHER</Organization>
EDUCATION&apos;S TURBULENT ENVIRONMENT&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> NEIL L. RUDENSTINE; &apos;PLANNED CHANGE IN
<Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> ORGANIZATIONS&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> HERBERT R. KELLS; &apos;THE ROLE AND CONTRIBUTION OF
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> TO CHANGE IN <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> PAUL POHLMAN; &apos;THE IMPACT OF THE
<Organization>HEA</Organization> TITLE 2-C PROGRAM: THREE YEARS EXPERIENCE AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PLANS&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> DICK W.
HAYS; &apos;NINE RECOMMENDATIONS&apos; A PROGRAM FOR NORTH <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos;,
<Organization>BY</Organization> BARBARA TURLINGTON.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3565
STANDARDS FOR <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
SUPPLEMENT DEVOTED TO STANDARDS FOR <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> COMPILED <Organization>BY</Organization> A SUB-COMMITTEE
OF THE BRITISH AND IRISH ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3566
<Organization>LAW</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization>.
     
REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> TOUR OF <Organization>CALIFORNIA</Organization> <Organization>LAW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
THE <Organization>CALIFORNIA WESTERN SCHOOL</Organization> OF LAW, <Location>SAN DIEGO</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3567
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; THE SITUATION IN THE <Location>FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF
GERMANY</Location>.
     
DISCUSSES <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS CONCERNED WITH
<Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location> AND LISTS <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
GROUPS OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH CONTAIN SYSTEMATICALLY BUILT-UP AND DEVELOPED
COLLECTIONS OF <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. MENTIONS IN PARTICULAR THE
WORK OF THE ARBEITSGEMEINSCHAFT DER SPECIALBIBLIOTHEKEN (<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
<Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization>) AND THE DEUTSCHE FORSCHUNGSGEMEINSCHAFT (<Organization>GERMAN</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
ASSOCIATION).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3568
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGICAL LIBRARIES-THE <Location>UNITED KINGDOM</Location> INFRASTRUCTURE.
     
BRIEFLY REVIEWS THE HISTORY OF <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGICAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE
INTEREST OF <Organization>VARIOUS</Organization> <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> BODIES IN <Organization>THEIR DEVELOPMENT</Organization>. THE WORK OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, <Organization>ASLIB</Organization> AND THE INSTITUTE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SCIENTISTS IN THE
FIELD OF <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS DISCUSSED. ALSO MENTIONS
GOVERNMENT INVOLVEMENT AND THE WORK OF THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3569
LATEST <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> IN <Organization>CAB</Organization>, IFIS AND IAALD.
     
RECENT <Organization>DEVELOPMENTS</Organization> IN THE ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>COMMONWEALTH</Organization> <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> BUREAUX
(<Organization>CAB</Organization>) AND THE INTERNATIONAL FOOD <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> (IFIS), AS WELL AS OF THE
INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> AND DOCUMENTALISTS
(IAALD) ARE SUMMARISED. AS REGARDS THE <Organization>CAB</Organization>, THE GROWTH IN OUTPUT OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> PRODUCTS, <Organization>FROM</Organization> 15 MAIN ABSTRACT JOURNALS IN 1939 TO 27 MAIN
ABSTRACT JOURNALS PLUS 16 SPECIALIST ABSTRACT JOURNALS IN 1981 IS REPORTED.
REGARDING IFIS, THE <Organization>COMPLETE DATA</Organization> <Organization>BASE</Organization> OF 2FOOD <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY
ABSTRACTS 1IS <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN MACHINE-READABLE FORM SINCE THE INCEPTION OF THE
SERVICE IN 1969, A UNIQUE FEATURE SHARED ONLY <Organization>BY</Organization> ONE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> INTERNATIONAL DATA
<Organization>BASE</Organization>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> A <Organization>NEW</Organization> SCHEME FOR MAKING THE <Organization>FSTA DATA</Organization> <Organization>BASE</Organization> <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization>, FREE OF
CHARGE, TO <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES SUBJECT TO CERTAIN CONDITIONS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3570
FIFTY YEARS OF SERVICING THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS OF <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND
PRACTICAL FARMING.
     
THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (CSAL), THE MAIN <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Location>USSR</Location>, CELEBRATED <Organization>ITS</Organization> 50<Organization>TH</Organization> ANNIVERSARY <Organization>ON</Organization> 23 JULY 1980. THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS THE <Organization>LARGEST</Organization> <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE WORLD AND ACTS AS THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>
ALL-UNION DEPOSITORY OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND FOREIGN <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>, THE CENTRE OF
<Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY AND THE <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND SYSTEMATIC CENTRE FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization>
<Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE <Location>USSR</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3571
<Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Location>NEPAL</Location>.
     
<Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> IN <Location>NEPAL</Location> IS UNDER PRESSURE TO <Organization>HELP</Organization> INCREASE FOOD
PRODUCTION. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARE FOUND <Organization>AT</Organization> KHUMALTAR,
KIRTIPUR, KATMANDU AND TERAL. DESCRIPTIONS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE GIVEN.
<Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RESOURCES IS LIMITED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE LACK OF
ORGANISATION OF <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>BY</Organization> THE ABSENCE OF <Organization>INTERLIBRARY
CO</Organization>-OPERATION. TRAINED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PERSONNEL ARE NEEDED TO CHANGE <Organization>THIS</Organization> SITUATION
AND PLANS ARE BEING <Organization>MADE</Organization> TO OBTAIN THEM.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3572
<Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> VETERINARY AND <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>BY</Organization> DIRECT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS
AND USERS OF AN <Organization>ONLINE DOCUMENTATION SERVICE</Organization>.
     
AS A RESULT OF A REDUCTION IN THE ACQUISITION BUDGET THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> VETERINARY AND
<Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CARRIED OUT AN ANALYSIS OF THE PRESENT <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> WAS DONE TO DETERMINE WHICH PARTS OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> COULD BE CUT
DOWN WITHOUT CAUSING TOO MUCH INCONVENIENCE TO THE SUERS. RESULTS SHOWED THAT
APPPROXIMATELY 85% OF REQUESTS FOR JOURNALS WERE COVERED <Organization>BY</Organization> APPROXIMATELY 7%
OF THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>. APPROXIMATELY 30% OF REQUESTS WERE FOR BOOKS. IT WAS
CONCLUDED THAT AN <Organization>EFFICIENT BACK-UP SERVICE</Organization> FOR AN <Organization>ON-LINE</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>
SERVICE COULD BE PROVIDED <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, THE <Organization>DANISH</Organization> <Organization>INTERLENDING</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STRUCTURE</Organization> AND SCANDINAVIAN CO-OPERATION AGREEMENTS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> BACK-UP
SERVICE IS PROVIDED FREE OF CHARGE IN EXCHANGE AGREEMENTS. IT WAS DECIDED THAT
A <Organization>JOINT SCANDINAVIAN UNION</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> OF FOREIGN <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ISDS FILE
WILL BE A VALUABLE TOOL IN THE <Organization>SCAN DINAVIAN INTERLENDING SYSTEMS</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3573
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DESCRIPTION&apos; WHERE MUSES ARE PRESERVED-THE <Organization>DUTCH LITERARY MUSEUM</Organization> AND
<Organization>ARCHIVES CENTRE</Organization>.
     
THE <Organization>NEDERLANDS LETTERKUNDIG MUSEUM</Organization> EN DOCUMENTATIECENTRUM WAS FOUNDED IN <Location>THE
HAGUE</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1953. THE MUSEUM WAS GREATLY EXPANDED IN 1954 <Organization>BY</Organization> A FORMER <Location>CITY</Location>
ARCHIVIST OF <Location>THE HAGUE</Location>, DR. W. MOLL, WHO DEPOSITED <Organization>ON</Organization> PERMANENT LOAN HIS
<Organization>PRIVATE</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF 360 BOXES OF <Organization>MATERIAL</Organization> RELATING TO <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> 1,500 <Organization>DUTCH</Organization>
AUTHORS. THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> NOW CONTAINS MANUSCRIPTS, CORRECTED PROOFS,
PUBLISHERS&apos; CONTRACTS, BOOK ILLUSTRATIONS, PORTRAITS AND GRAMOPHONE AND
TAPE-RECORDINGS RELATING TO <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> AUTHORS OF THE POST-1750 PERIOD. THE MUSEUM
IS FINANCED PARTLY <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> GOVERNMENT AND PARTLY <Organization>BY</Organization> THE <Organization>CITY COUNCIL</Organization> AND
HAS AN ANNUAL PURCHASE <Organization>GRANT</Organization> OF APPROXIMATELY *64,000. IN 1982 THE MUSEUM WILL
BE REHOUSED IN THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> ROYAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BUILDINGS <Organization>AT</Organization> PRESENT NEARING COMPLETION
IN <Location>THE HAGUE</Location>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3574
REPORTING REQUIREMENTS FOR THE <Organization>ARMY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
     
THE REPORTS DESCRIBED IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENT</Organization> <Organization>HAVE</Organization> BEEN DEVELOPED SPECIFICALLY FOR
THE <Organization>ARMY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>PENTAGON</Organization>. THEY CONSTITUTE A SUBSET OF THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> REPORTS
DEVELOPED FOR THE <Organization>CIRCULATION</Organization> MODULE OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF MEDICINE,
<Organization>LISTER HILL NATIONAL CENTER</Organization> FOR BIOMEDICAL <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3575
AN ACTIVE FACTOR IN THE PROGRESS/DEVELOPMENT OF THE BULGARIAN NATION.
     
WHEN INTERVIEWED <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> ACHIEVEMENTS, PRIORITIES AND <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> OF THE CYRIL AND
METHODIUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>SOFIA</Location>, <Organization>ITS</Organization> DIRECTOR EMPHASISES THE IMPORTANCE OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> OBTAINED THROUGH BOOKS, ESPECIALLY IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND
TECHNOLOGY, FOR THE COUNTRY&apos;S PROGRESS. ALTHOUGH THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS OF A
<Organization>SMALL</Organization> COUNTRY LIKE <Location>BULGARIA</Location> ARE ALMOST THE SAME AS THOSE OF THE LARGE COUNTRY,
THE FORMER MUST BE MUCH MORE SELECTIVE AND CAREFULLY BUDGETED BECAUSE OF <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>LIMITED FINANCIAL</Organization> RESOURCES IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, AND PARTICULARLY IN FOREIGN
CURRENCIES. THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S BOOK <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS IN FACT, OPEN TO THE
WHOLE COUNTRY <Organization>BY</Organization> MEANS OF <Organization>INTERLENDING</Organization>. IT HAS THE MAIN RESPONSIBILITY FOR
PUBLISHING THE BULGARIAN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY, COMPUTERISATION OF WHICH HAS
GRADUALLY BEEN INTRODUCED. EXTENSION OF THE PRESENT BUILDING, <Organization>CONSTRUCTION</Organization> OF
A DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TOGETHER WITH <Organization>OVERALL NEW INVESTMENT</Organization> WILL ALLOW THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO MEET THE <Organization>INCR EASING DEMANDS ON ITS SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>HELP</Organization> TO MAINTAIN
STANDARDS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3576
HISTORY OF THE KFAR GIL&apos;ADI LIBRARY-A CASE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF KIBBUTZ <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> (IN
HEBREW).
     
TRACES THE DEVELOPMENT OF KFAR GIL&apos;ADI&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ASSUMPTION THAT
DEVELOPMENT WAS SIMILAR IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> VETERAN KIBBUTZIM. IT IS <Organization>BASED</Organization> MOSTLY <Organization>ON</Organization> ORAL
AND WRITTEN DOCUMENTATION-A LENGTHY INTERVIEW WITH HAIM YISRAELI, FOUNDER OF
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, MINUTES OF KIBBUTZ <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> MEETINGS AND WRITTEN REPORTS <Organization>BY</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>. WHEN YISRAELI ARRIVED IN KFAR GIL&apos;ADI IN 1934 HE FOUND <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> 250
BOOKS. TOGETHER WITH HIS WIFE HE VOLUNTARILY ORGANISED THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND
ENHANCED IT <Organization>SO</Organization> THAT IN 1938 IT CONTAINED 10,000 VOLUMES AND BECAME AN
<Organization>IMPORTANT</Organization> INSTITUTION IN THE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE OF THE KIBBUTZ MEMBERS. TODAY THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS NO LONGER A <Organization>CULTURAL CENTRE</Organization> AND THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> DOES NOT MEET THE
NEEDS OF THE MEMBERS. DISCUSSES WAYS IN WHICH THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COULD ONCE MORE
BECOME AN <Organization>IMPORTANT CENTRE</Organization> FOR THE COMMUNITY.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3577
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>; AND STANDARDS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>.
     
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> REVIEW OF MATERIALS <Organization>RELATED</Organization> TO US <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STANDARDS, ARRANGED IN 6
SECTIONS&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STANDARDS AS MEASURABLE LEVELS OF PERFORMANCE; WHAT
STANDARDS ARE MEANT TO ACCOMPLISH; CHANGES IN DIRECTION; IMPACT <Organization>ON</Organization> IMPROVEMENT
OF SERVICES; REQUIREMENTS FOR MEANINGFUL STANDARDS; AND <Organization>CAN</Organization> STANDARDS BE <Organization>BASED</Organization>
<Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> INQUIRY? THE MAIN EMPHASIS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3578
PROCEEDINGS OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AUTHORITIES CONFERENCE 1980.
     
THE FOLLOWING PAPERS WERE PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AUTHORITIES
CONFERENCE, SOUTHPORT, 6-9 OCT 80: &apos;THE ROLE OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE
<Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>NETWORK</Organization>&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> ROYSTON BROWN; &apos;THE CONSEQUENCES FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES
OF RECENT LEGISLATION&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> N.P. HEPWORTH; &apos;THE POLITICAL VIEW&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> D.E. DELL;
&apos;TAKEN FOR GRANTED&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> ALEX HOWSON; &apos;DIRECTORATES-RIGHT OR WRONG?&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> ALAN
LONGWORTH; &apos;<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> CONSULTATIONS&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> W.J. MURISON; &apos;THE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
CHALLENGE FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos;, <Organization>BY</Organization> ROY SMITH.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3579
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STATISTICS. 1981-82 ESTIMATES.
     
INCLUDES FIGURES FOR 47 COUNTRIES, 32 <Location>LONDON</Location> BOROUGHS, THE <Location>CITY</Location> OF <Location>LONDON</Location>, 36
METROPOLITAN DISTRICTS AND 4 <Organization>WELSH</Organization> DISTRICTS.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3580
WHAT&apos;S TO BE DONE? MEASURES FOR THE DEVELOPMENT OF COMPREHENSIVE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> PROVISION.
     
THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> CONCEPT OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S TASKS AND DUTIES IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>
MUST BE CHANGED; OUTDATED STANDARDS ARE A HINDRANCE. THE CONCEPT SHOULD DEMAND
A FUNDAMENTAL UNITY OF PURPOSE AGREED <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> COUNCILLORS AND
ADMINISTRATION AND <Organization>PROVIDE</Organization> TASKS FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITHOUT PEDANTIC EMPHASIS <Organization>ON</Organization>
THEORETICAL NICETIES. THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> ASSIST IN
EXPLAINING THE PURPOSES AND FUNCTIONS OF LIBRARIANSHIP TO THE ADMINISTRATION.
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MUST EXPRESS THE NEED FOR <Organization>ADMINISTRATIVE</Organization> REFORM THROUGH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>
ASSOCIATIONS. <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PLANS FOR <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> SHOULD BE REASSESSED.
FEDERAL MINISTRIES AND ADVISORY CENTRES SHOULD BE MORE CLOSELY INVOLVED WITH
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND MORE <Organization>USE</Organization> SHOULD BE <Organization>MADE</Organization> OF <Organization>MASS MEDIA</Organization> PUBLICITY. SURVEYS SHOULD
BE CARRIED OUT <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> AND LARGE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD ASSIST IN THE
FINANCING OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3581
STATISTICS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN 1980.
     
THE NUMBER OF BORROWERS IN <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WENT DOWN <Organization>BY</Organization> 1% <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
PREVIOUS <Organization>YEAR</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE NUMBER OF BOOKS LOANED WENT UP <Organization>BY</Organization> 2%. AV <Organization>LOANS</Organization> WENT UP
<Organization>BY</Organization> 16%. THE <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> EXPENDITURE PER INHABITANT WAS 73 <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> MARKS. THERE WERE
1,343 FULL <Organization>TIME</Organization> PROFESSIONALS, AN INCREASE OF 8.8% <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PREVIOUS <Organization>YEAR</Organization>, AND
950 PART-TIME PROFESSIONALS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE NUMBER OF INHABITANTS IN
<Location>FINLAND</Location> WAS 4,748,688, THE NUMBER OF MAIN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 448, BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 937
(A DECREASE OF 3% <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PREVIOUS <Organization>YEAR</Organization>), AND THE <Organization>TOTAL</Organization> NUMBER OF BOOKS WAS
21.9 MILLION, 5 BOOKS PER INHABITANT.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3582
GOODBYE AND THANKS FOR THE FIGHT.
     
INTERVIEW WITH A <Organization>NORWEGIAN</Organization> CHIEF LIBRARIAN WHO HAS RECENTLY MOVED TO <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
ADMINISTRATION, HAVING <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>JOINT</Organization> POSTS SINCE 1967. DISCUSSES THE CHIEF
LIBRARIAN/<Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> SECRETARY RELATIONSHIP WITHIN <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> AND COUNTRY
ADMINISTRATION; THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>STATE</Organization>, THE MINISTRY OF CHURCH AND EDUCATION
AND THE <Organization>NATIONAL LIBRARY OFFICE</Organization> IN THE SECOND HALF OF THE 70S, A DIFFICULT
<Organization>TIME</Organization> FOR <Organization>NORWEGIAN</Organization> LIBRARIANSHIP; THE MAIN <Organization>PROBLEMS</Organization> FACING <Organization>NORWEGIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN THE 80S; HIS INVOLVEMENT WITH THE ASSOCIATION OF <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
EMPLOYEES; HIS GREATEST SATISFACTIONS (SALARY IMPROVEMENTS, <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization>&apos;
RECOGNITION AS A PROFESSION, AND THE FORWARD PROGRESS OF THE <Organization>NORWEGIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE) AND HIS GREATEST IRRITATION (THAT <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE NOT SUFFICIENTLY
POLITICALLY INVOLVED).
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3583
HERE THE LIBRARIAN DONATES HER SALARY TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
     
A TALK GIVEN TO THE 14<Organization>TH</Organization> NORDIC <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEETING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE THEME&apos; PART-TIME
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TODAY AND TOMORROW. WITH A DEFINITION OF PART-TIME <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS
THOSE OPEN ONLY A <Organization>FEW</Organization> HOURS A WEEK, <Location>ICELAND</Location> HAS ONLY 15 FULL-TIME <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
OUT OF 250; 25 OF 40 <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE PART-TIME. WITH 60% OF THE
POPULATION LIVING IN THE <Location>REYKJAVIK</Location> REGION AND THE REST SCATTERED IN <Organization>SMALL</Organization>
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES, IT IS NOT ECONOMICALLY POSSIBLE TO <Organization>HAVE</Organization> A <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>
WHICH FULFILS IFLA NORMS. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> OF 1976 <Organization>MADE</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES
FINANCIALLY RESPONSIBLE FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. MANY, THEREFORE, <Organization>COMBINED SCHOOL</Organization> AND
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>AS EDUCATION</Organization> RECEIVES <Organization>STATE</Organization> <Organization>SUPPORT</Organization>. MOST <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CHARGE
FEES FOR BORROWING AND MOST <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> ARE UNQUALIFIED. THE SOLUTION LIES IN
REDUCING THE NUMBER OF <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO 8; <Organization>THESE</Organization> SHOULD BE RUN <Organization>BY</Organization> THE
<Organization>STATE</Organization> AND <Organization>HAVE</Organization> <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD ALSO BE FEWER.
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR PART-TIME <Organization>LIBRARIANS</Organization> WITH PROPER SALARY CONDI TIONS SHOULD BE
INITIATED.
********************************************
<Organization>Document</Organization> 3584
A DELPHI <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> GOALS, INNOVATIONS, AND PERFORMANCE
MEASUREMENTS.
     
