Document 5627
<Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> A <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO ETHNIC MINORITIES.

A <Organization>MOBILE LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IS ONLY LIKELY TO HAVE TO CATER FOR ETHNIC MINORITIES
IN URBAN AREAS. AFTER THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> ETHNIC MINORITIES HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED A
REASONABLE STOCK OF BOOKS IN THE <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization> LANGUAGES MUST BE INCLUDED
BEARING IN MIND THAT SEVERAL ETHNIC MINORITIES ARE ENGLISH-SPEAKING E.G. WEST
INDIANS. STOCKS OF BOOKS FOR ETHNIC MINORITIES MUST PERFORCE BE LIMITED SINCE
ETHNIC MINORITIES <Organization>ALSO</Organization> READ BOOKS ORIGINATING <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE DOMINANT CULTURE&apos; A
SURFEIT <Organization>WOULD</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> ALIENATE THE NON-ETHNIC MINORITY USERS. THE PROBLEM OF
STOCK SELECTION OF FOREIGN LANGUAGE BOOKS CAN BE OVERCOME BY USING ETHNIC
MINORITY <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5628
<Organization>SWEDISH PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR IMMIGRANTS AND LINGUISTIC MINORITIES.

THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PARLIAMENT HAS ESTABLISHED THAT THE GOALS OF <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> IMMIGRATION
POLICY SHOULD BE EQUALITY, FREEDOM OF CHOICE AND COOPERATION. <Organization>THESE</Organization> AIMS APPLY
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR IMMIGRANTS AND ETHNIC MINORITIES. TODAY, <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE OVER A MILLION BOOKS IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> 80 LANGUAGES. DESCRIBES THE
FINANCING OF <Organization>SUCH SERVICES</Organization>, SOURCES OF SUPPLY, PURCHASING AND <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>,
MEDIA SELECTION, NEWSPAPERS AND MAGAZINES, <Organization>AV MEDIA</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> GRANTS FOR BOOKS AND <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5629
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> CHILDREN IN <Location>DENMARK</Location>.

SINCE THE MIDDLE OF THE 1970S THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN OF FOREIGN CITIZENS HAS
INCREASED HEAVILY AS THE RELATIVES OF FOREIGN WORKERS WERE GIVEN ENTRY
PERMITS. <Organization>DISCUSSES EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>HEALTH CARE</Organization>, <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ORGANISATIONS,
ORGANISATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIAL, STOCKTAKING AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ASPECTS OF PROVISION
FOR <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> CHILDREN.
********************************************
Document 5630
<Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.

IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> THERE ARE NOW MORE THAN 250,000 <Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
RELATIVES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE POORER <Location>MEDITERRANEAN</Location> COUNTRIES TOGETHER WITH A <Organization>FURTHER</Organization>
200,000 <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE FORMER <Organization>DUTCH</Organization> COLONIES. FOR A NUMBER OF YEARS BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
IN AREAS WITH LARGE NUMBERS OF <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> RESIDENTS HAVE PROVIDED MATERIAL IN
THE IMMIGRANTS&apos; NATIVE LANGUAGES. <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LEVEL THE NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK
EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>) SET UP A
<Organization>COMMITTEE ON PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR <Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> IN JAN 78. THE
REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE PUBLISHED IN 1979 <Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
COORDINATION OF THE PROVISION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR IMMIGRANTS AND THE
APPOINTMENT OF A STAFF-MEMBER <Organization>AT</Organization> THE NBLC WITH SPECIAL RESPONSIBILITY FOR
SERVICES TO IMMIGRANTS.
********************************************
Document 5631
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> FOR IMMIGRANTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Location>MEDITERRANEAN</Location> COUNTRIES&apos; PLANS <Organization>AT</Organization>
UTRECHT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

IN 1981 A <Organization>NEW</Organization> POST WITH SPECIAL RESPONSIBILITY FOR SERVICES TO FOREIGN WORKERS
AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES WAS CREATED <Organization>AT</Organization> UTRECHT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.
UTRECHT HAS ALMOST 20,000 IMMIGRANTS, MAINLY <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE POORER <Location>MEDITERRANEAN</Location>
COUNTRIES AND THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> POST WAS THE RESULT OF A REPORT PUBLISHED IN 1980 <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
PROVISION OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO <Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> WORKERS. THE REPORT RECOGNISED THE
DIFFICULTIES IN <Organization>PROVIDING SUCH SERVICES</Organization> AND <Organization>RECOMMENDED</Organization> ENLISTING THE <Organization>AID</Organization> OF
<Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization> IN SELECTING, OBTAINING AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> MATERIAL FOR THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. TO PUBLICISE <Organization>ITS SERVICES</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS ENDEAVOURING TO CONTACT
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> ORGANISATIONS CONCERNED WITH THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> WELFARE OF
<Organization>IMMIGRANT</Organization> FAMILIES AND TO GIVE PRESENTATIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SERVIVES <Organization>AT</Organization>
MEETINGS OF <Organization>IMMIGRANT WORKERS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5632
NON-USE AND LOSER STUDIES IN <Organization>COLLECTION DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.

JULY 80. ARGUES THAT <Organization>USE</Organization> AND <Organization>USER</Organization> STUDIES HAVE NOT BEEN WIDELY ADOPTED, OR
BEEN INFLUENTIAL IN <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization> PRIMARILY BECAUSE WE DO NOT YET
HAVE A GOOD <Organization>UNDERSTANDING</Organization> OF THE CONTEXT IN WHICH THEY SHOULD BE INTERPRETED.
<Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> THAT AN <Organization>UNDERSTANDING</Organization> OF THE RELEVANT ASPECTS OF THE SOCIOLOGY OF THE
COMMUNITY IS ESSENTIAL TO THE DESIGN OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, POLICIES AND GOALS,
AND TO THE MEANINGFUL INTERPRETATION OF STUDIES OF <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization> AND <Organization>USER</Organization>
PATTERNS. DESCRIBES BRIEFLY AN INTELLIGENCE <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>
DESIGNED TO PROVIDE <Organization>THIS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5633
A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF THE BEHAVIOUR OF USERS OF THE SERVICES OF A SPECIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

REPORT OF AN INVESTIGATION CARRIED OUT <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> NUCLEAR ENERGY
<Organization>RESEARCH INSTITUTE</Organization> (INSTITUTO DE PESQUISAS ENERGETICAS E NUCLEARES) IN 1979,
TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> REASONS FOR LOW <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE SCIENTIFIC <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION SERVICES</Organization>, FOR <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> AND REORGANISATION PURPOSES. A
PRELIMINARY REVIEW OF RECENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> STUDIES IS PRESENTED.
DATA WAS COLLECTED BY QUESTIONNAIRE AND <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>STATISTICAL RECORDS</Organization>. RESULTS ARE
REPORTED IN FULL, <Organization>GIVING</Organization> DETAILS OF <Organization>USER</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS; HABITS OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
FREQUENTATION; <Organization>USE</Organization> OF SERVICES; <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PUBLICATIONS; AND THE INFLUENCE
OF <Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HABITS. THE INITIAL HYPOTHESES, THAT SERVICES WERE
NOT GEARED TO <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>USER</Organization> HABITS <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> ADEQUATE FOR <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> NEEDS, AND
THAT PREVIOUS <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> INCREASED <Organization>USE</Organization>, WERE BORNE OUT. THE NEED TO PROMOTE
SERVICES IS EMPHASISED IN CONCLUSION.
********************************************
Document 5634
EVALUATING COLLECTIONS BY <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>.

<Location>NEW YORK</Location>, JULY 80. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> METHODS OF EVALUATING A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
IN TERMS OF THE VOLUME AND TYPE OF <Organization>USE</Organization> IT RECEIVES. DESCRIBES THE FINDINGS OF
SEVERAL STUDIES OF CIRCULATION PATTERNS, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> DERIVED <Organization>FROM</Organization> MACHINE
<Organization>READABLE RECORDS</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE APPLICATION, AND RELATIVE ADVANTAGES AND
DISADVANTAGES OF 2 TYPES OF STUDIES OF <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> USE-DOCUMENT DELIVERY TESTS,
AND SHELF AVAILABILITY STUDIES. INDICATES <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE PROBLEMS AND LIMITATIONS
ASSOCIATED WITH <Organization>SUCH</Organization> STUDIES, AND POINTS OUT THAT A CONSIDERABLE ADVANCE WILL
BE MADE WHEN THE METHODOLOGIES NOW APPLIED TO ONE-TIME EVALUATIONS ARE
MODIFIED SO THAT THEY CAN BE <Organization>USED</Organization> IN CONTINUOUS MONITORING OF PERFORMANCE.
********************************************
Document 5635
THE EFFECTIVENESS OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO USERS&apos; THE CASE OF THE <Organization>POLYTECHNIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, IBADAN.

(<Organization>MLS</Organization> THESIS). ATTEMPTS TO MEASURE THE EFFECTIVENESS OF THE SERVICES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>POLYTECHNIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>AT</Organization> IBADAN (<Location>NIGERIA</Location>), TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> USERS AND EMPLOYING <Organization>READER</Organization>
SATISFACTION AS THE TEST OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> EFFECTIVENESS VIA A QUESTIONNAIRE
TECHNIQUE.
********************************************
Document 5636
AROUSING AN INTEREST OR LOVE IN READERS, LITERARY CHILDREN AND YOUTH.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> WAYS IN WHICH TO MAKE THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MORE APPEALING. THE NEED TO TALK
TO CHILDREN AND DISCOVER <Organization>THEIR</Organization> INTERESTS IS STRESSED. A LACK OF INTEREST IN
BOOKS IS OFTEN A RESULT OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> DIFFICULTIES IN THE CHILD&apos;S OWN READING
ABILITIES. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> SURVEYS DONE <Organization>ON</Organization> WHAT READING MATTER APPEALS MOST TO
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>AGE</Organization> GROUPS.
********************************************
Document 5637
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>: THE LITERACY PLACE.

BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> A SPEECH GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>OTTAWA LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> CONFERENCE, OCT 81.
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>ONTARIO</Location> WERE CONTACTED IN ORDER TO INVESTIGATE CHILDREN&apos;S
LITERACY PROJECTS. SPECIAL PROGRAMMES WERE FOUND <Organization>AT</Organization> ETOBICOKE, NORTH <Location>YORK</Location> AND
<Location>LONDON</Location>. <Location>WINDSOR</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SPECIALISES IN READING TO CHILDREN. <Organization>SOME</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OFFER PRACTICAL WORKSHOPS; DO THEY HELP LITERACY? AUTHOR SUSAN
GLAZER SPECIFIES 7 LANGUAGE EXERCISES&apos; LISTENING; WRITING; ACTING; PLAYING;
CONSTRUCTING; READING; THINKING. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD SUPPLY <Organization>ALL</Organization> SITUATIONS
CONDUCIVE TO <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, E.G. STORY HOURS, BOOK MAKING, DRAMA GROUPS,
CRAFTS. OBSERVATION OF THE CHILDREN AND OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ATTENTION AND <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization>, AND
CONTACT WITH PARENTS, ARE ADVISED.
********************************************
Document 5638
BIBLIOTHERAPY&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN THE TREATMENT OF THE SICK.

AN INTRODUCTION TO BIBLIOTHERAPY-THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF BOOKS AND <Organization>RELATED</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN THE
TREATMENT OF THE SICK. <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> SELECTED ACTIVITY INVOLVING PLANNED, CONDUCTED,
CONTROLLED READING, BIBLIOTHERAPY MAY BE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO DEAL WITH EMOTIONAL AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
PROBLEMS. DESCRIBES THE <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization> IN WHICH BIBLIOTHERAPY MAY BE <Organization>USED</Organization>, AND
THE LIBRARIAN&apos;S ROLE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE TREATMENT TEAM WITHIN <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AN INSTITUTION.
********************************************
Document 5639
LOTKA&apos;S TEST.

PRESENTS A STEP-BY-STEP PROCEDURE FOR TESTING IF A GIVEN SET OF AUTHOR
<Organization>PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization> CONFORMS TO LOTKA&apos;S LAW. THE STEPS <Organization>PROPOSED</Organization> ARE&apos; <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
OF DATA; DETERMINATION OF THE SLOPE +N; CALCULATION OF THE CONSTANT +C; AND
APPLICATION OF KOLMOGOROV-SMIROV ONE SAMPLE GOODNESS-OF-FIT TEST TO
EXPERIMENTAL AND CALCULATED DATA.
********************************************
Document 5640
NORDINFO COURSE IN BIBLIOMETRICS, 1981-10-26-29, HANASSARI, <Location>HELSINKI</Location>,
<Organization>SWEDISH-FINNISH CULTURAL CENTRE</Organization> (IN <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>).

DESCRIBES THE DISCIPLINE OF BIBLIOMETRICS WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO A NORDINFO COURSE
ATTENDED IN <Location>HELSINKI</Location>. DEFINES BIBLIOMETRICS AS QUANTITATIVE MEASUREMENT OF
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TECHNIQUES. BIBLIOMETRIC METHODS CAN BE <Organization>USED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A GLOBAL SCALE, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
THEY CAN <Organization>ALSO</Organization> BE A TOOL TO CALCULATE THE BEST <Organization>USE</Organization> OF AN INDIVIDUAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S
RESOURCES. AMONG THE EMPIRICAL LAWS DEVELOPED, <Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S LAW IS THE MOST
APPLICABLE. DESCRIBES THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> LAW TO OBTAIN A GRAPH WITH AN
EXPONENTIALLY INCREASING PART, A SO-CALLED <Location>BRADFORD</Location> GRAPH. <Organization>THIS</Organization> CAN SHOW THE
RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> AUTHORS AND NUMBER OF ARTICLES, ARTICLES AND QUOTATIONS
AND CAN HELP TO DETERMINE THE <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> OF OBSOLESCENCE OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN A
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>OTHER</Organization> BIBLIOMETRIC LAWS ARE THOSE OF LOTKA AND ZIPF. THE METHODS ARE
USEFUL IN ACQUISITION, <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> OF SPACE ALLOCATION, WITHDRAWALS, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>,
AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREAS OF <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5641
COMPUTER PROGRAMS FOR ANALYSIS OF BIBLIOMETRIC DISTRIBUTIONS.

(<Organization>MSC DISSERTATION-CITY UNIVERSITY</Organization>, <Location>LONDON</Location>). A SUITE OF COMPUTER PROGRAMS IS
GIVEN FOR THE ANALYSIS OF AUTHOR AND JOURNAL <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization>. THE PROGRAMS
WERE WRITTEN USING SUBPROGRAMS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> PACKAGE FOR THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
SCIENCES, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization>, AND USING THE FORTRAN PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE. THE
AUTHOR <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization> PROGRAMS 1ST <Organization>PROCESS RAW AUTHOR PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization>
(CONSISTING OF AUTHOR CODES AND ARTICLE NUMBERS). THEN THE WEIBULL, NEGATIVE
BINOMIAL AND 2 FORMS OF THE LOTKA DISTRIBUTION ARE COMPARED WITH THE OBSERVED
DISTRIBUTIONS OF AUTHOR <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization>, USING THE CHI SQUARED AND
KOLMOGOROV-SMIRNOV GOODNESS-OF-FIT TESTS. THE JOURNAL <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization> PROGRAMS
<Organization>ALLOW RAW JOURNAL PRODUCTIVITY DATA</Organization> (CONSISTING OF JOURNAL CODES AND ARTICLE
NUMBERS) TO BE <Organization>PROCESSED</Organization>. THE <Organization>PROCESSED DATA</Organization> IS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO PLOT <Location>BRADFORD</Location>, YIELD
FORMULA AND NARANAN <Organization>GRAPHS BY COMPUTER</Organization>. REASONS FOR CHOOSING <Organization>THESE</Organization> AUTHOR AND
JOURNAL <Organization>PRODUCTIVITY</Organization> DISTRIBUTIONS ARE G IVEN, AND APPLICATIONS OF THE
PROGRAMS IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREAS OF BIBLIOMETRICS ARE EXAMINED. FINALLY, USEFUL
DEVELOPMENTS TO THE SUITE OF PROGRAMS ARE CONSIDERED.
********************************************
Document 5642
<Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S LAW OF BIBLIOGRAPHIC SCATTER.

ANALYSES THE AMBIGUITY INHERENT IN <Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S LAW, AND ATTRIBUTES <Organization>THIS</Organization> TO THE
INCONSISTENCIES <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE VERBAL AND GRAPHICAL FORMS OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> EXPRESSION.
DEMONSTRATES HOW BRADFORD&apos;S LAW CAN BE REWRITTEN SO THAT THEORY AND EMPIRICAL
RESULTS WILL CORRESPOND EXACTLY. TO EXTEND THE PRACTICAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A
MATHEMATICAL MODEL, INTRODUCES THE CONCEPTS OF NORMAL SITUATION AND
NORMALISATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, AND USES ZIPF&apos;S 2ND LAW TO <Organization>ESTABLISH</Organization> A MODEL VALID
FOR NORMAL SITUATIONS <Organization>BUT</Organization> WITH WIDER APPLICATION AND GREATER OBJECTIVITY THAN
<Location>BRADFORD</Location>&apos;S.
********************************************
Document 5643
THE SCATTER OF ARTICLES ACCORDING TO BRADFORD&apos;S LAW OF SCATTER&apos; A BIBLIOMETRIC
ANALYSIS.

REPORT OF A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> CARRIED OUT TO VERIFY BRADFORD&apos;S LAW IN A PARTICULAR CASE
AND COMPILE AS <Organization>COMPLETE</Organization> A BIBLIOGRAPHY AS POSSIBLE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> BRADFORD&apos;S
LAW. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF HOW THE REFERENCES WERE COLLECTED, USING <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>
COLLECTIONS IN THE <Organization>SAO PAULO UNIVERSITY</Organization>, AND CALCULATIONS PRESENTED IN FULL.
THE RESULTS OBTAINED WERE IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE LAW.
********************************************
Document 5644
COMIC STRIPS AND COMICS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>?.

THE BAVARIAN SECTION OF THE VEREIN DER BIBLIOTHEKARE AN OFFENTLICHEN
BIBLIOTHEKEN (ASSOCIATION OF LIBRARIANS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>) HELD AN ADVANCED
<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SESSION IN MAR 82 <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMICS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> STORIES IN PICTURE
FORM IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. SUBJECTS DISCUSSED INCLUDED&apos; THE HISTORY OF COMICS IN THE
<Location>USA</Location>, <Location>FRANCE</Location> AND GERMANY; TERMINOLOGY; MARKETING AND PRODUCTION; PURCHASING;
AND THE USES OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> TYPE OF MATERIAL FOR ADULTS, YOUNG CHILDREN AND TEENAGERS
IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. POPULAR THEMES IN COMICS INCLUDE ADVENTURE, TRAVEL,
ANIMALS AND MEN AND SUPERMAN INVOLVED IN THE CONQUEST OF EVIL. WHILE A
REGRETTABLE TENDENCY TOWARDS VIOLENT AND AGGRESSIVE MATERIAL IS APPARENT, THE
TENDENCY IS OFTEN LESS STRONG HERE THAN IN <Organization>OTHER MEDIA</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5645
<Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> ACCESS TO <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CANADIAN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION ANNUAL CONFERENCE, JUNE 81. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE PROBLEMS
CONCERNED WITH THE SUCCESSFUL IDENTIFICATION AND <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization> OF <Location>US</Location> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
PUBLICATIONS. DESCRIBES AN &apos;IDEAL&apos; <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> FOR <Organization>PROVIDING</Organization> ACCESS TO <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>
PUBLICATIONS, AND OUTLINES AN <Organization>ACTION</Organization> PROGRAMME FOR ACHIEVING <Organization>THIS</Organization>. HIGHLIGHTS
THE IMPORTANCE OF&apos; ASSESSING THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS OF POTENTIAL CLIENTELE;
PUBLICISING AND ENCOURAGING THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>; OBTAINING SUFFICIENT
RESOURCES; <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>; <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> THE COMPREHENSIVENESS AND SIMPLICITY OF
THE SYSTEMS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO ACCESS THE PUBLICATIONS; AND MAINTENANCE OF THE
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5646
OFFICIAL <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> PUBLICATIONS AND BIBLIOGRAPHIC WORK <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
PARLIAMENTARY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

ARTICLE PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE ANNUAL MEETING OF IFLA, <Organization>GENERAL RESEARCH COUNCIL</Organization>,
1981. BRIEFLY DESCRIBES THE HISTORY OF THE 2ANNUAL BIBLIOGRAPHY OF <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
OFFICIAL PUBLICATIONS1 WHICH 1ST APPEARED IN 1934 COVERING THE YEARS 1931-33.
IT WAS FOLLOWED BY ANNUAL VOLUMES COMPILED BY THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> PARLIAMENTARY
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WHICH RECEIVED A DEPOSIT COPY OF EVERY PRINTED OFFICIAL DOCUMENT. THE
2ANNUAL BIBLIOGRAPHY1 HAS ALWAYS BEEN <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> IN A <Organization>CONVENTIONAL</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization>. HOWEVER
AN <Organization>AUDIT GROUP</Organization> IS INVESTIGATING WHETHER IT SHOULD BE INSERTED INTO THE LIBRIS
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, <Organization>USED</Organization> BY <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5647
THE LUMLEY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; A SUPPLEMENTARY CHECKLIST.

PRESENTS <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> 89 PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF JOHN, LORD
LUMLEY (1534-1609), GLEANED SINCE THE PUBLICATION OF THE 1609 <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> OF THE
LUMLEY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> GIVEN IN THE NOTES FALLS INTO 4 CATEGORIES&apos;
ADDITIONAL BOOKS AND MANUSCRIPTS BEARING LUMLEY&apos;S OWNERSHIP INSCRIPTION
IDENTIFIED SINCE THE 1956 PUBLICATION OF THE <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>; 5 ITEMS, NOT YET
LOCATED, WHICH ARE LISTED IN THE <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> OF THE <Organization>OLD</Organization> ROYAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OR IN
BURBRIDGE AS OF CRANMER PROVENANCE; <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, CHIEFLY RELATING TO
PROVENANCE, ABOUT LUMLEY BOOKS ALREADY LISTED; AND NOTES <Organization>ON</Organization> RECENTLY CHANGED
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHELF-MARKS. DETAILED NOTES ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> OF THE 89 WORKS,
AND OF 7 OTHERS NOT LISTED IN THE 1609 <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5648
THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF TURKISH PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE. THE
BEGINNINGS OF OTTOMAN <Organization>PRINTING</Organization> (PART 1).

A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> MARKING THE CENTENARY OF THE BIRTH OF KEMEL ATATURK. A DETAILED
ACCOUNT IS GIVEN OF THE VISITS MADE BY TURKISH LEADERS TO THE <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> COURT IN
THE LATE 17TH AND EARLY 18TH CENTURIES, WHICH RESULTED IN THE ESTABLISHMENT OF
THE 1ST <Organization>PRINTING PRESS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN CONSTANTINOPLE IN 1727, WITH THE
OBJECTIVE OF ENCOURAGING A TURKISH CULTURE INDEPENDENT OF ARAB INFLUENCE.
INCLUDES A DETAILED DESCRIPTIVE LIST OF 17 <Organization>TITLES PRODUCED AT THIS PRESS</Organization>, HELD
IN THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5649
THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF TURKISH PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE. THE
BEGINNINGS OF OTTOMAN <Organization>PRINTING</Organization>. PART 2.

CONCLUSION OF AN ARTICLE BEGUN IN REVUE DE <Location>LA</Location> BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE I (I)
(SEE PRECEDING ABSTRACT), DESCRIBING 17 NOTABLE PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
CONSTANTINOPLE IN THE EARLY 18TH CENTURY BY THE PRINTER MUTEFERRIKA. DETAILS
ARE GIVEN OF SUBJECT MATTER, AUTHORS, AND HISTORICAL BACKGROUND, WITH
BIBLIOTHEQUE NATIONALE BIBLIOGRAPHIC DETAILS. <Organization>CONCLUDES</Organization> WITH A BRIEF
DISCUSSION OF THE ACHIEVEMENTS OF KEMAL ATATURK IN <Organization>PROMOTING EDUCATION</Organization> AND THE
EUROPEANISATION OF <Location>TURKEY</Location>, WITH A SKETCH OF MODERN BOOK PRODUCTION AND THE
AVAILABILITY OF RARE EDITIONS.
********************************************
Document 5650
<Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AND REGIONAL COLLECTIONS.

<Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF A 1978 CONFERENCE PAPER DISCUSSING ORGANISATION AND MANAGEMENT
POLICIES. CONSIDERS FIRSTLY THE <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> CONSTITUTING A <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IN
RELATION TO GEOGRAPHICAL RELEVANCE AND CRITERIA FOR SELECTION&apos; WORKS BY <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
AUTHORS, <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> BY <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> PRINTERS, OR DEALING WITH <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> SUBJECTS, ARE
CONSIDERED, AS WELL AS OFFICIAL ADMINISTRATIVE PUBLICATIONS AND EPHEMERA. THEN
PROBLEMS OF EXPLOITATION AND CONSERVATION ARE EXAMINED, IN AN ATTEMPT TO
RECONCILE ARCHIVAL RESPONSIBILITIES WITH <Organization>USER</Organization> NEEDS&apos; THE RANGE OF POTENTIAL
USERS, <Organization>FROM</Organization> SCHOLARLY RESEARCHERS TO INTERESTED NON-SPECIALISTS, IS DISCUSSED
IN RELATION TO PREPARATION OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> TOOLS PERMITTING MULTIPLE ACCESS
TO THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> TO CATER FOR VARIED APPROACHES; BASIC COMMONSENSE
PRECAUTIONS ARE SUGGESTED FOR MINIMISING DAMAGE TO BOOK <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, AND SPECIAL
MEASURES FOR MINOR DOCUMENTS <Organization>PROPOSED</Organization>. EMPHASISES THAT <Organization>EACH</Organization> LIBRARIAN MUST
EVOLVE HIS OWN POLICY TO MEET HIS OWN PARTICULAR SITUATION.
********************************************
Document 5651
STANDARDS OF PROVISION FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> STUDIES. REPORT &amp; POLICY STATEMENT.

REPORT OF A <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization>, OF THE LANCASHIRE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, TO EXAMINE <Organization>ALL</Organization> ASPECTS
OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PROVISION FOR <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> STUDIES AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> HISTORY WITHIN THE COUNTY.
********************************************
Document 5652
TOOLS OF THE <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> TRADE.

ANNOTATED BIBLIOGRAPHY, BY VARIOUS REVIEWERS, OF ITEMS RELATING TO <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>
LIBRARIANSHIP. ITEMS FALL INTO THE FOLLOWING MAIN CATEGORIES-COLLECTION
DEVELOPMENT-LIBRARIES; <Organization>LIBRARY ADMINISTRATION</Organization>-PERIODICALS; <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>;
PRESENTATION; AND SERIAL PUBLICATIONS-BIBLIOGRAPHY.
********************************************
Document 5653
A QUANTITATIVE AND QUALITATIVE EVALUATION OF THE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IN THE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>SAO PAULO</Location>.

REPORT OF A PILOT <Organization>STUDY</Organization> CARRIED OUT IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>SAO
PAULO</Location> INSTITUTE OF BIOMEDICAL SCIENCES, AS A PRELIMINARY TO A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization>
INVESTIGATION OF PERIODICAL RESOURCES THROUGHOUT THE UNIVERSITY, PRIOR TO THE
INTEGRATION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE <Organization>UNIVERSITY LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE
INSTITUTE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN RELATION TO PARTICULAR CHARACTERISTICS RENDERING IT
ATYPICAL OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> AS A WHOLE. THE OBJECTIVES, METHODOLOGY, DATA
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> PROCEDURES, CALCULATIONS AND RESULTS OF THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> ARE PRESENTED IN
FULL, WITH ACCOMPANYING TABLES AND DIAGRAMS. MODIFICATIONS NECESSARY FOR
APPLYING THE PILOT PROCEDURES TO THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> <Organization>STUDY</Organization> ARE NOTED, WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
<Organization>ALL</Organization> CIRCUMSTANCES AND CONDITIONS, <Organization>PHYSICAL</Organization>, HUMAN, AND FINANCIAL, OBSERVED
DURING THE COURSE OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> TESTING PHASE.
********************************************
Document 5654
EVALUATION OF THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> PERIODICAL <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE

REPORT, PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> A CONFERENCE IN 1979, BY A <Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> SET UP TO
INVESTIGATE PERIODICAL COLLECTIONS THROUGHOUT THE <Organization>FEDERAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> OF RIO
GRANDE DO SUL, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF DATA <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> PROCEDURES, AND
<Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND ANALYSIS TECHNIQUES. THE RESULTS SHOWED THAT THE <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> DID NOT ADEQUATELY MEET <Organization>USER</Organization> NEEDS. CONCLUDING
RECOMMENDATIONS COVER THE POINTS REQUIRING IMMEDIATE ATTENTION, AND LISTS OF
CRITERIA ARE PRESENTED FOR EVALUATING INDIVIDUAL PERIODICAL <Organization>USE</Organization> AND THE STATE
OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AS A WHOLE, TO PERMIT <Organization>CONTINUING</Organization> EVALUATION.
********************************************
Document 5655
<Organization>PERIODICALS SUPPORTING LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE BLIND AND PHYSICALLY
HANDICAPPED.

ANNOTATED BIBLIOGRAPHY OF <Organization>PERIODICALS SUPPORTING LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE BLIND
AND PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED. ITEMS FALL INTO THE FOLLOWING MAIN CATEGORIES&apos;
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization>; FOR <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> PROVIDERS; AND FOR PRINT HANDICAPPED READERS.
********************************************
Document 5656
ROLE OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS IN SCI-TECH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>).S

PECIAL <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO THE ROLE OF <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS IN <Location>US</Location> SCIENTIFIC AND
<Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. FOR ABSTRACTS OF THE INDIVIDUAL ARTICLES, 2SEE1 THE
FOLLOWING SERIAL NUMBERS&apos;-.
********************************************
Document 5657
THE TRUE FACTS ABOUT CENSORSHIP?.

REPLY TO AN ARTICLE BY E.J. GROESKAMP IN BIBLIOTHEEK EN SAMENLEVING 9 (12) DEC
81, 333-337 (FOR AN ABSTRACT OF WHICH 2SEE1 82/4167), IN WHICH ATTENTION WAS
DRAWN TO THE HIDDEN CENSORSHIP PRACTISED BY <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. GROESKAMP&apos;S
DEFINITION OF CENSORSHIP SHOULD MORE PROPERLY BE TERMED &apos;REJECTION <Organization>ON</Organization> ETHICAL
GROUNDS&apos;. BECAUSE OF LACK OF SPACE AND FINANCIAL RESOURCES, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> CANNOT
PURCHASE <Organization>ALL</Organization> BOOKS PUBLISHED AND SELECTION IS NECESSARY TO OBTAIN A BALANCED
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF MATERIAL. THE FACTS <Organization>ON</Organization> WHICH GROESKAMP&apos;S ARGUMENTS ARE BASED
INCLUDE 2 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SURVEYS, OF WHICH 1 <Organization>CONTAINED INSUFFICIENT DATA</Organization> TO DRAW ANY
FIRM CONCLUSIONS, WHILE THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> RESULTS IN CONFLICT WITH
GROESKAMP&apos;S DEDUCTIONS. FOR FINANCIAL REASONS IT IS TO BE EXPECTED THAT IN A
COMMUNITY OF 1 RELIGIOUS PERSUASION FEW BOOKS OF A <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> PERSUASION ARE
LIKELY TO BE FOUND IN THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5658
INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

THE 2ND INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE OF TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>STOCKHOLM</Location> 1981 INCLUDED
PAPERS, LECTURES, WORKSHOPS, AN EXTENSIVE TOY EXHIBITION, AND VISITS TO
HOSPITALS, <Organization>DAY</Organization> NURSERIES, CLINICS, PRESCHOOLS AND TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. APART <Organization>FROM</Organization>
LOANING TOYS, A TOY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AIMS TO ADVISE AND STIMULATE <Organization>THROUGH</Organization> PLAY,
PARTICULARLY TO DEPRIVED FAMILIES. VISITS (IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>) ARE BY APPOINTMENT AND
DOCTOR&apos;S REFERRAL. TOYS ARE SELECTED ACCORDING TO THE CHILD&apos;S <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> NEEDS.
SIBLINGS ARE INVOLVED. COUNTRIES ESPECIALLY SUPPORTING TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> INCLUDE
<Location>DENMARK</Location>, <Location>SWEDEN</Location>, <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>, <Location>ICELAND</Location>, <Location>UK</Location> AND ITALY. <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE
RARELY INVOLVED.
********************************************
Document 5659
TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>. A REPORT WITH SPECIAL ATTENTION TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE IN
SERVICES FOR YOUNG HANDICAPPED CHILDREN AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES.

THE GROWTH OF TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location> HAS BEEN RAPID AND EXTENSIVE DURING
THE 70S AND TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE BEEN ESTABLISHED IN <Organization>ALL</Organization> STATES AND TERRITORIES.
HOWEVER, EVIDENCE POINTS TO A LACK OF AWARENESS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE PART OF LAY PEOPLE AND
PROFESSIONALS ABOUT THE PURPOSES AND FUNCTIONS OF TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; ESPECIALLY IN
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE OF SERVING HANDICAPPED CHILDREN AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FAMILIES. THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>STUDY</Organization> IS TO HELP OVERCOME <Organization>THIS</Organization> LACK OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND BE OF ASSISTANCE TO
POLICY MAKERS AND THOSE <Organization>DEVELOPING SERVICES</Organization> WHICH IMPINGE <Organization>ON</Organization> AREAS IN WHICH
TOY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE PRESENTLY INVOLVED.
********************************************
Document 5660
<Organization>AUDIOVISUAL</Organization> AIDS IN THE <Location>FEDERAL REPUBLIC OF GERMANY</Location>.

IN THE PAST 10 YEARS <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> AIDS HAVE BECOME AN ESSENTIAL PART OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SUPPLIES</Organization> OFFERED IN <Location>WEST GERMANY</Location>. <Organization>AT</Organization> THE SAME TIME THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> <Organization>AID</Organization>
MEDIA HAVE DEVELOPED IN <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> DIRECTIONS. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> AIDS
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> IN <Organization>SOUND RECORDING MEDIA</Organization>, VIDEO AND SLIDES AND FILMS. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> MENTIONS
THE SERVICES OF THE EINKAUFSZENTRALE FUR OFFENTLICH BIBLIOTHEKEN REVIEWING AND
READING DEPARTMENTS AND THE DIFFICULTIES OF <Organization>CATALOGUING SOUND RECORDING MEDIA</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5661
<Organization>NATIONAL SERVICE</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE FIELD OF <Organization>AUDIOVISUAL MEDIA</Organization>. THE
SITUATION IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>.

<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE DEVELOPMENTS IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> WHICH HAVE LEAD TO THE INCLUSION
OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA</Organization> IN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>CENTRAL SERVICES</Organization> TO
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> FIELD. MENTIONS PROBLEMS REGARDING THE INCLUSION OF
<Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, THE EFFECTS OF THE 1975 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> WHICH MADE PROVISION FOR <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>, THE WORK OF THE
NEDERLANDS BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM (<Organization>DUTCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
CENTRE) AND <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> PRODUCTION <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> OF THE <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA SERVICE</Organization>.
SINCE 1981 THE NBLC HAS PROVIDED A <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization> SUPPLY OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>THIS SERVICE</Organization> HAS ENABLED <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO IMPROVE
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> STOCK.
********************************************
Document 5662
SERVICES AND <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR THE HANDICAPPED&apos; AN INSTITUTE FOR SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MEDIA PROFESSIONALS (DEKALB, ILLINOIS, AUGUST 12-17, 1979).

CONTAINS A NARRATIVE AND 2 EVALUATIONS OF A <Organization>WEEK-LONG INSTITUTE ON MEDIA</Organization>
SERVICES FOR HANDICAPPED STUDENTS WHICH WAS HELD <Organization>AT</Organization> NORTHERN ILLINOIS
UNIVERSITY. PURPOSES OF THE INSTITUTE WERE TO&apos; (1) EXTEND THE ABILITIES OF
<Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA</Organization> PROFESSIONALS TO PROVIDE MEDIA SERVICES TO HANDICAPPED
CHILDREN; (2) SUPPLY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> SOURCES OF <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> ESPECIALLY PERTINENT
FOR THE HANDICAPPED; (3) PROVIDE PARTICIPANTS WITH THE EXPERTISE NECESSARY TO
<Organization>PRESENT</Organization> IN-SERVICE SESSIONS FOR <Organization>TEACHERS ON SERVICE</Organization> TO THE HANDICAPPED; (4)
HELP PARTICIPANTS COMMUNICATE WITH PARENTS OF HANDICAPPED CHILDREN ABOUT
<Organization>AVAILABLE SERVICES</Organization>; AND (5) STIMULATE GREATER INITIATIVE AND INVOLVEMENT IN
<Organization>THIS</Organization> ASPECT OF <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA SERVICES</Organization>. PARTICIPANTS IN THE INSTITUTE
WERE PROFESSIONALS INVOLVED IN THE APPLICATION OF <Organization>LIBRARY MEDIA SERVICES</Organization> AND
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN RELATION TO SPECIAL EDUCATI <Organization>ON</Organization>. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5663
<Location>U.S.</Location> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> <Organization>AUDIOVISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization>.

<Location>US</Location> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization> <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> OFFER A VALUABLE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
RESOURCE WHICH IS OFTEN OVERLOOKED BY LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS. THE
LIBRARIAN WHO IS KNOWLEDGEABLE ABOUT <Organization>THEIR</Organization> AVAILABILITY WILL BE ABLE TO BRING
<Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> TO THE ATTENTION OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PATRONS TO WHOM THEY
COULD BE USEFUL. KNOWLEDGE OF THE INDEXES AND LISTS WHICH HAVE BEEN SPECIALLY
COMPILED FOR <Organization>THESE</Organization> RESOURCES WILL MAKE THEM AS ACCESSIBLE AS THE MORE FAMILIAR
PRINT <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> DOCUMENTS.
********************************************
Document 5664
MICROGRAPHICS AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. A GRADUATE COURSE.

THE <Organization>COMPLETE</Organization> SYLLABUS FOR A 15-SESSION COURSE IN MICROGRAPHICS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
ACQUISITION, HANDLING, INTERPRETATION, AND UTILISATION IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS
PRESENTED. SEMINAR TOPICS COVER THE SELECTION OF EQUIPMENT, MICROFORM
STANDARDS, COM, RESOURCES <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> MICROFORM, MICROPUBLISHING, RECORDS
MANAGEMENT LABORATORIES, BIBLIOGRAPHIC CONTROL OF MICROFORMS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
INDUSTRY, AND THE CREATION AND EVALUATION OF THE MICROFORM ENVIRONMENT. REPORT
NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5665
CONVERSION OF <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> PAPER TO MICROFORM.

EXAMINES THE ADVANTAGES TRADITIONALLY ASCRIBED TO MICROFORMAT <Organization>SERIALS</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS
COST AND SPACE SAVING, PERMANENCE, AND EASE OF HANDLING, IN THE LIGHT OF NEW
COST COMPARISONS, CONTINUED <Organization>USER</Organization> RESISTANCE AND THE UNCERTAIN RESULTS OF
PERMANENCE STUDIES.
********************************************
Document 5666
VIDEOCASSETTE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> MORGANTOWN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

DESCRIBES THE VIDEOCASSETTE MOVIE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> MORGANTOWN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
WEST <Organization>VIRGINIA</Organization>, WITH DETAILS OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> MOST POPULAR ITEMS. DURING <Organization>ITS</Organization> 1ST
YEAR THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> GREW TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> TARGET OF 100 CASSETTES, AND THE CORE
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS EXPANDING <Organization>FURTHER</Organization>. CIRCULATION FIGURES HAVE RISEN STEEPLY.
MOVIES ARE RATED BEFORE SCREENING, AND THERE ARE <Organization>SOME</Organization> RESTRICTIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>
BORROWING, WITH CHECKS <Organization>ON</Organization> PATRONS COPYING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S VIDEOCASSETTES AND
SWITCHING COPIES WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> OWN.
********************************************
Document 5667
THE <Organization>VIDEOGRAM</Organization> REPORT-PUBLISHED TOO LATE?.

THE <Organization>VIDEOGRAM COMMISSION</Organization>&apos;S REPORT <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD BE
DISTRIBUTION CENTRES FOR A BROAD SUPPLY OF GOOD QUALITY VIDEO RECORDINGS, <Organization>BUT</Organization>
VIDEO HAS ALREADY BECOME A MASS MARKET ARTICLE <Organization>SUPPLIED THROUGH INTERNATIONAL</Organization>
DISTRIBUTION CHANNELS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE LITTLE CHANCE OF MAKING AN IMPACT. A
<Organization>WORKING GROUP</Organization> OF REPRESENTATIVES OF <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization>, THE VIDMO-GROUP,
WAS FORMED ALREADY IN 1973; IT HOPED TO START EXPERIMENTS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH
PRODUCTION AND SHOWING OF VIDEOGRAMS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> TRADE UNION OPPOSITION MEANT THAT
THE <Organization>SWEDISH BROADCASTING CORPORATION</Organization>&apos;S PROGRAMMES COULD NOT BE <Organization>USED</Organization>. <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
REPORTS HAVE APPEARED POINTING TO THE ADVANTAGES OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS DISTRIBUTORS
OF VIDEO, <Organization>BUT WITHOUT STATE FINANCIAL</Organization> SUPPORT <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WILL NEVER BE
ABLE TO FULFIL <Organization>THIS</Organization> ROLE. <Organization>SOME</Organization> AREAS ARE, HOWEVER, OPEN TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, PROVIDED
THEY COOPERATE WITH <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ORGANISATIONS&apos; VIDEOGRAMS FOR THE
DEAF AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> HANDICAPPED; VIDEOGRAMS <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization>  DIRECTLY FOR THE MEDIUM BY
ARTISTS AND MEDIA WORKSHOPS; VIDEOGRAMS FOR CHILDREN; FOR EDUCATION IN
COOPERATION WITH THE <Organization>EDUCATIONAL RADIO</Organization> AND THE <Organization>AV CENTRE</Organization>; AND LOCALLY <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization>
MATERIAL FOR VIDEO.
********************************************
Document 5668
THE IMPACT OF <Organization>USER</Organization> FRUSTRATION OF HUMANITIES <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>.

REPORTS <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> TO PROVIDE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE CONSEQUENCE OF <Organization>USER</Organization>
FRUSTRATION AMONG HUMANITIES FACULTIES CAUSED BY <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> INADEQUACY <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>SUCH</Organization> FRUSTRATION DOES EXIST, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE LACK OF A STRONG HUMANITIES <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS
NOT DEEMED TO BE AN UNSURMOUNTABLE IMPEDIMENT TO <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. THE FREEDOM AND
ENCOURAGEMENT TO TRAVEL TO PRIMARY SOURCES AND A COMFORTABLE WORK ENVIRONMENT
WITH <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization>, <Organization>EFFECTIVE SERVICES</Organization> IS MOST IMPORTANT.
********************************************
Document 5669
THE VISNEWS FILM <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

VISNEWS IS 1 OF THE WORLD&apos;S <Organization>LEADING NEWSFILM AGENCIES</Organization> AND <Organization>SUPPLIES</Organization> MATERIAL TO
TV STATIONS. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>LONDON</Location> IS HELD TO BE THE LARGEST AND MOST
<Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> KIND. IT HAS A UNIQUE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF NEWSFILM <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF
WHICH DATES BACK TO 1896&apos; BESIDES <Organization>ITS</Organization> OWN <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IT OWNS 5 <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization>
CINEMA NEWSREEL COLLECTIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE PAST. AN EXTENSIVE CARD INDEX <Organization>CATALOGUES</Organization>
THE COLLECTIONS UNDER A VARIETY OF HEADINGS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS SUBJECT, LOCATION,
PERSONALITIES ETC. MUCH OF THE <Organization>OLD NITRATE HOLDINGS</Organization> ARE NOW <Organization>ON</Organization> VIDEO <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PREFERS TO KEEP MATERIAL <Organization>ON</Organization> FILM. VIEWING FACILITIES ARE <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> AND
COMPILATION OF ANY VISNEWS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MATERIAL IS POSSIBLE <Organization>ON</Organization> PAYMENT.
********************************************
Document 5670
THE MANAGEMENT AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>&apos; AN INTERDISCIPLINARY
CROSS-CITATION ANALYSIS.

A METHOD IS <Organization>PROPOSED</Organization> FOR MEASURING INTERDISCIPLINARY RELATIONS IN SCIENTIFIC
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> CROSS CITATION AMONG CORE JOURNALS EMPIRICALLY SELECTED <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE BASIS OF <Organization>USE</Organization> AND IMPORTANCE. THE METHOD IS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO TEST HYPOTHESES DERIVED
<Organization>FROM</Organization> A BIBLIOMETRIC DEFINITION OF INTERDISCIPLINARITY AMONG THE MANAGEMENT AND
<Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> LITERATURES. THE RESULTS REVEAL THAT THE MANAGEMENT <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
IS DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> SCIENCES, THAT IS MORE DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THEM THAN VICE
VERSA, AND THAT IT IS MORE DEPENDENT <Organization>ON</Organization> THEM THAN THEY ARE <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>EACH</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5671
<Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COMMUNITIES INFORMATION-HOW TO TRACK IT DOWN AND KEEP PACE WITH IT,
PART 2.

CONTINUATION OF A PREVIOUS ARTICLE (2SEE1 81/5645) WHICH LOOKED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization>
SOURCE <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> RELATING TO THE <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> COMMUNITIES. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> BRIEFLY&apos;
SCIENTIFIC, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> PUBLICATIONS; COMMERCIAL <Organization>ABSTRACTING</Organization>
SERVICES; <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>; GRANTS AND <Organization>LOAN</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>; DATA SYSTEMS; <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>
GUIDES; AND <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CENTRES AND DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5672
ABIDING BY THE LAW&apos; LEGAL <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

INCREASINGLY, LAW <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> ARE NEEDED BY AN EVER-WIDENING RANGE OF PEOPLE,
AND SINCE THE SOURCE OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> MOST READILY <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> TO THE <Organization>AVERAGE</Organization>
PERSON IS THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD BE THE MOST CONVENIENT
LOCATION FOR LEGAL <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. EXAMINES THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> RIGHT OF ACCESS TO
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> WITH REGARD TO INDIVIDUAL LEGAL PRACTICE AND THE ATTITUDES OF
LAWYERS, AND <Organization>SUGGESTS</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> BASIC LEGAL TEXTS FOR A CORE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>. HINTS ARE
GIVEN <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ORGANISATION OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, AND THE MORE IMPORTANT
BIBLIOGRAPHIC AIDS ARE CITED.
********************************************
Document 5673
PICK A TITLE 2&apos; A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF MEDIA ABOUT THE HANDICAPPED.

THE LISTING OF BOOKS, FILMS, <Organization>SOUND</Organization> CASSETTES, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MEDIA ABOUT THE
HANDICAPPED IS DIVIDED INTO 3 INTEREST LEVEL AREAS; PRE-SCHOOL AND PRIMARY,
MIDDLE OR INTERMEDIATE, AND YOUNG ADULT AND ADULT. A SECTION FOR PARENTS
CONTAINS INSTRUCTIONAL <Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> IN THE HOME. <Organization>ALSO</Organization> INCLUDED IS A
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> SECTION FOR <Organization>USE</Organization> BY <Organization>TEACHERS</Organization>, SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS, AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> PEOPLE INVOLVED WITH HANDICAPPED STUDENTS. <Organization>EACH</Organization> CITATION INCLUDES
A PRICE AND A SHORT CONTENT <Organization>SUMMARY</Organization>; THE ADDRESSES OF PUBLISHERS CITED ARE
GIVEN <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>END</Organization> OF THE BIBLIOGRAPHY. REPORT NOT <Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> NTIS.
********************************************
Document 5674
DIACHRONOUS <Organization>VS</Organization>. SYNCHRONOUS <Organization>STUDY</Organization> OF OBSOLESCENCE.

WAYS OF MEASURING OBSOLESCENCE WITHIN THE SUBJECT OF HUMAN AND <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
GENETICS. SYNCHRONOUS STUDIES (WHICH ARE MADE <Organization>ON RECORDS</Organization> OF <Organization>USE</Organization> OR
BIBLIOGRAPHIC REFERENCES MADE <Organization>AT</Organization> 1 POINT IN TIME AND COMPARE THE <Organization>USE</Organization> AGAINST
THE <Organization>AGE</Organization> DISTRIBUTION OF THE MATERIAL <Organization>USED</Organization> OR CITED) ARE MORE EASILY APPLIED
AND PRODUCE EQUIVALENT RESULTS TO THE APPARENTLY MORE THEORETICALLY DESIRABLE
DIACHRONOUS STUDIES (WHICH FOLLOW THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF PARTICULAR ITEMS <Organization>THROUGH</Organization>
SUCCESSIVE OBSERVATIONS <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> DATES).
********************************************
Document 5675
CITATION ANALYSIS AND BIBLIOMETRIC CHARACTERISTICS OF CORE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization>.

A REPORT OF THE PRELIMINARY STAGES OF A SPANISH STATE SPONSORED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
PROJECT. THE ANALYSIS COVERS CITATIONS OF PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> ANTINEOPLASTIC SUBSTANCES
IN 2CANCER <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>1 <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1976-79. A TOTAL OF 7,815 REFERENCES TO 576
<Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> CARRIED IN 284 PAPERS WAS OBTAINED, AND THE <Location>BRADFORD</Location> TECHNIQUE
APPLIED TO ASCERTAIN THE CORE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> RECEIVING AN <Organization>AVERAGE</Organization> OF 1 CITATION
PER MONTH. A COMPARISON WAS THEN MADE <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> CORE AND NON-CORE PERIODICAL
THEMATIC COVERAGE OF 8 ANTINEOPLASTIC SUBSTANCES; AND THE QUANTITATIVE
DIFFERENCE IN DISTRIBUTION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE 2 SETS OF <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> FOR <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AND
SPECIFIC THEMATIC DISTRIBUTION ESTABLISHED. FULL DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF <Organization>ALL</Organization>
CALCULATIONS MADE, AND RESULTS TABULATED. THE RESULTS OBTAINED SHOW THAT ONLY
THE CORE <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> CAN SATISFY THE BIBLIOGRAPHIC REQUIREMENTS OF THE FIELD,
AS REGARDS THEMATIC COVERAGE AND CITATION FREQUENCY.
********************************************
Document 5676
ANALYSIS OF <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL</Organization> PRODUCTION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>UFMG VETERINARY MEDICINE SCHOOL</Organization>,
<Location>BRAZIL</Location>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1973 TO 1977.

EXTRACT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A POSTGRADUATE DISSERTATION PRESENTED <Organization>AT UFMG LIBRARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
<Location>BRAZIL</Location>. THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization> WAS UNDERTAKEN TO INVESTIGATE THE DIRECTIONS OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
INTERESTS. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE ORGANISATION AND PERSONNEL OF THE SCHOOL.
<Organization>ALL</Organization> PERIODICAL ARTICLES PUBLISHED BY <Organization>STAFF</Organization> WERE ANALYSED BY PLACE OF
PUBLICATION; LANGUAGE; SINGLE AND MULTIPLE AUTHORSHIP; AND SUBJECT
DISTRIBUTION. RESULTS SHOWED THAT THE SCHOOL&apos;S <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROGRAMMES SUPPORTED
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>, STATE AND UNIVERSITY OBJECTIVES.
********************************************
Document 5677
BIBLIOMETRIC STUDIES <Organization>ON</Organization> A PROTEIN-RICH CROP: THE COWPEA.

2 BIBLIOGRAPHIES <Organization>ON</Organization> COWPEAS, ONE COVERING THE PERIOD 1888-1949 AND THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
1950-1973, WERE ANALYSED TO <Organization>STUDY</Organization> VARIOUS CHARACTERISTICS OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.
RESULTS SHOWED THAT GROWTH OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> HAS BEEN EXPONENTIAL, DOUBLING
EVERY 20 YEARS, WITH THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE ACCOUNTING FOR OVER 87% OF THE
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. THOUGH THE PERIODICAL WAS THE MOST POPULAR PUBLISHING MEDIUM,
FORMAT CHANGES WERE EVIDENT AND BRADFORD DISTRIBUTIONS OF THE 2 GROUPS
RESULTED IN A THIRD <Location>BRADFORD</Location> DISTRIBUTION WHEN MERGED.
********************************************
Document 5678
THE EXAMINATION OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> TRENDS BY ANALYSIS OF PUBLICATION NUMBERS.

DESCRIBES A METHOD <Organization>USED</Organization> TO EXAMINE TRENDS IN <Organization>TEXTILE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> OVER THE PERIOD
1960-79. THE METHOD CONSISTED OF A COUNT OF <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PAPERS AND PATENTS, IN
SPECIFIC SUBJECT AREAS, USING 2WORLD <Organization>TEXTILE</Organization> ABSTRACTS1, 2CHEMICAL ABSTRACTS1,
2JOURNAL OF THE <Organization>TEXTILE INSTITUTE</Organization>1 AND 2<Organization>TEXTILE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> JOURNAL1 AS SOURCES
OF DATA. THE <Organization>STATISTICAL</Organization> PROCEDURES <Organization>USED</Organization> TO <Organization>PROCESS</Organization> THE DATA ARE BRIEFLY
INDICATED.
********************************************
Document 5679
THE WORK OF THE <Location>GERMAN DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC</Location>&apos;S BRANCH OF THE INTERNATIONAL
ASSOCIATION OF MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, MUSIC ARCHIVES AND MUSIC <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> CENTRES.

THE BRANCH, FOUNDED IN 1959, HAS 27 CORPORATE MEMBERS <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> MUSIC
DEPARTMENTS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, MUSIC <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> CENTRES AND
COLLEGES, SCORE AND RECORD ARCHIVES. THE BRANCH&apos;S TASKS INCLUDE <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization>
COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> MUSIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>, <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> STANDARDS OF
MUSIC LIBRARIANSHIP, <Organization>PROMOTING</Organization> EXCHANGE AND <Organization>LOAN</Organization> OF MUSIC DOCUMENTS,
<Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> MUSIC BIBLIOGRAPHY, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND PROTECTING THE
MUSICAL HERITAGE. WORK IS CARRIED OUT <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL LEVELS <Organization>ON</Organization>
MUSICOLOGY, LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization>, COOPERATION WITH <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>&apos;S
<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> AND <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization> IN THE PRODUCTION OF THE BIBLIOGRAPHIC
WORK <Organization>REPERTOIRE INTERNATIONAL</Organization> DES SOURCES MUSICALES AND THE QUARTERLY
<Organization>ABSTRACTING SERVICE REPERTOIRE INTERNATIONAL</Organization> DE LITTERATURE MUSICALE BEING
PARTICULARLY IMPORTAN T.
********************************************
Document 5680
MUSIC AND THEATRE COLLECTIONS IN <Location>MADRID</Location> MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS DESCRIBED AS A &apos;HIDDEN JEWEL&apos; IN THE <Organization>OLD</Organization> CITY OF <Location>MADRID</Location>. IT WAS
FOUNDED IN 1876 AND SINCE 1930 HAS SHARED A <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> WITH THE MUNICIPAL
MUSEUM. IT HOUSES THE RICHEST <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF SPANISH MUSIC TO BE FOUND
ANYWHERE, AND MANY <Organization>OLD</Organization> MANUSCRIPTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> HISTORIC <Location>MADRID</Location> THEATRES. THERE ARE
8,430 VALUABLE LIBRETTI AND SCORES, MAINLY OF THE PERIOD 1750-1890, TOGETHER
WITH COLLECTIONS OF MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS, OPERAS AND PLAYS. A <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> WAS
PUBLISHED IN 1965.
********************************************
Document 5681
MURDER IN THE FISHER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

THE UNIVERSITY OF <Location>SYDNEY</Location>&apos;S FISHER <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HOLDS A <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> OF CRIME FICTION
THAT RANKS 3RD OR 4TH IN SIZE IN THE WORLD-NEARLY 18,000 VOLUMES. DESCRIBES
THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, STARTED IN THE EARLY 1970S. <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization>
MATERIAL <Organization>ON</Organization> THE GENRE HAS BEEN OBTAINED TO <Organization>FACILITATE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
VALUES OFFERED BY CRIME FICTION.
********************************************
Document 5682
REGIONAL COLLABORATION IN THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>.
<Location>SWEDEN</Location>&apos;S <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE BASICALLY OPERATED BY THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES. THE
STATE CAN PROVIDE GRANTS TO LEVEL OUT STANDARDS <Organization>BUT</Organization> DOES NOT INTERFERE IN THE
RUNNING OF <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND SWEDEN HAS NO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. MUNICIPAL
AUTHORITIES THEMSELVES DECIDE THE OBJECTIVES, SCALE AND STRUCTURE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. <Organization>ALL</Organization> OF <Location>SWEDEN</Location>&apos;S 279 MUNICIPALITIES PROVIDE MUNICIPAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES. CERTAIN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FUNCTIONS <Organization>WOULD</Organization> BE TOO EXPENSIVE TO <Organization>OPERATE</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A
PURELY MUNICIPAL BASIS-IT IS THEREFORE RATIONAL AND <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> TO TRANSFER
<Organization>THESE</Organization> TO THE REGIONAL OR SUPRAMUNICIPAL-THAT IS, COUNTY-LEVEL.
********************************************
Document 5683
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization> A <Organization>WAGON LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>SR-</Organization>6 STATE RAILWAY NETWORK, RIO
GRANDE DO SUL, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.

A PROJECT PRESENTED TO THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> RAILWAY BORAD IN 1980, BASED <Organization>ON</Organization> PREVIOUS
EXPERIENCE WITH <Organization>MOBILE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE <Organization>WAGON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>WOULD</Organization> CIRCULATE THROUGHOUT
THE NETWORK HOOKED UP TO A PASSENGER TRAIN; THE POTENTIAL BENEFITS IN
<Organization>PROMOTING</Organization> READING ARE DISCUSSED, AND DETAILS GIVEN OF THE ESTIMATED <Organization>STAFF</Organization>,
STOCK, AND EQUIPMENT REQUIRED. PROCEDURES FOR EVALUATING AND CONTROLLING THE
SERVICE ARE OUTLINED, AND A VARIETY OF ADDITIONAL EXTENSION <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> WHICH
COULD <Organization>OPERATE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>WAGON</Organization> AS A BASE SUGGESTED.
********************************************
Document 5684
INVISIBLE COLLEGES AS A BASIS FOR <Organization>PLANNING SPECIAL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>. A REVIEW
OF THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>.

EXPLAINS HOW INVISIBLE COLLEGES <Organization>FACILITATE</Organization> TRANSMISSION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AMONG
MEMBERS OF SCIENTIFIC COMMUNITIES, CITING PUBLISHED <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AS EVIDENCE.
THERE IS NO EVIDENCE IN THE <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> TO SHOW THAT LIBRARIANS HAVE
CAPITALISED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> PHENOMENON. PROPOSES THAT <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES IDENTIFY THE
INTERESTS OF <Organization>USER</Organization> COMMUNITIES AND KEEP FILES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>,
DISSEMINATING <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AS PART OF <Organization>THEIR REFERENCE SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5685
WHICH <Organization>WAY</Organization> FOR SCHOOL MEDIA SERVICES TO TURN?.

IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> THERE HAS BEEN MUCH DISCUSSION IN RECENT YEARS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
TRANSFER OF <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO THE
RESPONSIBILITY OF THE <Organization>LOCAL EDUCATION</Organization> AUTHORITIES. IN THE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> SITUATION OF
CUTBACKS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FINANCES THERE IS CONSIDERABLE SUPPORT FOR <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A
TRANSFER. HOWEVER, SCHOOL LIBRARIANS EMPLOYED BY THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
AUTHORITIES, ARE AS MUCH A PART OF THE SCHOOL &apos;SUPPORT&apos; <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AS <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization>
PSYCHOLOGISTS AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> WORKERS <Organization>ALSO</Organization> FOUND IN SCHOOLS. LIBRARIANS EXPERIENCED
IN THE PROVISION OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> ARE IN THE BEST POSITION TO
<Organization>ORGANISE SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH <Organization>THEIR</Organization> GROWING COLLECTIONS OF <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization>
<Organization>MATERIALS</Organization> AS WELL AS <Organization>THEIR</Organization> BOOKSTOCK.
********************************************
Document 5686
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK IN THE <Organization>SLOVAK</Organization> SOCIALIST REPUBLIC AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>FUTURE DEVELOPMENT</Organization>.

THE RECENT <Organization>COMMUNIST PARTY</Organization> CONGRESS AND REQUIREMENTS OF THE 7TH 5-YEAR-PLAN
(1981-85) HAVE GIVEN A <Organization>NEW</Organization> IMPETUS TO THE WHOLE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK IN <Location>SLOVAKIA</Location>.
SINCE 1 JAN 82, A SPECIAL SECTION OF MATICA SLOVENSKA, BASED IN <Location>BRATISLAVA</Location>,
HAS BEEN IN OPERATION. <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> HAVE TO WATCH, <Organization>DIRECT</Organization> AND CONTROL BOTH SHORT-
AND LONG-TERM <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THEY WILL <Organization>ALSO CARE</Organization> FOR COORDINATION
<Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND CENTRES OF SCIENTIFIC, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> AND ECONOMIC
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. CONTACTS WITH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE CZECH SOCIALIST REPUBLIC AS WELL
<Organization>AS INTERNATIONAL</Organization> CONNECTIONS WILL <Organization>ALSO</Organization> BE FURTHERED. THE OVERALL
RESPONSIBILITY FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, HOWEVER, RESTS UPON THE <Organization>SLOVAK MINISTRY</Organization> OF
CULTURE. FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PART, THE MINISTRY&apos;S OFFICIALS WILL MAKE EVERY EFFORT
TOWARDS UNIFICATION AND/OR STANDARDISATION OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>,
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP BOOK COLLECTIONS, RECORDS, STATISTICS AND THE LIKE.
AMONG <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PROBLEMS WHICH MUST BE TACKLED IN  THE FORSEEABLE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> ARE
COMPUTERISATION, MERGERS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>APPROPRIATE</Organization>,
AND INCORPORATION OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> INTO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> <Organization>INSTITUTIONS</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5687
NETWORKS.

REVISED VERSION OF A PAPER PRESENTED TO A MEETING <Organization>ON</Organization> REGIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
COOPERATION IN DEVENTER, 19 NOV 81. IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> COOPERATION AMONGST
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Organization>ALL</Organization> TYPES HAS COME UNDER CLOSE EXAMINATION AS A RESULT OF THE
INCLUSION OF <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>PROPOSED PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. THE
CONCEPT OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORKS DATES <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE EARLY 1900S WHEN THE NEED FOR
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> TO SHARE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RESOURCES WAS RECOGNISED. THE MOST <Organization>EFFECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
NETWORKS ARE THOSE NETWORKS WHICH <Organization>OPERATE THEIR SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A FINANCIAL BASIS.
IN ADDITION, THE COORDINATION OF ACQUISITION POLICIES, <Organization>CATALOGUING SERVICES</Organization>
AND <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization> AMONGST MEMBERS OF A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK REQUIRES THE
MOST UP-TO-DATE TELECOMMUNICATION AND COMPUTER EQUIPMENT. WITHIN <Organization>EACH</Organization> NETWORK
A <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD BE DESIGNATED TO <Organization>ACT</Organization> AS A CLEARING-HOUSE FOR THE
TRANSFER OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5688
EXTRA-MURAL FUNCTIONS OF UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

FOR OVER 10 YEARS <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE BEEN BUYING MORE ACADEMIC <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>
THAN BEFORE AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OFFERING THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> FACILITIES TO
PEOPLE OUTSIDE THE UNIVERSITY. <Organization>THIS</Organization> EXTRA-MURAL WORK MUST NOT BE REDUCED
BECAUSE OF FINANCIAL PROBLEMS; THE OBVIOUS NEED FOR ACADEMIC MATERIAL MUST BE
SATISFIED AND INTER-LIBRARY LOANS AND PURCHASING SCHEMES MUST RESULT IN A
<Organization>BETTER</Organization> COORDINATED AND MORE ECONOMICAL <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>. THE <Organization>BUILDING</Organization> UP OF
UNION <Organization>CATALOGUES USING ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> AND OF DECENTRALISED
MICROFICHE AND SCREEN <Organization>TEXT SERVICES</Organization> WILL EASE THE <Organization>DEMAND ON UNIVERSITY</Organization> SPECIAL
COLLECTIONS. ISOLATION OF UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WILL NOT IMPROVE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
IMAGE AND COULD PROVE COSTLY.
********************************************
Document 5689
THE WORK OF THE <Organization>STUDY GROUP</Organization> OF DIRECTORS OF UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.

IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>, THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF <Location>BERLIN</Location>,
<Location>DRESDEN</Location>, GREIFSWALD, HALLE, JENA, <Location>LEIPZIG</Location> AND ROSTOCK PLAY AN IMPORTANT PART
IN INTER-LIBRARY <Organization>LOAN</Organization> SCHEMES AND IN THE ACQUISITION OF SPECIALISED STOCKS. IN
1980 <Organization>THESE</Organization> UNIVERSITIES OWNED TOTAL STOCKS OF 18 MILLION ITEMS. THE <Organization>STUDY</Organization>
GROUP PROVIDES ADVICE <Organization>ON</Organization> ORGANISATION, WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE
DEVELOPMENT OF THE UNIFIED <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> OF A <Organization>CENTRAL UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH
ASSOCIATED BRANCHES AND PROMOTES EXCHANGES AND ANALYSES OF EXPERIENCE. THE
GROUP IS CURRENTLY CONCENTRATING <Organization>ON</Organization> INTER-LIBRARY COOPERATION WITHIN SUBJECT
NETWORKS, WITH A VIEW TO IMRPOVING PURCHASING POLICY. IMPROVEMENTS MUST <Organization>ALSO</Organization>
BE MADE IN THE COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES
AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, IN <Organization>USER</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> AND IN THE APPLICATION OF TECHNOLOGY.
********************************************
Document 5690
THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK.

A FULL PRESENTATION OF THE ORGANISATION AND OPERATION OF THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN</Organization>
INTER-UNIVERSITY <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization>, SHOWING HOW IT WAS CREATED TO INTEGRATE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization>
INITIATIVES AND IMPLEMENT A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> POLICY OF COOPERATION AND
RESOURCE SHARING. THE NETWORK&apos;S STRUCTURE IS DESIGNED TO MAXIMISE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
<Organization>AVAILABLE</Organization> RESOURCES <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>, REGIONAL AND <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> LEVELS; DETAILS ARE GIVEN
OF MEMBERSHIP AND ADMINISTRATION. 16 PROGRAMMES CURRENTLY IN <Organization>PROGRESS</Organization> ARE
OUTLINED; <Organization>THESE</Organization> INCLUDE PROJECTS FOR A <Organization>NATIONAL UNION</Organization> <Organization>PERIODICALS</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>,
<Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>LOAN</Organization>, DUPLICATES EXCHANGE, COOPERATIVE <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>
IN PUBLICATION, PREPARATION OF DIRECTORIES AND GUIDES, AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF BOTH
PERSONNEL AND USERS.
********************************************
Document 5691
INTERACTION WITHIN THE <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> REPORTS COMMUNITY.

THERE IS A GROWING INTERDEPENDENCE AMONG THE <Organization>MAJOR US FEDERAL</Organization> <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
REPORTS <Organization>PROCESSING AGENCIES</Organization>, THE <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization>/TECHNOLOGY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>/<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
CENTRES AND COMMERCIAL SERVICES WITH WHICH THEY INTERACT. IN <Organization>THIS</Organization>
INTERCONNECTED <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NETWORK, THE PARTICIPANTS BOTH FEED AND <Organization>USE</Organization> THE
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> TO FULFIL <Organization>THEIR</Organization> MISSIONS IN REGARD TO TRANSFERRING <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
AND DEVELOPMENT RESULTS. COOPERATIVE ARRANGEMENTS AMONG THE PARTICIPANTS AND
SHARING OF RESOURCES ARE BECOMING INCREASINGLY IMPERATIVE IN ORDER TO LOWER
<Organization>COSTS</Organization> AND INCREASE EFFICIENCY. RECENT STEPS TAKEN TOWARDS <Organization>THESE</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED.
********************************************
Document 5692
BACKGROUND TO THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN</Organization> LAW 11 OF 5 MARCH 1979 &apos;RECOGNISING THE PROFESSION
OF LIBRARIANSHIP AND REGULATING <Organization>ITS</Organization> EXERCISE&apos;.

DESCRIBES THE PREPARATION AND PRESENTATION OF EARLY VERSIONS OF THE <Organization>COLOMBIAN</Organization>
LAW NOW IN FORCE. DETAILS ARE GIVEN OF THE PROJECTS PRESENTED IN 1963, 1964,
AND 1971, FOLLOWING DISCUSSION BY THE <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> ASSOCIATIONS, TO REGULARISE
THE LEGAL BASIS OF LIBRARIANSHIP, TO ACCORD WITH <Organization>ITS</Organization> STATUS AS A UNIVERSITY
SUBJECT, AND EXPANDING RECRUITMENT. THE <Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF THE LAW IS APPENDED.
********************************************
Document 5693
DRAFT OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL&apos; <Organization>AMPUTATED CENTRAL ADMINISTRATION</Organization> AND MANY
POSSIBILITIES OF DISPENSATION.

<Organization>THIS</Organization> DRAFT, <Organization>ISSUED</Organization> BY THE <Organization>DANISH MINISTRY</Organization> OF <Organization>CULTURAL AFFAIRS</Organization> IN APR 81, TO
BECOME LAW <Organization>AT</Organization> THE EARLIEST JAN 83, OPERATES WITH A COMPLICATED <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization>
ADMINISTRATION, CONSISTING OF A CHIEF ADMINISTRATOR PRESIDING OVER A <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND A <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY DIRECTORATE</Organization>, <Organization>EACH</Organization> WITH A <Organization>LIBRARY BOARD</Organization>. <Organization>SOME</Organization>
LARGE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> UNDER A <Organization>DIFFERENT MINISTRY</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
MINISTRY OF CULTURE, WILL REMAIN OUTSIDE THE <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> CONTROL, <Organization>ALTHOUGH</Organization> <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
DEVELOPMENT <Organization>PLANNING</Organization> FOR <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS TO BE CENTRALLY
ADMINISTERED. THERE WILL BE NO <Organization>DIRECT STATE FINANCIAL</Organization> SUPPORT FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>SOME</Organization> SPECIFIED <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> WILL RECEIVE
STATE GRANTS. THE JOINT APPROPRIATION IS TO REMAIN AND WILL INCLUDE THE
<Organization>PRESENT DISPENSATION FUND</Organization>. DATES ARE SET FOR THE INTRODUCTION OF FULL TIME
SERVICE AND OF MUSICAL MATERIAL IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5694
IN CONVERSATION WITH THE MINISTER FOR CULTURE, <Organization>RECREATION</Organization> AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> AFFAIRS,
HANS DE BOER.

<Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF AN INTERVIEW WITH HANS DE BOER, MINISTER FOR CULTURE, <Organization>RECREATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>SOCIAL AFFAIRS</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>. DE BOER FIRMLY SUPPORTS THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
SERVICES <Organization>ACT</Organization> WHICH WILL DECENTRALISE RUNNING OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization>
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> LEVEL. DE BOER BELIEVES
THAT INVOLVEMENT OF THE <Organization>LOCAL COMMUNITY</Organization> IN THE RUNNING OF <Organization>THESE SERVICES</Organization> IS
THE BEST GUARANTEE FOR <Organization>IMPROVING</Organization> THE QUALITY OF THE SERVICE. PLANS FOR
EXTENDING THE <Organization>AGE</Organization> LIMIT FOR <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MEMBERSHIP <Organization>FROM</Organization> 16 TO 18 YEARS
OF <Organization>AGE</Organization> HAVE BEEN ABANDONED BY DE BOER BECAUSE OF FINANCIAL CUTBACKS IN
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> SUPPORT. THE ALTERNATIVE, DE BOER BELIEVES, <Organization>WOULD</Organization> HAVE BEEN A
REDUCTION IN THE STANDARD OF SERVICE.
********************************************
Document 5695
<Organization>ON</Organization> THE 10TH ANNIVERSARY OF <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> BIBLIOTHEEK EN LEKTUUR CENTRUM
(<Organization>DUTCH CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>)&apos; THE CHAIRMAN&apos;S TURN TO SPEAK
(PART) 2.

<Organization>TEXT</Organization> OF AN INTERVIEW WITH DR. J.J. POSTMA, CHAIRMAN OF THE NBLC <Organization>ON</Organization> THE 10TH
ANNIVERSARY OF THE FOUNDING OF THE CENTRE. POSTMA BELIEVES THAT LIBRARIANS IN
<Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location> SHOULD NOW COME TO TERMS WITH THE <Organization>NEW PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>,
WHICH WILL REPLACE THE <Organization>EXISTING</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization>. BY REFUSING TO ACCEPT
THE <Organization>ACT</Organization> LIBRARIANS ARE IN DANGER OF BEING LEFT OUT IN THE COLD. IN POSTMA&apos;S
VIEW THE DANGER OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> LIES IN THE DEVOLUTION OF RESPONSIBILITY FOR
THE <Organization>PUBLIC SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> TO <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization>. IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> AUTHORITIES, HE ADDS, TOWN FESTIVALS MAY RECEIVE
GREATER PRIORITY THAN THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. THE NBLC MUST CONVINCE THE
<Organization>GOVERNMENT</Organization> OF THE NEED FOR AN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ACT</Organization> WHICH INCLUDES THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>. (FOR AN ABSTRACT OF PART 1, 2SEE1 82/5007).
********************************************
Document 5696
<Organization>LIBRARY-INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> EVALUATION&apos; A <Organization>CASE-HISTORY FROM PHARMACEUTICAL</Organization> R
AND D.

DESCRIBES A 19-WEEK PROJECT TO EXAMINE AND EVALUATE THE <Organization>LIBRARY-INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICE <Organization>AT SYNTEX RESEARCH CENTRE</Organization>, RICCARTON, <Location>EDINBURGH</Location>, A PHARMACEUTICAL R
AND <Organization>D CENTRE</Organization>. AREAS LOOKED <Organization>AT</Organization> WERE&apos; <Organization>STOCK-USE RECORDS</Organization>; INTERLOAN REQUESTS; <Organization>USE</Organization>
OF <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> TIME AND THE <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> AWARENESS BULLETIN. 36 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS,
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> SCIENTISTS, WERE INTERVIEWED, AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>DEMAND</Organization> FOR <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES IS DESCRIBED. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE VALIDITY OF INDIVIDUAL
<Organization>LIBRARY-INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> EVALUATION TESTS AND PROBLEMS AND ATTRACTIONS OF
EVALUATING A <Organization>COMPLETE LIBRARY-INFORMATION SERVICE</Organization> &apos;IN THE ROUND&apos;.
********************************************
Document 5697
STUDIES IN <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization> VOLUME SEVEN.

COLLECTED PAPERS <Organization>ON</Organization> VARIOUS ASPECTS OF <Organization>LIBRARY MANAGEMENT</Organization> DIVIDED INTO 3 MAIN
SECTIONS&apos; (1) INCLUDES A NUMBER OF <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> TOPICS, AUTHORITATIVELY TREATED; (2)
INCLUDES STUDIES OF THE &apos;VALUE&apos; OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND OF <Organization>NEW TECHNOLOGY</Organization> IN
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; AND (3) PRESENTS MORE SPECIALISED STUDIES OF INTEREST TO LIBRARIANS
AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOL STUDENTS.
********************************************
Document 5698
<Organization>MANAGING MULTISITE POLYTECHNIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.

OUTLINES MANAGERIAL PROBLEMS COMMON TO MULTISITE <Organization>POLYTECHNIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
<Organization>THESE TIMES</Organization> OF ECONOMIC STRINGENCY. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>&apos; STYLES OF MANAGEMENT;
ALLOCATION OF RESOURCES; RATIONALISATION OF SYSTEMS; <Organization>STAFF</Organization> ALLOCATION;
MANAGEMENT OF GROWTH; <Organization>STAFF DEVELOPMENT</Organization>; AND <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> PROBLEMS.
********************************************
Document 5699
DISCUSSION AND <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> FOR <Organization>STAFF</Organization> IN THE HOOGEVEEN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.

IN 1971 A SCHEME OF WORKER <Organization>PARTICIPATION</Organization> WAS INTRODUCED <Organization>AT</Organization> HOOGEVEEN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>THE NETHERLANDS</Location>. <Organization>PREVIOUSLY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MEETINGS WERE RESTRICTED TO
ADMINISTRATIVE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> ONLY. UNDER THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>WEEKLY</Organization> MEETINGS WERE HELD <Organization>AT</Organization>
WHICH THE CHIEF LIBRARIAN AND HEADS OF THE ADULT AND CHILDREN&apos;S DEPARTMENTS
WERE <Organization>PRESENT</Organization>. REPORTS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> MEETINGS WERE CIRCULATED TO <Organization>ALL</Organization> HEADS OF
DEPARTMENTS. IN 1975 FOLLOWING THE OPENING OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> WAS REORGANISED INTO 8 DEPARTMENTS AND A <Organization>NEW</Organization> STRUCTURE OF
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> MEETINGS WAS INTRODUCED. IN ADDITION TO THE MEETINGS ATTENDED BY
ADMINISTRATIVE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND HEADS OF DEPARTMENTS, <Organization>ALL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF THE INTERNAL
SERVICES MEET EVERY 3 WEEKS, WHILE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> OF THE <Organization>EXTERNAL SERVICES</Organization> MEET <Organization>EACH</Organization>
WEEK. THE PURPOSE OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> MEETINGS IS TO IMPROVE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> MOTIVATION AND THEREBY
THE QUALITY OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S SERVICES.
********************************************
Document 5700
CENTRALISATION AND DECENTRALISATION&apos; ONE POINT OF VIEW.

EXAMINES THE DEBATE <Organization>ON</Organization> CENTRALISATION AND DECENTRALISATION IN RELATION TO&apos; THE
HISTORICAL ASPECTS, SHOWING HOW IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> THE <Organization>LATIN AMERICAN UNIVERSITY</Organization>
<Organization>SYSTEM</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>PRESENT</Organization> DEVELOPED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE ORIGINAL <Organization>EUROPEAN</Organization> PATTERN; THE
INSTITUTIONAL ASPECTS, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THE NECESSITY FOR UNIVERSITIES TO FULFIL <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
RESPONSIBILITIES DICTATES ADMINISTRATIVE STRUCTURES, IN TURN GOVERNING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ORGANISATION; THE TECHNICAL-ADMINISTRATIVE ASPECTS, OUTLINING THE ESSENTIAL
CHARACTERISTICS OF <Organization>CENTRALISED</Organization>, PARTIALLY DECENTRALISED, AND DECENTRALISED
SYSTEMS; AND GEOGRAPHICAL FACTORS. <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> LEADS TO THE CONCLUSION THAT
THE PARTICULAR CIRCUMSTANCES OF <Organization>EACH</Organization> PARTICULAR CASE SHOULD DETERMINE
ADMINISTRATIVE AND ORGANISATIONAL STRUCTURES.
********************************************
Document 5701
THE <Organization>METHODOLOGICAL CENTRE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION SERVICES</Organization> OF THE MINISTRY FOR UNIVERSITY AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> COLLEGE
AFFAIRS.

THE CENTRE ASSISTS IN THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>CENTRAL</Organization> SUBJECT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND SUBJECT
NETWORKS AND PROMOTES THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> CENTRES IN <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location>. GIVES ESTIMATES AND OPINIONS <Organization>ON</Organization>
INVESTMENT PROJECTS, DRAFT VERSIONS OF NEW REGULATIONS, ORGANISATIONAL
GUIDELINES; STANDARDS AND STATISTICS ARE <Organization>ALSO</Organization> <Organization>PRODUCED</Organization>. THE MAIN <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> PROJECTS INCLUDE&apos; A CLASSIFICATION FOR SUBJECT <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> IN
ACADEMIC <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>; THE <Organization>FURTHER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> OF <Organization>ELECTRONIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>PROCESSING</Organization> FOR
<Organization>USE</Organization> IN <Organization>LOAN SYSTEMS</Organization>, <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES; THE EXPANSION OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> WORK IN UNIVERSITIES; THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF FOREIGN
<Organization>MAGNETIC TAPE SERVICES</Organization>. THE CENTRE REPRESENTS <Location>EAST GERMANY</Location> IN THE WORK OF THE
INTERNATIONAL CENTRE FOR SCIENTIFIC AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN <Location>MOSCOW</Location>.
********************************************
Document 5702
ADVISORY BODIES IN LIBRARIANSHIP AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EFFECTIVENESS.

ADVISORY BODIES AND COMMITTEES DEALING WITH LIBRARIANSHIP IN <Location>SLOVAKIA</Location> ARE
LISTED. AMONG THE PROBLEMS TACKLED ARE NOT ONLY <Organization>CATALOGUING</Organization>, BIBLIOGRAPHY AND
PRESERVATION OF BOOK COLLECTIONS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> <Organization>ALSO</Organization> STANDARDISATION, <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> AND
STATISTICS IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, <Organization>AS WELL AS CONTINUING EDUCATION</Organization> OF LIBRARIANS.
SPECIAL COMMITTEES ATTEND TO THE RUNNING OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND
<Organization>ALSO</Organization> TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>. THE ENTIRE NETWORK IS HEADED BY THE
<Organization>SLOVAK LIBRARY COUNCIL</Organization> ESTABLISHED IN THE 1950S. THE MAIN OBJECTIVE OF THE
COUNCIL&apos;S ANNUAL PLANS IS TO MEET THE TARGETS SET BY THE <Organization>SLOVAK MINISTRY</Organization> OF
CULTURE. FOLLOWING A CAREFUL AND THOROUGH EXAMINATION IN THE COURSE OF THE
<Organization>CURRENT</Organization> 5 YEAR PLAN (1981-85), MEASURES WILL BE TAKEN TO ENSURE UNIFICATION OF
<Organization>ALL</Organization> ADVISORY <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> AND TO INCREASE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> IMPACT <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5703
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK AMONG ADULTS.

CONTRIBUTION TO AN <Organization>ISSUE</Organization> DEVOTED TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location>. A
COUNTRY WITH A RICH PUBLICATION OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> SHOULD <Organization>ALSO</Organization> HAVE
WELL-APPOINTED AND FLOURISHING CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE
EXISTED IN <Location>SWEDEN</Location> FOR 70 YEARS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> NOT UNTIL THE 1970S, WITH GREAT
<Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> REFORMS, WAS PRIORITY ACCORDED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization> FOR CHILDREN.
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE LATE 1970S, <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONSULTANTS&apos; POSTS HAVE BEEN ESTABLISHED <Organization>AT</Organization>
ALMOST <Organization>ALL</Organization> THE COUNTY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. DESCRIBES THE CONSULTANT&apos;S ROLE IN RELATION
TO THAT OF OTHERS CONCERNED WITH CHILD WELFARE.
********************************************
Document 5704
ZZZZ.

IN BOTH <Location>NORWAY</Location> AND SWEDEN, COMMITTEES HAVE BEEN APPOINTED TO LOOK INTO THE
FINANCING OF SERVICES IN <Organization>PUBLICLY FUNDED UNIVERSITY</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> A MEETING IN <Location>OSLO</Location> <Location>IN</Location> FEB 81, <Organization>AT</Organization> WHICH THE SECRETARY OF THE <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>
COMMITTEE TALKED ABOUT THAT COMMITTEE&apos;S <Organization>ACTIVITIES</Organization>, AND ARGUED THE CASE BOTH
FOR AND AGAINST CHARGING THE <Organization>USER</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 5705
STUDIES IN CREATIVE PARTNERSHIP. FEDERAL <Organization>AID</Organization> TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> DURING THE
<Organization>NEW</Organization> DEAL.

7 ARTICLES EXAMINING THE ACCOMPLISHMENTS OF THE <Location>US</Location> WORK PROJECTS
ADMINISTRATION (W.P.A., CREATED IN 1935 AS THE WORK <Organization>PROGRESS ADMINISTRATION</Organization>)
DURING THE 2ND &amp;H OF THE GREAT DEPRESSION: &apos;ALMOST A BOON...&apos; FEDERAL RELIEF
PROGRAMS AND THE ENOCH PRATT <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, 1933-1943, BY JOHN CALVIN COLSON;
THE <Location>CLEVELAND</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE W.P.A.&apos; A <Organization>STUDY</Organization> IN CREATIVE PARTNERSHIP,
BY DANIEL F. RING; THE <Location>CHICAGO</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> W.P.A. OMNIBUS PROJECT, BY ALEX
LADENSON; THE W.P.A. AND THE <Location>NEW YORK</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BY MARGOT KARP AND RHODA
GAROOGIAN; THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> DEAL WORK PROJECTS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Location>MILWAUKEE</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BY
DANIEL F. RING; THE <Location>MINNEAPOLIS</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE W.P.A. EXPERIENCE&apos;
COLLABORATION FOR COMMUNITY NEED, BY JOHN FRANKLIN WHITE; AND THE W.P.A. AND
<Location>SAN FRANCISCO</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, BY FAY M. BLAKE.
********************************************
Document 5706
<Organization>ALL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> SHOULD BE <Organization>FREE</Organization> OF CHARGE.
