Document 4501
SIMULATION IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>. A <Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A WORKSHOP AND SUBSEQUENT VISITS
TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SCHOOLS <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>EASTERN</Organization> SEABOARD OF THE <Location>USA</Location>.
     
THE DEGREE TO WHICH SIMULATIONS, ROLE-PLAY, CASE STUDIES AND <Organization>SIMILAR</Organization> EXERCISES
ARE <Organization>USED</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization> IN THE <Location>USA</Location> WAS INVESTIGATED WITH THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF
ASSESSING THE NEED FOR <Organization>SUCH</Organization> TECHNIQUES IN THE <Location>UK</Location>.
********************************************
Document 4502
<Location>GREENOCK</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; A DEVELOPMENT AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> 1635-1967.
     
<Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>GREENOCK</Location>, SCOTLAND, <Organization>FROM</Organization>
1635-1967, RELATING THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE LOCALITY TO THE DEVELOPMENT AND
INCREASING <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> OF ALL TYPES.
********************************************
Document 4503
<Location>INDIA</Location>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE WAITING.
     
OUTLINES THE PRESENT UNSTABLE POLITICAL AND ECONOMIC SITUATION IN <Location>INDIA</Location>. ONLY
5 STATES HAVE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LAWS, OPERATING WITH <Organization>INTEGRATED LIBRARY SYSTEMS</Organization>. THE
LAWS ARE, HOWEVER, WEAK AND <Organization>FINANCING</Organization> OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> INADEQUATE. <Organization>AT UNION</Organization> LEVEL,
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> LEGISLATION WAS THE <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> OF A COMMITTEE PROPOSAL PUT FORWARD IN
1964, <Organization>BUT</Organization> WITH LACK OF INTEREST AMONG THE <Organization>AUTHORITIES</Organization>, NO ACTION HAS BEEN
TAKEN YET. IN THE MEANTIME, <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FACE CHALLENGES <Organization>FROM</Organization> INCREASING NUMBERS
OF USERS, THE NEWLY LITERATE AND STUDENTS. THERE ARE MANY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TYPES; APART
<Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>CALCUTTA</Location>, THERE ARE STATE CENTRAL, DISTRICT,
BLOCK, VILLAGE, MOBILE, UNIVERSITY, COLLEGE AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF
VARIOUS <Organization>ASSOCIATIONS</Organization> AND SUBSCRIPTION <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE NUMEROUS. <Organization>BUT</Organization> THE NEED FOR
<Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>, AND PERHAPS A SUCCESSOR TO THE <Organization>DYNAMIC</Organization> S.R. RANGANATHAN, IS GREAT.
********************************************
Document 4504
<Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS REFLECTED IN THE <Organization>GERMAN DAILY PRESS</Organization>.
     
A CONTENT ANALYSIS OF REFERENCES TO <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE WEST <Organization>GERMAN</Organization>
<Organization>DAILY PRESS</Organization> REVEALS THAT ASPECTS <Organization>OTHER</Organization> THEN THE SUBSTANTIAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> CONCERNS
DOMINATE. A GREATER INTEREST IN ISSUES DEALING WITH THE <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
CONSERVATION CONSISTENTLY OVERSHADOWS PROBLEMS <Organization>ASSOCIATED</Organization> WITH THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. CORRESPONDING TO <Organization>THIS</Organization> ACCENTUATION AN UNCRITICAL SATISFACTION WITH
THE WORK OF <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> PREVAILS. IN ADDITION TO THE
SYSTEMATICAL SCOPE OF THE CONTENT ANALYSIS OF 326 NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
INVESTIGATED A <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> TEXT IS PRESENTED AND INTERPRETED.
********************************************
Document 4505
<Organization>AMERICAN EDUCATION</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> STUDY/<Organization>TRAINING</Organization> <Organization>DEBATE</Organization>.
     
AS LATE AS 1899, NO MORE THAN 1/3 OF THE TEACHERS IN MASSACHUSETTS HAD BEEN
EXPOSED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FACILITIES IN A <Organization>NORMAL SCHOOL</Organization>. DURING THE EARLY 20<Organization>TH</Organization>
CENTURY, A CHANGE TOOK PLACE WHICH <Organization>AFFECTED TEACHER EDUCATION</Organization> AS MUCH AS IT
DID <Organization>OTHER</Organization> DISCIPLINES. EDUCATION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COLLECTIONS <Organization>DEVELOPED</Organization>, EDUCATION
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> EXPANDED TO MEET A GROWING DEMAND. EDUCATION LIBRARIANS BEGAN
TO HOLD <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> MEETINGS AND TO <Organization>DEBATE</Organization> QUESTIONS OF STANDARDS, BOTH
<Organization>QUANTITATIVE</Organization> AND QUALITATIVE. THROUGHOUT <Organization>ITS</Organization> BRIEF <Organization>HISTORY</Organization>, EDUCATION
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN CAUGHT <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE PUSH FOR THE <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization>
STUDY OF EDUCATION AND THE PULL FOR THE PRACTICAL <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> OF TEACHERS.
********************************************
Document 4506
AVAILABILITY OF <Organization>VETERINARY</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN THE <Organization>VETERINARY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, MEMBERS OF
THE <Organization>VETERINARY</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> SECTION/<Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>, FOR <Location>LATIN AMERICA</Location>.
     
A PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 1981 INTERAMERICAN CONFERENCE OF <Organization>AGRICULTURAL</Organization>
LIBRARIANS AND DOCUMENTALISTS DESCRIBING THE ACTIVITIES OF THE <Organization>VETERINARY</Organization>
<Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> SECTION OF THE <Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> (<Organization>VMS</Organization>/<Organization>MLA</Organization>) WITH A VIEW TO
<Organization>INITIATING COOPERATIVE</Organization> PROJECTS WITH LATIN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>VETERINARY</Organization> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
INSTITUTIONS. <Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization> FOR <Organization>NORTH</Organization> <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>VETERINARY</Organization> USERS ARE
ORIENTED TOWARDS THE BIOMEDICAL <Organization>FIELD</Organization>. <Organization>VMS</Organization> REQUIRES DETAILED KNOWLEDGE <Organization>ABOUT</Organization>
THE NEEDS OF LATIN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> USERS TO PROVIDE <Organization>SPECIAL SERVICES</Organization>, PROBABLY IN THE
ANIMAL HUSBANDRY AND <Organization>INDUSTRY</Organization> FIELDS. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>HOW</Organization> <Organization>VMS</Organization> OPERATES THROUGH
COMMITTEES TO ORGANISE COOPERATIVE ACTIVITIES TO MAXIMISE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>
AMONG MEMBER <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. DETAILS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> OF THE SERVICES AVAILABLE, AND AN
INVITATION EXTENDED TO LATIN <Organization>AMERICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>FIELD</Organization> TO SHARE THE
HUMAN AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> RES OURCES THAT <Organization>VMS</Organization> PROVIDES.
********************************************
Document 4507
<Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ASSOCIATIONS</Organization> WORLDWIDE&apos; <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
     
(PAPER PRESENTED TO THE <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SECTION <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization> CONFERENCE, <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>,
AUG 81.) THE WORLDWIDE COMPASS OF THE VISUAL ARTS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> PARALLEL
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> BRINGS WITH IT THE NECESSITY FOR A WORLDWIDE NETWORK OF
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>RETRIEVAL</Organization>, <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> AND ORGANISATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
<Organization>THIS</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> COMMITMENT TO MATERIAL AND READERS, GIVES <Organization>ART</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> DISTINCTION-ONE WHICH, WITHIN <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>ORGANISATIONS</Organization> AND
WITHIN <Organization>IFLA</Organization>, HAS BEEN CONTINUOUSLY <Organization>DEVELOPED</Organization> AND SHARED OVER THE YEARS. A
PARTICULAR DUTY OF THE <Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> NOW MUST BE TO HELP PRESERVE THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
AND <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> QUALITIES OF <Organization>ART</Organization> AND LIFE WITHIN THE FRAMEWORK OF THE
INTERNATIONAL SCENE.
********************************************
Document 4508
<Organization>ART</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>IFLA</Organization> SECTION.
     
A <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization> OF THE <Organization>EVOLUTION</Organization> OF INTEREST IN COOPERATION AND NETWORK ACTIVITY
AMONG <Organization>ART</Organization> LIBRARIANS, LEADING TO THE CREATION OF A <Organization>NEW INTERNATIONAL GROUP</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization>
THE 1981 <Organization>IFLA</Organization> CONFERENCE <Organization>AT</Organization> LEIPZIG, COMPRISING 15 MEMBERS <Organization>FROM</Organization> 11 COUNTRIES.
DETAILS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> OF <Organization>EARLIER INITIATIVES AT VARIOUS INTERNATIONAL</Organization> CONFERENCES,
AND THE ACTIVITIES OF NOTABLE <Organization>PERSONNEL</Organization>, INVOLVED IN THE PRODUCTION OF
DIRECTORIES, BIBLIOGRAPHIES AND PERIODICAL LISTS. THE PROGRESSIVELY INCREASING
INTEREST <Organization>AT</Organization> PREVIOUS <Organization>IFLA</Organization> CONFERENCES IS DOCUMENTED WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO PAPERS
PRESENTED AND RESOLUTIONS PASSED, AND THE CREATION OF VARIOUS <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization>
<Organization>ASSOCIATIONS</Organization> RECORDED. FINALLY DETAILS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> OF THE ORGANISATION OF THE
NEW SECTION, ACTIVITIES CARRIED <Organization>OUT AT ITS FOUNDATION</Organization>, AND PROJECTS FOR THE
<Organization>FUTURE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4509
THE <Organization>JENA LITERARY MUSEUM</Organization> 1816-1919.
     
THE MUSEUM WAS ADMINISTERED BY A GROUP OF MEMBERS WITH LITERARY AND <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization>
INTERESTS WHO WISHED TO OBTAIN <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> POLITICAL AND TOPICAL MATTERS
OUTSIDE <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK. THE BUILDING UP OF A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> PERIODICAL <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>
FORESHADOWED A <Organization>MODERN</Organization> TREND. STOCKS WERE <Organization>ACQUIRED THROUGH COOPERATIVE</Organization>
AGREEMENTS WITH&apos; THE GRAND <Organization>DUKE</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Organization>WEIMAR</Organization>; JENA UNIVERSITY LIBRARY,
FOR WHICH THE MUSEUM BECAME A READING-ROOM UNTIL 1915; THE <Organization>WEIMAR BOOK MUSEUM</Organization>;
THE <Organization>CARL ZEISS FOUNDATION</Organization>. MANY PRIVATE MEMBERS ALSO DONATED <Organization>THEIR</Organization> JOURNALS TO
THE MUSEUM. WHEN THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> ROOM OPENED IN JENA IN 1896, REFLECTING
THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> AND POLITICAL THOUGHT, IT FLOURISHED; THE MUSEUM,
IN CONTRAST, WISHED TO REMAIN THE PRESERVE OF A WELL-EDUCATED, FEE-PAYING
MINORITY AND THUS <Organization>RESTRICTED ITS OWN DEVELOPMENT</Organization>. ULTIMATELY THE MUSEUM BECAME
PART OF THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4510
ICAM AND <Organization>ARCHITECTURAL</Organization> RECORDS.
     
<Organization>REPORT</Organization> OF THE 2ND CONFERENCE OF THE INTERNATIONAL CONFEDERATION OF
<Organization>ARCHITECTURAL</Organization> MUSEUMS (ICAM), <Location>LONDON</Location>, 26-30 APR 81. AN INCREASING <Organization>AWARENESS</Organization> OF
THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>ARCHITECTURAL RECORDS</Organization> AND <Organization>CONCERN</Organization> <Organization>ABOUT THEIR ACQUISITION</Organization>,
CONTROL, CONSERVATION AND EXHIBITION WAS <Organization>MADE</Organization> EVIDENT <Organization>AT</Organization> THE CONFERENCE, WHICH
WAS ATTENDED BY REPRESENTATIVES OF 16 COUNTRIES.
********************************************
Document 4511
<Organization>ARMY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLE.
     
SURVEYS THE ROLE OF POLISH <Organization>ARMY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WHICH DATA <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1765 TO THE PRESENT
<Organization>DAY</Organization>. THE CENTRALNA BIBLIOTEKA WOJSKOWA (CENTRAL <Organization>ARMY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>) AND THE
BIBLIOTEKA NAUKOWA SZTABA GENERALNEGA (<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>) AND
THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization> MAIN <Organization>ARMY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE DESCRIBED. <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ROLES VARY <Organization>BUT</Organization> COVER THE
FOLLOWING NEEDS&apos; <Organization>ARMY</Organization> NEEDS, DISPLAY, <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, SOCIO-POLITICAL
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, <Organization>MEDICAL DATA</Organization>, <Organization>NAVAL DATA</Organization> AND <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF WAR. THE NEED TO <Organization>COLLECT</Organization>,
CONSERVE AND <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> IN BOOKS, PERIODICALS AND <Organization>ON</Organization> FILM IS
STRESSED.
********************************************
Document 4512
THE CHANGING FACE OF THE BRITISH COUNCIL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos; A CASE STUDY.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE ORIGIN OF BRITISH COUNCIL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>INDIA</Location> AND <Organization>HOW</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
IN <Location>DELHI</Location> STARTED IN THE HEART OF THE <Location>CITY</Location>. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> IN DETAIL THE PROBLEMS
FACED IN RENOVATION WORK AND UTILISATION OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> ADDITIONAL SPACE <Organization>MADE</Organization>
AVAILABLE IN 1967 (AFTER 20 YEARS) AND FINALLY THE TASK OF DESIGNING AND
MOVING THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE 2ND FLOOR TO THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> FLOOR OF THE <Organization>SAME</Organization> <Organization>OLD</Organization>
BUILDING IN 1979 <Organization>AT</Organization> VERY SHORT NOTICE WITH MINIMUM PERIOD OF CLOSURE OF THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>. <Organization>DEALS</Organization> IN DETAIL WITH THE <Organization>LAY</Organization> <Organization>OUT</Organization> PLANS OF THE EXPANSION
WORK IN 1976 AND THE COMPLETE PLAN OF THE REDESIGNED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN 1979 <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
1<Organization>ST</Organization> FLOOR WITH ALL FITTINGS, FIXTURES FURNITURE, ETC.
********************************************
Document 4513
<Organization>FROM</Organization> BESTIARIES TO BUS TICKETS. FOUR HUNDRED YEARS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BODLEIAN.
     
A SHORT INTERVIEW WITH JULIAN ROBERTS, KEEPER OF PRINTED BOOKS <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BODLEIAN
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, OXFORD.
********************************************
Document 4514
THE AUSTRIAN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
     
PAPER PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> AUSTRIAN-SOVIET <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE ROLE OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
A COUNTRY&apos;S SOCIO-ECONOMIC AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> LIFE, <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE LENIN STATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>,
20-22 MAR 79. AFTER AN OUTLINE OF THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE OSTERREICHISCHE
NATIONALBIBLIOTHEK (AUSTRIAN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>) <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> FUNCTION AND
PRESENT ORGANISATIONAL STRUCTURE. DESIGNATED THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN THE 1920S
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS ALSO THE CENTRE FOR FOREIGN MATERIALS IN HUMANITIES. THE MAIN
DUTIES OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARE&apos; <Organization>SYSTEMATIC ACQUISITION</Organization> OF MATERIALS, ADMINISTRATION
OF <Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> LOANS, COMPILATION OF THE AUSTRIAN <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> BIBLIOGRAPHY, THE
AUSTRIAN PUBLICATIONS <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> (AUSTRIATICA), CONVERSION OF THE AUTHOR
<Organization>CATALOGUE INTO INTERNATIONAL</Organization> FORMAT, <Organization>RETROSPECTIVE</Organization> <Organization>INDEXING</Organization>, <Organization>READER SERVICES</Organization>
<Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> EXHIBITIONS, PARTICIPATION IN INTERNATIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ACTIVITIES AND A
ROLE IN <Organization>LIBRARY EDUCATION</Organization>. <Organization>THESE</Organization> TASKS ARE CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> BY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S 9
DEPARTMENTS WHOSE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> CHARACTERISTICS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4515
FIRST SWEDISH-SOVIET <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> &apos;THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITHIN A COUNTRY&apos;S
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES&apos; DEVELOPMENT PROSPECTS&apos; (<Location>MOSCOW</Location>, 21-22
NOVEMBER 1978).
     
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> SECTION DEVOTED TO PAPERS PRESENTED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> SWEDISH-SOVIET <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization>
<Organization>ON</Organization> &apos;THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITHIN A COUNTRY&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES&apos;
DEVELOPMENT PROSPECTS&apos; <Organization>HELD</Organization> IN <Location>MOSCOW</Location>, 21-22 NOV 78, FOR ABSTRACTS OF WHICH
2SEE1 THE FOLLOWING <Organization>SERIAL</Organization> NUMBERS&apos;-.
********************************************
Document 4516
BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY LENDING DIVISION</Organization> (IN <Organization>SWEDISH</Organization>).
     
THE BLLD WAS FORMED IN 1973 THROUGH THE AMALGAMATION OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> CENTRAL
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR <Organization>SCIENCE</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGY. THE <Organization>AIM</Organization>
IS THAT ALMOST ALL ORDERS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHALL BE FULFILLED <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>OWN</Organization> STOCK AND PROCESSED THE <Organization>SAME</Organization> <Organization>DAY</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization> NECESSITATES A
<Organization>COMPREHENSIVE ACQUISITION</Organization> POLICY, <Organization>EFFICIENT</Organization> WORK ROUTINES, AND CENTRAL
LOCATION, <Organization>AT BOSTON SPA</Organization>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> GIFT &amp; EXCHANGE SECTION SERVES A USEFUL FUNCTION
AS DEPOSIT FOR WITHDRAWN MATERIAL <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. A MUSIC <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> IS
BEING BUILT UP. THE <Organization>LARGEST</Organization> DEPARTMENTS ARE THOSE FOR <Organization>SERIALS</Organization> AND BOOKS, AND
TOTAL STOCK COMPRISES 4 MILLION VOLUMES AND 2.5 MILLION DOCUMENTS OR FICHES.
ALL PERIODICALS, <Organization>BUT</Organization> MAINLY ENGLISH LANGUAGE MONOGRAPHS ONLY, ARE <Organization>ACQUIRED</Organization>.
<Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ATTENTION IS <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> TO COVERAGE OF RUSSIAN <Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization>
PUBLICATIONS. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE SELECTION METHODS. THE ROUTINES ARE SIMPLE AND FEW
OF THE <Organization>STAFF HAVE HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>, EMPHASIS BEI NG <Organization>ON</Organization> ADMINISTRATIVE SKILLS.
THE SERVICES PAY FOR THEMSELVES OVERALL AND THE BUDGET IS GENEROUS. <Organization>USE</Organization> OF
BACK-UP <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS <Organization>MADE</Organization>, MOSTLY THE LEGAL DEPOSIT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. VARIOUS
CATALOGUES ARE AVAILABLE, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE UNION <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization> OF BOOKS LISTING THE
HOLDINGS OF BLLD AND <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4517
THE FUNCTION OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN SOCIETY.
     
<Organization>AGAINST</Organization> THE BACKGROUND OF AN ANALYSIS OF FIRSTLY, THE NEED FOR AND FUNCTIONS
OF <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> IN SOCIETY; SECONDLY, THE FUNCTIONS OF THE RECORD AS A MEANS
OF <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization>; AND THIRDLY, THE ROLE OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS AN AGENT OF
<Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> IN ACTIVATING THE RECORD, THE <Organization>ESSENTIAL</Organization> FUNCTIONS OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARE STATED AS THE ADVANCEMENT OF CULTURE, THE <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF USEFUL
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, AND RECREATION. THEN THE QUESTION IS CONSIDERED WHETHER THE
<Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF RECREATIONAL MATERIALS 2PER <Organization>SE</Organization>1 SHOULD BE A FUNCTION OF THE
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND WHETHER THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS NOT WEAKENING <Organization>ITS</Organization> POSITION IN
SOCIETY BY PROVIDING RECREATIONAL <Organization>READING</Organization> MATERIALS <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>LARGE</Organization> SCALE, THUS
COMPETING WITH COMMERCIAL SOURCES OF RECREATION.
********************************************
Document 4518
DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN WEST SUSSEX 1981-1990.
     
THE <Organization>AIM</Organization> OF THE STUDY WAS TO EXAMINE THE POLICIES AND PRIORITIES OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE IN WEST SUSSEX IN THE LIGHT OF BOTH <Organization>CURRENT</Organization> AND POSSIBLE <Organization>FUTURE</Organization>
LEGISLATION; TO EXAMINE THE BALANCE OF THE SERVICE PROVIDED AND THE EFFECTS OF
INCREASING POPULATION IN THE <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> AND TO RECOMMEND A <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> STRATEGY, FOR
1981-1990, TO MEET THE PRIORITY NEEDS OF THE <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization> IN WEST SUSSEX WITHIN <Organization>SUCH</Organization>
FINANCIAL CONSTRAINTS AS MAY EXIST.
********************************************
Document 4519
<Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> COMPARISONS AND THE CIFC.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE BACKGROUND TO, AND THE PROGRESS <Organization>MADE</Organization> <Organization>SO</Organization> FAR BY THE STUDY OF
<Organization>INTERLIBRARY</Organization> COMPARISONS UNDERTAKEN BY THE CENTRE FOR INTERFIRM COMPARISON
(CIFC) AND THE BRITISH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. EXAMINES THE FOLLOWING ASPECTS OF
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> ARISING <Organization>OUT</Organization> OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization> INCEPTION IN 1977 UP TO
LATE 1980&apos; THE THINKING TO BE DETECTED IN SUCCESSIVE DRAFTS OF RELEVANT
DOCUMENTS; THE DIMENSIONS OF BRITISH <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO BE DEDUCED <Organization>FROM</Organization>
DATA OBTAINED; AND THE CONCLUSIONS WHICH A <Organization>GIVEN AUTHORITY</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> DERIVE <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> COLLECTED.
********************************************
Document 4520
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>FRANCE</Location>. <Organization>ITS</Organization> ACTUAL SITUATION AND <Organization>FUTURE</Organization> PROSPECTS.
     
A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> AND CRITICAL <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> ARGUING THE URGENT NEED TO PROVIDE EQUAL
LEVELS OF SERVICE FOR BOTH URBAN AND RURAL USERS. IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> SEES
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AS <Organization>OUT</Organization> OF DATE, UNDER-RESOURCED, AND UNATTRACTIVE, AND IS LARGELY
UNAWARE OF RECENT <Organization>NEW</Organization> DEVELOPMENTS BECAUSE <Organization>THESE</Organization> ARE <Organization>RESTRICTED</Organization> TO A FEW
<Organization>CENTRES</Organization> OF EXCELLENCE. THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SHOULD PROVIDE <Organization>FREE</Organization> <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization>
SERVICES FOR ALL&apos; <Organization>DESCRIBES THESE SERVICES</Organization> IN DETAIL, AS THEY RELATE TO
<Organization>DOCUMENTATION</Organization> AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>, AND <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> ACTIVITIES. THE DIVISION OF
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> <Organization>INTO</Organization> URBAN AND RURAL STRUCTURES HAS RESULTED IN INADEQUATE
SERVICES FOR COUNTRY AREAS; INSTEAD, THE SYSTEM SHOULD BE REORGANISED <Organization>INTO</Organization> A
NETWORK PATTERN TO EQUALISE DISTRIBUTION OF <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>. CRITICISMS OF <Organization>MUNICIPAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, CENTRAL <Organization>LENDING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>FRENCH PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN
<Organization>GENERAL</Organization> ARE SUMMARISED IN AN APPENDED MEMORANDUM, AND <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> ILLUSTRATED BY
AN ANALYSIS OF THE ORGANISATION OF SERVICES IN THE CAMBRAI REGION.
********************************************
Document 4521
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND TECHNOLOGICAL PROGRESS IN <Organization>BULGARIAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
AFTER THE <Organization>SOCIALIST</Organization> REVOLUTION IN <Location>BULGARIA</Location> IN 1944, ALMOST 62% OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE ALLOCATED LARGER PREMISES. 5 OF THE CENTRAL <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
ESTABLISHED AS <Organization>SUCH</Organization> IN 1953, MOVED <Organization>INTO</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDINGS, <Organization>WHILE</Organization> 2 <Organization>OTHER</Organization> BUILDINGS
WERE ERECTED FOR <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>. IN SPITE OF <Organization>THESE</Organization>
IMPROVEMENTS, THERE IS <Organization>STILL</Organization> A CONSIDERABLE SHORTAGE OF SPACE IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>,
WHICH, IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>, ARE ALSO IN NEED OF MODERNISATION. REPROGRAPHIC EQUIPMENT,
COMPUTER APPLICATION AND <Organization>COMMUNICATION</Organization> TECHNOLOGY MUST NOT ONLY ENSURE <Organization>BETTER</Organization>
<Organization>LENDING SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> INTERLENDING, <Organization>BUT</Organization> ALSO <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
<Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> AS WELL AS A <Organization>WIDER</Organization> DISSEMINATION OF <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>. <Organization>LIKE</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
COUNTRIES, MOBILE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD CATER FOR HAMLETS AND <Organization>SMALL</Organization> COMMUNITIES OF
<Organization>SOME</Organization> 1,000 INHABITANTS, AND ALSO FOR URBAN POPULATIONS LIVING <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>NEW</Organization> HOUSING
ESTATES AND/OR IN <Organization>OTHER</Organization> AREAS TEMPORARILY WITHOUT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. PURPOSE-BUILT
BUILDINGS SHOULD BE ENVISAGED FOR E VERY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WITH 70,000 AND MORE VOLUMES.
DEPOSITORY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, BOTH <Organization>ON</Organization> A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> LEVEL, SHOULD ALSO BE
PLANNED TO STORE VALUABLE BOOKS AND RARELY REQUESTED BOOKS.
********************************************
Document 4522
FOCUS <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; ROBERTSON REGION.
     
BRIEFLY <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE REGION OF ROBERTSON, <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>, WHICH HAS 17 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND 6 DEPOTS.
********************************************
Document 4523
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>ONTARIO</Location>&apos; <Organization>STATISTICS</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> ENDING DEC 80.
     
<Organization>STATISTICS</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> ENDING 31 DEC 80 COMPILED BY THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND
COMMUNITY <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> BRANCH, <Organization>ONTARIO MINISTRY</Organization> OF CULTURE AND RECREATION.
FIGURES FOR 1980 ARE COMPARED WITH CORRESPONDING FIGURES FOR 1979.
********************************************
Document 4524
LENINIST PRINCIPLES IN <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>CUBA</Location>.
     
OUTLINES THE DEVELOPMENT OF <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN <Location>CUBA</Location> SINCE 1959. THE <Organization>MAJOR</Organization>
ACHIEVEMENT OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> PERIOD WAS THE ESTABLISHMENT OF THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
NETWORK WITH THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> JOSE MARTI <Organization>AT</Organization> THE HEAD. THE FUNCTION OF
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAS CHANGED <Organization>FROM</Organization> MERE COLLECTIONS OF BOOKS TO LIVING INSTITUTIONS
TAKING PART IN THE <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> DEVELOPMENT. <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> PLAY AN IMPORTANT ROLE IN THE LITERACY CAMPAIGN. <Organization>EXTENSION</Organization>
ACTIVITIES ARE AN IMPORTANT PART OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> WORK ESPECIALLY IN CHILDREN&apos;S
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>STATISTICAL DATA</Organization> ILLUSTRATE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> IN THE PAST 20 YEARS.
********************************************
Document 4525
DIAGNOSTIC ANALYSIS OF <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>LATIN AMERICA</Location> AND THE CARIBBEAN.
     
IN PREPARATION FOR THE 1982 <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> CONFERENCE, <Organization>IFLA</Organization>, <Organization>UNESCO</Organization>, IABN AND CERLAL
(THE <Organization>REGIONAL CENTRE</Organization> FOR <Organization>BOOK</Organization> PROMOTION IN <Location>LATIN AMERICA</Location> AND THE CARIBBEAN)
HAVE COLLABORATED IN PREPARING AND ADMINISTERING <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization>. THE
OBJECTIVES, LEVELS, AND SCOPE OF THE STUDY ARE DETAILED&apos; THE INTENTION IS TO
EFFECT A <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> INVESTIGATION OF THE ENTIRE SYSTEM THROUGHOUT THE AREA.
THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> VERSION OF THE <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> HAS ALREADY BEEN CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization> IN <Location>VENEZUELA</Location> AND
<Location>COLOMBIA</Location>, AND A 2ND VERSION IS UNDER <Organization>DISCUSSION</Organization>. THE IMPORTANCE OF FULL
PARTICIPATION <Organization>FROM</Organization> ALL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> RELEVANT INSTITUTIONS IS
EMPHASISED.
********************************************
Document 4526
STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN <Location>NEW ZEALAND</Location> 1980.
     
<Organization>STATISTICS</Organization> ARE PRESENTED WHICH RELATE TO <Organization>FINANCING</Organization> AND COST, BOOKS AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
MATERIALS, BUILDINGS, <Organization>LENDING</Organization> AND <Organization>OTHER</Organization> ACTIVITIES. <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization>
2STANDARDS FOR <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>1 (1973) AND 2INTERIM MINIMUM STANDARDS FOR
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>1 (<Organization>LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> OF <Location>AUSTRALIA</Location>, 1972).
********************************************
Document 4527
PEMBURY&apos; THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE COMMUNITY IT SERVES.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE SETTING UP OF THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> PEMBURY, KENT, <Location>UK</Location> AND A
COMMUNITY PROFILE PRIOR TO OPENING WITH A FOLLOW UP A <Organization>YEAR</Organization> LATER IN SEPT 79 TO
ASSESS THE IMPACT OF THE BRANCH <Organization>ON</Organization> THE COMMUNITY.
********************************************
Document 4528
INTAMEL-FAREWELL TO BUDAPEST.
     
IN A VERY <Organization>PERSONAL</Organization> VIEW <Organization>ON</Organization> THE MERITS OF INTAMEL (INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF
METROPOLITAN <Location>CITY</Location> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>), AN ORIGINAL <Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE INTAMEL MEETING
(<Location>BUDAPEST</Location>, 1981) IS PRESENTED BY THE PRESIDENT OF INTAMEL.
********************************************
Document 4529
THE ALLOA ACCOUNT.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN ALLOA IN SCOTLAND <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>ITS</Organization>
ESTABLISHMENT IN 1885 TO <Organization>ITS</Organization> AMALGAMATION WITH THE <Organization>COUNTY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN 1936.
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE TYPE OF BOOKS PURCHASED BY THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, AND PROVIDES <Organization>SOME</Organization>
<Organization>STATISTICS</Organization> COMPARING ALLOA&apos;S PERFORMANCE AS A <Organization>LIBRARY AUTHORITY</Organization> WITH THAT OF
<Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>SCOTTISH</Organization> BURGHS OF A <Organization>SIMILAR</Organization> SIZE IN 1935.
********************************************
Document 4530
THE DUMBARTON <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> 1881-1981.
     
DEPICTS THE <Organization>WAY</Organization> THE DUMBARTON <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE <Organization>DEVELOPED</Organization> DURING <Organization>THEIR</Organization> 1<Organization>ST</Organization>
100 YEARS. <Organization>FROM</Organization> HUMBLE BEGINNINGS IN THE <Organization>HIGH</Organization> STREET, THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> HAS
GROWN <Organization>INTO</Organization> A NETWORK OF BRANCH AND MOBILE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> THROUGHOUT THE DISTRICT.
********************************************
Document 4531
THE PRINCIPAL <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE NORTHERN REGION OF <Location>FRANCE</Location>.
     
A SERIES OF 20 SHORT REPORTS, PREPARED BY THE DIRECTORS OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE
AREA SERVING URBAN POPULATIONS OF OVER 20,000. IN EACH CASE, DETAILS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization>
OF BUILDINGS, COLLECTIONS, LAYOUT, FACILITIES, SERVICES, <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> ACTIVITIES,
<Organization>STATISTICAL DATA</Organization>, ADMINISTRATION, AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization>. THE <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> INCLUDES BOTH <Organization>OLD</Organization> AND
<Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, AND 1 CENTRAL <Organization>LENDING</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> OF THE REPORTS DESCRIBE
PROBLEMS CAUSED BY INADEQUATE <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization>. A BRIEF INTRODUCTION OUTLINES THE
ORGANISATION AND OPERATION OF SERVICES IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> THROUGHOUT THE REGION.
********************************************
Document 4532
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN A JAPANESE COMMUNITY.
     
FOLLOWING A STUDY PLACEMENT IN A JAPANESE CENTRAL <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN 1978-79, A
<Organization>BRAZILIAN UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Organization>HOW</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS ADAPTED <Organization>ITS</Organization>
SERVICES TO MEET PARTICULAR <Organization>USER</Organization> NEEDS. GIVES A SKETCH OF THE BUSY COMMERCIAL
CENTRE AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> ACTIVE POPULATION, CORRELATING <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization> OF LIFE WITH THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S PROVISIONS. DETAILS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> OF THE STOCK AND FACILITIES AVAILABLE,
INTERNAL AND EXTERNAL.
********************************************
Document 4533
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK AMONG <Location>DELHI</Location>&apos;S ILLITERATES.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> <Location>DELHI</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, OPENED IN 1951. BORROWING IS <Organization>FREE</Organization>, ALTHOUGH
THERE IS AN INITIAL DEPOSIT TOO <Organization>HIGH</Organization> FOR MANY <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization>. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> RUNS 4
<Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WITH 20 BRANCH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, EVENTUALLY TO BE SELF-GOVERNING.
IT ALSO HAS DEPOSIT COLLECTIONS IN 3 HOSPITALS, THE PRISON, AND INSTITUTIONS
FOR THE BLIND, <Organization>USING</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>OWN</Organization> BRAILLE BOOKS. MATERIALS HAVE TO BE IN
MANY LANGUAGES, WITH HINDI, URDU, PUNJABI AND ENGLISH THE MOST COMMON. THERE
IS AN <Organization>ADULT</Organization> <Organization>LENDING</Organization> SECTION, <Organization>READING</Organization> ROOM, <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> SECTION, AND CHILDREN&apos;S
SECTION; THE LATTER IS, HOWEVER, <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> LOW PRIORITY. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ARRANGES <Organization>FREE</Organization>
ACTIVITIES FOR ADULTS AND CHILDREN, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS FILMS, BOOK-TALKS, AUTHOR
WORK-SHOPS, AND ORGANISES STUDY GROUPS. THE <Organization>BOOK</Organization> SELECTION PROCEDURES ARE
SOMEWHAT HAPHAZARD; STRESS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> INDIAN AND WESTERN CLASSICS. <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>POPULAR</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> WORKS ARE NOW AVAILABLE IN HINDI. <Location>DELHI</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> APPEARS A
<Organization>TRADITIONAL WESTERN LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>, WITH LITTLE ATTEMPT TO CATER FOR THE <Organization>MASS</Organization>
OF ILLITERATE AND POTENTIAL USERS.
********************************************
Document 4534
CHANGING CONCEPTS OF THE ROLE AND OBJECTIVES OF THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN
<Location>PALESTINE</Location>, AS EXEMPLIFIED BY THE <Organization>SHA</Organization>&apos;AR ZION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN JAFFA AND TEL-AVIV (IN
HEBREW).
     
TRACES THE EVOLVING CONCEPTIONS OF THE ROLE AND OBJECTIVES OF THE <Organization>SHA</Organization>&apos;AR ZION
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AS FORMULATED BY <Organization>ITS</Organization> FOUNDERS, LIBRARIANS AND THE <Organization>TOWN</Organization> FATHERS
DURING THE PERIOD OF THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> 4 WAVES OF ZIONIST IMMIGRATION, <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE 1880S TO
1931. THE EMPHASIS IS <Organization>ON</Organization> ANALYSIS OF THE CLASH <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE CONCEPT OF THE
<Organization>POPULAR</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WHOSE PRIMARY PURPOSE WAS TO <Organization>SERVE</Organization> PREDOMINANTLY THE
IMMEDIATE AND TOPICAL NEEDS OF THE IMMIGRANTS AND HELP IN <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ABSORPTION,
AND THE CONCEPT OF THE SCHOLARLY <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, WHICH EMPHASISES THE
<Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF SERVICES TO A LIMITED CLIENTELE OF SCHOLARS, WRITERS AND TEACHERS
IN THE <Organization>FIELD</Organization> OF <Organization>JEWISH</Organization> STUDIES. OPENS WITH A DESCRIPTION OF THE <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization>
BACKGROUND OF THE PERIOD. THE 2ND PART <Organization>DEALS</Organization> WITH THE ORIGINS OF THE <Organization>SHA</Organization>&apos;AR
ZION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE CONTRIBUTION OF VOLUNTARY <Organization>ORGANISATIONS</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS THE B&apos;NAI
BRITH AND  B&apos;NAI MOSHE ORDERS TOWARDS THE FORMULATION OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> MISSION. THE 3<Organization>RD</Organization>
AND 4<Organization>TH</Organization> SECTIONS ANALYSE THE DELIBERATIONS AND CONTENTIONS OF MEMBERS OF THE
<Organization>TOWN COUNCIL</Organization> AND OF ADVISORS WITH REGARD TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OBJECTIVES DURING THE
PERIOD OF THE 3<Organization>RD</Organization> AND 4<Organization>TH</Organization> WAVES OF IMMIGRATION (1919-31). IN THE LAST SECTION,
ATTEMPTS TO DRAW <Organization>SOME</Organization> CONCLUSIONS WITH REGARD TO THE ROLE PLAYED BY THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN <Location>PALESTINE</Location> IN THE PROCESS OF REALISATION OF ZIONIST IDEOLOGY,
ESPECIALLY <Organization>ITS</Organization> FUNCTION AS AN AGENCY FOR EDUCATING THE POPULACE IN THE SPIRIT
OF THAT IDEOLOGY, AND IN REALISING THE <Organization>IDEAL</Organization> OF THE CREATION OF A <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>JEWISH</Organization>
SOCIETY IN <Location>PALESTINE</Location> WHICH WOULD PRESERVE AND MAINTAIN <Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> EXCELLENCE
AND SUPREMACY.
********************************************
Document 4535
FOCUS <Organization>ON</Organization>&apos; <Location>CAPE TOWN</Location> REGION.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> IN THE <Location>CAPE TOWN</Location> REGION OF <Location>SOUTH AFRICA</Location>
WITH CONSIDERATIONS OF THE 13 <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND BRIEF DETAILS OF THE 12
DEPOTS.
********************************************
Document 4536
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> SERVICES.
     
<Organization>DISCUSSES VARIOUS LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> GENERALLY AVAILABLE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE UNIVERSITY
LEVEL. HIGHLIGHTS THE RELEVANCE AND UTILITY OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF THE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization>
SERVICES THAT WERE REGARDED AS THE FEATURES OF <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization>. IT
POINTS <Organization>OUT</Organization> THE ADVANTAGES OF <Organization>SUPPORTING SERVICES</Organization>, <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS <Organization>REPROGRAPHY</Organization> AND
<Organization>TRANSLATION SERVICES</Organization> IN THE UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SET-UP AND ALSO STRESSES THE
NEED FOR, AND IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>EXTENSION SERVICE</Organization> AS PART OF THE UNIVERSITY
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4537
<Location>OSLO</Location> AND <Organization>ITS</Organization> MOST IMPORTANT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
<Location>OSLO</Location>, WITH 456,000 INHABITANTS, ENJOYS A <Organization>PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> <Organization>FROM</Organization> 2 MAIN
<Organization>CENTRES-THE UNIVERSITY</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> (<Organization>UBO</Organization>) AND THE DEICHMANSKE BIBLIOTEKET. THE <Organization>UBO</Organization>
SERVES BOTH AS A UNIVERSITY AND <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, THEREBY CREATING A SERIES OF
DIFFICULTIES IN THE STRUCTURAL ORGANISATION OF THE SERVICE. <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC</Organization> WORK
HAS BEEN FACILITATED BY THE <Organization>USE</Organization> OF COMPUTERS, AND <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> AND INTERNATIONAL
BIBLIOGRAPHIES ARE IN PROCESS. THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> HAS A SINGLE ALPHABETICAL AUTHOR AND
<Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> <Organization>CATALOGUE</Organization>, AND BUREAUCRATIC FORMALITIES HAVE BEEN REDUCED TO A
MINIMUM. THE DEICHMANSKE IS DISTINGUISHED <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> SCANDINAVIAN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> BY
<Organization>ITS WIDESPREAD SERVICE</Organization> TO SCHOOLS AND <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTES. IT AIMS TO
PROCURE AND LEND BOOKS UNOBTAINABLE <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>OTHER</Organization> SOURCES. BOTH <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> LEAVE
THE IMPRESSION OF AN <Organization>EFFICIENT SERVICE</Organization> WHICH HAS ELIMINATED ALL SOURCES OF
DISCOURAGEMENT TO USERS.
********************************************
Document 4538
APPLICATION OF THE GUIDELINES FOR THE 12<Organization>TH</Organization> PARTY CONGRESS IN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF
THE <Organization>KOSSUTH LAJOS UNIVERSITY</Organization> IN DEBRECEN.
     
<Organization>THESE</Organization> GUIDELINES ENCOURAGE THE <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND THE MANAGEMENT OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO
<Organization>STRENGTHEN</Organization> THE POLITICAL COMMITMENT OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> ACTIVITY, INCREASE PRODUCTIVITY,
EFFECTIVENESS AND ECONOMIC EFFICIENCY AS WELL AS TO ATTACH MORE IMPORTANCE TO
<Organization>INFORMATION SERVICES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4539
UNB <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NEARS 200 YEARS.
     
A <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF THE UNIVERSITY OF <Organization>NEW</Organization> BRUNSWICK AND <Organization>ITS</Organization>
PREDECESSORS, CONCENTRATING <Organization>ON</Organization> THE EARLY YEARS <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE LATE 18<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY AND
19<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY. THE BONAR LAW-BENNET <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WAS OPENED IN 1931 AND ENLARGED IN
1950-51. IN 1967 THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> HARRIET IRVING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OPENED AND THE BONAR
LAW-BENNET BUILDING BECAME THE <Organization>PROVINCIAL</Organization> ARCHIVES.
********************************************
Document 4540
A <Organization>MEDICAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN <Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location>.
     
(<Organization>MLS DISSERTATION-LOUGHBOROUGH UNIVERSITY</Organization> OF TECHNOLOGY.) THE UNIVERSITY OF
<Location>PAPUA NEW GUINEA</Location> <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS DESCRIBED IN THE CONTEXT OF THE PRIORITIES
AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> NEEDS OF THE <Organization>HEALTH CARE SERVICES</Organization>. ASPECTS OF <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> A
<Organization>NATIONAL MEDICAL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> ARE DISCUSSED.
********************************************
Document 4541
COLLEGE LIBRARIANS AND THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> INITIATIVE.
     
COLLEGES OF <Organization>FURTHER EDUCATION</Organization> WILL BE INVOLVED IN A PERIOD OF <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization> PRIOR TO THE INTRODUCTION OF THE GOVERNMENT&apos;S PROPOSED YOUTH <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
SCHEME IN SEPTEMBER 1983. YTS COURSES WILL INCLUDE A &apos;<Organization>BASIC</Organization> SKILLS&apos; COMPONENT
<Organization>INTO</Organization> WHICH &apos;<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SKILLS&apos; WORK <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE INCORPORATED. THE <Organization>FURTHER</Organization>
EDUCATION UNIT <Organization>REPORT</Organization> 2A BASIS FOR CHOICE 1<Organization>CAN</Organization> BE <Organization>USED</Organization> TO INDICATE POINTS <Organization>AT</Organization>
WHICH COLLEGE LIBRARIANS MIGHT MAKE A USEFUL CONTRIBUTION TO YTS <Organization>CURRICULUM</Organization>
<Organization>PLANNING</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4542
GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>LEARNING RESOURCES CENTER DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN TRADITIONALLY <Organization>BLACK</Organization>
FOUR-YEAR STATE-SUPPORTED COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES.
     
(<Organization>PHD DISSERTATION-FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY</Organization>.) INVESTIGATION <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE
DEVELOPMENT OF GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> <Organization>CENTRES</Organization>, <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> A STUDY OF
<Organization>SELECTED</Organization> <Organization>CENTRES</Organization> IN TRADITIONALLY <Organization>BLACK</Organization> 4-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> STATE-SUPPORTED COLLEGES AND
UNIVERSITIES, 1972-77. ATTEMPTS TO DETERMINE THE EXTENT TO WHICH <Organization>TITLE</Organization> III,
<Organization>ADVANCED INSTITUTIONAL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PROGRAM (AIDP) FUNDING IS <Organization>USED</Organization> TO EFFECT
MODIFICATION OF COLLEGE AND UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>SO</Organization> THAT THEY BECOME EFFECTIVE
<Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> <Organization>CENTRES</Organization> AND TO DEVELOP GUIDELINES WHICH WOULD BE USEFUL IN
DETERMINING THE EFFECTIVENESS OF <Organization>LEARNING RESOURCES CENTRE DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN
TRADITIONALLY <Organization>BLACK</Organization> 4-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> STATE-SUPPORTED COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES.
********************************************
Document 4543
GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>TWO-YEAR COLLEGE</Organization> <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> PROGRAMS (REVISED). PART 1.
     
THE GUIDELINES ARE DESIGNED TO GIVE DIRECTION TO <Organization>TWO-YEAR</Organization> COLLEGES WISHING TO
DEVELOP <Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> PROGRAMMES.
********************************************
Document 4544
GUIDELINES FOR <Organization>TWO-YEAR COLLEGE</Organization> <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> PROGRAMS (REVISED). PART 2.
     
GUIDELINES DESIGNED TO GIVE DIRECTION TO 2-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> COLLEGES WISHING TO DEVELOP
<Organization>COMPREHENSIVE</Organization> <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> PROGRAMMES. FOR PART 1, 2SEE1 PREVIOUS
ABSTRACT.
********************************************
Document 4545
COLLEGES OF <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> IN ENGLAND AND WALES&apos; THREE VIEWS.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> BRIEFLY THE REORGANISATION OF TEACHER <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> WHICH TOOK PLACE IN
THE <Location>UK</Location> DURING THE 1970S, AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> <Organization>ITS EFFECTS ON COLLEGE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
CONSIDERS <Organization>SOME</Organization> ASPECTS OF RECENT <Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization> IN THE <Organization>NEW</Organization> COLLEGES OF
<Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization>, <Organization>INCLUDING</Organization> THE GROWTH OF <Organization>MULTI MEDIA SERVICES</Organization>, AND THE
GROUPING OF ALL <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> <Organization>INTO</Organization> ONE DEPARTMENT. OUTLINES THE SERVICES
AND FACILITIES PROVIDED BY THE <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCE</Organization> <Organization>CENTRES</Organization> OF <Organization>AMERICAN COMMUNITY</Organization>
COLLEGES, WHICH IT IS SUGGESTED, <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE COMPARED TO BRITISH COLLEGES OF
<Organization>FURTHER</Organization> AND <Organization>HIGHER</Organization> EDUCATION. ARGUES THAT THE CONDITIONS ARE RIGHT FOR
COLLEGES OF <Organization>HIGHER EDUCATION</Organization> THAT <Organization>SO</Organization> CHOOSE, TO FOLLOW THE <Organization>AMERICAN COMMUNITY</Organization>
COLLEGES IN <Organization>THEIR INVESTMENT</Organization> IN <Organization>LEARNING</Organization> <Organization>RESOURCES</Organization> FOR GROUP AND <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization>
STUDY.
********************************************
Document 4546
THE <Organization>MEDIA CENTRE</Organization> IN A <Organization>VOCATIONAL TRAINING SCHOOL</Organization>.
     
STUDENTS IN A <Organization>VOCATIONAL TRAINING SCHOOL</Organization> WILL INCLUDE FORMER PUPILS OF BOTH
GRAMMAR AND <Organization>SECONDARY</Organization> <Organization>MODERN</Organization> SCHOOLS. <Organization>SOME</Organization> STUDENTS WILL BE <Organization>ON</Organization> PART TIME, <Organization>SOME</Organization>
<Organization>ON</Organization> FULL TIME COURSES; MOST OF THEM WILL HAVE HAD <Organization>SOME</Organization> WORK EXPERIENCE AND MANY
WILL HAVE PRACTICAL RATHER THAN <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> ABILITY. THE <Organization>MEDIA CENTRE</Organization> NEEDS A
WIDE RANGE OF <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> MATERIAL FOR ALL <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> LEVELS. SELF-TEACHING
PROGRAMMES ARE VERY IMPORTANT; <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL MEDIA</Organization> ARE PARTICULARLY HELPFUL IN
DEMONSTRATING THE OPERATION OF MACHINERY. <Organization>SOME</Organization> STUDENTS WILL HAVE <Organization>LEARNING</Organization>
DIFFICULTIES AND A LACK OF MOTIVATION; <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF MATERIAL FOR LEISURE AS
WELL AS <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> ACTIVITIES SHOULD ENCOURAGE THEM TO <Organization>USE</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>WHERE</Organization>
THEY MAY FIND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> LAST CHANCE TO MAKE UP FOR <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> DEFICITS. THE MEDIA
CENTRE SHOULD ALSO PROMOTE THE IDEA OF JOB FLEXIBILITY.
********************************************
Document 4547
PERSPECTIVES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE 1980S&apos; INDICATORS
<Organization>FROM</Organization> A DELPHI STUDY.
     
A DELPHI STUDY WAS UNDERTAKEN TO IDENTIFY THE CHANGES IN <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ROLES AND
FUNCTIONS THAT THE DIRECTORS OF <Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> <Organization>SCIENCES</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> BELIEVE
WILL OCCUR OVER THE NEXT DECADE. THE METHODOLOGY IS DESCRIBED AND THE RESULTS
ARE SUMMARISED. 2 SCENARIOS RESULTED&apos; ONE HIGHLY DESIRABLE; THE <Organization>OTHER</Organization>, HIGHLY
PROBABLE, AND THEY OVERLAP BY 64%. <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DIRECTORS EXPECT MODERATE
EVOLUTIONARY CHANGES IN THE NEXT 10 YEARS. USERS ARE PERCEIVED TO BE THE FORCE
MAINTAINING THE STATUS QUO, <Organization>WHILE TECHNOLOGY</Organization> IS THE FORCE ADVANCING CHANGE.
THE ADOPTION OF TECHNOLOGY IS SEEN AS DESIRABLE AND WITHIN THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; SPAN
OF CONTROL. EDUCATION AND SERVICE ROLES OF LIBRARIANS WILL EXPAND. <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND
<Organization>INSTITUTIONAL</Organization> PRIORITIES ARE SEEN AS OBSTACLES TO CHANGE.
********************************************
Document 4548
<Organization>VETERINARY SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Location>UNITED STATES</Location> AND CANADA 1977/78.
     
DATA <Organization>ON</Organization> 7 ASPECTS OF <Organization>VETERINARY MEDICAL SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE PRESENTED AND
DISCUSSED&apos; <Organization>DEMOGRAPHIC DATA</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE SCHOOLS OF <Organization>VETERINARY</Organization> MEDICINE THE
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SUPPORT, NUMBER OF BOUND VOLUMES <Organization>HELD</Organization> AND NUMBER OF <Organization>SERIAL</Organization> TITLES
RECEIVED, <Organization>AUDIO-VISUAL</Organization> MATERIALS, STAFFING LEVELS AND SALARIES, MATERIALS
BUDGETS, PHYSICAL SIZE AND ACCESS TO <Organization>COMPUTERISED</Organization> <Organization>BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA</Organization> BASES.
THE GREAT VARIABILITY, ESPECIALLY IN <Organization>COLLECTION</Organization> SIZE IS STRESSED AND
ATTRIBUTED TO <Organization>SUCH</Organization> FACTORS AS SIZE AND PROGRAMMES OF THE <Organization>VETERINARY SCHOOL</Organization>,
<Organization>AGE</Organization> OF THE SCHOOL AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, GEOGRAPHIC LOCATION, ACCESSIBILITY OF <Organization>OTHER</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, ADMINISTRATIVE STRUCTURE AND EXCHANGE PROGRAMMES.
********************************************
Document 4549
SNI-<Location>FINLAND</Location>&apos;S INSTITUTE FOR CHILDREN&apos;S BOOKS.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> SUOMEN NUORISOKIRJALLISUUDEN INSTITUUTTI, THE <Organization>FINNISH INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>YOUNG</Organization>. IT WAS FOUNDED IN 1978 IN <Location>TAMPERE</Location>, HAS A BOARD OF 15
WITH A CHAIRMAN, AND ADMITS INDIVIDUALS AND <Organization>ORGANISATIONS</Organization> AS MEMBERS. IT
COLLECTS ALL <Organization>FINNISH</Organization> BOOKS AND JOURNALS FOR CHILDREN AND <Organization>YOUNG</Organization> <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization> AND
TRANSLATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>FINNISH</Organization>, AND THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> COMPRISES TODAY 15,000 BOOKS AND
100 JOURNALS. <Organization>NEW</Organization> PUBLICATIONS ARE RECEIVED AS DONATIONS <Organization>FROM</Organization> HELSINGFORS
UNIVERSITY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND OTHERS. THE INSTITUTE SUPPORTS <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization>, HAS CONTACT
WITH <Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND THE <Organization>SWEDISH INSTITUTE</Organization> FOR CHILDREN&apos;S BOOKS,
AND UNDERTAKES PUBLISHING. A <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> TO <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> THE <Organization>HISTORY</Organization> OF <Location>FINLAND</Location>&apos;S
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> FOR CHILDREN AND <Organization>YOUNG</Organization> <Organization>PEOPLE AWAITS FINANCIAL</Organization> SUPPORT. SNI
ORGANISES <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> MEETINGS, EXHIBITIONS, AND CONFERENCES. AS <Organization>FROM</Organization> 1980, THE
INSTITUTE HAS BEEN <Organization>RECEIVING FINANCIAL</Organization> SUPPORT <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE STATE AS WELL AS <Organization>FROM</Organization>
<Organization>TAMPERE TOWN COUNCIL</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4550
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AFTER THE 10<Organization>TH</Organization> PARTY CONFERENCE.
     
A DEVELOPMENT PLAN FOR <Organization>TRADES UNION</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN 1981 WAS DRAWN UP TO <Organization>FURTHER</Organization>
<Organization>SCIENTIFIC</Organization> AND <Organization>TECHNICAL</Organization> PROGRESS; THE PLAN&apos;S EFFECT <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IN VEB
KOMBINAT NARVA, AN <Organization>EAST BERLIN ELECTRIC</Organization> LIGHT BULB FACTORY IS DESCRIBED. CLOSE
COOPERATION IS ADVOCATED WITH THE COLLECTIVES AND WITH <Organization>OTHER</Organization> <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization>
<Organization>ORGANISATIONS</Organization> AND THE EXPANSION OF STOCKS AND <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> SERVICES. STUDENTS
<Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>INDUSTRIAL TRAINING SCHOOL</Organization> WERE TO BE INTRODUCED TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES <Organization>AT</Organization> THE START OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> COURSES AND <Organization>SUITABLE</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> PROVIDED FOR
<Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> AND POLITICAL STUDIES AND FOR LEISURE ACTIVITIES. AS A RESULT
<Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> APPRENTICE CLASSES <Organization>MADE</Organization> VISITS TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND MORE LITERARY EVENTS
AND DISPLAYS WERE ORGANISED. IT IS HOPED THAT 1981 LOANS WILL INCREASE TO
75,000 AND THAT <Organization>AT</Organization> LEAST 55% OF WORKERS UNDER 25 WILL BE REGISTERED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
MEMBERS.
********************************************
Document 4551
THE SUPPORT OF <Organization>ADULT EDUCATION</Organization> AND <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>.
     
THE ARRIVAL OF <Organization>NEW PLANT</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE PETROCHEMICAL COMBINE <Organization>AT</Organization> SCHWEDT MEANT THAT
RETRAINING FOR <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND MORE <Organization>ADVANCED</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> FOR OTHERS HAD TO BE
CARRIED <Organization>OUT</Organization>. THE TRADE UNION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE WORKS HAD TO PARTICIPATE BY
ACQUIRING MULTIPLE COPIES AND CLASS SETS OF <Organization>SOME</Organization> BOOKS AND DISCARDING OUTDATED
MATERIAL. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OBTAINED TEXTBOOKS REQUESTED BY THE <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
SCHOOL, CHECKING AVAILABLE MATERIAL AND FILLING IN GAPS IN <Organization>SUBJECT</Organization> COVERAGE.
ALL STUDENTS WERE PROVIDED WITH LEAFLETS DESCRIBING <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FACILITIES. AS A
RESULT LOANS IN 1980 TOTALLED 42,400, COMPARED WITH 35,065 FOR 1979. <Organization>SIMILAR</Organization>
ARRANGEMENTS WERE <Organization>MADE</Organization> FOR THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> TO PROVIDE THE MATERIAL NEEDED FOR
POLITICAL EDUCATION.
********************************************
Document 4552
<Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
EXTRACT <Organization>FROM</Organization> A PAPER PRESENTED TO THE <Organization>FIJI LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE &apos;<Organization>MINI</Organization>
CONVENTION&apos;, WESTERN <Organization>REGIONAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, LAUTOKA, <Location>FIJI</Location>, 29 NOV 80. <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization> THE
VALUE AND PURPOSES OF <Organization>INDUSTRIAL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, PARTICULARLY IN COUNTRIES <Organization>SUCH</Organization> AS
<Location>FIJI</Location> <Organization>WHERE</Organization> <Organization>SPECIALISED</Organization> <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> AND <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> ARE NOT READILY AVAILABLE.
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE <Organization>TRAINING CENTRE</Organization> <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>FIJI ELECTRICITY</Organization>
AUTHORITY.
********************************************
Document 4553
THE DEVELOPMENT AND WORK OF HOSPITAL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SERVICES FOR
PATIENTS, AS <Organization>BASED</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE REGULATIONS OF THE MINISTRY OF HEALTH IN THE <Location>GERMAN
DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC</Location>.
     
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK IS <Organization>COORDINATED</Organization> BY DISTRICT <Organization>WORKING</Organization> PARTIES, WITH <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> GROUPS
SUPERVISING PATIENTS&apos; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN MENTAL <Organization>HEALTH</Organization> CLINICS <Organization>WHERE</Organization> BIBLIOTHERAPY
PLAYS A PROMINENT PART. CLOSE LINKS ARE MAINTAINED WITH DISTRICT <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
OFFICERS. <Organization>SOME</Organization> HOSPITALS ARE <Organization>STILL</Organization> WITHOUT PATIENTS&apos; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND EVERY
EFFORT IS BEING <Organization>MADE</Organization> TO IMPROVE THE SERVICE AND RELATIONSHIPS WITH <Organization>MEDICAL</Organization>
<Organization>STAFF</Organization>. IT IS IMPORTANT TO SELECT STOCK THAT WILL ASSIST RECOVERY; REGULAR
DISCUSSIONS ARE <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>SUITABLE</Organization> MATERIAL. THE ARRANGEMENT AND APPEARANCE OF
PATIENTS&apos; <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE VERY IMPORTANT; <Organization>OLD HOSPITAL</Organization> BUILDINGS ARE OFTEN
WITHOUT <Organization>SUITABLE</Organization> PREMISES FOR A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. IN <Organization>NEW</Organization> BUILDINGS A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ROOM IS
ALWAYS PROVIDED. IN MANY HOSPITALS THE PATIENTS&apos; <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> IS AMALGAMATED WITH
THE TRADE UNION <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>SO</Organization> THAT EXTRA FINANCE AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> ARE AVAILABLE.
********************************************
Document 4554
THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IN PENAL ESTABLISHMENTS IN KENT.
     
A DETAILED <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> OF H.M. PRISON MAIDSTONE AND H.M. PRISON
STANDFORD HILL WITH SURVEYS OF SERVICES IN 7 <Organization>OTHER</Organization> PENAL ESTABLISHMENTS IN
KENT, <Location>UK</Location>.
********************************************
Document 4555
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE PHYSICALLY DISABLED.
     
THE CELEBRATION OF THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> 1981 AS THE &apos;<Organization>YEAR</Organization> FOR THE DISABLED PERSONS&apos; WAS A
PART OF THE <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF THE <Organization>UNITED NATIONS</Organization> TO AMELIORATE THE
CONDITION OF HANDICAPPED PERSONS. <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> EDUCATE AND PROVIDE RECREATION
TO THE PHYSICALLY DISABLED.
********************************************
Document 4556
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND THE <Organization>UN</Organization>&apos;S INTERNATIONAL <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OF THE DISABLED.
     
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ROLE IN BREAKING DOWN BARRIERS WHICH PREVENT
HANDICAPPED READERS GAINING ACCESS TO PRINTED MATERIAL. ARGUES THAT MOST OF
THE 50% IN <Location>DENMARK</Location> WHO ARE NOT <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> USERS ARE MORE OR LESS HANDICAPPED.
<Organization>SOME</Organization> ARE HANDICAPPED <Organization>FROM</Organization> PHYSICAL CAUSES, AND OTHERS ARE SLOW OR <Organization>NEW</Organization> READERS
AND DYSLEXICS. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE IMPORTANCE OF <Organization>READING</Organization> IN <Organization>DAILY</Organization> LIFE AND THE
REASONS FOR LACK OF SKILL IN <Organization>READING</Organization>. OUTLINES RULES FOR LANGUAGE AND LAY-OUT
WHICH MAKE A <Organization>BOOK</Organization> EASIER TO READ AND THE <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> TYPES OF <Organization>BOOK</Organization> AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization>
<Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> GROUPS (&apos;ORDINARY&apos; BOOKS, EASY READERS, MAGNAPRINT, BRAILLE, SPOKEN
BOOKS, <Organization>BOOK</Organization> 0 TAPE). <Organization>THIS</Organization> KIND OF MATERIAL IS <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> TOO LITTLE PRIORITY BY
<Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>SPECIAL CARE</Organization> SHOULD BE TAKEN IN DESIGN OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
TO MAKE THEM ACCESSIBLE TO THE HANDICAPPED. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> MUST DISSEMINATE <Organization>ITS</Organization>
SERVICES WIDELY TO THE HANDICAPPED. DURING THE INTERNATIONAL <Organization>YEAR</Organization> IT IS
IMPORTANT THAT <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> MAKE A <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization>  EFFORT AND ARE REPRESENTED <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
ORGANISING COMMITTEES.
********************************************
Document 4557
IYDP 1981: WHAT <Organization>DOES</Organization> IT MEAN TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND LIBRARIANS?.
     
CHANGES IN <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> ARE BEING DEMANDED IN <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO THE DISABLED
CLIENT. <Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> FORMS OF DISABILITIES AND MAKES <Organization>SOME</Organization> SUGGESTIONS AS TO <Organization>HOW</Organization>
SERVICE TO DISABLED <Organization>CLIENTS</Organization> <Organization>CAN</Organization> BE IMPROVED. <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> MENTION IS <Organization>MADE</Organization> OF THE
NEED FOR ATTENTION TO <Organization>THIS</Organization> AREA IN <Organization>LIBRARIANSHIP</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> PROGRAMMES.
********************************************
Document 4558
CONSIDERING THE DISABLED IN SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>&apos; ATTITUDES AND <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> DESIGN.
     
WITH THE INTRODUCTION AND INCREASING PREVALENCE OF <Organization>MAINSTREAMING</Organization> IN SCHOOLS,
IT IS INEVITABLE THAT <Organization>SOME</Organization> STUDENTS WILL HAVE TO COPE WITH <Organization>SOME</Organization> DEGREE OF
DISABILITY. DISABILITIES VARY TREMENDOUSLY, BOTH IN TYPE AND DEGREE TO WHICH
<Organization>NORMAL</Organization> FUNCTIONING IS IMPAIRED. IT IS <Organization>ESSENTIAL</Organization> THAT ALL STUDENTS BE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> THE
<Organization>SAME</Organization> CONSIDERATION AND RESPECT REGARDLESS OF <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> DIFFERENCES.
LIBRARIANS <Organization>CAN</Organization> CONTRIBUTE MOST BY UNDERSTANDING THE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> DIFFICULTIES AND
NEEDS OF THE CHILD. ABILITIES RATHER THAN DISABILITIES NEED TO BE EMPHASISED.
BESIDES PSYCHOLOGICAL AND <Organization>SOCIAL</Organization> BARRIERS, THE PROBLEM OF SIMPLE PHYSICAL
ACCESS MUST BE CONSIDERED. DESIGN FEATURES THAT MUST BE CONSIDERED INCLUDE
ACCESS TO THE BUILDING, ACCESS WITHIN THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND ACCESS TO ALL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICES.
********************************************
Document 4559
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO PHYSICALLY DISABLED PERSONS.
     
THE INTERNATIONAL <Organization>YEAR</Organization> FOR DISABLED PERSONS 1981 HAS DRAWN THE ATTENTION TO
THE 8% OF THE WORLD POPULATION WHO ARE DISABLED IN <Organization>SOME</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization>. CONSIDERABLE
ATTENTION HAS BEEN <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> TO THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NEEDS OF <Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization>. IN ORDER TO
<Organization>OFFER</Organization> THEM EQUAL RIGHTS AND EQUAL OPPORTUNITIES AS ABLE PERSONS IN THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, <Organization>SEVERAL</Organization> REQUIREMENTS FOR THE PHYSICAL LAY-OUT AND EQUIPMENT SHOULD BE
CONSIDERED. BLIND PERSONS HAVE A WELL-COORDINATED <Organization>SOUTH</Organization> <Organization>AFRICAN</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
SERVICE WITH BOOKS IN BRAILLE OR MOON PRINT AND BOOKS <Organization>ON</Organization> TAPE <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
DISPOSAL. ALMOST ALL <Organization>OTHER</Organization> DISABLED PERSONS <Organization>CAN</Organization> RELY WITH CONFIDENCE <Organization>ON</Organization> THE
SERVICE OF <Organization>THEIR</Organization> NEARBY <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> ATTEMPTS WILL BE <Organization>MADE</Organization> TO SUPPLY THEM
WITH BOOKS, IN <Organization>GENERAL</Organization> AS WELL AS AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>SPECIFIC</Organization> NEEDS. E.G. <Organization>HOW</Organization> TO
ADAPT TO <Organization>THEIR</Organization> <Organization>WAY</Organization> OF LIVING AS DISABLED PERSONS (DEALING WITH THE PRACTICAL
ASPECTS <Organization>LIKE</Organization> CLOTHING AND HOUSING) AND <Organization>HOW</Organization> TO ACCEPT REALITY (HEALING OF THE
MIND).
********************************************
Document 4560
A <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> GUIDE TO <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR THE VISUALLY HANDICAPPED IN <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.
     
THE GUIDE, COMPILED BY A <Organization>WORKING PARTY</Organization> SET UP BY THE <Organization>BRAZILIAN</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES ASSOCIATION</Organization>, IS PRESENTED IN FULL, WITH A BRIEF INTRODUCTION BY THE
COORDINATOR OF THE GROUP. THE <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE LISTED BY REGION; UNDER EACH ENTRY
DETAILS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> OF THE PARENT INSTITUTION, COLLECTIONS, AND SERVICES.
ALPHABETICAL AND <Organization>GEOGRAPHICAL</Organization> INDEXES ARE SUPPLIED.
********************************************
Document 4561
<Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> FOR THE BLIND AND FOR <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization> WITH SIGHT PROBLEMS: THE PUBLISHING
<Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> CENTRAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR THE BLIND.
     
THE <Organization>GERMAN</Organization> CENTRAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR THE BLIND (DEUTSCHE ZENTRALBUCHEREI FUR BLINDE)
WAS OPENED IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location> <Location>IN</Location> 1894, THE 1<Organization>ST</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> OF <Organization>ITS</Organization> KIND IN <Location>GERMANY</Location>. <Organization>CURRENT</Organization>
STOCKS OF BRAILLE WORKS TOTAL 7,700, COMPRISING 26,700 VOLUMES, SINCE WORKS IN
BRAILLE REQUIRE MORE VOLUMES THAN <Organization>NORMAL</Organization> PRINT BOOKS. BOOKS INCLUDE FICTION
AND NON-FICTION FOR CHILDREN AND ADULTS AND <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IS ALSO PROVIDED <Organization>ON</Organization>
TAPES (67,000), CASSETTES (25,000) AND RECORDS. SOUND RECORDINGS ARE
PARTICULARLY USEFUL FOR THE ELDERLY, WHO FIND IT <Organization>HARD</Organization> TO LEARN BRAILLE. MOST
CONTACTS WITH READERS ARE <Organization>MADE</Organization> BY POST OR <Organization>TELEPHONE</Organization>, <Organization>BUT</Organization> THERE IS A <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>READING</Organization> ROOM WITH CATALOGUES IN <Organization>NORMAL</Organization> PRINT AND BRAILLE. THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> HAS
<Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND EQUIPMENT FOR THE PRODUCTION OF BRAILLE BOOKS, TALKING BOOKS AND THE
REPRODUCTION OF TAPES AND CASSETTES. A LIST OF RECENT ACQUISITIONS OF <Organization>LARGE</Organization>
PRINT BOOKS IS INCLUDED.
********************************************
Document 4562
THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR TALKING BOOKS AND BRAILLE (PART) II.
     
PART I OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> ARTICLE APPEARED IN 2BIBLIOTEKSBLADET1 66 (6) 1981 (+S+E+E
82/573). THE PUBLISHING OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR TALKING BOOKS AND BRAILLE (<Organization>TPB</Organization>) IS
VERY IMPORTANT FOR THE SUPPLY OF TALKING BOOKS. 1200 TITLES ANNUALLY ARE
PRODUCED FOR <Organization>LOAN</Organization> IN <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>, OF WHICH THE <Organization>TPB</Organization> ACCOUNTS FOR 900. THE
SELECTION OF BOOKS INCLUDES ALL EASY READERS AND 25% OF PRODUCTION ARE BOOKS
FOR CHILDREN AND <Organization>YOUNG</Organization> <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization>. THE AGED FORM THE <Organization>LARGEST USER GROUP</Organization>. BRAILLE
BOOKS ARE NOW IN A MINORITY; THEY ARE LENT DIRECTLY TO READERS. CATALOGUES OF
THE <Organization>TPB</Organization>&apos;S STOCK AND <Organization>NEW</Organization> ACQUISITIONS ARE BEING PREPARED <Organization>USING</Organization> THE <Organization>BUMS DATA</Organization>
<Organization>BASE</Organization>. <Organization>SOME</Organization> BOOKS FOR IMMIGRANTS ARE AVAILABLE. AS A <Organization>LOAN CENTRE</Organization> THE <Organization>TPB</Organization> IS
OBLIGED TO LEND TO <Organization>DIFFERENT</Organization> INSTITUTIONS AND COLLATE <Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>LOCAL</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> STOCKS. IT AIMS TO DEVELOP THE DECENTRALISATION OF TALKING <Organization>BOOK</Organization>
<Organization>PROVISION</Organization> AND THEREFORE WISHES TO TRANSFER TO THE <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> THE
RESPONSIBILITY FOR DIRECT <Organization>LENDING</Organization> TO INDIVIDUALS AND PURCHASE OF AN ADEQUATE
STOCK <Organization>FROM</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4563
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> TO HEARING IMPAIRED CHILDREN.
     
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> HEARING IMPAIRMENT AND THE <Organization>RESULTING</Organization> <Organization>MAJOR</Organization> PROBLEMS FOR THE HEARING
IMPAIRED CHILD. UNDERSTANDING OF THE PROBLEMS AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> EFFECTS AND
IMPLICATIONS FOR EDUCATION ARE OUTLINED. THE <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OFFERED <Organization>AT</Organization> THE
<Organization>GLENDONALD SCHOOL</Organization> FOR DEAF CHILDREN IS DESCRIBED WITH PARTICULAR <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO
<Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4564
MORE ATTENTION TO SENIOR READERS.
     
1982 BEING PROCLAIMED BY UNESCO AS THE <Organization>YEAR</Organization> OF <Organization>AGE</Organization> <Organization>CONCERN</Organization>, A THOUGHT SHOULD
BE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> TO SENIOR READERS. THERE ARE OVER 2,400,000 POTENTIAL READERS IN
<Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location> WHO ARE OVER 60 AND <Organization>THEIR</Organization> NUMBER IS LIKELY TO INCREASE IN
<Organization>FUTURE</Organization>. <Organization>THIS</Organization>, 1<Organization>ST</Organization> PART OF A SERIES <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>THIS</Organization> THEME, IS LOOKING <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>OLD</Organization> <Organization>AGE</Organization> AS A
NATURAL PROCESS AND RECOUNTS CARE AFFORDED TO SENIOR CITIZENS IN
<Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location>.
********************************************
Document 4565
<Organization>VISITING LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>&apos; A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF <Location>ONTARIO</Location>&apos;S <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
     
<Organization>PRESENTS</Organization> RESULTS OF A <Organization>SURVEY</Organization> OF <Location>ONTARIO</Location> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>INTO</Organization> THE <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF
<Organization>VISITING LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization> TO <Organization>OLD</Organization> PEOPLES&apos; APARTMENT BUILDINGS, NURSING HOMES
AND HOSPITALS STAFFED BY VOLUNTEER <Organization>STAFF</Organization> AND VOLUNTEER/<Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4566
THE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND AN AGEING POPULATION.
     
THE ROLE OF CANADIAN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> OF SERVICES TO <Organization>OLD</Organization>
<Organization>PEOPLE</Organization> IS REVIEWED.
********************************************
Document 4567
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK WITH CHILDREN IN <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES.
     
<Organization>REPORT</Organization> <Organization>ON</Organization> THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization>/<Organization>UNESCO</Organization> <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES <Organization>ON</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK FOR CHILDREN AND <Organization>YOUNG</Organization> <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization>, <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>, AUG 81. THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization> THEME
WAS DISCUSSED WITH <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> TO <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> COUNTRIES IN <Location>AFRICA</Location>, <Location>ASIA</Location> AND LATIN
<Location>AMERICA</Location>, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> MANY CHILDREN <Organization>ATTEND SCHOOL</Organization> ONLY BRIEFLY OR NOT <Organization>AT</Organization> ALL, <Organization>SO</Organization> THEY
REMAIN ILLITERATE. MANY PARENTS ARE ALSO ILLITERATE <Organization>SO</Organization> <Organization>READING</Organization> IN LEISURE
HOURS IS NOT ENCOURAGED. WHAT SCHOOL BOOKS AND LESSONS THERE ARE EXIST ONLY IN
AN <Organization>OFFICIAL</Organization> LANGUAGE, GENERALLY THAT OF A <Organization>COLONISING POWER</Organization>. THERE IS A LACK OF
PUBLISHED MATERIAL IN <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> LANGUAGES, <Organization>SOME</Organization> OF WHICH HAVE NEVER EVEN BEEN
WRITTEN DOWN. IN <Organization>THESE</Organization> COUNTRIES A <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK MUST BE ESTABLISHED AND THE
GROWTH OF <Organization>READING</Organization> ENCOURAGED WITH THE HELP OF <Organization>PROFESSIONAL</Organization> AND VOLUNTARY
<Organization>STAFF</Organization>. <Organization>LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> FOR THE HANDICAPPED POSE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> PROBLEMS.
********************************************
Document 4568
THE PRE-SESSION <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> FOR LIBRARIANS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES, <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>,
DDR, 10-15 AUGUST 1981.
     
THE <Organization>UNESCO</Organization>/<Organization>IFLA</Organization> PRE-SESSION <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> FOR EXPERTS <Organization>FROM</Organization> <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> COUNTRIES WAS
DEVOTED TO <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> WORK FOR CHILDREN AND <Organization>YOUNG</Organization> ADULTS. THE PRINCIPLES FOR THE
ORGANISATION OF THE <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> ARE LISTED.
********************************************
Document 4569
THE PRESENT SITUATION OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> FOR <Organization>YOUNG</Organization> <Organization>PEOPLE</Organization> IN <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.
     
A BRIEF <Organization>HISTORICAL</Organization> SKETCH IS <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> OF THE <Organization>EVOLUTION</Organization> OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN
<Location>BRAZIL</Location>; NUMBERS ARE <Organization>STILL</Organization> <Organization>SMALL</Organization> <Organization>BUT</Organization> PLANS TO AROUSE <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND GOVERNMENT
INTEREST ARE IN HAND. EXAMINES THE ROLE OF THE CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>, IN
PREPARING THE CHILD FOR THE <Organization>ADULT</Organization> WORLD AND <Organization>DEVELOPING</Organization> THE <Organization>READING</Organization> HABIT;
<Organization>DESCRIBES</Organization> THE VARIOUS KINDS OF MEDIA TO BE <Organization>MADE</Organization> AVAILABLE; CONSIDERS THE
RELATIONSHIP <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> AND THE <Organization>WIDER COMMUNITY</Organization>; AND <Organization>DISCUSSES</Organization>
VARIOUS <Organization>EXTENSION</Organization> ACTIVITIES FOR CHILDREN AND ADULTS OUTSIDE THE IMMEDIATE
AREA OF THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>. EMPHASISES THE NEED TO INCREASE THE NUMBER OF <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>
AND DEVELOP THE SERVICES ALREADY IN OPERATION.
********************************************
Document 4570
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>MALI</Location>&apos; PROBLEMS AND DEVELOPMENT.
     
LECTURE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization>/<Organization>UNESCO</Organization> <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>, AUG 81. IN PRE-COLONIAL
TIMES EDUCATION IN <Location>MALI</Location> WAS PROVIDED WITHIN THE FAMILY; IN THE COLONIAL
PERIODS, THE MEDIAEVAL BERBERS AND 19<Organization>TH</Organization> CENTURY <Organization>FRENCH</Organization> ESTABLISHED <Organization>SOME</Organization>
SCHOOLS AND <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> 1960 AND 1980, AFTER INDEPENDENCE, THE
EDUCATION SYSTEM WAS <Organization>REFORMED</Organization> AND A LITERACY CAMPAIGN PROMOTED IN THE
COUNTRY&apos;S 4 MAIN LANGUAGES. SINCE THE 1970S 46 <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE BEEN
OPENED, EACH OF WHICH <Organization>CONTAINS</Organization> A CHILDREN&apos;S DEPARTMENT. KEYPOINTS IN THE
DEVELOPMENT OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE THE PRODUCTION OF <Organization>SUITABLE</Organization> <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization>,
STOCK EXPANSION AND <Organization>STAFF</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>, A <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> <Organization>COORDINATED</Organization> BY THE CENTRAL
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> FOR CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LITERATURE</Organization> IN <Location>BAMAKO</Location>. LIBRARIANS, AUTHORS AND
<Organization>PUBLISHERS</Organization> ARE <Organization>WORKING</Organization> TOGETHER TO MAKE COLLECTIONS OF <Organization>NATIONAL</Organization> LEGENDS AND
STORIES, ORGANISE <Organization>CULTURAL</Organization> EVENTS AND ENCOURAGE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>USE</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4571
TWO NOTABLE EXPERIMENTS IN CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>: CLAMART, <Location>FRANCE</Location> AND SAO
<Location>PAULO</Location>, <Location>BRAZIL</Location>.
     
FOLLOWING A VISIT TO THE CLAMART &apos;JOY THROUGH BOOKS&apos; <Organization>PROJECT</Organization> IN 1979, THE
<Organization>LIBRARIAN</Organization> IN CHARGE OF THE <Location>SAO PAULO</Location> CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> NETWORK COMMENTS <Organization>ON</Organization>
THE SIMILARITIES <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> THE 2 SCHEMES, BOTH DESIGNED TO PROVIDE FOR <Organization>THEIR</Organization>
RESPECTIVE USERS PLACES <Organization>WHERE</Organization> CHILDREN <Organization>CAN</Organization> LEARN <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> THE WORLD AND BECOME
AWARE OF THE VALUE OF BOOKS. DETAILS ARE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> OF THE ORGANISATION AND
OPERATION OF THE 2 SCHEMES, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> CONVENTIONAL <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> PRACTICES HAVE BEEN
<Organization>REPLACED</Organization> BY MORE INNOVATIVE APPROACHES.
********************************************
Document 4572
CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>NIGERIA</Location>.
     
LECTURE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>IFLA</Organization>/<Organization>UNESCO</Organization> <Organization>SEMINAR</Organization> IN <Location>LEIPZIG</Location>, AUG 81. <Organization>GENERAL</Organization>
CONDITIONS ARE ILLUSTRATED BY A DESCRIPTION OF CHILDREN&apos;S <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN BENDEL
PROVINCE, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> CHILDREN&apos;S DEPARTMENTS IN <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND SCHOOL
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> HAVE BEEN ESTABLISHED SINCE THE 1970S. <Organization>REFERENCE</Organization> DEPARTMENTS IN
<Organization>LARGE</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ALSO STOCK <Organization>SOME</Organization> MATERIAL FOR CHILDREN. <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> <Organization>STAFF</Organization> ORGANISE
<Organization>READING</Organization> SESSIONS, FILMS, DANCING AND ARTISTIC ACTIVITIES AND HOPE TO DEVELOP
<Organization>THESE</Organization> <Organization>FURTHER</Organization> AND TO EXPAND READERSHIP. BENDEL&apos;S <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY SERVICE</Organization> IS
ADMINISTERED BY A CENTRE IN CHARGE OF ALL PURCHASING AND LOANS. SHORT <Organization>TRAINING</Organization>
COURSES ARE ORGANISED FOR TEACHER-LIBRARIANS AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> ASSISTANTS
ALSO HELP IN THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4573
AN <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>/SCHOOLS <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEM FOR <Location>MALTA</Location>.
     
(<Organization>FLA</Organization> THESIS.) PROVIDES A PLAN TO STANDARDISE DEVELOPMENT IN THE
STATE-CONTROLLED <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> AND SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>MALTA</Location>, OVER A 10-<Organization>YEAR</Organization> PERIOD,
IN LIGHT OF THE FAILURE OF THE 7-<Organization>YEAR MALTA DEVELOPMENT</Organization> PLAN TO MENTION
<Organization>LIBRARY DEVELOPMENT</Organization>. STRESSES THE FACT THAT <Location>MALTA</Location> HAS A SUFFICIENTLY WELL
EDUCATED AND APPRECIATIVE POPULATION TO EMBARK <Organization>ON</Organization> <Organization>SUCH</Organization> A <Organization>PROGRAMME</Organization> OF
<Organization>INTEGRATED SERVICE</Organization> AND <Organization>PROVISION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4574
SCHOOL LIBRARIES-A DREAM OF THE 1970S.
     
<Organization>EDUCATIONAL</Organization> REFORM <Organization>CAN</Organization>NOT TAKE PLACE WITHOUT THE INCLUSION OF THE <Organization>BASIC</Organization>
<Organization>CULTURAL TECHNOLOGY</Organization>. PARTICULAR SUCCESS IN <Organization>THIS</Organization> <Organization>FIELD</Organization> HAS BEEN SHOWN IN THE 3
<Organization>COMBINED SCHOOL</Organization> AND <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>HANOVER</Location>, WHICH <Organization>CONTAINS</Organization> A WIDE RANGE
OF MATERIAL AND EQUIPMENT FOR CLASS AND <Organization>INDIVIDUAL</Organization> STUDY AND FOR LEISURE
ACTIVITIES. IF PURCHASING, PROCESSING AND CONTROL OF <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY MEDIA</Organization>
STOCKS ARE TO BE <Organization>INTEGRATED</Organization> <Organization>INTO CENTRALISED PUBLIC LIBRARY SERVICES</Organization>, THE
RIGHT TO FINANCIAL <Organization>PROVISION</Organization> MUST BE GUARANTEED. MORE CLARITY IS NEEDED
REGARDING THE CALCULATION OF PROCESSING COSTS; STAFFING COSTS SHOULD BE BORNE
BY <Organization>LOCAL</Organization> GOVERNMENT, MATERIAL AND BINDING COSTS BY THE SCHOOLS. <Organization>SOME</Organization> PROBLEMS
CONCERNING THE ORGANISATION OF <Organization>USE</Organization> PROCEDURES, E.G. TICKET WRITING AND FINE
<Organization>COLLECTION</Organization>, REMAIN UNSOLVED.
********************************************
Document 4575
THE MINISTER HAS BEEN LED ASTRAY.
     
THE CONTRIBUTION BY A MEMBER OF THE <Organization>DANISH LIBRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>&apos;S <Organization>EXECUTIVE</Organization>
COMMITTEE TO A <Organization>DEBATE ON SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> <Organization>HELD</Organization> <Organization>AT</Organization> THE <Organization>DANISH SCHOOL</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ASSOCIATION&apos;S ANNUAL MEETING, OCT 81. ARGUES THAT THE MINISTRY OF CULTURE IN
<Organization>ITS</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL HAS DISREGARDED THE <Organization>LIBRARY COMMISSION</Organization>&apos;S PROPOSALS FOR SCHOOL
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. ALTHOUGH <Organization>RESEARCH</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> WERE NOT INCLUDED IN THE 1964 <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization>
ACT, A UNIFIED <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> SYSTEM WAS BROUGHT <Organization>ABOUT</Organization> WITH THE INCLUSION OF SCHOOL
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization>. THE <Organization>IDEAL</Organization> OF UNITY IS NOW BEING SET ASIDE. <Organization>BUT</Organization> IF THE SCHOOL
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE TO BE TRANSFERRED TO THE SCHOOLS, THE MINIMUM DEMAND TO ENSURE
<Organization>THEIR</Organization> EXISTENCE MUST BE BY-LAWS GOVERNING <Organization>THEIR</Organization> RELATIONSHIP TO <Organization>PUBLIC</Organization>
<Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> AND A SEPARATE BUDGET. <Organization>THESE</Organization> REQUIREMENTS WERE CONFIRMED BY THE
MINISTER OF CULTURE. YET THE <Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BILL MAKES NO MENTION OF THEM AND REDUCES
THE SEPARATE BUDGET TO AN ACCOUNTING ITEM IN THE <Organization>LOCAL AUTHORITY</Organization> FINANCES. THE
BILL IS, THEREFORE, TOTALLY UNACCEPTABLE TO THE <Organization>DANISH LI BRARY ASSOCIATION</Organization>.
********************************************
Document 4576
SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN LOWER SAXONY.
     
LECTURE <Organization>GIVEN</Organization> TO THE CONFERENCE OF LIBRARIANS IN LOWER SAXONY, CELLE, APR 81.
SINCE 1979 THE <Organization>SCHOOL LIBRARY CENTRE</Organization> IN <Location>HANOVER</Location> HAS PROVIDED CENTRALISED
PURCHASING, PROCESSING AND ADVISORY SERVICES FOR THE SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Organization>ITS</Organization>
AREA. THE QUESTION AS TO WHETHER SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> SHOULD BE RUN BY LIBRARIANS
OR TEACHERS IS <Organization>STILL</Organization> DISPUTED. SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE PARTICULARLY IMPORTANT IN&apos;
THE <Organization>REFORMED GRAMMAR SCHOOL</Organization>, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THEY PROMOTE INDEPENDENT STUDY AND
COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN</Organization> TEACHERS AND PUPILS; SCHOOLS OPEN ALL <Organization>DAY</Organization>, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THE
<Organization>LIBRARY</Organization> BECOMES A <Organization>COMMUNICATION CENTRE</Organization> CATERING FOR LEISURE AS WELL AS
<Organization>ACADEMIC</Organization> ACTIVITY; <Organization>VOCATIONAL</Organization> <Organization>TRAINING</Organization> SCHOOLS, <Organization>WHERE</Organization> THEY CATER FOR STUDENTS
<Organization>FROM</Organization> ALL LEVELS OF <Organization>SECONDARY EDUCATION</Organization>, PROVIDE <Organization>SPECIAL</Organization> HELP FOR FOREIGN
STUDENTS WITH LANGUAGE PROBLEMS AND DEVELOP POSSIBILITIES FOR JOB FLEXIBILITY.
CLEAR, PREFERABLY BINDING, REGULATIONS <Organization>ON</Organization> COOPERATION <Organization>BETWEEN SCHOOL</Organization> AND
<Organization>PUBLIC</Organization> <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> ARE NEEDED.
********************************************
Document 4577
THE DEVELOPMENT OF SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN THE CZECHOSLOVAK <Organization>SOCIALIST</Organization> REPUBLIC.
     
SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IN <Location>CZECHOSLOVAKIA</Location> CAME TO LIFE <Organization>AT</Organization> THE BEGINNING OF THE LAST
CENTURY, <Organization>BUT THEIR FULL DEVELOPMENT</Organization> BEGAN AFTER WORLD WAR II. IN 1976 A
REORGANISATION TOOK PLACE AIMED <Organization>AT</Organization> <Organization>TEACHING</Organization> PUPILS TO FIND <Organization>OUT</Organization> <Organization>REQUIRED</Organization>
<Organization>INFORMATION</Organization> INDEPENDENTLY AND CREATIVELY. THE IMPLICATION OF <Organization>THIS</Organization> WITH <Organization>ITS</Organization>
<Organization>RESULTING</Organization> TASKS FOR SCHOOL <Organization>LIBRARIES</Organization> IS DISCUSSED.
